<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol1'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:22
    </extid>
    <num>
      22
    </num>
    <head>
      RURAL DEVELOPMENT COORDINATION
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            Sec. 301, 80
          </aref>
           Stat. 379, 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='5' sect='301' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/5/301.html'>
              5 U.S.C. 301
            </subref>
          </aref>
           and delegations of authority by the Secretary of Agriculture, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            38 FR 14944
          </aref>
          -14948, 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR 
            <subref title='7' part='2' sect='23' psec='' tq='N'>
              2.23
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , as amended by 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            38 FR 24633
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            38 FR 29020
          </aref>
          , Oct. 18, 1973, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='770'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:22:A:22.101
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        22.101
      </num>
      <head>
        The Rural Development Act of 1972 (Pub. L. 92-419).
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='22' sect='101' psec='' tq='N'>
              22.101
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          The Rural Development Act of 1972 (Pub. L. 92-419).
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The Rural Development Act of 1972 (Pub. L. 92-419), herein called the
          Act consists of six titles designed to facilitate the development of
          rural communities through a series of authorizations including grants,
          loans, and administrative provisions. This Act adds new statutory
          rural development coordination responsibilities to certain Federal
          departments and agencies to be carried out under the leadership of the
          Secretary of Agriculture.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='771'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:22:A:22.102
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        22.102
      </num>
      <head>
        Summary of authorities.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='22' sect='102' psec='' tq='N'>
              22.102
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Summary of authorities.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The purpose of this section is to give notice that certain authorities
          have been delegated by the Secretary of USDA agencies for
          implementation. New Secretarial delegations covering the Rural
          Development Act were effective May 31, 1973, and were published in the
          
          <E T='04'>
            Federal Register
          </E>
           June 7, 1973 (
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            38 FR 14944
          </aref>
          -14953). These are as follows:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Title I (
            <aref type='FREGIST'>
              38 FR 14948
            </aref>
            ). Responsibility delegated to the Assistant Secretary for Rural
            Development. The responsibility for administering loan and grant
            authorities is redelegated to the Farmers Home Administration,
            except the responsibility for administering loan authorities with
            respect to rural electrification and telephone facilities and
            service which has been redelegated to the Rural Electrification
            Administration.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Titles II (
            <aref type='FREGIST'>
              38 FR 14945
            </aref>
            -14948), III (
            <aref type='FREGIST'>
              38 FR 14945
            </aref>
            -14948), and V (
            <aref type='FREGIST'>
              38 FR 14945
            </aref>
            -14948. Responsibility delegated to the Assistant Secretary for
            Conservation, Research and Education and redelegated as follows:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Titles II (
            <aref type='FREGIST'>
              38 FR 14951
            </aref>
            -14952) and III (
            <aref type='FREGIST'>
              38 FR 14951
            </aref>
            -14952) to the Administrator, Soil Conservation Service.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Title V (
            <aref type='FREGIST'>
              38 FR 14949
            </aref>
            -14950) to the Administrators, Cooperative State Research Service
            and the Extension Service respectively.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Title IV (
            <aref type='FREGIST'>
              38 FR 14945
            </aref>
            -14948). Responsibility delegated to the Assistant Secretary for
            Conservation, Research and Education and redelegated (
            <aref type='FREGIST'>
              38 FR 14950
            </aref>
            -14951) to the Chief of the Forest Service.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Title VI, 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 603
            </aref>
             (
            <aref type='FREGIST'>
              38 FR 14948
            </aref>
            ). Responsibility delegated to Assistant Secretary for Rural
            Development and redelegated (
            <aref type='FREGIST'>
              38 FR 14953
            </aref>
            ) to the Administrator, Rural Development Service.
          </text>
        </P>
        <FP>
          The Rural Development Act recognizes that many Federal departments and
          agencies of the executive branch of government administer programs and
          provide services which are applicable to the needs of rural
          communities. 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            Section 603 of
          </aref>
           the Rural Development Act charges the Secretary of Agriculture with
          providing governmentwide leadership for, and with coordinating a
          nationwide rural development program. In such coordination, the
          Secretary shall seek measures that will achieve effective integration
          of relevant Federal services in rural areas as provided by Agriculture
          agencies and other Departments and agencies. This section also
          requires that the Secretary shall establish goals and report to the
          Congress on progress in complying with 
          <PRTPAGE P='511' />
          specified purposes of the Act. The Federal Regional Council will play
          a major role in coordination at the field level. An organic Act of the
          Department (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='2201' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/2201.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 2201
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ) has been amended to require the Secretary to add Rural Development
          to those purposes for which he is authorized to acquire and diffuse
          useful information.
        </FP>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='772'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:22:A:22.103
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        22.103
      </num>
      <head>
        Purpose.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='22' sect='103' psec='' tq='N'>
              22.103
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Purpose.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The purpose of these regulations is to establish the policies,
          procedures, and responsibilities required by 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 603 of
          </aref>
           the Rural Development Act.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='773'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:22:A:22.104
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        22.104
      </num>
      <head>
        General policy.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='22' sect='104' psec='' tq='N'>
              22.104
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General policy.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Federal implementation of the Act will be consistent with the
          President&apos;s policy of decentralized decisionmaking and
          administrative responsibility which gives fullest possible
          consideration to State and local rural development goals and
          priorities. As a result of 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            section 817(4
          </aref>
          ) of the Agriculture and Consumer Protection Act of 1973 (
          <aref target='_blank' title='Pub. L. 93-86' alt='Pub. L. 93-86' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d93:./list/bd/d93pl.lst:86%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Pub. L. 93-86
          </aref>
          ) which prohibits prior approval by any State officials of any loan or
          grant under any program authorized by title I of the Rural Development
          Act of 1972 (Pub. L. 92-419), it has been necessary to substantially
          modify the planned administration of programs under 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 603 of
          </aref>
           the Rural Development Act.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='774'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:22:B:22.201
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        22.201
      </num>
      <head>
        Coordination.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='22' sect='201' psec='' tq='N'>
              22.201
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Coordination.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The following identifies types and levels of coordination:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Washington level interdepartmental and interagency coordination for
            purposes of the Act.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Coordination for purposes of the Act among agencies within the U.S.
            Department of Agriculture.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Coordination among and between the field operations of Federal
            agencies for purposes of the Act.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Coordination for purposes of the Act between levels of field
            operations of the Federal government and State governments.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='775'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:22:B:22.202
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        22.202
      </num>
      <head>
        Federal unit responsibilities.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='22' sect='202' psec='' tq='N'>
              22.202
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Federal unit responsibilities.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The following Federal units have major responsibilities in
          implementing the Act.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Rural Development policy questions requiring resolution by the
            Committee on Community Development of the President&apos;s Domestic
            Council may be so referred by the Secretary of Agriculture, who will
            sit as a member and as Chairman of the Rural Development Committee.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Under Secretary of Agriculture will represent the Secretary in
            matters pertaining to rural development policy when such matters are
            of mutual concern to the Under Secretaries&apos; Group for Regional
            Operations (Executive Order 11647 as amended by E.O. 11731) and the
            Federal Regional Councils, or at such other times that he or the
            Secretary may deem appropriate.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Assistant Secretary of Agriculture for Rural Development will
            chair an Assistant Secretaries&apos; Working Group consisting of
            interdepartmental and interagency members from Agriculture, Health,
            Education, and Welfare, Housing and Urban Development, Defense,
            Labor, Commerce, Transportation, Environmental Protection Agency,
            Small Business Administration and others as appropriate. This
            working group will operate under the aegis of the Rural Development
            Committee of the Domestic Council. The purpose of this working group
            is:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To develop and recommend rural development policy applicable to
            more than one executive department or agency.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To develop cooperative procedures between and among executive
            departments and agencies in matters pertaining to rural development.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To devise effective rural development strategies and to bring
            Federal resources and services to bear toward their realization.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To advise the Under Secretaries&apos; Group on involvement of
            Federal Regional Councils in rural development activities.
          </text>
        </P>
        <FP>
          The Secretary of Agriculture may utilize the services of the Assistant
          Secretaries&apos; Working Group in performing his rural development
          functions for the 
          <PRTPAGE P='512' />
          Rural Development Committee of the Domestic Council.
        </FP>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Administrator, Rural Development Service, under the policy
            direction of the Assistant Secretary for Rural Development shall
            coordinate rural development activities under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 603 of
            </aref>
             the Rural Development Act as directed by the Secretary. In the
            fulfillment of such responsibilities, he is authorized to
            communicate directly with other Federal department and agency
            officials of corresponding levels of authority and with State and
            Federal Regional Council officials.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Federal Regional Councils shall have primary responsibility for
            interagency program coordination at the field level and will provide
            assistance to and liaison with States in promoting rural
            development. Federal attention to this type of cooperation and
            coordination will be emphasized. In addition, the Federal Regional
            Councils, operating within policy determined at the Washington
            level, shall be responsible for performing an oversight function to
            assess how well the machinery is working in carrying out the Rural
            Development Act authorities. Each Federal Regional Council shall
            create an appropriate management structure to accomplish the
            foregoing. This may include the creation of a Rural Development
            Committee. The Department of Agriculture will chair such Rural
            Development Committees or otherwise assume the lead in managing
            rural development activities of the Federal Regional Councils.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Procedures for the coordination of rural development activities
            will be consistent with the policies expressed herein and with any
            specific Federal guideline based on these regulations or on
            Executive Order 11647, as amended by Executive Order 11731.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Councils shall exercise authority under Executive Order 11647, as
            amended by Executive Order 11731, to promote in rural areas
            integrated program and funding plans involving several Federal
            agencies.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='776'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:22:B:22.203
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        22.203
      </num>
      <head>
        Major responsibilities under title VI, Sec. 603.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='22' sect='203' psec='' tq='N'>
              22.203
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Major responsibilities under title VI, 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            Sec. 603
          </aref>
          .
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Title VI, 
              <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
                section 603
              </aref>
            </E>
            (
            <E T='03'>
              b
            </E>
            ). (1) 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              Section 603(b) of
            </aref>
             the Rural Development Act charges the Secretary of Agriculture with
            providing leadership in the development of a nationwide rural
            development program. Included in this program would be pertinent
            Federal departments and agencies which might contribute to this
            rural development mission. In carrying out his responsibilities, the
            Secretary shall report annually, prior to September 1, to the
            Congress on rural development goals for employment, income,
            population, housing, and quality of community services and
            facilities. To carry out the provisions of the Act specified above,
            the following major responsibilities are identified:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Rural Development Committee of the Domestic Council will assume
            responsibility for interdepartmental policy formulation and
            resolution of issues pertaining to this section of the Act as
            determined by the Secretary of Agriculture. This committee consists
            of members of the Community Development Committee of the Domestic
            Council, to wit: The Secretary of Agriculture, Chairman of the Rural
            Development Committee; the Secretary of HUD, Chairman of the Urban
            Development Committee; the Secretary of Transportation, Chairman of
            the Transportation Policy Development Committee; the Secretaries of
            Treasury, Commerce, and Labor and the Director of OMB.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Secretary of Agriculture shall be responsible for Washington
            level coordination pursuant to this section of the Act.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             At the regional level, the Federal Regional Councils shall develop
            and implement procedures designed to identify and facilitate access
            to Federal resources appropriate for rural development purposes
            within States. Such procedures will be consistent with policies
            expressed or endorsed by the Under Secretaries&apos; Group. The
            Councils shall also be responsible for monitoring the effectiveness
            with which the Rural Development Act is implemented within their
            respective regions.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='iii_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Secretary of Agriculture is also authorized to initiate or
            expand research and development efforts related to solution of rural
            development problems including problems of rural water supply, rural
            sewage and solid 
            <PRTPAGE P='513' />
            waste management, and rural industrialization.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='iii_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Rural Development Service will operate a rural development
            research program and may also participate in rural development
            research in cooperation with Federal, State, and private research
            units.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Title VI, 
              <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
                section 603
              </aref>
            </E>
            (
            <E T='03'>
              c
            </E>
            ) 
            <E T='03'>
              of the Rural Development Act.
            </E>
             (1) Under guidance by the Under Secretaries&apos; Group, and under
            the leadership of the U.S. Department of Agriculture member on each
            of the Federal Regional Councils, the Rural Development Committees
            of the Federal Regional Councils or other Federal Regional Council
            mechanisms assigned to work with rural development, shall be
            responsible for proposing to the appropriate Federal and State
            agencies actions in such areas as:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Adjustment, where appropriate, of administrative boundaries used by
            field staffs of Federal and federally supported agencies to conform
            with boundaries of multicounty jurisdictions. “Multicounty
            jurisdictions” as used means substate planning districts or other
            combinations of county jurisdictions as designated by States for
            State planning purposes.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Co-location of field units of Federal agencies and consolidation of
            offices in the vicinity of principal centers of local government
            administration (including multicounty jurisdictional
            administration), to encourage increased cooperation within and among
            different governmental levels.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Exchange of personnel between Federal and State agencies under the
            Intergovernmental Personnel Act (Pub. L. 91-648), to supplement and
            broaden staffs administering rural development programs, and provide
            specific technical expertise for certain projects.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Interchange of personnel among Federal agencies for the purposes
            expressed in paragraph (b)(1)(ii) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='iv_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In addition, the U.S. Department of Agriculture member on the
            Federal Regional Councils shall, by July 31, of each year, report to
            the Assistant Secretary for Rural Development who shall in turn
            report to the Under Secretaries&apos; Group and the Congress on
            progress made in carrying out the programs outlined in paragraphs
            (b)(1)(ii) through (iv) of this section and plans for programs to be
            implemented during the following fiscal year. The first report will
            be due to the Assistant Secretary by July 31, 1974.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='777'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:22:B:22.204
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        22.204
      </num>
      <head>
        Rural development committees.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='22' sect='204' psec='' tq='N'>
              22.204
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Rural development committees.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          State rural development committees, consisting of USDA agency members
          and, in most instances, State governments and other Federal agency
          representatives are available to assist States in accomplishing their
          rural development objectives. Such assistance if requested by the
          State can take the form of technical assistance and cooperative
          services to States in carrying out their rural development priorities.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='778'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:22:B:22.205
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        22.205
      </num>
      <head>
        Allocation of loan and grant funds.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='22' sect='205' psec='' tq='N'>
              22.205
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Allocation of loan and grant funds.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Title I grant funds and approved loan funding levels will be
            allocated among States by a formula designed to ensure equitable
            treatment. This applies to amounts made available for business and
            industrial loans, water, sewer and other community facilities except
            electrical and telephone facilities provided by or through the Rural
            Electrification Administration.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             During the second half of the fiscal year, the Secretary of
            Agriculture shall review State and multicounty jurisdictional rural
            development programs and projects so that unused allocations may be
            shifted from one State to another so as to enable the obligation of
            all available funds prior to the end of the fiscal year.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The formula used for fund allocation will ensure that a minimum
            loan and grant level is established so that no State receives an
            amount too small to serve the purposes of the Act. A percentage of
            total loan and grant authority will be withheld from initial
            allocation to allow subsequent appropriate technical adjustments in
            amounts allocated to individual States.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Title V funds shall be distributed by the Secretary under the
            formula specified in the Act. Title V activities will be consistent
            with the principle that States and multicounty jurisdictions have
            responsibility for the rural development planning and priority
            setting functions.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='779'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:22:C:22.301
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        22.301
      </num>
      <head>
        Selection and designation.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='22' sect='301' psec='' tq='N'>
              22.301
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Selection and designation.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Procedures for implementing the Act are designed to give the fullest
          possible consideration to planning and development goals and
          strategies at the State and multicounty jurisdictional levels. The
          governing bodies of multicounty organizations should include
          representatives of local governments contained within the respective
          multicounty jurisdictions. State development strategies and priorities
          shall be fully considered in the Federal administration of Rural
          Development Act authorities.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='780'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:22:C:22.302
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        22.302
      </num>
      <head>
        Area eligibility.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='22' sect='302' psec='' tq='N'>
              22.302
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Area eligibility.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Eligibility for programs under the Act will be based on the criteria
          of community size and location of population as specified in the Act.
          State designations of eligible areas will be duly considered by the
          Federal government in the determination of eligibility for loan and
          grant assistance.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='781'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:22:C:22.303
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        22.303
      </num>
      <head>
        Cooperation with Federal Regional Councils.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='22' sect='303' psec='' tq='N'>
              22.303
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Cooperation with Federal Regional Councils.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          States are urged to establish and maintain close and cooperative
          relationships with the Federal Regional Councils which will be in a
          position to assist the States and multicounty jurisdictions in the
          identification and application of available resources. States may
          authorize direct communications and liaison between the Regional
          Councils and multicounty jurisdictions within States.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='782'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:22:C:22.304
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        22.304
      </num>
      <head>
        Multiyear planning and programming.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='22' sect='304' psec='' tq='N'>
              22.304
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Multiyear planning and programming.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          State and multicounty jurisdictions are encouraged to adopt multiyear
          planning and development programs. As administrative procedures for
          implementing the Act support the feasibility of such a process, these
          programs should consider joint State, Federal, and local budget
          planning factors and be refined to conform to the actual fund
          availability as annual budgets are finalized and allocated. Such
          programs, once initiated, will be extended by the annual addition of a
          new planning year until programs are completed or terminated.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='783'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:22:C:22.305
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        22.305
      </num>
      <head>
        Conformance with OMB Circular No. A-95.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='22' sect='305' psec='' tq='N'>
              22.305
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Conformance with OMB Circular No. A-95.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The State and multicounty jurisdictional rural development planning
          process must conform to the review requirements expressed in OMB
          Circular No. A-95 under parts I, III, and IV as appropriate.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='784'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:22:C:22.306
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        22.306
      </num>
      <head>
        Financing rural development planning.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='22' sect='306' psec='' tq='N'>
              22.306
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Financing rural development planning.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          States will be required to finance rural development planning through
          their own resources, revenue-sharing allocations, or the Department of
          Housing and Urban Development planning and management assistance
          program or other available Federal planning programs.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='785'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:22:C:22.307
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        22.307
      </num>
      <head>
        Program evaluation.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='22' sect='307' psec='' tq='N'>
              22.307
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Program evaluation.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The Department of Agriculture is responsible for continuous program
          evaluation to determine if individual projects and the entire program
          is cost effective in terms of reaching rural development goals. As a
          result, USDA is responsible for conducting and reporting an annual
          evaluation of selected rural development projects and the overall
          rural development program. USDA shall include as a part of its
          evaluation Federal Regional Council assessment of the effectiveness of
          interagency coordination and delivery of services within the overall
          rural development program. States and multicounty districts are
          encouraged to participate in the joint preparation of such program
          evaluations. Copies of such evaluations should be supplied to the
          Administrator, Rural Development Service, Department of Agriculture
          and to the Federal Regional Councils, in sufficient time so as to
          arrive not later than July 1. The initial evaluation, due July 1,
          1974, in addition to the requirements listed below, should include a
          background statement and should summarize first year program efforts
          and results. Annual evaluation should:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Describe the process used in planning, project selection and
            priority setting, and the criteria and process used in evaluating
            program effectiveness.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Describe the specific objectives of the programs.
            <PRTPAGE P='515' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Describe and assess the cost and effectiveness of projects being
            pursued within individual multicounty jurisdictions.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Express observations, conclusions and recommendations based on such
            evaluations which may contribute to the development of better
            management, coordination and planning procedures.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='786'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:22:C:22.308
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        22.308
      </num>
      <head>
        Project approval.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='22' sect='308' psec='' tq='N'>
              22.308
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Project approval.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          State and multicounty jurisdictional planning is a State and local
          prerogative. Federal agencies will be responsive to State rural
          development strategies and priorities. However, determination of
          eligibility and feasibility and final approval of individual projects
          involving Federal funds must remain with the Federal government
          consistent with the Act and implementing regulations.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='787'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:22:C:22.309
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        22.309
      </num>
      <head>
        Seeking Federal review.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='22' sect='309' psec='' tq='N'>
              22.309
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Seeking Federal review.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          States may, if they elect, submit multicounty development plans and
          proposals to the Federal Regional Councils and to the Rural
          Development Service, USDA, for review and comment. Such review will
          neither obligate the Federal government with respect to such programs
          nor require States to conform with suggestions supplied by the USDA or
          the Federal Regional Council.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>