<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol7'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:C:735
    </extid>
    <num>
      735
    </num>
    <head>
      REGULATIONS FOR THE UNITED STATES WAREHOUSE ACT
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='241' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/241.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 241
            </subref>
          </aref>
          <E T='03'>
            et seq.
          </E>
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            67 FR 50763
          </aref>
          , Aug. 5, 2002, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='6605'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:C:735:A:735.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        735.1
      </num>
      <head>
        Applicability.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='735' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              735.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Applicability.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The regulations of this part set forth the terms and conditions
            under which the Secretary of Agriculture through the Farm Service
            Agency (FSA) will administer the United States Warehouse Act (USWA
            or the Act) and sets forth the standards and the terms and
            conditions a participant must meet for eligibility to act under the
            USWA. The extent the provisions of this part are more restrictive,
            or more lenient, with respect to the same activities governed by
            State law, the provisions of this part shall prevail.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Additional terms and conditions may be set forth in applicable
            licensing agreements, provider agreements and other documents.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Compliance with State laws relating to the warehousing, grading,
            weighing, storing, merchandising or other similar activities is not
            required with respect to activities engaged in by a warehouse
            operator in a warehouse subject to a license issued in accordance
            with this part.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6606'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:C:735:A:735.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        735.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Administration.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='735' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              735.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Administration.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FSA will administer all provisions and activities regulated under
            the Act under the general direction and supervision of the
            FSA&apos;s Deputy Administrator, Commodity Operations (DACO), or a
            designee.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             DACO may waive or modify the licensing or authorization
            requirements or deadlines in cases where lateness or 
            <PRTPAGE P='50' />
            failure to meet such requirements does not adversely affect the
            licensing or authorizations operated under the Act.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             DACO will provide affected licensees or authorized providers with
            changes to their licensing or provider agreements before the
            effective date.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Licensing and authorization agreement updates will be available at:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             DACO&apos;s USWA website, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The following address: Deputy Administrator, Commodity Operations,
            Farm Service Agency, United States Department of Agriculture, STOP
            0550, 1400 Independence Avenue, SW, Washington, DC 20250-0550.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6607'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:C:735:A:735.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        735.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='735' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              735.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Words used in this part will be applicable to the activities
          authorized by this part and will be used in all aspects of
          administering the Act.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Access
          </E>
           means the ability, when authorized, to read, change, and transfer
          warehouse receipts or other applicable document information retained
          in a central filing system.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Agricultural product
          </E>
           means an agriculturally-produced product stored or handled for the
          purposes of interstate or foreign commerce, including a processed
          product of such agricultural product, as determined by DACO.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Central filing system (CFS)
          </E>
           means an electronic system operated and maintained by a provider, as
          a disinterested third party, authorized by DACO where information
          relating to warehouse receipts, USWA documents and other electronic
          documents is recorded and maintained in a confidential and secure
          fashion independent of any outside influence or bias in action or
          appearance.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Certificate
          </E>
           means a USWA document that bears specific assurances under the Act or
          warrants a person to operate or perform in a certain manner and sets
          forth specific responsibilities, rights, and privileges granted to the
          person under the Act.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Control of the facility
          </E>
           means ultimate responsibility for the operation and integrity of a
          facility by ownership, lease, or operating agreement.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Department
          </E>
           means the Department of Agriculture.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Electronic document
          </E>
           means any document that is generated, sent, received, or stored by
          electronic, optical, or similar means, including, but not limited to,
          electronic data interchange, advanced communication methods,
          electronic mail, telegram, telex, or telecopy.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Electronic warehouse receipt
          </E>
           (EWR) means a warehouse receipt that is authorized by DACO to be
          issued or transmitted under the Act in the form of an electronic
          document.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Examiner
          </E>
           means an individual designated by DACO for the purpose of examining
          warehouses or for any other activities authorized under the Act.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Financial assurance
          </E>
           means the surety or other financial obligation authorized by DACO
          that is a condition of receiving a license or authorization under the
          Act.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Force majeure
          </E>
           means severe weather conditions, fire, explosion, flood, earthquake,
          insurrection, riot, strike, labor dispute, act of civil or military,
          non-availability of transportation facilities, or any other cause
          beyond the control of the warehouse operator or provider that renders
          performance impossible.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Holder
          </E>
           means a person that has possession in fact or by operation of law of
          a warehouse receipt, USWA electronic document, or any electronic
          document.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            License
          </E>
           means a license issued under the Act by DACO.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Licensing agreement
          </E>
           means the document and any amendment or addenda to such agreement
          executed by the warehouse operator and FSA specifying licensing terms
          and conditions specific to the warehouse operator and the agricultural
          product licensed to be stored.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Non-storage agricultural product
          </E>
           means an agricultural product received temporarily into a warehouse
          for conditioning, transferring or assembling for shipment, or lots of
          an agricultural product moving through a warehouse for current
          merchandising or milling use, against which no warehouse receipts are
          issued and no storage charges assessed.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Official Standards of the United States
          </E>
           means the standards of the quality or condition for an agricultural
          product, fixed and established under (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='51' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/51.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 51
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ) the United States Cotton Standards Act, (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='71' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/71.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 71
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ) the United States 
          <PRTPAGE P='51' />
          Grain Standards Act, (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='1622' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1622.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 1622
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ) the Agricultural Marketing Act of 1946, or other applicable official
          United States Standards.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Other electronic documents
          </E>
           (OED) means those electronic documents, other than an EWR or USWA
          electronic document, that may be issued or transferred, related to the
          shipment, payment or financing of agricultural products that DACO has
          authorized for inclusion in a provider&apos;s CFS.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Person
          </E>
           means a person as set forth in 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='1' sect='1' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/1/1.html'>
              1 U.S.C. 1
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , a State; or a political subdivision of a State.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Provider
          </E>
           means a person authorized by DACO, as a disinterested third party,
          which maintains one or more confidential and secure electronic systems
          independent of any outside influence or bias in action or appearance.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Provider agreement
          </E>
           means the document and any amendment or addenda to such agreement
          executed by the provider and FSA that sets forth the provider&apos;s
          responsibilities concerning the provider&apos;s operation or
          maintenance of a CFS.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Receipt
          </E>
           means a warehouse receipt issued in accordance with the Act,
          including an electronic warehouse receipt.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Schedule of charges
          </E>
           means the tariff or uniform rate or amount charged by an authorized
          person for specific services offered or rendered under the Act.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Schedule of fees
          </E>
           means the fees charged and assessed by FSA for licensing, provider
          agreements or services furnished under the Act to help defray the
          costs of administering the Act, and as such are shown in a schedule of
          fees attached to the licensing or provider agreement.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Service license
          </E>
           means the document and any amendment to such document, issued under
          the Act by DACO to individuals certified competent by the licensed
          warehouse operator to perform inspection, sampling, grading
          classifying, or weighing services according to established standards
          and procedures, set forth in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='735' sect='202' psec='' tq='N'>
              735.202
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , at the specific warehouse license.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Stored agricultural products
          </E>
           means all agricultural products received into, stored within, or
          delivered out of the warehouse that are not classified as a
          non-storage agricultural product under this part.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            User
          </E>
           means a person that uses a provider&apos;s CFS.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            USWA electronic document
          </E>
           means a USWA electronic document initiated by DACO to be issued,
          transferred or transmitted that is not identified as an EWR or OED in
          the appropriate licensing or provider agreement or as determined by
          DACO.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Warehouse
          </E>
           means a structure or other authorized storage facility, as determined
          by DACO, in which any agricultural product may be stored or handled
          for the purpose of interstate or foreign commerce.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Warehouse capacity
          </E>
           means the maximum quantity of an agricultural product that the
          warehouse will accommodate when stored in a manner customary to the
          warehouse as determined by DACO.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Warehouse operator
          </E>
           means a person lawfully engaged in the business of storing or
          handling agricultural products.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Warehousing activities and practices
          </E>
           means any legal, operational, managerial or financial duty that a
          warehouse operator has regarding an agricultural product.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6608'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:C:735:A:735.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        735.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Fees.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='735' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              735.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Fees.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FSA will assess persons covered by the Act fees to cover the costs
            of administering the Act.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Warehouse operators, licensees, applicants, or providers must pay:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An annual fee as provided in the applicable licensing or provider
            agreement; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Fees that FSA assesses for specific services, examinations and
            audits, or as provided in the applicable licensing or provider
            agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The schedule of fees showing the current fees or any annual fee
            changes will be provided as an addendum to the applicable licensing
            or provider agreement or/and:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Will be available at DACO&apos;s USWA Web site, or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             May be requested at the following address: Deputy Administrator,
            Commodity Operations, Farm Service Agency, United States Department
            of 
            <PRTPAGE P='52' />
            Agriculture, STOP 0550, 1400 Independence Avenue, SW., Washington,
            DC 20250-0550.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             At the sole discretion of DACO, these fees may be waived.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6609'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:C:735:A:735.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        735.5
      </num>
      <head>
        Penalties.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          67 FR 50763
        </aref>
        , Aug. 5, 2002, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 17560
        </aref>
        , Apr. 7. 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='735' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              735.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Penalties.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          If a person fails to comply with any requirement of the Act, the
          regulations set forth in this part or any applicable licensing or
          provider agreement, DACO may assess, after an opportunity for a
          hearing as provided in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='735' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              735.8
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , a civil penalty:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Of not more than the amount specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='3' sect='91' psec='#b_10_i' tq='N'>
                3.91(b)(10)(i)
              </subref>
               of this title
            </aref>
             per violation, if an agricultural product is not involved in the
            violation; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Of not more than 100 percent of the value of the agricultural
            product, if an agricultural product is involved in the violation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            67 FR 50763
          </aref>
          , Aug. 5, 2002, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 17560
          </aref>
          , Apr. 7. 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6610'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:C:735:A:735.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        735.6
      </num>
      <head>
        Suspension, revocation and liquidation.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='735' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              735.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Suspension, revocation and liquidation.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             DACO may, after an opportunity for a hearing as provided in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='735' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
                735.8
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , suspend, revoke or liquidate any license or agreement issued under
            the Act, for any violation of or failure to comply with any
            provision of the Act, regulations or any applicable licensing or
            provider agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The reasons for a suspension, revocation or liquidation under this
            part include, but are not limited to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Failure to perform licensed or authorized services as provided in
            this part or in the applicable licensing or provider agreement;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Failure to maintain minimum financial requirements as provided in
            the applicable licensing or provider agreement;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Failure to submit a proper annual financial statement within the
            established time period as provided in the applicable licensing or
            provider agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Failure to maintain control of the warehouse or provider system.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The warehouse operator or provider requests closure, cancellation
            or liquidation. and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Commission of fraud against FSA, any depositor, EWR or OED holder
            or user, or any other function or operation under this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FSA retains USWA&apos;s full authority over a warehouse operator or
            provider for one year after such license revocation or provider
            agreement termination or until satisfaction of any claims filed
            against such warehouse operator or provider are resolved, whichever
            is later.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon DACO&apos;s determination that continued operation of a
            warehouse by a warehouse operator or an electronic provider system
            by a provider is likely to result in probable loss of assets to
            storage depositors, or loss of data integrity to EWR or OED holders
            and users. DACO may immediately suspend, close, or take control and
            begin an orderly liquidation of such warehouse inventory or provider
            system data as provided in this part or in the applicable licensing
            or provider agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any disputes involving probable loss of assets to storage
            depositors, or loss of data integrity to EWR or OED holders and
            users will be determined by DACO for the benefit of the depositors,
            or EWR or OED holders and users and such determinations shall be
            final.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6611'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:C:735:A:735.7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        735.7
      </num>
      <head>
        Return of suspended or revoked certificates of licensing or certificates
        of authorization.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='735' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              735.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Return of suspended or revoked certificates of licensing or
          certificates of authorization.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When a license issued to a warehouse operator or service license
            ends or is suspended or revoked by DACO, such certificates of
            licensing and applicable licensing agreement and certificates of
            authorization must be immediately surrendered and returned to DACO.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When an agreement with a provider ends or is suspended or revoked
            by DACO, such certificates of authorization and applicable provider
            agreement must be immediately surrendered to DACO
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6612'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:C:735:A:735.8
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        735.8
      </num>
      <head>
        Appeals.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='735' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              735.8
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Appeals.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any person who is subject to an adverse determination made under
            the Act may appeal the determination by filing a written request
            with DACO at the following address: Deputy Administrator, Commodity
            Operations, Farm Service Agency, United States Department of
            Agriculture, STOP 0550, 1400 
            <PRTPAGE P='53' />
            Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC 20250-0550.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any person who believes that they have been adversely affected by a
            determination under this part must seek review by DACO within
            twenty-eight calendar days of such determination, unless provided
            with notice by DACO of a different deadline.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The appeal process set forth in this part is applicable to all
            licensees and providers under any provision of the Act, regulations
            or any applicable licensing agreement as follows:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             DACO will notify the person in writing of the nature of the
            suspension, revocation or liquidation action;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The person must notify DACO of any appeal of its action within
            twenty-eight calendar days;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The appeal and request must state whether:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A hearing is requested,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The person will appear in person at such hearing, or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Such hearing will be held by telephone;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             DACO will provide the person a written acknowledgment of their
            request to pursue an appeal;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When a person requests an appeal and does not request a hearing
            DACO will allow that person:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_5_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To submit in writing the reasons why they believe DACO&apos;s
            determination to be in error,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_5_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Twenty-eight calendar days from the receipt of the acknowledgment
            to file any statements and documents in support of their appeal,
            unless provided with notice by DACO of a different deadline, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_5_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An additional fourteen calendar days to respond to any new issues
            raised by DACO in response to the person&apos;s initial submission,
            unless provided with notice by DACO of a different deadline;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the person requests to pursue an appeal and requests a hearing,
            DACO will:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_6_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notify the person of the date of the hearing,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_6_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Determine the location of the hearing, when the person asks to
            appear in person,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_6_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notify the person of the location of the hearing,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_6_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Afford the person twenty-eight calendar days from the receipt of
            the notification of the scheduling of the hearing to submit any
            statements and documents in support of the appeal, unless provided
            with notice by DACO of a different deadline, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_6_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Allow the person an additional fourteen calendar days from the date
            of the hearing to submit any additional material, unless provided
            with notice by DACO of a different deadline;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Determinations of DACO will be final and no further appeal within
            USDA will be available except as may be specified in the final
            determination of DACO; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A person may not initiate an action in any court of competent
            jurisdiction concerning a determination made under the Act prior to
            the exhaustion of the appeal process set forth in this section.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6613'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:C:735:A:735.9
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        735.9
      </num>
      <head>
        Dispute resolution and arbitration of private parties.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='735' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
              735.9
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Dispute resolution and arbitration of private parties.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A person may initiate legal action in any court of competent
            jurisdiction concerning a claim for noncompliance or an unresolved
            dispute with respect to activities authorized under the Act.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any claim for noncompliance or an unresolved dispute between a
            warehouse operator or provider and another party with respect to
            activities authorized under the Act may be resolved by the parties
            through mutually agreed-upon arbitration procedures or as may be
            prescribed in the applicable licensing or provider agreement. No
            arbitration determination or award will affect DACO&apos;s authority
            under the Act.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In no case will USDA provide assistance or representation to
            parties involved in an arbitration proceeding arising with respect
            to activities authorized under the Act.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6614'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:C:735:A:735.10
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        735.10
      </num>
      <head>
        Posting of certificates of licensing, certificates of authorization or
        other USWA documents.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='735' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
              735.10
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Posting of certificates of licensing, certificates of authorization or
          other USWA documents.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The warehouse operator must post, in a conspicuous place in the
            principal place where warehouse receipts are issued, any applicable
            certificate furnished by DACO that the warehouse operator is an
            authorized licensee under the Act.
            <PRTPAGE P='54' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Immediately upon receipt of their certificate of service licensing
            or any modification or extension thereof under the Act, the licensee
            and warehouse operator must jointly post the same, and thereafter,
            except as otherwise provided in the regulations in this part or as
            prescribed in the applicable licensing agreement, keep such
            certificate of licensing conspicuously posted in the office where
            all or most of the services are done, or in such place as may be
            designated by DACO.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The provider must post, in a conspicuous place in the principal
            place of business, any applicable certificate of authorization
            furnished by DACO that the provider is authorized to offer and
            provide specific services under the Act.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6615'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:C:735:A:735.11
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        735.11
      </num>
      <head>
        Lost or destroyed certificates of licensing, authorization or
        agreements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='735' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
              735.11
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Lost or destroyed certificates of licensing, authorization or
          agreements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          FSA will replace lost or destroyed certificates of licensing,
          certificate of authorization or applicable agreement upon satisfactory
          proof of loss or destruction. FSA will mark such certificates or
          agreements as duplicates.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6616'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:C:735:A:735.12
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        735.12
      </num>
      <head>
        Safe keeping of records.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='735' sect='12' psec='' tq='N'>
              735.12
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Safe keeping of records.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Each warehouse operator or provider must take necessary precautions to
          safeguard all records, either paper or electronic format, from
          destruction.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6617'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:C:735:A:735.13
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        735.13
      </num>
      <head>
        Information of violations.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='735' sect='13' psec='' tq='N'>
              735.13
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Information of violations.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Every person licensed or authorized under the Act must immediately
          furnish DACO any information they may have indicating that any
          provision of the Act or the regulations in this part has been
          violated.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6618'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:C:735:A:735.14
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        735.14
      </num>
      <head>
        Bonding and other financial assurance requirements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='735' sect='14' psec='' tq='N'>
              735.14
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Bonding and other financial assurance requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             As a condition of receiving a license or authorization under the
            Act, the person applying for the license or authorization must
            execute and file with DACO a bond or provide such other financial
            assurance as DACO determines appropriate to secure the person&apos;s
            compliance with the Act.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Such bond or assurance must be for a period of not less than one
            year and in such amount as required by DACO.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Failure to provide for, or renew, a bond or a financial assurance
            instrument will result in the immediate and automatic revocation of
            the warehouse operator&apos;s license or provider&apos;s agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If DACO determines that a previously accepted bond or other
            financial assurance is insufficient, DACO may immediately suspend or
            revoke the license or authorization covered by the bond or other
            financial assurance if the person that filed the bond or other
            financial assurance does not provide such additional bond or other
            financial assurance as DACO determines appropriate.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To qualify as a suitable bond or other financial assurance, the
            entity issuing the bond or other financial assurance must be subject
            to service of process in lawsuits or legal actions on the bond or
            other financial assurance in the State in which the warehouse is
            located.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6619'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:C:735:B:735.100
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        735.100
      </num>
      <head>
        Application.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='735' sect='100' psec='' tq='N'>
              735.100
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Application.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An applicant for a license must submit to DACO information and
            documents determined by DACO to be sufficient to conclude that the
            applicant can comply with the provisions of the Act. Such documents
            must include a current review or an audit-level financial statement
            prepared according to generally accepted accounting standards as
            defined by the American Institute of Certified Public Accountants.
            For any entity that is not an individual, a document that
            establishes proof of the existence of the entity, such as:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For a partnership, an executed partnership agreement; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For a corporation:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Articles of incorporation certified by the Secretary of State of
            the applicable State of incorporation;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bylaws; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Permits to do business; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For a limited partnership, an executed limited partnership
            agreement; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For a limited liability company:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_4_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Articles of organization or similar documents; and
            <PRTPAGE P='55' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_4_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Operating agreement or similar agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The warehouse facilities of an operator licensed under the Act
            must, as determined by DACO, be:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Physically and operationally suitable for proper storage of the
            applicable agricultural product or agricultural products specified
            in the license;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Operated according to generally accepted warehousing activities and
            practices in the industry for the applicable agricultural product or
            agricultural products stored in the facility; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subject to the warehouse operator&apos;s control of the facility
            including all contiguous storage space with respect to such
            facilities.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             As specified in individual licensing agreements, a warehouse
            operator must:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Meet the basic financial requirements determined by DACO; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Meet the net worth requirements determined by DACO;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In order to obtain a license, the warehouse operator must correct
            any exceptions made by the warehouse examiner at the time of the
            original warehouse examination.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             DACO may issue a license for the storage of two or more
            agricultural products in a single warehouse as provided in the
            applicable licensing agreements. The amount of the bond or financial
            assurance, net worth, and inspection and license fees will be
            determined by DACO in accordance with the licensing agreements
            applicable to the specific agricultural product, based upon the
            warehouses&apos; total capacity for storing such product, that would
            require:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The largest bond or financial assurance;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The greatest amount of net worth; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The greatest amount of fees.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6620'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:C:735:B:735.101
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        735.101
      </num>
      <head>
        Financial records and reporting requirements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='735' sect='101' psec='' tq='N'>
              735.101
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Financial records and reporting requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Warehouse operators must maintain complete, accurate, and current
            financial records that must be available to DACO for review or audit
            at DACO&apos;s request as may be prescribed in the applicable
            licensing agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Warehouse operators must, annually, present a financial statement
            as may be prescribed in the applicable licensing agreement to DACO.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6621'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:C:735:B:735.102
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        735.102
      </num>
      <head>
        Financial assurance requirements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='735' sect='102' psec='' tq='N'>
              735.102
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Financial assurance requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Warehouse operators must file with DACO financial assurances
            approved by DACO consisting of:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A warehouse operator&apos;s bond; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Obligations that are unconditionally guaranteed as to both interest
            and principal by the United States, in a sum equal at their par
            value to the amount of the bond otherwise required to be furnished,
            together with an irrevocable power of attorney authorizing DACO to
            collect, sell, assign and transfer such obligations in case of any
            default in the performance of any of the conditions required in the
            licensing agreement; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An irrevocable letter of credit issued in the favor of DACO with a
            term of not less than two years; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A certificate of participation in, and coverage by, an indemnity or
            insurance fund as approved by DACO, established and maintained by a
            State, backed by the full faith and credit of the applicable State,
            which guarantees depositors of the licensed warehouse full
            indemnification for the breach of any obligation of the licensed
            warehouse operator under the terms of the Act. If a warehouse
            operator files a bond or financial assurance in the form of a
            certification of participation in an indemnity or insurance fund,
            the certification may only be used to satisfy any deficiencies in
            assets above the minimum net worth requirement as prescribed in the
            applicable licensing agreement. A certificate of participation and
            coverage in this fund must be furnished to DACO annually; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Other alternative instruments and forms of financial assurance
            approved by DACO as may be prescribed in the applicable licensing
            agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The warehouse operator may not withdraw obligations required under
            this section until one year after license termination or until
            satisfaction of any claims against the obligations, whichever is
            later.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6622'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:C:735:B:735.103
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        735.103
      </num>
      <head>
        Amendments to license.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='56' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='735' sect='103' psec='' tq='N'>
              735.103
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Amendments to license.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          FSA will issue an amended license upon:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Receipt of forms prescribed and furnished by DACO outlining the
            requested changes to the license;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payment of applicable licensing and examination fees;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Receipt of bonding or other financial assurance if required in the
            applicable licensing agreement; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Receipt of a report on the examination of the proposed facilities
            pending inclusion or exclusion, if determined necessary by DACO.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6623'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:C:735:B:735.104
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        735.104
      </num>
      <head>
        Insurance requirements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='735' sect='104' psec='' tq='N'>
              735.104
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Insurance requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Each warehouse operator must comply fully with the terms of insurance
          policies or contracts covering their licensed warehouse and all
          products stored therein, and must not commit any acts, nor permit
          others to do anything, that might impair or invalidate such insurance.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6624'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:C:735:B:735.105
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        735.105
      </num>
      <head>
        Care of agricultural products.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='735' sect='105' psec='' tq='N'>
              735.105
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Care of agricultural products.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Each warehouse operator must at all times, including during any period
          of suspension of their license, exercise such care in regard to stored
          and non-storage agricultural products in their custody as required in
          the applicable licensing agreement.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6625'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:C:735:B:735.106
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        735.106
      </num>
      <head>
        Excess storage and transferring of agricultural products.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='735' sect='106' psec='' tq='N'>
              735.106
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Excess storage and transferring of agricultural products.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If at any time a warehouse operator stores an agricultural product
            in a warehouse subject to a license issued under the Act in excess
            of the warehouse capacity for which it is licensed, such warehouse
            operator must immediately notify DACO of such excess storage and the
            reason for the storage.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A warehouse operator who desires to transfer stored agricultural
            products to another warehouse may do so either by physical movement,
            by other methods as may be provided in the applicable licensing
            agreement, or as authorized by DACO.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6626'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:C:735:B:735.107
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        735.107
      </num>
      <head>
        Warehouse charges and tariffs.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='735' sect='107' psec='' tq='N'>
              735.107
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Warehouse charges and tariffs.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A warehouse operator must not make any unreasonable or exorbitant
            charge for services rendered.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A warehouse operator must follow the terms and conditions for each
            new or revised warehouse tariff or schedule of charges and rates as
            prescribed in the applicable licensing agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6627'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:C:735:B:735.108
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        735.108
      </num>
      <head>
        Inspections and examinations of warehouses.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='735' sect='108' psec='' tq='N'>
              735.108
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Inspections and examinations of warehouses.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Warehouse operators must permit any agent of the Department to
            enter and inspect or examine, on any business day during the usual
            hours of business, any licensed warehouse, the offices of the
            warehouse operator, the books, records, papers, and accounts.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Routine and special inspections and examinations will be
            unannounced.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Warehouse operators must provide safe access to all storage
            facilities.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Warehouse operators must inform any agent of the Department, upon
            arrival, of any hazard.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Agents of the Department must accomplish inspections and
            examinations of warehouses in a manner that is efficient and
            cost-effective without jeopardizing any inspection and examination
            integrity.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6628'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:C:735:B:735.109
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        735.109
      </num>
      <head>
        Disaster loss to be reported.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='735' sect='109' psec='' tq='N'>
              735.109
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Disaster loss to be reported.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          If at any time a disaster or loss occurs at or within any licensed
          warehouse, the warehouse operator must report immediately the
          occurrence of the disaster or loss and the extent of damage, to DACO.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6629'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:C:735:B:735.110
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        735.110
      </num>
      <head>
        Conditions for delivery of agricultural products.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='735' sect='110' psec='' tq='N'>
              735.110
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Conditions for delivery of agricultural products.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the absence of a lawful excuse, a warehouse operator will,
            without unnecessary delay, deliver the agricultural product stored
            or handled in the warehouse on a demand made by:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The holder of the warehouse receipt for the agricultural product;
            or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The person that deposited the agricultural product, if no warehouse
            receipt has been issued.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Prior to delivery of the agricultural product, payment of the
            accrued charges associated with the storage or handling of the
            agricultural product, including satisfaction of the warehouse
            operator&apos;s lien, must be made if requested by the warehouse
            operator.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When the holder of a warehouse receipt requests delivery of an
            agricultural product covered by the warehouse 
            <PRTPAGE P='57' />
            receipt, the holder must surrender the warehouse receipt to the
            warehouse operator before obtaining the agricultural product.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A warehouse operator must cancel each warehouse receipt surrendered
            to the warehouse operator upon the delivery of the agricultural
            product for which the warehouse receipt was issued and in accordance
            with the applicable licensing agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For the purpose of this part, unless prevented from doing so by
            force majeure, a warehouse operator will deliver or ship such
            agricultural products stored or handled in their warehouse as
            prescribed in the applicable licensing agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6630'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:C:735:B:735.111
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        735.111
      </num>
      <head>
        Fair treatment.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='735' sect='111' psec='' tq='N'>
              735.111
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Fair treatment.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Contingent upon the capacity of a warehouse, a warehouse operator
            will deal in a fair and reasonable manner with persons storing, or
            seeking to store, an agricultural product in the warehouse if the
            agricultural product is:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Of the kind, type, and quality customarily stored or handled in the
            area in which the warehouse is located;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Tendered to the warehouse operator in a suitable condition for
            warehousing; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Tendered in a manner that is consistent with the ordinary and usual
            course of business.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Nothing in this section will prohibit a warehouse operator from
            entering into an agreement with a depositor of an agricultural
            product to allocate available storage space.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6631'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:C:735:B:735.112
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        735.112
      </num>
      <head>
        Terminal and futures contract markets.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='735' sect='112' psec='' tq='N'>
              735.112
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Terminal and futures contract markets.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             DACO may issue service licenses to weigh-masters or their deputies
            to perform services relating to warehouse receipts that are
            deliverable in satisfaction of futures contracts in such contract
            markets or as may be prescribed in any applicable licensing
            agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             DACO may authorize a registrar of warehouse receipts issued for an
            agricultural product in a warehouse licensed under the Act that
            operates in any terminal market or in any futures contract market
            the official designated by officials of the State in which such
            market is located if such individual is not:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An owner or employee of the licensed warehouse;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The owner of, or an employee of the owner of, such agricultural
            product deposited in any such licensed warehouse; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             As may be prescribed in any applicable licensing or provider
            agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6632'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:C:735:C:735.200
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        735.200
      </num>
      <head>
        Service licenses.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='735' sect='200' psec='' tq='N'>
              735.200
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Service licenses.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FSA may issue to a person a license for:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Inspection of any agricultural product stored or handled in a
            warehouse subject to the Act;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Sampling of such an agricultural product;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Classification of such an agricultural product according to
            condition, grade, or other class and certify the condition, grade,
            or other class of the agricultural product;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Weighing of such an agricultural product and certify the weight of
            the agricultural product; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Performing two or more services specified in paragraphs (a)(1),
            (a)(2), (a)(3) or (a)(4) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each person seeking a license to perform activities described in
            this section must submit an application on forms furnished by DACO
            that contain, at a minimum, the following information:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The name, location and license number of the warehouses where the
            applicant would perform such activities;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A statement from the warehouse operator that the applicant is
            competent and authorized to perform such activities at specific
            locations; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Evidence that the applicant is competent to inspect, sample,
            classify, according to grade or weigh the agricultural product.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The warehouse operator will promptly notify DACO in writing of any
            changes with respect to persons authorized to perform such
            activities at the licensed warehouse.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6633'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:C:735:C:735.201
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        735.201
      </num>
      <head>
        Agricultural product certificates; format.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='58' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='735' sect='201' psec='' tq='N'>
              735.201
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Agricultural product certificates; format.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Each inspection, grade, class, weight or combination certificate
          issued under the Act by a licensee to perform such services must be:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In a format prescribed by DACO;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Issued and maintained in a consecutive order; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             As prescribed in the applicable licensing or provider agreement and
            authorized by DACO.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6634'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:C:735:C:735.202
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        735.202
      </num>
      <head>
        Standards of grades for other agricultural products.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='735' sect='202' psec='' tq='N'>
              735.202
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Standards of grades for other agricultural products.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Official Standards of the United States for any kind, class or grade
          of an agricultural product to be inspected must be used if such
          standards exist. Until Official Standards of the United States are
          fixed and established for the kind of agricultural product to be
          inspected, the kind, class and grade of the agricultural product must
          be stated, subject to the approval of DACO. If such standards do not
          exist for such an agricultural product, the following will be used:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State standards established in the State in which the warehouse is
            located,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the absence of any State standards, in accordance with the
            standards, if any, adopted by the local board of trade, chamber of
            commerce, or by the agricultural product trade generally in the
            locality in which the warehouse is located, or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the absence of the standards set forth in paragraphs (a) and (b)
            of this section, in accordance with any standards approved for the
            purpose by DACO.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6635'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:C:735:D:735.300
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        735.300
      </num>
      <head>
        Warehouse receipt requirements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='735' sect='300' psec='' tq='N'>
              735.300
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Warehouse receipt requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Warehouse receipts may be:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Negotiable or non-negotiable;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For a single unit, multiple units, identity preserved or commingled
            lot; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In a paper or electronic format that, besides complying with the
            requirements of the Act, must be in a format as prescribed in the
            applicable licensing or provider agreement and authorized by DACO.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The warehouse operator must:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             At the request of a depositor of an agricultural product stored or
            handled in a warehouse licensed under the Act, issue a warehouse
            receipt to the depositor;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Not issue a warehouse receipt for an agricultural product unless
            the agricultural product is actually stored in their warehouse at
            the time of issuance;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Not issue a warehouse receipt until the quality, condition and
            weight of such an agricultural product is ascertained by a licensed
            inspector and weigher;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Not directly or indirectly compel or attempt to compel the
            depositor to request the issuance of a warehouse receipt omitting
            the statement of quality or condition;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Not issue an additional warehouse receipt under the Act for a
            specific identity-preserved or commingled agricultural product lot
            (or any portion thereof) if another warehouse receipt representing
            the same specific identity-preserved or commingled lot of the
            agricultural product is outstanding. No two warehouse receipts
            issued by a warehouse operator may have the same warehouse receipt
            number or represent the same agricultural product lot;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When issuing a warehouse receipt and purposefully omitting any
            information, notate the blank to show such intent;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Not deliver any portion of an agricultural product for which they
            have issued a negotiable warehouse receipt until the warehouse
            receipt has been surrendered to them and canceled as prescribed in
            the applicable licensing agreement;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Not deliver more than 90% of the receipted quantity of an
            agricultural product for which they have issued a non-negotiable
            warehouse receipt until such warehouse receipt has been surrendered
            or the depositor or the depositor&apos;s agent has provided a
            written order for the agricultural product and the warehouse receipt
            surrendered upon final delivery; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Deliver, upon proper presentation of a warehouse receipt for any
            agricultural product, and payment or tender 
            <PRTPAGE P='59' />
            of all advances and charges, to the depositor or lawful holder of
            such warehouse receipt the agricultural product of such identity,
            quantity, grade and condition as set forth in such warehouse
            receipt.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the case of a lost or destroyed warehouse receipt, a new
            warehouse receipt upon the same terms, subject to the same
            conditions, and bearing on its face the number and the date of the
            original warehouse receipt may be issued.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6636'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:C:735:D:735.301
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        735.301
      </num>
      <head>
        Notification requirements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='735' sect='301' psec='' tq='N'>
              735.301
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Notification requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Warehouse operators must file with DACO the name and genuine signature
          of each person authorized to sign warehouse receipts for the licensed
          warehouse operator, and will promptly notify DACO of any changes with
          respect to persons authorized to sign.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6637'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:C:735:D:735.302
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        735.302
      </num>
      <head>
        Paper warehouse receipts.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='735' sect='302' psec='' tq='N'>
              735.302
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Paper warehouse receipts.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Paper warehouse receipts must be issued as follows:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             On distinctive paper specified by DACO;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Printed by a printer authorized by DACO; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Issued, identified and maintained in a consecutive order.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6638'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:C:735:D:735.303
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        735.303
      </num>
      <head>
        Electronic warehouse receipts.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='735' sect='303' psec='' tq='N'>
              735.303
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Electronic warehouse receipts.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Warehouse operators issuing EWR under the Act may issue EWR&apos;s
            for the agricultural product stored in their warehouse. Warehouse
            operators issuing EWR&apos;s under the Act must:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Only issue EWR&apos;s through one FSA-authorized provider annually;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Inform DACO of the identity of their provider, when they are a
            first time user of EWR&apos;s, 60 calendar days in advance of
            issuing an EWR through that provider. DACO may waive or modify this
            60-day requirement as set forth in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='735' sect='2' psec='#b' tq='N'>
                735.2(b)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Before issuing an EWR, request and receive from FSA a range of
            consecutive warehouse receipt numbers that the warehouse will use
            consecutively for issuing their EWR&apos;s;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When using an authorized provider, issue and cancel all warehouse
            receipts as EWR&apos;s;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Cancel an EWR only when they are the holder of the warehouse
            receipt;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be the holder of an EWR to correct information contained within any
            required data field;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Receive written authorization from FSA at least 30 calendar days
            before changing providers. Upon authorization, they may request
            their current provider to transfer their EWR data from its Central
            Filing System (CFS) to the CFS of the authorized provider whom they
            select; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notify all holders of EWR&apos;s by inclusion in the CFS at least
            30 calendar days before changing providers, unless otherwise
            required or allowed by FSA.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An EWR establishes the same rights and obligations with respect to
            an agricultural product as a paper warehouse receipt and possesses
            the following attributes:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The holder of an EWR will be entitled to the same rights and
            privileges as the holder of a paper warehouse receipt.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Only the current holder of the EWR may transfer the EWR to a new
            holder.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The identity of the holder must be confidential and included as
            information for every EWR.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Only one person may be designated as the holder of an EWR at any
            one time.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A warehouse operator may not issue an EWR on a specific
            identity-preserved or commingled lot of agricultural product or any
            portion thereof while another valid warehouse receipt representing
            the same specific identity-preserved or commingled lot of
            agricultural product remains not canceled. No two warehouse receipts
            issued by a warehouse operator may have the same warehouse receipt
            number or represent the same agricultural product lot.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An EWR may only be issued to replace a paper warehouse receipt if
            requested by the current holder of the paper warehouse receipt.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Holders and warehouse operators may authorize any other user of
            their provider or the provider itself to act on 
            <PRTPAGE P='60' />
            their behalf with respect to their activities with this provider.
            This authorization must be in writing, and acknowledged and retained
            by the warehouse operator and provider.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A warehouse operator not licensed under the Act may, at the option
            of the warehouse operator, issue EWRs in accordance with this
            subpart, except this option does not apply to a warehouse operator
            that is licensed under State law to store agricultural products in a
            warehouse if the warehouse operator elects to issue an EWR under
            State law.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6639'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:C:735:E:735.400
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        735.400
      </num>
      <head>
        Administration.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='735' sect='400' psec='' tq='N'>
              735.400
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Administration.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          This subpart sets forth the regulations under which DACO may authorize
          one or more electronic systems under which:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Electronic documents relating to the shipment, payment, and
            financing of the sale of agricultural products may be issued or
            transferred; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Electronic receipts may be issued and transferred.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6640'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:C:735:E:735.401
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        735.401
      </num>
      <head>
        Electronic warehouse receipt and USWA electronic document providers.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='735' sect='401' psec='' tq='N'>
              735.401
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Electronic warehouse receipt and USWA electronic document providers.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To establish a USWA-authorized system to issue and transfer
            EWR&apos;s and USWA electronic documents, each applicant must submit
            to DACO information and documents determined by DACO to be
            sufficient to determine that the applicant can comply with the
            provisions of the Act. Each provider operating pursuant to this
            section must meet the following requirements:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Have and maintain a net worth as specified in the applicable
            provider agreement;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Maintain two insurance policies; one for “errors and omissions” and
            another for “fraud and dishonesty.” Each policy&apos;s minimum
            coverage and maximum deductible amounts and applicability of other
            forms of financial assurances as set forth in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='735' sect='14' psec='' tq='N'>
                735.14
              </subref>
            </aref>
             will be prescribed in the applicable provider agreement. Each
            policy must contain a clause requiring written notification to FSA
            30 days prior to cancellation or as prescribed by FSA;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Submit a current review or an audit level financial statement
            prepared according to generally accepted accounting standards as
            defined by the American Institute of Certified Public Accountants;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For any entity that is not an individual, a document that
            establishes proof of the existence, such as:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_4_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For a partnership, an executed partnership agreement; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_4_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For a corporation:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='a_4_ii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Articles of incorporation certified by the Secretary of State of
            the applicable State of incorporation;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='a_4_ii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bylaws; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='a_4_ii_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Permits to do business; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_4_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For a limited partnership, an executed limited partnership
            agreement; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_4_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For a limited liability company:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='a_4_iv_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Articles of organization or similar documents; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='a_4_iv_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Operating agreement or similar agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Meet any additional financial requirements as set forth in the
            applicable provider agreement;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Pay user fees annually to FSA, as set and announced annually by FSA
            prior to April 1 of each calendar year; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Operate a CFS as a neutral third party in a confidential and secure
            fashion independent of any outside influence or bias in action or
            appearance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The provider agreement will contain, but not be limited to, these
            basic elements:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Scope of authority;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Minimum document and warehouse receipt requirements;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Liability;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Transfer of records protocol;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Records;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Conflict of interest requirements;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             USDA common electronic information requirements;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Financial requirements
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Terms of insurance policies or assurances;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provider&apos;s integrity statement;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_11'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (11)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Security audits; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_12'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (12)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Submission, authorization, approval, use and retention of
            documents.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             DACO may suspend or terminate a provider&apos;s agreement for cause
            at any time.
            <PRTPAGE P='61' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Hearings and appeals will be conducted in accordance with
            procedures as set forth in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='735' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
                735.6
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='735' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
                735.8
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Suspended or terminated providers may not execute any function
            pertaining to USDA, USWA documents, or USWA or State EWR&apos;s
            during the pendency of any appeal or subsequent to this appeal if
            the appeal is denied, except as authorized by DACO.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The provider or DACO may terminate the provider agreement without
            cause solely by giving the other party written notice 60 calendar
            days prior to termination.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each provider agreement will be automatically renewed annually on
            April 30th as long as the provider complies with the terms contained
            in the provider agreement, the regulations in this subpart, and the
            Act.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6641'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:C:735:E:735.402
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        735.402
      </num>
      <head>
        Providers of other electronic documents.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='735' sect='402' psec='' tq='N'>
              735.402
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Providers of other electronic documents.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To establish a USWA-authorized system to issue and transfer OED,
            each applicant must submit to DACO information and documents
            determined by DACO to be sufficient to determine that the applicant
            can comply with the provisions of the Act. Each provider operating
            pursuant to this section must meet the following requirements:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Have and maintain a net worth as specified in the applicable
            provider agreement;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Maintain two insurance policies; one for &apos;errors and
            omissions&apos; and another for &apos;fraud and dishonesty&apos;.
            Each policy&apos;s minimum coverage and maximum deductible amounts
            and applicability of other forms of financial assurances as set
            forth in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='735' sect='14' psec='' tq='N'>
                735.14
              </subref>
            </aref>
             will be prescribed in the applicable provider agreement. Each
            policy must contain a clause requiring written notification to FSA
            30 days prior to cancellation or as prescribed by FSA;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Submit a current review or an audit level financial statement
            prepared according to generally accepted accounting standards as
            defined by the American Institute of Certified Public Accountants;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For any entity that is not an individual, a document that
            establishes proof of the existence, such as:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_4_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For a partnership, an executed partnership agreement; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_4_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For a corporation:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='a_4_ii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Articles of incorporation certified by the Secretary of State of
            the applicable State of incorporation;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='a_4_ii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bylaws; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='a_4_ii_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Permits to do business; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_4_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For a limited partnership, an executed limited partnership
            agreement; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_4_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For a limited liability company:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='a_4_iv_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Articles of organization or similar documents; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='a_4_iv_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Operating agreement or similar agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Meet any additional financial requirements as set forth in the
            applicable provider agreement;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Pay user fees annually to FSA, as set and announced annually by FSA
            prior to April 1 of each calendar year; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Operate a CFS as a neutral third party in a confidential and secure
            fashion independent of any outside influence or bias in action or
            appearance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The provider agreement will contain, but not be limited to, these
            basic elements:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Scope of authority;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Minimum document and warehouse receipt requirements;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Liability;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Transfer of records protocol;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Records;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Conflict of interest requirements;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             USDA common electronic information requirements;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Financial requirements;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Terms of insurance policies or assurances;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provider&apos;s integrity statement;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_11'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (11)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Security audits; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_12'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (12)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Submission, authorization, approval, use and retention of
            documents.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             DACO may suspend or terminate a provider&apos;s agreement for cause
            at any time.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Hearings and appeals will be conducted in accordance with
            procedures as set forth in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='735' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
                735.6
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='735' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
                735.8
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Suspended or terminated providers may not execute any function
            pertaining to USDA, USWA documents, USWA or State EWR&apos;s or
            OED&apos;s during the pendency of any appeal or subsequent to this
            appeal if the appeal is denied, except as authorized by DACO.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each provider agreement will be automatically renewed annually on 
            <PRTPAGE P='62' />
            April 30th as long as the provider complies with the terms contained
            in the provider agreement, the regulations in this subpart, and the
            Act.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In addition to audits prescribed in this section the provider must
            submit a copy of any audit, examination or investigative report
            prepared by any Federal regulatory agency with respect to the
            provider including agencies such as, but not limited to, the
            Comptroller of the Currency, Department of the Treasury, the Federal
            Trade Commission, and the Commodity Futures Trading Commission.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6642'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:C:735:E:735.403
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        735.403
      </num>
      <head>
        Audits.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='735' sect='403' psec='' tq='N'>
              735.403
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Audits.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No later than 120 calendar days following the end of the
            provider&apos;s fiscal year, the provider authorized under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='735' sect='401' psec='' tq='N'>
                735.401
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='735' sect='402' psec='' tq='N'>
                735.402
              </subref>
            </aref>
             must submit to FSA an annual audit level financial statement and an
            electronic data processing audit that meets the minimum requirements
            as provided in the applicable provider agreement. The electronic
            data processing audit will be used by DACO to evaluate current
            computer operations, security, disaster recovery capabilities of the
            system, and compatibility with other systems authorized by DACO.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each provider will grant the Department unlimited, free access at
            any time to all records under the provider&apos;s control relating
            to activities conducted under this part and as specified in the
            applicable provider agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6643'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:C:735:E:735.404
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        735.404
      </num>
      <head>
        Schedule of charges and rates.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='735' sect='404' psec='' tq='N'>
              735.404
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Schedule of charges and rates.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A provider authorized under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='735' sect='401' psec='' tq='N'>
                735.401
              </subref>
               or 
              <subref title='7' part='735' sect='402' psec='' tq='N'>
                735.402
              </subref>
            </aref>
             must furnish FSA with copies of its current schedule of charges and
            rates for all services as they become effective.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Charges and rates assessed any user by the provider must be in
            effect for a minimum period of one year.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Providers must furnish FSA and all users a 60-calendar day advance
            notice of their intent to change any charges and rates.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>