<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol10'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1437
    </extid>
    <num>
      1437
    </num>
    <head>
      NONINSURED CROP DISASTER ASSISTANCE PROGRAM
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='7333' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/7333.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 7333
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='15' sect='714' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/15/714.html'>
              15 U.S.C. 714
            </subref>
          </aref>
          <E T='03'>
            et seq.
          </E>
          ; and 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='48' sect='1469' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/48/1469.html'>
              48 U.S.C. 1469
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            67 FR 12448
          </aref>
          , Mar. 19, 2002, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='12800'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1437:A:1437.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1437.1
      </num>
      <head>
        Applicability.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              1437.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Applicability.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Noninsured Crop Disaster Assistance Program (NAP) is intended
            to provide eligible producers of eligible crops coverage equivalent
            to the catastrophic risk protection level of crop insurance. NAP is
            designed to help reduce production risks faced by producers of
            commercial crops or other agricultural commodities. NAP will reduce
            financial losses that occur when natural disasters cause a
            catastrophic loss of production or where producers are prevented
            from planting an eligible crop.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The provisions contained in this part are applicable to eligible
            producers and eligible crops for which catastrophic coverage under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 508(b)
            </aref>
             the Federal Crop Insurance Act (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='1508' note='' psec='#b' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1508.html#b'>
                7 U.S.C. 1508(b)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ), as amended, or its successors, is not available.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The regulations of this part are applicable to the 2001 and
            subsequent crop years.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12801'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1437:A:1437.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1437.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Administration.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          67 FR 12448
        </aref>
        , Mar. 19, 2002, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          71 FR 13742
        </aref>
        , Mar. 17, 2006]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='722' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              1437.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Administration.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NAP is administered under the general supervision of the Executive
            Vice-President, CCC (who also serves as Administrator, Farm Service
            Agency), and shall be carried out by State and county FSA committees
            (State and county committees).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State and county committees, and representatives and their
            employees, do not have authority to modify or waive any of the
            provisions of the regulations of this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State committee shall take any action required by the
            regulations of this part that the county committee has not taken.
            The State committee shall also:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Correct, or require a county committee to correct, any action taken
            by such county committee that is not in accordance with the
            regulations of this part; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Require a county committee to withhold taking any action that is
            not in accordance with this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No provision or delegation to a State or county committee shall
            preclude the Executive Vice-President, CCC, or a designee, from
            determining any question arising under the program or from reversing
            or modifying any determination made by a State or county committee.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Deputy Administrator may authorize State and county committees
            to waive or modify deadlines (except statutory deadlines) in cases
            where lateness to file does not adversely affect operation of the
            program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Items including, but not limited to, application periods, coverage
            periods, application deadlines, fees, prices, yields, and payment
            factors established for NAP in accordance with this part that are
            used for similarly situated participants and eligible crops are not
            to be construed to be individual program eligibility determinations
            or extent of eligibility determinations and are, therefore, not
            subject to administrative review.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            67 FR 12448
          </aref>
          , Mar. 19, 2002, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            71 FR 13742
          </aref>
          , Mar. 17, 2006]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12802'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1437:A:1437.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1437.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          67 FR 12448
        </aref>
        , Mar. 19, 2002, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          71 FR 13742
        </aref>
        , Mar. 17, 2006; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          76 FR 4805
        </aref>
        , Jan. 27, 2011]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              1437.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The definitions and program parameters set out in this section shall
          be applicable for all purposes of administering the Noninsured Crop
          Disaster Assistance Program provided for in this part. Although the
          terms defined in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='718' tq='N'>
              718 of this title
            </subref>
          </aref>
           and 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
              1400 of this chapter
            </subref>
          </aref>
           shall also be applicable, the definitions set forth in this section
          shall govern for all purposes of administering the Program.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Administrative county office
          </E>
           means the county FSA office designated to make determinations, handle
          official records, and issue payments for the producer in accordance
          with 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR part 
            <subref title='7' part='718' tq='N'>
              718
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Animal Unit Days (AUD)
          </E>
           means an expression of expected or actual stocking rate for pasture
          or forage.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Application Closing Date
          </E>
           means the last date, as determined by CCC, producers can submit an
          application for coverage for noninsured crops for the specified crop
          year.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Catastrophic coverage
          </E>
           means a catastrophic risk protection (CAT) level of crop insurance
          available in accordance with 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 508(b) of
          </aref>
           the Federal Crop Insurance Act, as amended.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Controlled environment
          </E>
           means, with respect to those crops for which a controlled environment
          is expected to be provided, including but not limited to ornamental
          nursery, aquaculture (including ornamental fish), and floriculture, an
          environment in which everything that can practicably be controlled
          with structures, facilities, growing media (including but not limited
          to water, soil, or nutrients) by the producer, is in fact controlled
          by the producer.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Crop year
          </E>
           means the calendar year in which the crop is normally harvested or in
          which the majority of the crop would have been harvested. For value
          loss and other specific commodities, see the applicable subpart and
          section of this part. For crops for which catastrophic coverage is
          available, the crop year will be as defined by such coverage.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Fiber
          </E>
           means a slender and greatly elongated natural plant filament, e.g.
          cotton, flax, etc. used in manufacturing, as determined by CCC.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Final planting date
          </E>
           means the date which marks the end of the planting 
          <PRTPAGE P='723' />
          period for the crop and in particular the last day, as determined by
          CCC, the crop can be planted to reasonably expect to achieve 100
          percent of the expected yield in the intended harvest year or planting
          period.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Food
          </E>
           means a material consisting essentially of protein, carbohydrates,
          and fat used in the body to sustain growth, repair, and vital
          processes including the crops used for the preparation of food, as
          determined by CCC.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Good farming practices
          </E>
           means the cultural practices generally used for the crop to make
          normal progress toward maturity and produce at least the individual
          unit approved yield. These practices are normally those recognized by
          the National Institute of Food and Agriculture as compatible with
          agronomic and weather conditions.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Harvested
          </E>
           means the producer has removed the crop from the field by hand,
          mechanically, or by grazing of livestock. The crop is considered
          harvested once it is removed from the field and placed in a truck or
          other conveyance or is consumed through the act of grazing. Crops
          normally placed in a truck or other conveyance and taken off the crop
          acreage, such as hay are considered harvested when in the bale,
          whether removed from the field or not.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Industrial crop
          </E>
           means a commercial crop, or other agricultural commodity utilized in
          manufacturing. Industrial crops include caster beans, chia, crambe,
          crotalaria, cuphea, guar, guayule, hesperaloe, kenaf, lesquerella,
          meadowfoam, milkweed, plantago, ovato, sesame and other crops
          specifically designated by CCC.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Intended Use
          </E>
           means for a crop or a commodity, the end use for which it is grown
          and produced.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Multiple planted
          </E>
           means the same crop is planted and harvested during two or more
          distinct planting periods in the same crop year, as determined by CCC.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Normal harvest date
          </E>
           means the date harvest of the crop is normally completed in the
          administrative county, as determined by CCC.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Seed crop
          </E>
           means propagation stock commercially produced for sale as seed stock
          for eligible crops.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Seeded forage
          </E>
           means forage on acreage mechanically seeded with forage vegetation at
          regular intervals, at least every 7 years, in accordance with good
          farming practices.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            T-Yield
          </E>
           means the yield which is based on the county expected yield of the
          crop for the crop year and is used on an adjusted or unadjusted basis
          to calculate the approved yield for crops covered under the NAP when
          less than four years of actual, assigned, or appraised yields are
          available in the APH data base.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Transitional yield
          </E>
           means an estimated yield of that name provided in the Federal Crop
          Insurance Corporation (FCIC) actuarial table which is used to
          calculate an average/approved APH yield for crops insured under the
          Federal Crop Insurance Act when less than four years of actual,
          temporary, and/or assigned yields are available on a crop by county
          basis.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            67 FR 12448
          </aref>
          , Mar. 19, 2002, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            71 FR 13742
          </aref>
          , Mar. 17, 2006; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 4805
          </aref>
          , Jan. 27, 2011]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12803'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1437:A:1437.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1437.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Eligibility.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          67 FR 12448
        </aref>
        , Mar. 19, 2002, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          67 FR 62324
        </aref>
        , Oct. 7, 2002; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          71 FR 13742
        </aref>
        , Mar. 17, 2006]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              1437.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Eligibility.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Noninsured crop disaster assistance is available for loss of
            production or prevented planting of eligible commercial crops or
            other agricultural commodities:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Planted during the planting period, which means the time during
            which a majority of the crop is normally planted in the area, as
            determined by CCC, and is considered timely-planted for NAP
            purposes;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Prevented from being planted during the planting period;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Planted during the late planting period, which means the time after
            the planting period, during which certain crops, as determined by
            CCC, may be planted and remain eligible for reduced NAP coverage;
            and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Determined by CCC to be eligible crops:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_4_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For which catastrophic coverage is not available; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_4_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For specific perils not included under available catastrophic
            coverage.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When other conditions are met, NAP may be available for an eligible
            loss of:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any commercial crop grown for food, excluding livestock and their
            by-products;
            <PRTPAGE P='724' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any commercial crop planted and grown for livestock consumption,
            including but not limited to grain and forage crops; except for the
            2001 and preceding crop years assistance for forage produced on
            Federal- and State-owned lands is available only for seeded forage.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any commercial crop grown for fiber, excluding trees grown for
            wood, paper, or pulp products; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any commercial production of:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_4_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Aquacultural species (including ornamental fish);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_4_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Floricultural crops;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_4_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Ornamental nursery plants;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_4_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Christmas tree crops;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_4_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Turfgrass sod;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_4_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Industrial crops;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_4_vii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Seed crops, including propagation stock such as non-ornamental
            seedlings, sets, cuttings, rootstock, and others, as determined by
            CCC; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_4_viii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (viii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Sea grass and sea oats.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            67 FR 12448
          </aref>
          , Mar. 19, 2002, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            67 FR 62324
          </aref>
          , Oct. 7, 2002; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            71 FR 13742
          </aref>
          , Mar. 17, 2006]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12804'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1437:A:1437.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1437.5
      </num>
      <head>
        Coverage period.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          67 FR 12448
        </aref>
        , Mar. 19, 2002, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          71 FR 13742
        </aref>
        , Mar. 17, 2006]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              1437.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Coverage period.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The coverage period is the time during which coverage is available
            against loss of production of the eligible crop as a result of
            natural disaster.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The coverage period for annual crops, including annual forage
            crops, begins the later of 30 calendar days after the date the
            application for coverage is filed; or the date the crop is planted,
            not to exceed the late planting period; and ends on the earlier of
            the date harvest is complete; the normal harvest date of the crop in
            the area; the date the crop is abandoned; or the date the crop is
            destroyed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as otherwise specified in this part, the coverage period for
            biennial and perennial crops begins 30 calendar days after the
            application closing date; and ends as determined by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as otherwise specified in this part, the coverage period for
            value loss crops, including ornamental nursery, aquaculture,
            Christmas tree crops, ginseng, and turfgrass sod; and other eligible
            crops, including floriculture and mushrooms begins 30 calendar days
            after the application closing date; and ends the last day of the
            crop year, as determined by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The coverage period for honey begins 30 calendar days after the
            application closing date and ends the last day of the crop year, as
            determined by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The coverage period for maple sap begins 30 calendar days after the
            application closing date and ends on the earlier of the date harvest
            is complete; or the normal harvest date.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For biennial and perennial forage crops the coverage period begins
            the later of 30 calendar days after the application closing date;
            for first year seedings, the date the crop was planted; or the date
            following the normal harvest date. The coverage ends on the normal
            harvest date of the subsequent year.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            67 FR 12448
          </aref>
          , Mar. 19, 2002, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            71 FR 13742
          </aref>
          , Mar. 17, 2006]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12805'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1437:A:1437.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1437.6
      </num>
      <head>
        Application for coverage and service fee.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          67 FR 12448
        </aref>
        , Mar. 19, 2002, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          71 FR 13742
        </aref>
        , Mar. 17, 2006]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              1437.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Application for coverage and service fee.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             With respect to each crop, commodity, or acreage, producers must
            file an application for coverage under this part in the
            administrative county FSA office no later than the application
            closing date.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The service fee must be paid at the time of the application. The
            service fee is $100 per crop per administrative county, up to $300
            per producer per administrative county, but not to exceed $900 per
            producer.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The service fee will be applied per administrative county by crop
            definition and planting period, as determined by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Limited resource farmers may request that the service fee be waived
            and must request such a waiver prior to, or at the same time the
            application for coverage is filed. For this purpose, a “limited
            resource farmer” shall be given the meaning assigned by 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR 
              <subref title='7' part='457' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
                457.8
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            67 FR 12448
          </aref>
          , Mar. 19, 2002, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            71 FR 13742
          </aref>
          , Mar. 17, 2006]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12806'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1437:A:1437.7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1437.7
      </num>
      <head>
        Records.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          67 FR 12448
        </aref>
        , Mar. 19, 2002, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          71 FR 13742
        </aref>
        , Mar. 17, 2006]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              1437.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Records.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Producers must maintain records of crop acreage, acreage yields,
            and production for the crop for which an application for coverage is
            filed in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
                1437.5
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . For those crops 
            <PRTPAGE P='725' />
            or commodities for which it is impractical, as determined by CCC, to
            maintain crop acreage, yields or production, producers must maintain
            records, in addition to the available records required by this
            section, as may be required in subparts C, D and E, of this part.
            Producers must retain records of the production and acreage yield
            for a minimum of 3 years for each crop for which an application for
            coverage is filed in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
                1437.6
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . Producers may be selected on a random or targeted basis and be
            required to provide records acceptable to CCC to support the
            certification provided. For each harvested crop for which producers
            file an application for payment in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
                1437.10
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , producers must provide documentary evidence acceptable to CCC of
            production and the date harvest was completed, including production
            of crops planted after the planting period or late planting period.
            Such documentary evidence must be provided no later than the acreage
            reporting date for the crop in the subsequent crop year. Records of
            a previous crop year&apos;s production for inclusion in the actual
            production history database used to calculate an approved yield for
            the current crop year must be certified by the producer no later
            than the acreage reporting date for the crop in the current crop
            year. Production data provided after the acreage reporting date in
            the current crop year for the crop may be included in the actual
            production history data base for the calculation of subsequent
            approved yield calculations if accompanied by acceptable records of
            production as determined by CCC. Records of production acceptable to
            CCC may include:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Commercial receipts, settlement sheets, warehouse ledger sheets, or
            load summaries if the eligible crop was sold or otherwise disposed
            of through commercial channels provided the records are reliable or
            verifiable as determined by CCC; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Such documentary evidence such as contemporaneous measurements,
            truck scale tickets, and contemporaneous diaries, as is necessary in
            order to verify the information provided if the eligible crop has
            been fed to livestock, or otherwise disposed of other than through
            commercial channels, provided the records are reliable or verifiable
            as determined by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             During any crop year that a notice of loss is filed according to
            this part:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Producers of hand-harvested crops shall, in addition to providing
            acceptable production records according to this part, notify the
            administrative county office that harvest is complete. This
            notification must be made before deterioration or destruction of the
            crop residue and within 15 days after harvest is completed. If an
            appraisal of the crop acreage is determined necessary by CCC, the
            producer shall not destroy the crop residue until the crop acreage
            is released by an FCIC- or CCC-qualified loss adjustor. Producers
            may, at their expense, request that an appraisal by certified FCIC
            or CCC loss adjusters of hand-harvested crop acreage be completed
            during non-loss crop years in order to maintain accurate actual
            production history.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Producers shall not allow the gathering (gleaning) of any produce
            left in the field following normal harvest of the crop acreage until
            the crop acreage is released by a qualified CCC or FCIC loss
            adjustor, as determined by CCC. Except, crop acreage may be released
            by an authorized CCC representative for acceptable gleaning
            operations, as determined by CCC, when producers and gleaners agree
            to provide acceptable records, as determined by CCC, of the quantity
            of the crop gleaned.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Producers must provide verifiable evidence, as determined by CCC,
            of:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An interest in the commodity produced or control of the crop
            acreage on which the commodity was grown at the time of disaster;
            and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The authority of the applicable individual to execute program
            documents.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Reports of acreage planted or intended but prevented from being
            planted must be provided to CCC at the administrative FSA office for
            the acreage no later than the date specified by CCC for each crop
            and location. Reports of acreage filed beyond the date specified by
            CCC for the crop and location may, however, be considered timely
            filed if all the provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR 
              <subref title='7' part='718' sect='103' psec='' tq='N'>
                718.103
              </subref>
            </aref>
             are 
            <PRTPAGE P='726' />
            met. In the case of a crop-share arrangement, all producers will be
            bound by the acreage report filed by the landowner or operator
            unless the producer files a separate acreage report prior to the
            date specified by CCC for the crop and location. Reports of acreage
            planted or intended and prevented from being planted must include
            all of the following information:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Number of acres of the eligible crop in the administrative county
            (for each planting in the event of multiple planting) in which the
            producer has a share;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Zero acres planted when the producer&apos;s crop for which an
            application for coverage was filed, is not planted;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The producer&apos;s share of the eligible crop at the time an
            application for coverage was filed;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The FSA farm serial number;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The identity of the crop, practices, intended uses, and for forage
            crops, the predominant species or type and variety of the
            vegetation;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The identity of all producers sharing in the crop;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The date the crop was planted or planting was completed, including
            the age of the perennial crops; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The acreage intended but prevented from being planted.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Producers receiving a guaranteed payment for planted acreage, as
            opposed to receiving a payment only upon delivery of the production
            must provide documentation of any written or verbal contract or
            arrangement with the buyer to CCC. Net production, as determined by
            CCC, may be adjusted upward by the amount of production
            corresponding to the amount of the contract payment received.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Producers must provide documentation of any salvage value received
            by or made available for the quantity of the crop or commodity that
            cannot be marketed or sold in any market, as determined by CCC and
            any value received by or made available for a secondary use of the
            crop or commodity.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Producers requesting payment under this part must maintain records
            which substantiate gross revenue for the tax year preceding the crop
            year for which coverage is requested.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Producers requesting a waiver of service fees as a limited resource
            producer must maintain records which substantiate annual gross
            income for the two tax years preceding the crop year for which
            coverage is requested.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            67 FR 12448
          </aref>
          , Mar. 19, 2002, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            71 FR 13742
          </aref>
          , Mar. 17, 2006]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12807'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1437:A:1437.8
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1437.8
      </num>
      <head>
        Unit definition.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          71 FR 13743
        </aref>
        , Mar. 17, 2006]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              1437.8
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Unit definition.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The unit identifies the interest of the producer in the
            administrative county on the basis of the unique relationship of the
            owner to one or more operators. The unit is the foundation for all
            determinations of acreage, production, value, AUD, approved yields,
            requisite losses, payments, and other program requirements.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Separate and distinct units are:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             One-hundred percent interest as owner/operator;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Less than one-hundred percent interest as owner or operator; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Less than one-hundred percent interest, as owner or operator in an
            inverse relationship.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            71 FR 13743
          </aref>
          , Mar. 17, 2006]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12808'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1437:A:1437.9
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1437.9
      </num>
      <head>
        Causes of loss.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          71 FR 13743
        </aref>
        , Mar. 17, 2006]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
              1437.9
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Causes of loss.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be eligible for benefits under this part, an eligible cause of
            loss must result in:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A loss of production greater than 50 percent of the approved yield
            in accordance with subpart B of this part;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Prevented planting of greater than 35 percent of the intended crop
            acreage according to subpart C of this part;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A value loss of greater than 50 percent of the pre-disaster value
            according to subpart D of this part, or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An AUD loss of greater than 50 percent of the expected AUD
            according to subpart E of this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The quantity of the crop or commodity will not be reduced for any
            quality consideration unless a zero value is established.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Eligible causes of loss include:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Damaging weather occurring before or during harvest, including but
            not limited to drought, hail, excessive moisture, freeze, tornado,
            hurricane, excessive wind, or any combination thereof;
            <PRTPAGE P='727' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Adverse natural occurrence before or during harvest, such as
            earthquake, flood, or volcanic eruption; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A related condition, including but not limited to heat, insect
            infestation, or disease, which occurs as a result of an adverse
            natural occurrence or damaging weather occurring before or during
            harvest that directly causes, accelerates, or exacerbates the
            destruction or deterioration of an eligible crop, as determined by
            CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Due to the unique requirements, such as controlled environments,
            necessary for successful production of some crops and commodities;
            not all eligible causes of loss will apply to all crops and
            commodities.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Ineligible causes of loss include but are not limited to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Negligence or malfeasance of the producer;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Failure of the producer to reseed to the same crop during the same
            planting period in those areas and under such circumstances where it
            is customary;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Failure of the producer to follow good farming practices, as
            determined by CCC;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Water contained or released by any governmental, public, or private
            dam or reservoir project, if an easement exists on the acreage
            affected for the containment or release of the water;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Failure or breakdown of irrigation equipment or facilities;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except for tree crops and perennials and as provided for in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='201' psec='' tq='N'>
                1437.201
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , inadequate irrigation resources at the beginning of the crop year;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A loss of inventory or yield of aquaculture (including ornamental
            fish), floriculture or ornamental nursery stemming from drought or
            any failure to provide water, soil, or growing media to such crop
            for any reason; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any failure to provide a controlled environment or exercise good
            nursery practices when such controlled environment or practices are
            a condition of eligibility under this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            71 FR 13743
          </aref>
          , Mar. 17, 2006]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12809'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1437:A:1437.10
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1437.10
      </num>
      <head>
        Notice of loss, appraisal requirements, and application for payment.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          67 FR 12448
        </aref>
        , Mar. 19, 2002, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          71 FR 13743
        </aref>
        , Mar. 17, 2006]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
              1437.10
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Notice of loss, appraisal requirements, and application for payment.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When an eligible crop is damaged by an eligible cause of loss, at
            least one producer having a share in the unit must provide a notice
            of loss to CCC in the administrative FSA county office for the unit,
            within:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For prevented planting claims, 15 calendar days after the final
            planting date,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For low yield claims and allowable value loss, the earlier of:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             15 calendar days after the damaging weather or adverse natural
            occurrence, or date loss of the crop or commodity becomes apparent
            for low yield claims; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             15 calendar days after the normal harvest date.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For each crop for which a notice of loss is filed, producers must
            provide the following information:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Crop by type or variety, as applicable;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The cause of the crop damage;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Date the loss occurred, as applicable;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Date the damage or loss became apparent;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The existence of a guaranteed payment through a contract or
            agreement for planted acreage as opposed to delivery of production,
            if one exists;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Type of crop loss occurred, e.g. prevented planting or low yield;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Practices employed to grow the crop, e.g. irrigated or
            non-irrigated;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For prevented planting:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_8_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Total acreage intended to be planted to the crop in the
            administrative county;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_8_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Total acreage planted by the producer to the crop in the
            administrative county;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_8_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whether a purchase, delivery, or arrangement for purchase or
            delivery was made for seed, chemicals, fertilizer, etc; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_8_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             What and when land preparation measures, e.g. cultivation, etc.
            were completed and indicate what has been done or will be done with
            the acreage, e.g. abandoned, replanted, etc.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For low yield:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_9_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Total acreage planted by the producer to the crop in the
            administrative county;
            <PRTPAGE P='728' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_9_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Total acreage of the crop in the administrative county affected;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_9_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             What and when land preparation measures and practices, e.g.
            cultivation, planting, irrigated, etc. were completed before and
            after the loss; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_9_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             What will be done with the affected crop acreage, e.g. harvested,
            destroyed and replanted to a different crop, abandoned, etc.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any such other information requested by CCC to establish the loss.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A notice of loss provided beyond the time specified in paragraph
            (a) of this section may be considered timely filed if, at the
            discretion of CCC, provided at such time to permit an authorized CCC
            representative the opportunity to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Verify the information on the notice of loss by inspection of the
            specific acreage or crop involved; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Determine, based on information obtained by inspection of the
            specific acreage or crop involved, that an eligible cause of loss,
            as opposed to other circumstance, caused the claimed damage or loss.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Producers who file a notice of loss, using the appropriate CCC
            form, for crop acreage that will not be harvested as intended, such
            as abandoned, put to another use, replanted to the same or a
            different crop, or in the case of forage, acreage intended to be
            mechanically harvested that will be both mechanically harvested and
            grazed, must:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Not put the crop to another use or prepare the acreage for
            replanting or otherwise change any conditions of the crop or acreage
            until written notification of release of the crop or acreage is
            received from CCC;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Request, using the appropriate FSA form, an appraisal of the
            un-harvested acreage for potential production and release of the
            crop or acreage:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No less than 15 calendar days before replanting or in the case of
            forage intended to be mechanically harvested, grazing of the crop
            acreage.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Within 15 calendar days after the acreage is abandoned, for
            example, discontinued care for the crop or provided care so
            insignificant as to provide no benefit to the crop, as determined by
            CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No later than the normal harvest date of the crop, as determined by
            CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Request the loss adjustor on the day the initial appraisal is
            completed, or request in any manner of written correspondence
            received in the FSA administrative county office no later than 15
            calendar days after the request for initial appraisal is submitted,
            that the appraisal be deferred until the end of the growing season,
            the producer be permitted to establish representative sample areas
            according to paragraph (d)(4) of this section, and that the acreage
            be released immediately when:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Time is critical for replanting, or other urgent reasons; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Producers and loss adjustors cannot resolve disagreement with the
            initial appraisal of the acreage to be released.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Establish representative sample areas of the acreage according to
            the loss adjustor&apos;s instructions received on the day the
            initial appraisal is completed or, if the loss adjustor is not
            available, according to the FCIC Loss Adjustment Manual (LAM) and
            applicable FCIC crop handbooks. Report the size, number, and
            location of the areas in any manner of written correspondence
            received in the FSA administrative county office, no later than 15
            calendar days after requesting a deferred appraisal and before the
            acreage is put to another use or replanted. Representative sample
            areas must be of adequate construction and numbers to provide
            acceptable sampling results and maintained in sound condition, as
            determined by CCC, until released by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If possible, be present for the appraisal involving un-harvested
            crop acreage and accept or contest the results of the loss
            adjustor&apos;s appraisal. Producers unable to be present for the
            appraisal may contest the results of the appraisal in the FSA
            administrative county office.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For the 2005 and subsequent crop years, crop acreage for which an
            application for coverage has been filed, that is intended for
            production of forage seed and for which a notice of loss is filed
            indicating the crop acreage will not be harvested as seed, will be
            appraised for potential production of seed when producers provide
            CCC acceptable evidence of a contract to produce seed 
            <PRTPAGE P='729' />
            for the current crop year or acceptable records of acreage and seed
            production for three or more of the last 5 consecutive crop years,
            as determined by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Forage acreage for which a notice of loss is filed that was
            intended to be mechanically harvested but will be grazed and not
            mechanically harvested, or that was intended to be grazed but will
            be mechanically harvested and not grazed, does not require an
            appraisal or release of crop acreage.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Producers must apply for payments prior to the earlier of the:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Date an application for coverage is filed for the crop for the
            subsequent crop year; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Application closing date for the crop for the subsequent crop year.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            67 FR 12448
          </aref>
          , Mar. 19, 2002, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            71 FR 13743
          </aref>
          , Mar. 17, 2006]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12810'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1437:A:1437.11
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1437.11
      </num>
      <head>
        Average market price and payment factors.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          67 FR 12448
        </aref>
        , Mar. 19, 2002, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          71 FR 13744
        </aref>
        , Mar. 17, 2006]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
              1437.11
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Average market price and payment factors.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An average market price will be used to calculate assistance under
            this part and will be:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A dollar value per the applicable unit of measure of the eligible
            crop;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Determined on a harvested basis without the inclusion of
            transportation, storage, processing, marketing, or other
            post-harvest expenses, as determined by CCC;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Comparable with established FCIC prices; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Determined, as practicable, for each intended use of a crop type
            within a State, as determined by CCC, for a crop year.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For these purposes, where needed, an Animal-unit-days (AUD) value
            will be based on the national average price of corn and the daily
            requirement of 13.6 megacalories of net energy for maintenance of 1
            animal unit.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payment factors will be used to calculate assistance for crops
            produced with significant and variable harvesting expenses that are
            not incurred because the crop acreage was prevented planted or
            planted but not harvested, as determined by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An adjusted market price will be calculated based on the provisions
            in this section and others as may apply. A final payment price will
            be determined by multiplying, as appropriate, the average market
            price by the applicable payment factor (
            <E T='03'>
              i.e.
            </E>
            , harvested, unharvested, or prevented planting) by 55 percent or,
            by multiplying the applicable AUD (as adjusted, if adjusted) by 55
            percent.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            67 FR 12448
          </aref>
          , Mar. 19, 2002, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            71 FR 13744
          </aref>
          , Mar. 17, 2006]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12811'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1437:A:1437.12
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1437.12
      </num>
      <head>
        Crop definition.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='12' psec='' tq='N'>
              1437.12
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Crop definition.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For the purpose of providing benefits under this part, CCC will, at
            its discretion, define crops as specified in this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC may separate or combine types and varieties as a crop when
            specific credible information as determined by CCC is provided
            showing the crop of a specific type or variety has a significantly
            different or similar value when compared to other types or
            varieties, as determined by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC may recognize two or more different crops planted on the same
            acreage intended for harvest during the same crop year as two or
            more separate crops. The crop acreage may include a crop intended
            for harvest before planting of a succeeding crop or a succeeding
            crop interseeded with the preceding crop prior to intended harvest
            of the preceding crop. The acreage must be in an area where the
            practice is recognized as a good farming practice, as determined by
            CCC, and all crops are recognized by CCC as able to achieve the
            expected yield, as determined by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC may consider crop acreage that is harvested more than once
            during the same crop year from the same plant as a single crop. The
            acreage must be in an area where the practice is recognized as a
            good farming practice, as determined by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC may consider each planting period of multiple planted acreage
            as a separate crop. The acreage must be in an area where the
            practice is recognized as a good farming practice, as determined by
            CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC may define forage as separate crops according to the intended
            method of harvest, either mechanical harvest or grazed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Forage acreage intended to be grazed may be further defined as warm
            and cool season forage crops.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Forage acreage intended to be mechanically harvested may be defined
            
            <PRTPAGE P='730' />
            as a separate crop from grazed forage and may be separated based
            upon the commodity used as forage, to the extent such separation is
            allowed under paragraph (b) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Crop acreage intended for the production of seed may be considered
            a separate crop from other intended uses, as determined by CCC, if
            all the following criteria apply:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The specific crop acreage is seeded, or intended to be seeded, with
            an intent of producing commercial seed as its primary intended use;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             There is no possibility of other commercial uses of production from
            the same crop without regard to market conditions; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The growing period of the specific crop acreage is uniquely
            conducive to the production of commercial seed and not conducive to
            the production of any other intended use of the crop, (e.g.
            vernalization in a biennial crop such as carrots and onions) and
            that accommodation renders the possibility of production for any
            other intended use of the crop improbable.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12812'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1437:A:1437.13
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1437.13
      </num>
      <head>
        Multiple benefits.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='13' psec='' tq='N'>
              1437.13
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Multiple benefits.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a producer is eligible to receive payments under this part and
            benefits under any other program administered by the Secretary for
            the same crop loss, the producer must choose whether to receive the
            other program benefits or payments under this part, but shall not be
            eligible for both. The limitation on multiple benefits prohibits a
            producer from being compensated more than once for the same loss.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The limitation on multiple benefits in paragraph (a) of this
            section shall not apply in any respect to Emergency Loans under
            subtitle C of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='1961' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1961.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 1961
              </subref>
            </aref>
            <E T='03'>
              et seq
            </E>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The restriction on multiple benefits does not relieve the producer
            from the requirements of making a production and acreage report.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the other USDA program benefits are not available until after an
            application for benefits has been filed under this part, the
            producer may, to avoid this restriction on such other benefits,
            refund the total amount of the payment to the administrative FSA
            office from which the payment was received.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12813'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1437:A:1437.14
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1437.14
      </num>
      <head>
        Payment and income limitations.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='14' psec='' tq='N'>
              1437.14
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Payment and income limitations.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NAP payments shall not be made in excess of $100,000 per person per
            crop year under this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NAP payments shall not be made to a person who has qualifying gross
            revenues in excess of $2 million for the most recent tax year
            preceding the year for which assistance is requested. Qualifying
            gross revenue means:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             With respect to a person who receives more than 50 percent of such
            person&apos;s gross income from farming, ranching, and forestry
            operations, the annual gross income for the taxable year from such
            operations; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             With respect to a person who receives 50 percent or less of such
            person&apos;s gross income from farming, ranching, and forestry
            operations, the person&apos;s total gross income for the taxable
            year from all sources.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC will pay, for up to one year, simple interest on payments to
            producers which are delayed. Interest will be paid on the net amount
            ultimately found to be due, and will begin accruing on the 31st day
            after the date the producer signs, dates, and submits a properly
            completed application for payment on the designated form, or the
            31st day after a disputed application is adjudicated. Interest will
            be paid unless the reason for failure to timely pay is due to the
            producer&apos;s failure to provide information or other material
            necessary for the computation of payment, or there was a genuine
            dispute concerning eligibility for payment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Rules set out in 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
                1400
              </subref>
            </aref>
             shall apply in implementing the restrictions of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12814'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1437:A:1437.15
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1437.15
      </num>
      <head>
        Miscellaneous provisions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='15' psec='' tq='N'>
              1437.15
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Miscellaneous provisions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be eligible for benefits under this part, producers must be in
            compliance with the highly erodible land and wetlands provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='12' tq='N'>
                12 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='718' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
                718.11
              </subref>
               of this title
            </aref>
            , providing for ineligibility for benefits for offenses involving
            controlled substances, shall apply.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A person shall be ineligible to receive assistance under this part
            for the 
            <PRTPAGE P='731' />
            crop year plus two subsequent crop years if it is determined by the
            State or county committee or an official of FSA that such person
            has:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Adopted any scheme or other device that tends to defeat the purpose
            of a program operated under this part;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Made any fraudulent representation with respect to such program; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Misrepresented any fact affecting a program determination.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All amounts paid by CCC to any such producer, applicable to the
            crop year in which a violation of this part occurs, must be refunded
            to CCC together with interest and other amounts as determined
            appropriate to the circumstances by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All persons with a financial interest in the operation receiving
            benefits under this part shall be jointly and severally liable for
            any refund, including related charges, which is determined to be due
            CCC for any reason under this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the event that any request for assistance or payments under this
            part was established as result of erroneous information or a
            miscalculation, the assistance or payment shall be recalculated and
            any excess refunded with applicable interest.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The liability of any person for any penalty under this part or for
            any refund to CCC or related charge arising in connection therewith
            shall be in addition to any other liability of such person under any
            civil or criminal fraud statute or any other provision of law
            including, but not limited to: 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='18' sect='286' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/18/286.html'>
                18 U.S.C. 286
              </subref>
              , 
              <subref title='18' sect='287' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/18/287.html'>
                287
              </subref>
              , 
              <subref title='18' sect='371' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/18/371.html'>
                371
              </subref>
              , 
              <subref title='18' sect='641' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/18/641.html'>
                641
              </subref>
              , 
              <subref title='18' sect='651' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/18/651.html'>
                651
              </subref>
              , 
              <subref title='18' sect='1001' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/18/1001.html'>
                1001
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='18' sect='1014' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/18/1014.html'>
                1014
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ; 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='15' sect='714m' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/15/714m.html'>
                15 U.S.C. 714m
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ; and 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='31' sect='3729' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/31/3729.html'>
                31 U. S. C. 3729
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The appeal regulations at 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              parts 
              <subref title='7' part='11' tq='N'>
                11
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='780' tq='N'>
                780 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
             apply to decisions made according to this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any payment or portion thereof to any person shall be made without
            regard to questions of title under State law and without regard to
            any claim or lien against the crop, or proceeds thereof.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For the purposes of 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='28' sect='3201' note='' psec='#e' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/28/3201.html#e'>
                28 U.S.C. 3201(e)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , the Secretary hereby waives the restriction on receipt of funds or
            benefits under this program but only as to beneficiaries who as a
            condition of such waiver agree to apply the benefits to reduce the
            amount of the judgement lien.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              parts 
              <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
                1400, 1403
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='1404' tq='N'>
                1404 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
             apply to NAP.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='l'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (l)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the case of death, incompetence or disappearance of any person
            who is eligible to receive payments under this part, such payments
            will be disbursed in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='707' tq='N'>
                707 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12815'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1437:B:1437.101
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1437.101
      </num>
      <head>
        Actual production history.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          71 FR 13744
        </aref>
        , Mar. 17, 2006]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='101' psec='' tq='N'>
              1437.101
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Actual production history.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Actual production history (APH) is the unit&apos;s record of crop
          yield by crop year for the APH base period. The APH base period
          consists of ten crop years of actual yield, T-yield, assigned yield,
          and zero credited yield, immediately preceding the crop year for which
          an approved yield is calculated in accordance with this part. APH will
          be used, except as otherwise indicated in this part, as the basis for
          providing noninsured crop disaster assistance.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            71 FR 13744
          </aref>
          , Mar. 17, 2006]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12816'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1437:B:1437.102
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1437.102
      </num>
      <head>
        Yield determinations.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          67 FR 12448
        </aref>
        , Mar. 19, 2002, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          71 FR 13744
        </aref>
        , Mar. 17, 2006; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          76 FR 4805
        </aref>
        , Jan. 27, 2011]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='102' psec='' tq='N'>
              1437.102
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Yield determinations.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An actual yield is the total amount of harvested and appraised
            production from unit acreage for the crop year on a per-acre, or
            other basis, as applicable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A T-yield (county expected yield):
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is the Olympic average (disregarding the high and low yields) of
            historical yields of the crop in the county for the five consecutive
            crop years immediately preceding the previous crop year. For
            example, for the 2005 crop year, the five consecutive crop years
            immediately preceding the previous crop year would be 1999 through
            2003.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Will be the same as the FCIC transitional yield if crop insurance
            is available for the crop, (but not necessarily for the cause of
            loss if excluded by policy provisions), in the administrative
            county.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Will be calculated so as to be comparable to the FCIC transitional
            yield most reasonable to the area if crop insurance was available
            for the crop (but not necessarily for the cause of loss) in
            contiguous counties, but not in the immediate county.
            <PRTPAGE P='732' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Will be based on the most representative available historical
            information, as determined by CCC, from such sources as, but not
            limited to, actual acreage and production data of participating
            producers in the county; or in similar areas; National Agricultural
            Statistics Service data; National Institute of Food and Agriculture
            records, Federal Crop Insurance data, and credible non-government
            studies. Such data is based on the acreage intended for harvest.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             May be adjusted on an administrative county-wide basis for:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_5_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Yield variations due to different farming practices in the
            administrative county such as irrigated, non-irrigated, and organic
            practices; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_5_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Cultural practices when such practices in the administrative county
            are different from those used on acreage to establish the yield.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Will, for all land for those producers who have land physically
            located in multiple counties and administered in one county office,
            be based on the administrative county&apos;s expected yield for the
            crop.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             May be reduced, on a specific APH basis, when, as determined by
            CCC, it does not accurately reflect the productive capability of
            specific crop acreage.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Will be used in the actual production history base period when less
            than four consecutive crop years of actual, assigned, or
            zero-credited yields, as applicable, are available.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An assigned yield is:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Equal to 75 percent of the approved yield calculated for the most
            recent crop year for which the producer did not certify a report of
            production.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Used, after the first crop year an approved yield for the crop is
            calculated, in the actual production history base period when the
            producer reports acreage for the crop but fails to certify a report
            of production. Producers may have only one assigned yield in the
            actual production history base period.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             May be replaced with an actual yield when the producers provide a
            certification of production and acceptable production records for
            the applicable crop year in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
                1437.7
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             May not be used if the acreage of a crop in the administrative
            county in which the unit is located for the crop year increases by
            more than 100 percent over any year in the preceding seven crop
            years, or significantly from the previous crop years, as determined
            by CCC, unless producers provide:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_4_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Detailed documentation of production costs, acres planted, and
            yield for the crop year for which the producer is requesting
            assistance, or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_4_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If CCC determines the documentation is inadequate, proof that the
            eligible crop, had it been harvested, could have been marketed at a
            reasonable price.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             May be used, notwithstanding paragraph (c)(4) of this section, if:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_5_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The planted acreage for the crop has been inspected by a third
            party acceptable to CCC, or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_5_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The FSA county executive director, with the concurrence of the FSA
            state executive director, makes a recommendation for an exemption
            from the requirements and CCC approves such recommendation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A zero-credited yield:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Will be used in the applicable crop year of the actual production
            history base period for each crop year following the crop year
            containing an assigned yield, for which producers do not certify a
            report of acreage or production, as determined by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             May be replaced with an actual yield when the producer provides a
            certification of production and acceptable production records for
            the applicable crop year in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
                1437.7
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An approved yield:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is used in the calculation of the requisite loss and payment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is a simple average of a minimum of four base period crop year
            yields, 
            <E T='03'>
              i.e.
            </E>
            , actual yield, T-yield, assigned yield, or zero-credited yield. The
            base period is 10 crop years, except 5 crop years for apples and
            peaches, immediately preceding the crop year for which an approved
            yield is calculated, not including any crop year the crop was out of
            rotation, not planted, or prevented from being planted.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Shall be calculated according to the following criteria when the
            producer does not have at least four consecutive crop years of
            actual, assigned, or zero credited yields beginning with the most
            recent crop year.
            <PRTPAGE P='733' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If there are no certified acceptable production records of actual
            production for the most recent crop year, or zero credited or
            assigned yields in the producer&apos;s APH base period, and no
            formula provided for the producer under paragraphs (e)(3)(ii)
            through (iv) of this section, then the approved yield for the
            current crop year will be calculated on the simple average of 65
            percent of the applicable T-yield for each of the minimum four APH
            crop years.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If certified acceptable production records of actual production are
            available for only the most recent crop year and there are no zero
            credited or assigned yields in the producer&apos;s APH base period,
            the approved yield for the current crop year will be calculated on
            the simple average of the one actual yield plus 80 percent of the
            applicable T-yield for the remaining three of the minimum four APH
            crop years.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If certified acceptable production records of actual production are
            available for only the two most recent crop years and there are no
            zero credited or assigned yields in the producer&apos;s APH base
            period, the approved yield for the current crop year will be
            calculated on the simple average of the two actual yields plus 90
            percent of the applicable T-yield for the remaining two of the
            minimum four APH crop years.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_3_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If certified acceptable production records of actual production are
            available for only the three most recent crop years and there are no
            zero credited or assigned yields in the producer&apos;s APH base
            period, the approved yield for the current crop year will be
            calculated on the simple average of the three actual yields plus 100
            percent of the applicable T-yield for the remaining crop year of the
            minimum four APH crop years.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If, for one or more actual production history crop years used to
            establish the approved yield, the actual or appraised yield is less
            than 65 percent of the current crop year T-yield due to losses
            incurred in a disaster year, as determined by CCC, producers may
            request CCC replace the applicable yield with a yield equal to 65
            percent of the current crop year T-yield.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If approved yields were calculated for any of the 1995 through 2000
            crop years, and subsequently in that period production was not
            certified, producers may request CCC replace the missing yields for
            such years with yields equal to the higher of 65 percent of the
            current crop year T-yield or the missing crop years actual yield.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If producers add land in the farming operation and do not have
            available production records for the added land CCC will calculate
            an approved yield for the new unit by utilizing the actual
            production history yields for the existing unit. In the event the
            crop suffers a loss greater than 50 percent of the initial approved
            yield for the crop year and unit acreage has increased by more than
            75 percent of the historical average acreage, CCC may adjust the
            approved yield, as determined by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a producer is a new producer, the approved yield may be based on
            unadjusted T-Yields or a combination of actual yields and unadjusted
            T-Yields. A new producer is a person who has not been actively
            engaged in farming for a share of the production of the eligible
            crop in the administrative county for more than two APH crop years.
            Formation or dissolution of an entity which includes individuals
            with more than two APH crop years of production history during the
            base period does not qualify the new entity as a new producer for
            APH determination purposes.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A producer who has not shared in the risk of the production of the
            crop for more than two crop years during the base period, as
            determined by CCC, will have an approved yield calculated based on a
            combination of 100 percent of the applicable T-yield and any actual
            yield for the minimum crop years of the producer&apos;s APH base
            period. Producers who have produced the crop for one or two crop
            years must provide CCC, at the administrative FSA office serving the
            area in which the crop is located, a certification of production and
            production records for the applicable crop years in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
                1437.7
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Further adjustments may be made as necessary to accomplish the
            purposes of this program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            67 FR 12448
          </aref>
          , Mar. 19, 2002, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            71 FR 13744
          </aref>
          , Mar. 17, 2006; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 4805
          </aref>
          , Jan. 27, 2011]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12817'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1437:B:1437.103
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1437.103
      </num>
      <head>
        Late-planted acreage.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          71 FR 13745
        </aref>
        , Mar. 17, 2006]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='734' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='103' psec='' tq='N'>
              1437.103
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Late-planted acreage.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Producers planting crop acreage after the final planting date and
            during the late planting period, as determined by CCC, may be
            eligible for reduced coverage.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Multiple-planted crops, crops with a growing period of 60 calendar
            days or less, value-loss crops, and fall season small grain crops
            intended only for grain are not eligible for reduced coverage under
            late planting provisions.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For crops with a growing period of:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             61 to 120 calendar days and planted:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             One to five calendar days after the final planting date, production
            will be assigned equal to 5 percent of expected production of the
            applicable late-planted crop acreage regardless of the day planted.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Six to twenty calendar days after the final planting date,
            production will be assigned equal to 5 percent of expected
            production of the applicable late-planted crop acreage plus an
            additional one percent of the expected production of the applicable
            late-planted crop acreage for each day beyond five days.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             21 or more calendar days after the final planting date, production
            will be assigned equal to 50 percent of the producer&apos;s expected
            production of the applicable late-planted crop acreage.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             121 days and up and planted:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             One to five calendar days after the final planting date, production
            will be assigned equal to 5 percent of expected production of the
            applicable late-planted crop acreage regardless of the day planted.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Six to 25 days after the final planting date, production will be
            assigned equal to 5 percent of expected production of the applicable
            late-planted crop acreage plus an additional one percent of the
            applicable late-planted crop acreage for each day beyond five days.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             26 or more calendar days after the final planting date, production
            will be assigned equal to 50 percent of the producer&apos;s expected
            production of the applicable late-planted crop acreage.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            71 FR 13745
          </aref>
          , Mar. 17, 2006]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12818'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1437:B:1437.104
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1437.104
      </num>
      <head>
        Assigned production.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          71 FR 13745
        </aref>
        , Mar. 17, 2006]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='104' psec='' tq='N'>
              1437.104
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Assigned production.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When determining losses under this section, assigned production
            will be used to offset the loss of production when, as determined by
            CCC, any of the following has occurred:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The loss is a result of an ineligible cause of loss and the loss
            has not been otherwise accounted for.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The unit acreage was destroyed without consent notwithstanding 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='10' psec='#d' tq='N'>
                1437.10(d)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The producer has a contract to receive a guaranteed payment for all
            or a portion of the production, as opposed to or regardless of
            delivery of such production.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The crop is planted after the STC-established final planting date
            according to 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='103' psec='' tq='N'>
                1437.103
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Irrigation equipment is not capable of supplying adequate water to
            sustain the expected production of a normal irrigated crop.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For normal irrigated annual, biennial, and perennial crops, the
            irrigation practice is not used.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For normal irrigated annual and biennial crops, the supply of
            available water at the beginning of the crop year is not adequate.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For normal irrigated perennial crops, the supply of available water
            at the beginning of the crop year is not adequate as a result of an
            ineligible cause of loss.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            71 FR 13745
          </aref>
          , Mar. 17, 2006]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12819'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1437:B:1437.105
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1437.105
      </num>
      <head>
        Determining payments for low yield.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          67 FR 12448
        </aref>
        , Mar. 19, 2002. Redesignated and amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          71 FR 13745, 13746
        </aref>
        , Mar. 17, 2006]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='105' psec='' tq='N'>
              1437.105
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Determining payments for low yield.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except to the extent that the loss calculation provisions of other
            subparts apply, and subject to limitations set out elsewhere in this
            part and in this title and to the availability of funds, payments
            under this part shall be made on eligible crops with eligible losses
            by:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Multiplying the total eligible acreage planted to the eligible crop
            by the producers share, and subject to provisions for specific crops
            provided elsewhere in this part;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Multiplying the product of paragraph (a)(1) of this section by 50
            percent of the approved yield per acre for the commodity for the
            producer.
            <PRTPAGE P='735' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Multiplying the net production of the total eligible acreage by the
            producer&apos;s share;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subtracting the product of paragraph (a)(3) of this section from
            the product of paragraph (a)(2) of this section;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Multiplying the difference calculated under paragraph (a)(4) of
            this section by the final payment price calculated under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
                1437.11
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Multiplying the value of salvage and secondary use by the
            producer&apos;s share and subtracting the result from the result of
            paragraph (a)(5) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Further adjustments may be made as needed to accomplish the
            purposes and goals of the program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            67 FR 12448
          </aref>
          , Mar. 19, 2002. Redesignated and amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            71 FR 13745, 13746
          </aref>
          , Mar. 17, 2006]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12820'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1437:B:1437.106
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1437.106
      </num>
      <head>
        Honey.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          67 FR 12448
        </aref>
        , Mar. 19, 2002. Redesignated at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          71 FR 13745
        </aref>
        , Mar. 17, 2006]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='106' psec='' tq='N'>
              1437.106
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Honey.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Honey production eligible for benefits under this part includes
            table and non-table honey produced commercially.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All of a producer&apos;s honey will be considered a single crop,
            regardless of type or variety of floral source or intended use.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The crop year for honey production is the calendar year, January 1
            through December 31.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In addition to filing a report of acreage in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
                1437.7
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , honey producers must provide a record of colonies to CCC. The
            report of colonies must be filed before the crop year for which
            producers seek to maintain coverage. The report of colonies shall
            include:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The address of the producer&apos;s headquarters and FSA farm serial
            number, if available;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Names and shares of each person sharing in the honey produced from
            the unit;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The number of all colonies of bees belonging to the unit;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The names of counties in which colonies of bees are located as of
            the date of the report; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A certification of the number of colonies reported including all
            colonies from which production is expected.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The honey unit shall consist of all the producer&apos;s bee
            colonies, regardless of location.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Producers must designate a FSA office as the control office for the
            honey operation. Producers must complete the following actions only
            in the control office:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             File an application for coverage;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             File a report of colonies;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Report total unit production; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Request to change a unit&apos;s control office.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Actions that may be taken in any Administrative FSA office
            includes:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Designating or selecting another control office; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Filing a notice of loss in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
                1437.10
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Producers must notify the control office designated in accordance
            with paragraph (f) of this section within 30 calendar days of the
            date of:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any changes in the total number of colonies; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The movement of any colonies into any additional counties.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payments will be based on the amount of losses for this community
            in excess of a 50 percent loss level at a rate determined in accord
            with this part and the authorizing legislation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            67 FR 12448
          </aref>
          , Mar. 19, 2002. Redesignated at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            71 FR 13745
          </aref>
          , Mar. 17, 2006]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12821'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1437:B:1437.107
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1437.107
      </num>
      <head>
        Maple sap.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          67 FR 12448
        </aref>
        , Mar. 19, 2002. Redesignated at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          71 FR 13745
        </aref>
        , Mar. 17, 2006]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='107' psec='' tq='N'>
              1437.107
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Maple sap.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NAP assistance for maple sap is limited to maple sap produced on
            private property for sale as sap or syrup. Eligible maple sap must
            be produced from trees that:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Are located on land the producer controls by ownership or lease;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Are managed for production of maple sap;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Are at least 30 years old and 12 inches in diameter; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Have a maximum of 4 taps per tree according to the tree&apos;s
            diameter.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The crop year for maple sap production is the calendar year,
            January 1 through December 31.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If producers file an application for coverage in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
                1437.6
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , tree acreage containing trees from which maple sap is produced or
            is to be produced must be reported to CCC no later than the
            beginning of the crop year.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In addition to the applicable records required under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
                1437.7
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , producers must report the:
            <PRTPAGE P='736' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Total number of eligible trees on the unit;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Average size and age of producing trees; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Total number of taps placed or anticipated for the tapping season.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A maximum county-expected-yield for maple sap shall be 10 gallons
            of sap per tap per crop year unless acceptable documentary evidence,
            as determined by CCC, is available to CCC to support a higher
            county-expected-yield.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The average market price for maple sap must be established for the
            value of the sap before processing into syrup. If price data is
            available only for maple syrup, this data must be converted to a
            maple sap basis. The wholesale price for a gallon of maple syrup
            shall be multiplied by 0.00936 to arrive at the average market price
            of a gallon of maple sap.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The actual production history for maple sap shall be recorded on
            the basis of gallons of sap per tap.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The unit&apos;s expected production is determined by:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Multiplying the number of taps placed in eligible trees; by
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The approved per tap yield as determined in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='102' psec='' tq='N'>
                1437.102
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payments will be based on the amount of losses for this community
            in excess of a 50 percent loss level at a rate determined in accord
            with this part and the authorizing legislation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            67 FR 12448
          </aref>
          , Mar. 19, 2002. Redesignated at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            71 FR 13745
          </aref>
          , Mar. 17, 2006]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12822'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1437:B:1437.108-1437.200
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1437.108-1437.200
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='108-1437' psec='' tq='N'>
              1437.108-1437
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .200
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12823'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1437:C:1437.201
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1437.201
      </num>
      <head>
        Prevented planting acreage.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          71 FR 13746
        </aref>
        , Mar. 17, 2006]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='201' psec='' tq='N'>
              1437.201
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Prevented planting acreage.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In addition to the provisions of this section, the provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='718' sect='103' psec='' tq='N'>
                718.103
              </subref>
               of this title
            </aref>
             shall apply.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When determining losses under this section:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Producers must be prevented from planting more than 35 percent of
            the total eligible acreage intended for planting to the eligible
            crop and in the case of multiple planting, more than 35 percent of
            the total eligible acres intended to be planted within the
            applicable planting period.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Prevented planted acreage will be considered separately from
            low-yield losses of planted acreage of the same crop.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Acreage and units ineligible for prevented planting coverage
            includes, but is not limited to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Value-loss crops, including, but not limited to, Christmas trees,
            aquaculture, and ornamental nursery;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Tree crops and other perennials, unless:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The producer can prove resources unique to the planting of tree
            crops and other perennials were available to plant, grow, and
            harvest the crop, as determined by CCC; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC has approved the planting period for the crop;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Uninsured crop acreage that is unclassified for insurance purposes;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any acreage on which a crop was harvested, hayed, or grazed during
            the crop year;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Acreage of which the producer or any other person received a
            prevented planted payment for any crop for the same acreage,
            excluding share arrangements; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Acreage planted during the late-planting period.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            71 FR 13746
          </aref>
          , Mar. 17, 2006]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12824'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1437:C:1437.202
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1437.202
      </num>
      <head>
        Determining payments for prevented planting.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          67 FR 12448
        </aref>
        , Mar. 19, 2002, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          71 FR 13746
        </aref>
        , Mar. 17, 2006]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='202' psec='' tq='N'>
              1437.202
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Determining payments for prevented planting.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subject to limitations, availability of funds, and specific
            provisions dealing with specific crops, a payment for prevented
            planting will be determined by:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Adding the total planted and prevented-planted acres;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Multiplying the sum of paragraph (a)(1) of this section by .35;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subtracting the product of paragraph (a)(2) of this section from
            the total prevented planted acres;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Multiplying the producer&apos;s share by the approved yield by the
            positive result of paragraph (a)(3) of this section;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Multiplying the producer&apos;s share by the assigned production;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subtracting the product of paragraph (a)(5) of this section from
            the product of paragraph (a)(4) of this section; and
            <PRTPAGE P='737' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Multiplying the result of paragraph (a)(6) of this section by the
            final payment price calculated under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
                1437.11
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Yields for purposes of paragraph (a) of this section shall be
            calculated in the same manner as for low-yield claims.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            67 FR 12448
          </aref>
          , Mar. 19, 2002, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            71 FR 13746
          </aref>
          , Mar. 17, 2006]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12825'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1437:C:1437.203-1437.300
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1437.203-1437.300
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='203-1437' psec='' tq='N'>
              1437.203-1437
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .300
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12826'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1437:D:1437.301
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1437.301
      </num>
      <head>
        Value loss.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='301' psec='' tq='N'>
              1437.301
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Value loss.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Special provisions are required to assess losses and calculate
            assistance for a few crops and commodities which do not lend
            themselves to yield loss situations. Assistance for these
            commodities is calculated based on the loss of value at the time of
            disaster. The agency shall determine which crops shall be treated as
            value-loss crops, but unless otherwise announced, such crops shall
            be limited to those identified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='303' psec='' tq='N'>
                1437.303
              </subref>
            </aref>
             through 1437.309 as value loss crops. Lost productions of value
            loss crops shall be compensable only under this subpart.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The crop year for all value loss crops is October 1 through
            September 30.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Producers must file an application for coverage in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
                1437.6
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , and must:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provide a report of the crop, commodity, and facility to CCC for
            the acreage or facility, in a form prescribed by CCC, no later than
            the beginning of the crop year.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Maintain a verifiable inventory of the eligible crop throughout the
            crop year; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provide an accurate accounting of the inventory, as required by
            CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12827'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1437:D:1437.302
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1437.302
      </num>
      <head>
        Determining payments.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='302' psec='' tq='N'>
              1437.302
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Determining payments.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Subject to all restrictions and the availability of funds, value loss
          payments for qualifying losses will be determined by:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Multiplying the field market value of the crop before the disaster
            by 50 percent;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subtracting the sum of the field market value after the disaster
            and value of ineligible causes of loss from the result from
            paragraph (a)(1) of this section;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Multiplying the result from paragraph (a)(2) of this section by the
            producer&apos;s share;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Multiplying the result from paragraph (a)(3) of this section by 55
            percent plus whatever factor deemed appropriate to reflect savings
            from non-harvesting of the damaged crop or other factors as
            appropriate;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Multiplying the salvage value by the producer&apos;s share;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subtracting the result from paragraph (a)(5) of this section from
            the result from paragraph (a)(4) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12828'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1437:D:1437.303
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1437.303
      </num>
      <head>
        Aquaculture, including ornamental fish.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='303' psec='' tq='N'>
              1437.303
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Aquaculture, including ornamental fish.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Aquaculture is a value loss crop and is compensable only in accord
            with restrictions set in this section. Eligible aquacultural species
            shall only include:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any species of aquatic organisms grown as food for human
            consumption as determined by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Fish raised as feed for other fish that are consumed by humans; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Ornamental fish propagated and reared in an aquatic medium.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The aquacultural facility must be:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A commercial enterprise on private property;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Owned or leased by the producer, with readily identifiable
            boundaries; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Managed and maintained using good aquacultural growing practices.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Producers must:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Ensure adequate and proper flood prevention, growing medium,
            fertilization or feeding, irrigation and water quality, predator
            control, and disease control; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Have control of the waterbed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Eligible aquacultural species must be:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Placed in the facility and not be indigenous to the facility; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Kept in a controlled environment; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Planted or seeded in containers, wire baskets, net pens, or similar
            device designed for the protection and containment of the seeded
            aquacultural species.
            <PRTPAGE P='738' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the crop year in which a notice of loss is filed, producers may
            be required, at the discretion of CCC, to provide evidence that the
            aquacultural species are produced in a facility in accordance with
            paragraphs (b), (c) and (d) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12829'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1437:D:1437.304
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1437.304
      </num>
      <head>
        Floriculture.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='304' psec='' tq='N'>
              1437.304
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Floriculture.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Floriculture, except for seed crops as specified in paragraph (d)
            of this section, is a value loss crop and is compensable only in
            accord with restrictions set in this section. Eligible floriculture
            shall be limited to commercial production of:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Field-grown flowers, including flowers grown in containers or other
            growing medium maintained in a field setting according to industry
            standards, as determined by CCC; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Tubers and bulbs, for use as propagation stock of eligible
            floriculture plants; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Seed for propagation of eligible floriculture plants.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Floriculture does not include flowering plants indigenous to the
            location of the floriculture facility or acreage.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Eligible floriculture must be grown in a region or controlled
            environment conducive to the successful production of flowers,
            tubers, and bulbs, as determined by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Claims on losses on the production of flower seed for propagation
            of eligible floriculture plants will not be treated under “value
            loss” rules, but under the rules for normal production low yield
            crops under subpart B of this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The facility or acreage for eligible floriculture must be managed
            and maintained using good floriculture growing practices. At a
            minimum, producers are responsible for providing a controlled
            environment and must ensure adequate and proper fertilization,
            irrigation, weed control, insect and disease control, and rodent and
            wildlife control.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the crop year in which a notice of loss is filed, producers may
            be required, at the discretion of CCC, to provide evidence the
            floriculture is produced in accordance with paragraph (e) of this
            section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Flowers having any dollar value shall be counted as having full
            value for loss calculations. Damaged plants that are determined able
            to rejuvenate or determined to be merely stunted shall be counted as
            worth full value.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12830'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1437:D:1437.305
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1437.305
      </num>
      <head>
        Ornamental nursery.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='305' psec='' tq='N'>
              1437.305
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Ornamental nursery.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Eligible ornamental nursery stock is a value loss crop and is
            compensable only in accord with restrictions set out in this
            section. Eligible ornamental nursery stock is limited to field-grown
            and containerized decorative plants grown in a controlled
            environment for commercial sale.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The property upon which the nursery stock is located must be owned
            or leased by the producer.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The eligible nursery stock must be placed in the ornamental nursery
            facility and not be indigenous to the facility.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The facility must be managed and cared for using good nursery
            growing practices for the geographical region. At a minimum
            producers must provide a controlled environment and ensure adequate
            and proper flood prevention, growing medium, fertilization,
            irrigation, insect and disease control, weed control, rodent and
            wildlife control, and over-winterization storage facilities.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An ornamental plant having any value as an ornamental plant, or a
            damaged ornamental plant that may rejuvenate and re-establish value
            as an ornamental plant, shall be considered as worth full value
            based on the age or size of the plant at the time of disaster.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the crop year in which a notice of loss is filed, producers may
            be required, at the discretion of CCC, to provide evidence the
            ornamental nursery is maintained in accordance with this section.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12831'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1437:D:1437.306
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1437.306
      </num>
      <head>
        Christmas tree crops.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='306' psec='' tq='N'>
              1437.306
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Christmas tree crops.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A Christmas tree is a value loss crop and may generate a claim for
            benefits under this part only if the tree was grown exclusively for
            commercial use as a Christmas tree, and only if other requirements
            of this section are met.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The unit of measure for all Christmas tree crops is a plant.
            <PRTPAGE P='739' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A Christmas tree having any value as a Christmas tree, or a damaged
            Christmas tree that may rejuvenate and re-establish value as a
            Christmas tree, shall be considered as worth full value based on the
            age of the tree at the time of disaster.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12832'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1437:D:1437.307
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1437.307
      </num>
      <head>
        Mushrooms.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='307' psec='' tq='N'>
              1437.307
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Mushrooms.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Eligible mushrooms is a value loss crop and is only compensable in
            accord with the restrictions of this section. To be eligible, the
            mushrooms must be grown as a commercial crop in a facility with a
            controlled environment utilizing good mushroom growing practices.
            The facility must be located on private property either owned or
            leased by the producer.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The controlled environment for eligible mushrooms must include
            primary and backup systems for:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Temperature and humidity controls;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Proper and adequate lighting; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Positive air pressurization and filtration.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The growing medium must consist of a substrate (a habitat and
            nutrient base) sterilized by heat treatment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Good mushroom growing practices must be used, and they consist of
            proper and adequate insect and disease control and the maintenance
            of a sterile environment. Maintaining a sterile environment includes
            at a minimum:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Adequate hygiene;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Overall cleanliness;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Isolation or minimum contact procedures;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Use of footpaths; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Availability and frequent utilization of wash-down facilities.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the crop year in which a notice of loss is filed, producers may
            be required, at the discretion of CCC, to provide evidence the
            mushrooms are maintained in accordance with this section.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12833'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1437:D:1437.308
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1437.308
      </num>
      <head>
        Ginseng.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='308' psec='' tq='N'>
              1437.308
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Ginseng.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Ginseng is a value loss crop and is compensable only as allowed in
            this section. Ginseng is eligible only if:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The ginseng includes stratified seeds for use as propagation stock
            in a commercial ginseng operation or rootlet for commercial sale
            that are grown in a controlled, cultivatable environment on private
            property either owned or leased by the producer; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The ginseng is grown using good ginseng growing practices with all
            plant needs supplied and under control of the producer;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Ginseng will not be eligible to generate benefits under this part
            if it:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is indigenous to the facility;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is grown solely for medicinal purposes; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Includes wild ginseng rootlet that is harvested and transplanted
            from woodland grown ginseng.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Good ginseng growing practices must be followed, and include, but
            are not limited to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Adequate drainage;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Proper and adequate shade;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Accurate pH level;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Adequate and timely fertilization, including an adequate supply to
            ensure nutrient reserves to the ginseng plants and customary
            application equipment;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Adequate pest control, including but not limited to, weed, rodent,
            and wildlife control; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Disease control.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Ginseng producers must:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provide a report of inventory of all ginseng, as determined by CCC;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provide production and sales records necessary to determine the
            value of eligible ginseng;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Allow a CCC-certified loss adjustor to verify loss, including
            physically removing representative samples;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Maintain and provide, as determined by CCC, adequate records of
            fertilization, and pest and disease controls used or put into place
            during the crop year; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Possess a valid food processing license issued by the applicable
            State Department of Agriculture or equivalent and subject to food
            regulations administered by the Food and Drug Administration.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the crop year in which a notice of loss is filed, producers may
            be required, at the discretion of CCC, to provide evidence the
            ginseng was produced in accordance with this section.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12834'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1437:D:1437.309
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1437.309
      </num>
      <head>
        Turfgrass sod.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='309' psec='' tq='N'>
              1437.309
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Turfgrass sod.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Turfgrass sod is a value loss crop and is the upper stratum of soil
            bound by mature grass and plant roots into a 
            <PRTPAGE P='740' />
            thick mat produced in commercial quantities for sale.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Specific species, types or varieties of grass intended for
            turfgrass sod will be considered a separate crop without regard to
            other intended uses.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The unit of measure for all turfgrass sod shall be a square yard.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Turfgrass sod having any value shall be considered as worth full
            value.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In addition to the records required in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
                1437.7
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , producers seeking payment must provide information to CCC
            regarding the average number of square yards per acre and all
            unharvested areas.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12835'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1437:D:1437.310
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1437.310
      </num>
      <head>
        Sea grass and sea oats.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          67 FR 62324
        </aref>
        , Oct. 7, 2002]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='310' psec='' tq='N'>
              1437.310
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Sea grass and sea oats.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Sea grass and sea oats are value loss crops and eligibility will be
            limited to ornamental plants grown for commercial sale and seeds and
            transplants produced for commercial sale as propagation stock.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An eligible commodity under this section intended for sale on a
            commercial basis as:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An ornamental plant can produce a claim in the event of a loss due
            to a qualifying condition only in the same manner and subject to the
            same conditions as ornamental nursery stock under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='305' psec='' tq='N'>
                1437.305
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and such claims shall not, as such, be subject to the provisions of
            paragraphs (c) through (h) of this section, except to the extent
            that similar provisions apply to claims under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='305' psec='' tq='N'>
                1437.305
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Propagation stock (seed or transplant) can produce a claim under
            this part but only in accord with the provisions that follow in this
            section and subject to other conditions on payment as may be imposed
            elsewhere in this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For purposes of a loss calculation arising under paragraph (b)(2)
            of this section, the value of:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Seed will be determined on a yield basis made in accordance with
            subpart B of this part and average market price established in
            accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
                1437.11
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Transplant losses will be determined based on inventory that
            existed immediately before and after the disaster and average market
            price established in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
                1437.11
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Transplant producers must have up-to-date inventory and sales
            records and other documents, sufficient to document actual losses,
            as determined by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The land, waterbed, or facility in which the eligible commodity was
            located at the time of loss must:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be owned or leased by the producer;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Have readily identifiable boundaries; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be managed and maintained using acceptable growing practices for
            the geographical region, as determined by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The producer must have control of the land, waterbed, or facility
            and must ensure adequate and proper:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Flood prevention;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Growing medium;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Fertilization or feeding;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Irrigation and water quality;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Weed control;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Pest and disease control;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Rodent and wildlife control; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Over-winterization facilities, as applicable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The eligible commodity must be:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Grown in a region or controlled environment conducive to successful
            production, as determined by CCC; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Placed in the waterbed or facility in which the loss occurs and not
            be indigenous to the waterbed or facility.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Eligible commodities having any dollar value after the disaster
            shall be considered as having full value when making loss
            calculations. Also, damaged plants that do not have any value after
            the disaster but that can be rejuvenated or may, if not fully
            rejuvenated, reacquire value, shall be counted as worth full value
            as well.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the crop year in which a notice of loss is filed, producers may
            be required, at the discretion of CCC, to provide evidence that the
            eligible commodity was produced in accordance with paragraphs (e),
            (f), and (g) of this section and other provisions of this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            67 FR 62324
          </aref>
          , Oct. 7, 2002]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12836'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1437:D:1437.311-1437.400
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1437.311-1437.400
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='741' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='311-1437' psec='' tq='N'>
              1437.311-1437
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .400
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12837'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1437:E:1437.401
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1437.401
      </num>
      <head>
        Forage.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          67 FR 12448
        </aref>
        , Mar. 19, 2002, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          71 FR 13746
        </aref>
        , Mar. 17, 2006]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='401' psec='' tq='N'>
              1437.401
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Forage.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Forage eligible for benefits under this part is limited to mature
            vegetation, as determined by CCC, produced in a commercial operation
            in three or more of the last five crop years, except producers who
            have not produced forage for the minimum period in order to preserve
            vegetation and prevent erosion, or otherwise mitigate the impact of
            disaster conditions, as determined by CCC, shall not be penalized.
            Benefits are not available for first-year seeding of alfalfa and
            similar vegetation when production is not produced in the seeding
            year, as determined by CCC. The commercial operation must use
            acceptable farming, pasture and range management practices for the
            location necessary to sustain sufficient quality and quantity of the
            vegetation so as to be suitable for grazing livestock or mechanical
            harvest as hay or seed. Forage to be mechanically harvested shall be
            treated under the rules for low-yield crops as calculated under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='103' psec='' tq='N'>
                1437.103
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , except claims on forage for grazing benefits will be determined
            according to paragraph (f) of this section. The provisions in this
            subpart, however, shall govern for all claims including forage for
            mechanical harvest.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Producers of forage must, in addition to the records required in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
                1437.7
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , specify the intended method of harvest of all acreage intended as
            forage for livestock consumption as either mechanically or grazed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Producers must, in the administrative FSA office for the unit,
            request an appraisal prior to the onset of grazing of any intended
            mechanically harvested forage acreage that will be both mechanically
            harvested and grazed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Forage acreage reported to CCC as intended to be mechanically
            harvested, but which is, instead, subsequently grazed, will be
            considered, for crop definition purposes, as mechanically harvested.
            Expected production of the specific acreage will be calculated on
            the basis of carrying capacity. The loss of such grazed forage shall
            be determined according to paragraph (f) of this section. Except,
            beginning with the 2005 crop year, for acreage intended to be
            mechanically harvested which is instead, subsequently grazed, the
            loss of intended mechanically harvested forage may alternatively be
            determined based on a review of acceptable production evidence or
            appraisal of the specific crop acreage. As part of the payment
            computation for this loss, intended mechanically harvested forage
            crop acreage that is not mechanically harvested, but instead grazed,
            shall be deemed to be un-harvested for the purposes of determining a
            payment factor.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Small grain forage is the specific acreage of wheat, barley, oats,
            triticale, or rye intended for use as forage. Small grain forage
            shall be considered separate crops and distinct from any other
            forage commodities and other intended uses of the small grain
            commodity. In addition to the records required in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
                1437.7
              </subref>
            </aref>
             producers must specify whether the intended forage crop is intended
            for fall/winter, spring, or total season forage. In addition to
            other eligibility requirements, CCC will consider other factors,
            such as, water sources and available fencing, and adequate
            fertilization to determine small grain forage eligibility, yields,
            and production.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC will establish forage losses of acreage intended to be grazed
            including, in some cases, acreage intended to be mechanically
            harvested but instead subsequently grazed, on the basis of:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The percentages of loss of similar mechanically-harvested forage
            acreage on the farm, or on similar farms in the area when approved
            yields have been calculated to determine loss, or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Where there is no similar mechanically-harvested forage acreage on
            the farm or similar farms in the area, the collective percentage of
            loss as determined by CCC for the geographical region after
            consideration of at least two independent assessments of grazed
            forage acreage conditions. The assessments shall be completed by
            forage or range specialists in Federal, State, and local government
            agencies, educational institutions, and private companies not having
            a financial interest in the outcome of the assessment. Neither the
            assessments themselves, nor collective 
            <PRTPAGE P='742' />
            loss percentages established pursuant thereto are subject to appeal.
            CCC&apos;s determinations of geographical area for assessments and
            collective grazing loss are generally applicable to all similarly
            situated participants farming in such defined geographical region.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            67 FR 12448
          </aref>
          , Mar. 19, 2002, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            71 FR 13746
          </aref>
          , Mar. 17, 2006]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12838'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1437:E:1437.402
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1437.402
      </num>
      <head>
        Carrying capacity.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='402' psec='' tq='N'>
              1437.402
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Carrying capacity.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC will establish a carrying capacity for all grazed forage
            present in the county for purposes of administering this program and
            to that end:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Multiple carrying capacities may be determined for a specific
            vegetation if factors, such as soil type, elevation, and topography,
            result in a significant difference of carrying capacity within the
            county.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC may establish separate carrying capacities for irrigated and
            non-irrigated forage acreage when acreage of traditionally irrigated
            forage (forage actually irrigated 3 of the last 5 crop years) is
            present in the county.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Producers may provide evidence that unit forage management and
            maintenance practices are improvements over those practices
            generally associated with the established carrying capacity. Based
            on this evidence, CCC may adjust the expected AUD for the specific
            forage acreage upward for the crop year NAP assistance is requested
            by:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Three percent when at least 1 practice was completed at least 1
            time in the previous 5 crop years and such practice can be expected
            to have a positive impact on the forage&apos;s carrying capacity in
            the crop year NAP assistance is requested;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Five percent when 2 or more practices were completed at least 1
            time in the previous 5 crop years and such practices can be expected
            to have a positive impact on the forage&apos;s carrying capacity in
            the crop year NAP assistance is requested; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Greater than 5 percent when producers provide acceptable records,
            as determined by CCC, of higher forage production or an increase in
            animal units supported on the specific forage acreage in 3 of the 5
            crop years immediately before the crop year NAP assistance is
            requested.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12839'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1437:E:1437.403
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1437.403
      </num>
      <head>
        Determining payments.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          67 FR 12448
        </aref>
        , Mar. 19, 2002, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          71 FR 13747
        </aref>
        , Mar. 17, 2006]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='403' psec='' tq='N'>
              1437.403
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Determining payments.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Subject to payment limits, availability of funds, and other limits as
          may apply, payments for losses of forage reported to FSA as intended
          to be grazed will be determined by:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Multiplying the eligible acreage by the producer&apos;s share;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Dividing the result from paragraph (a) of this section by the
            carrying capacity or adjusted per day carrying capacity established
            for the specific acreage, as determined by CCC;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Multiplying the result from paragraph (b) of this section by the
            number of days established as the grazing period;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Adding adjustments of AUD for practices and production to the
            product of paragraph (c) of this section;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Multiplying the result from paragraph (d) of this section by the
            applicable percentage of loss established by CCC;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Multiplying the amount of assigned AUD, as determined by CCC, by
            the producer&apos;s share;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subtracting the result from paragraph (f) of this section from the
            result from paragraph (e) of this section;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Multiplying the result from paragraph (d) of this section by 0.50;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subtracting the result from paragraph (h) of this section from the
            result from paragraph (g) of this section; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Multiplying the result from paragraph (i) of this section by the
            final payment price established in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
                1437.11
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            67 FR 12448
          </aref>
          , Mar. 19, 2002, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            71 FR 13747
          </aref>
          , Mar. 17, 2006]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12840'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1437:E:1437.404
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1437.404
      </num>
      <head>
        Information collection requirements under the Paperwork Reduction Act;
        OMB control number.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='404' psec='' tq='N'>
              1437.404
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Information collection requirements under the Paperwork Reduction Act;
          OMB control number.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          An agency may not conduct or sponsor, and a person is not required to
          respond to, a collection of information unless it displays a currently
          valid OMB control number. The OMB control number for the regulation in
          this part is 0560-0175.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12841'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1437:F:1437.501
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1437.501
      </num>
      <head>
        Applicability; definition of “tropical region” and additional
        definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='501' psec='' tq='N'>
              1437.501
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Applicability; definition of “tropical region” and additional
          definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This subpart shall only apply to covered tropical crops in the
            tropical region for the 2006 and subsequent crops years, as those
            terms are defined in this subpart. Benefits under this part may be
            extended to those crops only to the extent that they are otherwise
            eligible for assistance under this part. Covered crops shall not
            apply to “value loss” crops, as defined elsewhere in this part. For
            those crops that are covered by this subpart, loss and payment
            determinations for the program covered in this part shall be
            determined by the rules that otherwise apply to the program subject
            to the modifications provided by this subpart. The rules that
            otherwise apply include, but are not limited to, limitations on
            payments that appear elsewhere in this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For purposes of this subpart:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Tropical region
            </E>
             includes, as may be further limited by the Deputy Administrator:
            Hawaii, American Samoa, Guam, the U.S. Virgin Islands, Puerto Rico,
            and the former Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands (the
            Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, the Republic of the
            Marshall Islands, the Federated States of Micronesia, and the
            Republic of Palau).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              2006 and subsequent crops
            </E>
             means those crops in the ground on or after January 1, 2006.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Covered tropical crops
            </E>
             means those crops and commodities in the tropical region governed
            by this subpart, those being all crops and commodities in the
            tropical region that are otherwise eligible for generating a benefit
            claim under this part, except for value-loss crops as defined
            elsewhere in this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Deputy Administrator may adjust requirements for assistance so
            as to provide a fair transition from previous rules for crop covered
            by this subpart to those provisions which are provided for in this
            subpart.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12842'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1437:F:1437.502
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1437.502
      </num>
      <head>
        Coverage periods and fees for covered tropical crops.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='502' psec='' tq='N'>
              1437.502
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Coverage periods and fees for covered tropical crops.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The crop year for all covered tropical crops is the calendar year
            (January 1 through December 31 beginning in 2006 through subsequent
            years).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The application closing date for all covered tropical crops is
            December 1 of the calendar year before the applicable crop year.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For covered tropical crops, per county per crop year, a maximum
            service fee of $100.00 is required of the producer for coverage of:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             With respect to annual and biennial crops, all plantings of the
            same crop planted during the crop year, as determined by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             With respect to perennial crops, all acreage of the crop existing
            during the crop year, as determined by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Multiple planting periods and final planting dates are not
            applicable for covered tropical crops. However, nothing in this
            section shall prohibit assigning different production expectations
            to different fields.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The coverage period for perennial and other crops covered by this
            subpart begins on January 1 of the relevant crop year and ends on
            December 31 of that year.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12843'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1437:F:1437.503
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1437.503
      </num>
      <head>
        Covered losses and recordkeeping requirements for covered tropical
        crops.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='503' psec='' tq='N'>
              1437.503
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Covered losses and recordkeeping requirements for covered tropical
          crops.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Prevented planting coverage is not available for covered tropical
            crops, other than in Hawaii and Puerto Rico, except as approved by
            the Deputy Administrator in special cases.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except in Hawaii and Puerto Rico, or as otherwise approved by the
            Deputy Administrator in individual cases, eligible causes of loss
            for covered tropical crops will only include hurricanes, typhoons,
            and named tropical storms.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Producers who have applied for coverage on covered tropical crops
            must maintain for the full coverage period contemporaneous records.
            Contemporaneous records are those created at the time of planting
            and harvesting of the crop for which the application for coverage is
            filed. In this regard:
            <PRTPAGE P='744' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Producers may be selected on a random or targeted basis for
            compliance review with this requirement and any other requirements
            that may apply to this program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A failure to maintain acceptable contemporaneous records throughout
            the crop year may be treated by CCC as grounds of ineligibility for
            benefits under this part.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12844'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1437:F:1437.504
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1437.504
      </num>
      <head>
        Notice of loss for covered tropical crops.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='504' psec='' tq='N'>
              1437.504
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Notice of loss for covered tropical crops.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='10' psec='#c' tq='N'>
                1437.10(c)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             regarding late filed notice of loss do not apply to covered
            tropical crops.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Where a notice of loss for covered tropical crops is provided
            according to 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
                1437.10
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , producers must provide records maintained according to 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              § 1437.503(c) of
            </aref>
             the:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Number of acres or other basis of measurement, as applicable, of
            the crop from which production could be achieved existing on the day
            the eligible natural disaster occurred or, for prolonged natural
            disasters, such as a drought and similar damage where applicable,
            existing on the day the notice of loss is filed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Amount, including zero, as applicable, of production harvested,
            before or after the disaster, from those crop plantings (damaged or
            undamaged) which were in existence on the farm at the time of the
            disaster including production from the covered plantings (in
            existence at the time of the loss event) that may occur after the
            loss event even when, to the extent provided for in paragraph (c) of
            this section, the harvest occurs after the end of the crop year.
            Crop acreage of the covered crop that is in existence at the time of
            the loss event that can be harvested after the eligible natural
            disaster must be harvested, or continue to be harvested, and the
            harvested acres and production reported to FSA according to this
            subpart, except that for perennial crops the requirement ends with
            the end of the crop year. For non-perennial crops the obligation to
            harvest ends with the end of the life-cycle for the plantings that
            were in existence at the time of the loss event. In this regard:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as otherwise determined by FSA, such production, before or
            after the loss event, will be taken into account in computing
            eligibilities.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Production that must be reported under paragraph (b)(2)(i) of this
            section includes, except in the case of perennial plants, all
            production irrespective of whether the production occurs in the same
            crop year.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For perennial plants, only production in the same crop year must be
            reported.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All production that must be reported for covered tropical crops
            will, except as specified by the Deputy Administrator, be taken into
            account in the loss determinations made under this part. The
            producer is obligated to maximize that production. That is,
            harvesting and other production activities for the plants in the
            ground at the time of the disaster must be undertaken or continue to
            be undertaken, to the maximum extent possible, for the full
            reporting period, that being the period for which production could
            count against a loss as indicated in this subpart.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Failure to keep sufficient records to allow the computations
            provided for in this subpart is grounds for denial of the claim.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Producers with coverage of a covered tropical crop for a crop year
            must, by the earlier of 90 calendar days after the crop year ends or
            the date a notice of loss is filed, file a certified report setting
            out the:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Collective acres of the crop acreage planted or in the ground
            during the crop year.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Total production harvested from the crop acreage for the full crop
            year in the case of a perennial plant and for the full life of the
            plants for other crops.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             With respect to the report required in paragraph (c) of this
            section:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a report is filed before the end of the crop year, an updated
            crop report must be filed within 90 calendar days from the end of
            the crop year to supplement the original report;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the report is for any annual or biennial crops where production
            continued or could have continued beyond the period covered in the
            reports otherwise filed under this section, an additional report of
            production must be filed within 30 days of the end of the 
            <PRTPAGE P='745' />
            last countable production for the covered crop or 30 days after the
            last date on which such production could have been obtained,
            whichever is later.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A failure to file an adequate report where a report is required by
            this section may result in the producer being treated as having a
            zero yield capability for the crop year involved for purposes of
            constructing a crop history. Alternatively, the Deputy Administrator
            may assign another sanction for that failure. In addition to other
            sanctions as may apply, a failure to file such reports may be
            grounds for denial of a claim. The Deputy Administrator may adjust
            crop histories as determined appropriate to create, to the extent
            practicable, an appropriate crop history for loss computation
            purposes.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Such reports as are provided for in this subsection must be filed
            for every crop year for which there is coverage, irrespective of
            whether a claim is filed for that year.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Unless otherwise specified by the Deputy Administrator, appraisals
            are not required of crop acreage for covered tropical crops on Guam,
            Virgin Islands, American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the Northern
            Mariana Islands, the Republic of the Marshall Islands, the Federated
            States of Micronesia, and the Republic of Palau.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All crop acreage for covered tropical crops for which a notice of
            loss is filed must not be destroyed until authorized by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12845'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1437:F:1437.505
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1437.505
      </num>
      <head>
        Application for payment for the tropical region.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='505' psec='' tq='N'>
              1437.505
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Application for payment for the tropical region.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For producers of covered tropical crops in Guam, Virgin Islands,
            American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana
            Islands, the Republic of the Marshall Islands, the Federated States
            of Micronesia, and the Republic of Palau, an application for payment
            must be filed at the same time as the filing of the notice of loss
            required under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
                1437.10
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='504' psec='' tq='N'>
                1437.504
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For producers in Puerto Rico and Hawaii, an application for payment
            for such crops must be filed by the later of:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The date on which the notice of loss is filed in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
                1437.10
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='1437' sect='502' psec='#i' tq='N'>
                1437.502(i)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The date of the completion of harvest for the specific crop acreage
            that existed at the time of loss for which the notice of loss was
            filed.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>