<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol7'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701
    </extid>
    <num>
      701
    </num>
    <head>
      EMERGENCY CONSERVATION PROGRAM, EMERGENCY FOREST RESTORATION PROGRAM, AND
      CERTAIN RELATED PROGRAMS PREVIOUSLY ADMINISTERED UNDER THIS PART
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='16' sect='2201-220' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/2201-220.html'>
              16 U.S.C. 2201-220
            </subref>
          </aref>
          6; 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            Sec. 101
          </aref>
          , 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Pub. L. 109-148' alt='Pub. L. 109-148' href='http://www.gpo.gov/fdsys/pkg/PLAW-109publ148/html/PLAW-109publ148.htm'>
            Pub. L. 109-148
          </aref>
          , 
          <aref target='_blank' title='119 Stat. 2747' alt='119 Stat. 2747' href='http://www.gpo.gov/fdsys/pkg/STATUTE-119/html/STATUTE-119-Pg2747.htm'>
            119 Stat. 2747
          </aref>
          ; and 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Pub. L. 111-212' alt='Pub. L. 111-212' href='http://www.gpo.gov/fdsys/pkg/PLAW-111publ212/html/PLAW-111publ212.htm'>
            Pub. L. 111-212
          </aref>
          , 
          <aref target='_blank' href='http://frwebgate.access.gpo.gov/cgi-bin/getpage.cgi?dbname=111_statutes2_at_large&amp;position=all&amp;page=2302'>
            124 Stat. 2302
          </aref>
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            69 FR 10302
          </aref>
          , Mar. 4, 2004, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='6489'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:A:701.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        701.1
      </num>
      <head>
        Administration.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          69 FR 10302
        </aref>
        , Mar. 4, 2004, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 70087
        </aref>
        , Nov. 17, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Administration.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subject to the availability of funds, this part provides the terms,
            conditions and requirements of the Emergency Conservation Program
            (ECP) and the Emergency Forest Restoration Program (EFRP)
            administered by the Farm Service Agency (FSA). Neither program is an
            entitlement program and payments will only be made 
            <PRTPAGE P='8' />
            to the extent that the Deputy Administrator announces the
            eligibility of benefits for certain natural disasters, the areas in
            which such benefits will be available, the time period in which the
            disaster and the rehabilitation must occur, and only so long as all
            the conditions for eligibility specified in this part and elsewhere
            in law are met. However, the Deputy Administrator will not apply any
            non-statutory limitation on payments provided for in this part in
            such a way that it would necessarily result in the non-expenditure
            of program funds required to otherwise be made by law.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             ECP and EFRP are administered by the Administrator, FSA through the
            Deputy Administrator, FSA, and shall be carried out in the field by
            State and county FSA committees (State and county committees),
            subject to the availability of funds. Except as otherwise provided
            in this rule, discretionary determinations to be made under this
            rule will be made by the Deputy Administrator. Matters committed to
            the discretion of the Deputy Administrator shall be considered in
            all cases to be permissive powers and no person or legal entity
            shall, under any circumstances, be considered to be entitled to an
            exercise of such power in their favor.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State and county committees, and representatives and employees, do
            not have authority to modify or waive any regulations in this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State committee may take any action authorized or required of
            the county committee by this part, but which the county committee
            has not taken, such as:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Correct or require a county committee to correct any action taken
            by such county committee that is not in accordance with this part;
            or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Require a county committee to withhold taking any action that is
            not in accordance with this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No provision or delegation herein to a State or county committee
            shall preclude the Administrator, FSA, or a designee, from
            determining any question arising under the program or from reversing
            or modifying any determination made by a State or county committee.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Deputy Administrator may authorize State and county committees
            to waive or modify deadlines and other requirements in cases where
            lateness or failure to meet such other requirements does not
            adversely affect the operation of the program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Deputy Administrator may limit the authority of state and
            county committees to approve cost share in excess of specified
            amounts.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Data furnished by the applicants will be used to determine
            eligibility for program benefits. Furnishing the data is voluntary;
            however, the failure to provide data could result in program
            benefits being withheld or denied.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FSA may consult with any other Federal agency, State agency, or
            other provider of technical assistance for such assistance as is
            determined by FSA to be necessary to implement ECP or EFRP. FSA is
            responsible for the technical aspects of ECP and EFRP but may enter
            into a Memorandum of Agreement with another party to provide
            technical assistance. If the requirement for technical assistance
            results in undue delay or significant hardship to producers in a
            county, the State committee may request in writing that FSA waive
            this requirement for that county. However, nothing in this paragraph
            or in this part creates a right of appeal or action for an applicant
            with respect to provisions relating to internal procedures of FSA.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The provisions in this part shall not create an entitlement in any
            person or legal entity to any ECP or EFRP cost share or claim or any
            particular notice or form or procedure.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Additional terms and conditions may be set forth in the application
            or the forms participants will be required to sign for participation
            in the ECP or EFRP.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            69 FR 10302
          </aref>
          , Mar. 4, 2004, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 70087
          </aref>
          , Nov. 17, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6490'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:A:701.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        701.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          69 FR 10302
        </aref>
        , Mar. 4, 2004, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 70087
        </aref>
        , Nov. 17, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The terms defined in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='718' tq='N'>
                718 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
             shall be applicable to this part and all documents issued in
            accordance with this part, except as otherwise provided in this
            section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The following definitions shall apply to this part:
            <PRTPAGE P='9' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Agricultural producer
          </E>
           means an owner, operator, or tenant of a farm or ranch used to
          produce for food or fiber, crops (including but not limited to, grain
          or row crops; seed crops; vegetables or fruits; hay forage or pasture;
          orchards or vineyards; flowers or bulbs; or field grown ornamentals)
          or livestock (including but not limited to, dairy or beef cattle;
          poultry; swine; sheep or goats; fish or other animals raised by
          aquaculture; other livestock or fowl) for commercial production.
          Producers of animals raised for recreational uses only are not
          considered agricultural producers.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Annual agricultural production
          </E>
           means production of crops for food or fiber in a commercial operation
          that occurs on an annual basis under normal conditions.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Applicant
          </E>
           means a person or legal entity who has submitted to FSA a request to
          participate in the ECP or EFRP.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Cost-share payment
          </E>
           means the payment made by FSA to assist a program participant under
          this part to establish practices required to address qualifying damage
          suffered in connection with a qualifying disaster.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Deputy Administrator
          </E>
           means the Deputy Administrator for Farm Programs, FSA, the ECP
          Program Manager, or designee.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Farmland
          </E>
           means land devoted to agricultural production, including land used
          for aquaculture, or other land as may be determined by the Deputy
          Administrator.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Natural disaster
          </E>
           means wildfires, hurricanes or excessive winds, drought, ice storms
          or blizzards, floods, or other naturally-occurring resource impacting
          events as determined by FSA. For EFRP, a natural disaster also
          includes insect or disease infestations as determined by FSA in
          consultation with other Federal and State agencies as appropriate.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            69 FR 10302
          </aref>
          , Mar. 4, 2004, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 70087
          </aref>
          , Nov. 17, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6491'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:A:701.3-701.12
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        701.3-701.12
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='3-701' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.3-701
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .12
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6492'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:A:701.13
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        701.13
      </num>
      <head>
        Submitting requests.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          69 FR 10302
        </aref>
        , Mar. 4, 2004, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 70088
        </aref>
        , Nov. 17, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='13' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.13
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Submitting requests.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subject to the availability of funds, the Deputy Administrator
            shall provide for an enrollment period for submitting ECP or EFRP
            cost-share requests.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Requests may be accepted after the announced enrollment period, if
            such acceptance is approved by the Deputy Administrator and is in
            accordance with the purposes of the program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            69 FR 10302
          </aref>
          , Mar. 4, 2004, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 70088
          </aref>
          , Nov. 17, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6493'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:A:701.14
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        701.14
      </num>
      <head>
        Onsite inspections.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          69 FR 10302
        </aref>
        , Mar. 4, 2004, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 70088
        </aref>
        , Nov. 17, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='14' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.14
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Onsite inspections.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An onsite inspection must be made before approval of any request
            for ECP or EFRP assistance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notwithstanding paragraph (a) of this section, onsite inspections
            may be waived by FSA, in its discretion only, where damage is so
            severe that an onsite inspection is unnecessary, as determined by
            FSA.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            69 FR 10302
          </aref>
          , Mar. 4, 2004, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 70088
          </aref>
          , Nov. 17, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6494'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:A:701.15
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        701.15
      </num>
      <head>
        Starting practices before cost-share request is submitted;
        non-entitlement to payment; payment subject to the availability of
        funds.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          69 FR 10302
        </aref>
        , Mar. 4, 2004, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 70088
        </aref>
        , Nov. 17, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='15' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.15
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Starting practices before cost-share request is submitted;
          non-entitlement to payment; payment subject to the availability of
          funds.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subject to paragraphs (b) and (c) of this section, costs will not
            be shared for practices or components of practices that are started
            before a request for cost share under this part is submitted with
            the applicable county FSA office.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Costs may be shared for drought and non-drought practices or
            components of practices that are started before a request is
            submitted with the county FSA office, only if:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Considered and approved on a case-by-case basis in accordance with
            instructions of the Deputy Administrator;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The disaster that is the basis of a claim for cost-share assistance
            created a situation that required the producer to take immediate
            action to prevent further losses;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Deputy Administrator determines that the request for assistance
            was filed within a reasonable amount of time after the start of the
            enrollment period; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The practice was started no more than 60 days before the ECP or
            EFRP designation was approved for the applicable county office.
            <PRTPAGE P='10' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any action taken prior to approval of a claim is taken at the
            producer&apos;s own risk.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An application for relief may be denied for any reason.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All payments under this part are subject to the availability of
            funds.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            69 FR 10302
          </aref>
          , Mar. 4, 2004, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 70088
          </aref>
          , Nov. 17, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6495'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:A:701.16
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        701.16
      </num>
      <head>
        Practice approval.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          69 FR 10302
        </aref>
        , Mar. 4, 2004, and amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 70088
        </aref>
        , Nov. 17, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='16' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.16
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Practice approval.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Requests shall be prioritized before approval based on factors
            deemed appropriate by FSA, which include, but are not limited to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Type and degree of damage;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Type of practices needed to address the problem;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Availability of funds;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Availability of technical assistance;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Environmental concerns;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Safety factors; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the case of ECP, welfare of eligible livestock.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Requests for cost-share assistance may be approved if:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Funds are available; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The requested practice is determined eligible.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            69 FR 10302
          </aref>
          , Mar. 4, 2004, and amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 70088
          </aref>
          , Nov. 17, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6496'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:A:701.17-701-20
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        701.17-701-20
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='17-701-20' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.17-701-20
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6497'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:A:701.21
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        701.21
      </num>
      <head>
        Filing payment application.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='21' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.21
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Filing payment application.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Cost-share assistance is conditioned upon the availability of funds
          and the performance of the practice in compliance with all applicable
          specifications and program regulations.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Completion of practice.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             After completion of the approved practice, the participant must
            certify completion and request payment by the payment request
            deadline. FSA will provide the participant with a form or another
            manner to be used to request payment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Proof of completion.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Participants shall submit to FSA, at the local county office, the
            information needed to establish the extent of the performance of
            approved practices and compliance with applicable program
            provisions.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Payment request deadline.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The time limits for submission of information shall be determined
            by the Deputy Administrator. The payment request deadline for each
            ECP practice will be provided in the agreement after the application
            is approved. Time limits may be extended where failure to submit
            required information within the applicable time limits is due to
            reasons beyond the control of the participant.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6498'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:A:701.22
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        701.22
      </num>
      <head>
        Eligibility to file for cost-share assistance.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='22' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.22
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Eligibility to file for cost-share assistance.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Any eligible participant, as defined in this part, who paid part of
          the cost of an approved practice may file an application for
          cost-share payment.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6499'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:A:701.23
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        701.23
      </num>
      <head>
        Eligible costs.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          69 FR 10302
        </aref>
        , Mar. 4, 2004, and amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 70088
        </aref>
        , Nov. 17, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='23' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.23
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Eligible costs.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Cost-share assistance may be authorized for all reasonable costs
            incurred in the completion of the practice, up to the maximums
            provided in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='701' sect='126' psec='' tq='N'>
                701.126
              </subref>
              , 
              <subref title='7' part='701' sect='127' psec='' tq='N'>
                701.127
              </subref>
              , and 
              <subref title='7' part='701' sect='226' psec='' tq='N'>
                701.226
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Eligible costs shall be limited as follows:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Costs for use of personal equipment shall be limited to those
            incurred beyond the normal operation of the eligible land.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Costs for personal labor shall be limited to personal labor not
            normally required in the operation of the eligible land.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Costs for the use of personal equipment and labor must be less than
            that charged for such equipment and labor by commercial contractors
            regularly employed in such areas.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Costs shall not exceed those needed to achieve the minimum
            performance necessary to resolve the problem being corrected by the
            practice. Any costs above those levels shall not be considered to be
            eligible costs for purposes of calculations made under this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Costs shall not exceed the practice specifications in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='701' sect='112' psec='#d' tq='N'>
                701.112(d)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             or 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='701' sect='212' psec='#d' tq='N'>
                701.212(d)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             for cost-share calculations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The gross amount on which the cost-share eligibility may be
            computed will not include any costs that were reimbursed by a third
            party including, but not limited to, an insurance indemnity payment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Total cost-share payments from all sources shall not exceed the
            total of eligible costs of the practice to the applicant.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            69 FR 10302
          </aref>
          , Mar. 4, 2004, and amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 70088
          </aref>
          , Nov. 17, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6500'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:A:701.24
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        701.24
      </num>
      <head>
        Dividing cost-share among more than one participant.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='11' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='24' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.24
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Dividing cost-share among more than one participant.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For qualifying cost-share assistance under this part, the cost
            shall be credited to the participant who personally performed the
            practice or who paid to have it performed by a third party. If a
            payment or credit was made by one participant to another potential
            participant, paragraph (c) of this section shall apply.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If more than one participant contributed to the performance of the
            practice, the cost-share assistance for the practice shall be
            divided among those eligible participants in the proportion they
            contributed to the performance of the practice. FSA may determine
            what proportion was contributed by each participant by considering
            the value of the labor, equipment, or material contributed by each
            participant and any other factors deemed relevant toward
            performance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Allowance by a participant of a credit to another participant
            through adjustment in rent, cash or other consideration, may be
            considered as a cost of a practice to the paying party only if FSA
            determines that such credit is directly related to the practice. An
            applicant who was fully reimbursed shall be considered as not having
            contributed to the practice performance.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6501'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:A:701.25
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        701.25
      </num>
      <head>
        Practices carried out with aid from ineligible persons or ineligible
        legal entities.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          69 FR 10302
        </aref>
        , Mar. 4, 2004, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 70088
        </aref>
        , Nov. 17, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='25' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.25
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Practices carried out with aid from ineligible persons or ineligible
          legal entities.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Any assistance provided by someone other than the eligible
          participant, including assistance from a State or Federal agency,
          shall be deducted from the participant&apos;s total costs incurred for
          the practice for the purpose of computing ECP or EFRP cost shares. If
          unusual conditions exist, the Deputy Administrator may waive deduction
          of such contributions upon a request from the State committee and
          demonstration of the need for such a waiver.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            69 FR 10302
          </aref>
          , Mar. 4, 2004, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 70088
          </aref>
          , Nov. 17, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6502'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:A:701.26-701.30
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        701.26-701.30
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='26-701' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.26-701
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .30
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6503'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:A:701.31
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        701.31
      </num>
      <head>
        Maintenance and proper use of practices.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='31' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.31
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Maintenance and proper use of practices.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each participant receiving cost-share assistance is responsible for
            the required maintenance and proper use of the practice. Some
            practices have an established life span or minimum period of time
            during which they are expected to function as a conservation
            practice with proper maintenance. Cost-share assistance shall not be
            authorized for normal upkeep or maintenance of any practice.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a practice is not properly maintained for the established life
            span, the participant may be required to refund all or part of
            cost-share assistance received. The Deputy Administrator will
            determine what constitutes failure to maintain a practice and the
            amount that must be refunded.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6504'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:A:701.32
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        701.32
      </num>
      <head>
        Failure to comply with program provisions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='32' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.32
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Failure to comply with program provisions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Costs may be shared for performance actually rendered even though the
          minimum requirements otherwise established for a practice have not
          been satisfied if a reasonable effort was made to satisfy the minimum
          requirements and if the practice, as performed, will adequately
          address the need for the practice.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6505'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:A:701.33
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        701.33
      </num>
      <head>
        Death, incompetency, or disappearance.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='33' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.33
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Death, incompetency, or disappearance.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          In case of death, incompetency, or disappearance of any participant,
          any cost-share payment due shall be paid to the successor, as
          determined in accordance with 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='707' tq='N'>
              707 of this chapter
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6506'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:A:701.34
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        701.34
      </num>
      <head>
        Appeals.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          69 FR 10302
        </aref>
        , Mar. 4, 2004, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 70088
        </aref>
        , Nov. 17, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='34' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.34
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Appeals.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            Part 
            <subref title='7' part='11' tq='N'>
              11 of this title
            </subref>
          </aref>
           and 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            parts 
            <subref title='7' part='614' tq='N'>
              614
            </subref>
             and 
            <subref title='7' part='780' tq='N'>
              780 of this chapter
            </subref>
          </aref>
           apply to determinations made under this part.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            69 FR 10302
          </aref>
          , Mar. 4, 2004, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 70088
          </aref>
          , Nov. 17, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6507'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:A:701.35
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        701.35
      </num>
      <head>
        Compliance with regulatory measures.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          69 FR 10302
        </aref>
        , Mar. 4, 2004, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 70088
        </aref>
        , Nov. 17, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='35' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.35
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Compliance with regulatory measures.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Participants who perform practices shall be responsible for obtaining
          the authorities, permits, rights, easements, or other approvals
          necessary to the performance and maintenance of the practices
          according to applicable laws and regulations. The ECP or EFRP
          participant shall be wholly responsible for any actions taken with
          respect to the project and shall, in addition, be responsible for
          returning and refunding any ECP or EFRP cost shares made, 
          <PRTPAGE P='12' />
          where the purpose of the project cannot be accomplished because of the
          applicants&apos; lack of clearances or other problems.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            69 FR 10302
          </aref>
          , Mar. 4, 2004, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 70088
          </aref>
          , Nov. 17, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6508'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:A:701.36
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        701.36
      </num>
      <head>
        Schemes and devices and claims avoidances.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          69 FR 10302
        </aref>
        , Mar. 4, 2004, and amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 70088
        </aref>
        , Nov. 17, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='36' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.36
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Schemes and devices and claims avoidances.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If FSA determines that a participant has taken any action designed
            to defeat, or has the effect of defeating, the purposes of this
            program, the participant shall be required to refund all or part of
            any of the program payments otherwise due or paid that participant
            or related person or legal entity for that particular disaster.
            These actions include, but are not limited to, failure to properly
            maintain or deliberately destroying a practice and providing false
            or misleading information related to practices, costs, or
            arrangements between entities or individuals that would have an
            effect on any eligibility determination, including, but not limited
            to, a payment limit eligibility.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All or any part of cost-share assistance that otherwise would be
            due any participant may be withheld, or required to be refunded, if
            the participant has adopted, or participated in, any scheme or
            device designed to evade the maximum cost-share limitation that
            applies to the program or to evade any other requirement or
            provision of the program or this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If FSA determines that a participant has employed any scheme or
            device to deprive any other person or legal entity of cost-share
            assistance, or engaged in any actions to receive payments under this
            part that also were designed to avoid claims of the United States or
            its instrumentalities or agents against that party, related parties,
            or third parties, the participant shall refund all or part of any of
            those program payments paid to that participant for the project.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For purposes of this section, a scheme or device can include, but
            is not limited to, instances of coercion, fraud, or
            misrepresentation regarding the claim for ECP or EFRP assistance and
            the facts and circumstances surrounding such claim.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A participant who has knowingly supplied false information or filed
            a false claim shall be ineligible for cost-share assistance related
            to the disaster for which the false information was filed, or for
            any period of time FSA deems appropriate. False information or a
            false claim includes, but is not limited to, a request for payment
            for a practice not carried out, a false billing, or a billing for
            practices that do not meet required specifications.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            69 FR 10302
          </aref>
          , Mar. 4, 2004, and amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 70088
          </aref>
          , Nov. 17, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6509'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:A:701.37
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        701.37
      </num>
      <head>
        Loss of control of the property during the practice life span.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          69 FR 10302
        </aref>
        , Mar. 4, 2004, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 70088
        </aref>
        , Nov. 17, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='37' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.37
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Loss of control of the property during the practice life span.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          In the event of voluntary or involuntary loss of control of the land
          by the ECP or EFRP cost-share recipient during the practice life-span,
          if the person or legal entity acquiring control elects not to become a
          successor to the ECP or EFRP agreement and the practice is not
          maintained, each participant who received cost-share assistance for
          the practice may be jointly and severally liable for refunding any ECP
          or EFRP cost-share assistance related to that practice. The practice
          life span, for purposes of this section, includes any maintenance
          period that is essential to its success.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            69 FR 10302
          </aref>
          , Mar. 4, 2004, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 70088
          </aref>
          , Nov. 17, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6510'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:A:701.38-701.40
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        701.38-701.40
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='38-701' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.38-701
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .40
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6511'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:A:701.41
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        701.41
      </num>
      <head>
        Cost-share assistance not subject to claims.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='41' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.41
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Cost-share assistance not subject to claims.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Any cost-share assistance or portion thereof due any participant under
          this part shall be allowed without regard to questions of title under
          State law, and without regard to any claim or lien against any crop or
          property, or proceeds thereof, except liens and other claims of the
          United States or its instrumentalities. The regulations governing
          offsets and withholdings at 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            parts 
            <subref title='7' part='792' tq='N'>
              792
            </subref>
             and 
            <subref title='7' part='1403' tq='N'>
              1403 of this title
            </subref>
          </aref>
           shall be applicable to this program and the provisions most favorable
          to a collection of the debt shall control.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6512'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:A:701.42
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        701.42
      </num>
      <head>
        Assignments.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='42' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.42
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Assignments.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Participants may assign ECP cost-share assistance payments, in whole
          or in part, according to 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='1404' tq='N'>
              1404 of this title
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6513'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:A:701.43
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        701.43
      </num>
      <head>
        Information collection requirements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='13' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='43' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.43
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Information collection requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Information collection requirements contained in this part have been
          approved by the Office of Management and Budget under the provisions
          at 44 U.S.C. Chapter 35 and have been assigned OMB Number 0560-0082.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6514'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:A:701.44
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        701.44
      </num>
      <head>
        Agricultural Conservation Program (ACP) contracts.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          69 FR 10302
        </aref>
        , Mar. 4, 2004, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 70088
        </aref>
        , Nov. 17, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='44' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.44
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Agricultural Conservation Program (ACP) contracts.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Contracts for ACP that are, or were, administered under this part or
          similar contracts executed in connection with the Interim
          Environmental Quality Incentives Program, shall, unless the Deputy
          Administrator determines otherwise, be administered under, and be
          subject to, the regulations for ACP contracts and the ACP program that
          were contained in the 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR parts 
            <subref title='7' part='700' tq='N'>
              700
            </subref>
          </aref>
           to 899, edition revised as of January 1, 1998, and under the terms of
          the agreements that were entered into with participants.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            69 FR 10302
          </aref>
          , Mar. 4, 2004, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 70088
          </aref>
          , Nov. 17, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6515'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:A:701.45
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        701.45
      </num>
      <head>
        Forestry Incentives Program (FIP) contracts.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          69 FR 10302
        </aref>
        , Mar. 4, 2004, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 70088
        </aref>
        , Nov. 17, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='45' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.45
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Forestry Incentives Program (FIP) contracts.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The regulations governing the FIP as of July 31, 2002, and contained
          in the 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR parts 
            <subref title='7' part='700' tq='N'>
              700
            </subref>
          </aref>
           to 899, edition revised as of January 1, 2002, shall continue to
          apply to FIP contracts in effect as of that date, except as provided
          in accord with a delegation of the administration of that program and
          such delegation and actions taken thereunder shall apply to any other
          FIP matters as may be at issue or in dispute.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            69 FR 10302
          </aref>
          , Mar. 4, 2004, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 70088
          </aref>
          , Nov. 17, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6516'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:B:701.100-701.102
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        701.100-701.102
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='100-701' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.100-701
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .102
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6517'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:B:701.103
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        701.103
      </num>
      <head>
        Scope.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          69 FR 10302
        </aref>
        , Mar. 4, 2004. Redesignated and amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 70088
        </aref>
        , Nov. 17, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='103' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.103
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Scope.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FSA will provide cost-share assistance to farmers and ranchers to
            rehabilitate farmland damaged by wind erosion, floods, hurricanes,
            or other natural disasters as determined by the Deputy
            Administrator, and to carry out emergency water conservation
            measures during periods of severe drought, subject to the
            availability of funds and only for areas, natural disasters, and
            time periods approved by the Deputy Administrator.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The objective of the ECP is to make cost-share assistance available
            to eligible participants on eligible land for certain practices, to
            rehabilitate farmland damaged by floods, hurricanes, wind erosion,
            or other natural disasters, and for the installation of water
            conservation measures during periods of severe drought.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payments may also be made under this subpart for:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Emergency water conservation or water enhancement measures
            (including measures to assist confined livestock) during periods of
            severe drought; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Floodplain easements for runoff and other emergency measures that
            the Deputy Administrator determines is necessary to safeguard life
            and property from floods, drought, and the products of erosion on
            any watershed whenever fire, flood, or other natural occurrence is
            causing or has caused, a sudden impairment of the watershed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payments under this part are subject to the availability of
            appropriated funds and any limitations that may otherwise be
            provided for by Congress.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            69 FR 10302
          </aref>
          , Mar. 4, 2004. Redesignated and amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 70088
          </aref>
          , Nov. 17, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6518'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:B:701.104
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        701.104
      </num>
      <head>
        Producer eligibility.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          69 FR 10302
        </aref>
        , Mar. 4, 2004. Redesignated and amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 70088
        </aref>
        , Nov. 17, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='104' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.104
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Producer eligibility.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be eligible to participate in the ECP the Deputy Administrator
            must determine that a person or legal entity is an agricultural
            producer with an interest in the land affected by the natural
            disaster, and that person or legal entity must be liable for or have
            paid the expense that is the subject of the cost share. The
            applicant must be a landowner or user in the area where the
            qualifying event has occurred, and must be a party who will incur
            the expense that is the subject of the cost share.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Federal agencies and States, including all agencies and political
            subdivisions of a State, are ineligible to participate in the ECP.
            <PRTPAGE P='14' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All producer eligibility is subject to the availability of funds
            and an application may be denied for any reason.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            69 FR 10302
          </aref>
          , Mar. 4, 2004. Redesignated and amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 70088
          </aref>
          , Nov. 17, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6519'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:B:701.105
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        701.105
      </num>
      <head>
        Land eligibility.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          69 FR 10302
        </aref>
        , Mar. 4, 2004. Redesignated at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 70088
        </aref>
        , Nov. 17, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='105' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.105
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Land eligibility.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For land to be eligible, the Deputy Administrator must determine
            that land that is the subject of the cost share:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Will have new conservation problems caused as a result of a natural
            disaster that, if not treated, would:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Impair or endanger the land;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Materially affect the productive capacity of the land;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Represent unusual damage that, except for wind erosion, is not of
            the type likely to recur frequently in the same area; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be so costly to repair that Federal assistance is or will be
            required to return the land to productive agricultural use.
            Conservation problems existing prior to the disaster are not
            eligible for cost-share assistance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be physically located in a county in which the ECP has been
            implemented; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be one of the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land expected to have annual agricultural production,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A field windbreak or a farmstead shelterbelt on which the ECP
            practice to be implemented involves removing debris that interferes
            with normal farming operations on the farm and correcting damage
            caused by the disaster; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A farm access road on which debris interfering with the normal
            farming operation needs to be removed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land is ineligible for cost share if the Deputy Administrator
            determines that it is, as applicable:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Owned or controlled by the United States;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Owned or controlled by States, including State agencies or other
            political subdivisions of a State;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Protected by a levee or dike that was not effectively and properly
            functioning prior to the disaster, or is protected, or intended to
            be protected, by a levee or dike not built to U.S. Army Corps of
            Engineers, NRCS, or comparable standards;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Adjacent to water impoundment reservoirs that are subject to
            inundation when the reservoir is filled to capacity;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land on which levees or dikes are located;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subject to frequent damage or susceptible to severe damage
            according to paragraph (c) of this section;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subject to flowage or flood easements and inundation when water is
            released in normal operations;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Between any levee or dike and a stream, river, or body of water,
            including land between two or more levees or dikes;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Located in an old or new channel of a stream, creek, river or other
            similar body of water, except that land located within or on the
            banks of an irrigation canal may be eligible if the Deputy
            Administrator determines that the canal is not a channel subject to
            flooding;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In greenhouses or other confined areas, including but not limited
            to, land in corrals, milking parlors, barn lots, or feeding areas;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_11'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (11)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land on which poor farming practices, such as failure to farm on
            the contour, have materially contributed to damaging the land;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_12'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (12)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Unless otherwise provided for, not considered to be in annual
            agricultural production, such as land devoted to stream banks,
            channels, levees, dikes, native woodland areas, roads, and
            recreational uses; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_13'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (13)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Devoted to trees including, but not limited to, timber production.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To determine the likely frequency of damage and of the
            susceptibility of the land to severe damage under paragraph (b)(6)
            of this section, FSA will consider all relevant factors, including,
            but not limited to, the location of the land, the history of damage
            to the land, and whether the land was or could have been protected
            by a functioning levee or dike built to U. S. Army Corps of
            Engineers, NRCS, or comparable standards. Further, in making such
            determinations, information may be obtained and used from the
            Federal Emergency Management Agency or any other Federal, State
            (including State agencies or political subdivisions), or other
            entity or individual providing information regarding, for 
            <PRTPAGE P='15' />
            example, flood susceptibility for the land, soil surveys, aerial
            photographs, or flood plain data or other relevant information.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            69 FR 10302
          </aref>
          , Mar. 4, 2004. Redesignated at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 70088
          </aref>
          , Nov. 17, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6520'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:B:701.106-701.109
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        701.106-701.109
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='106-701' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.106-701
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .109
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6521'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:B:701.110
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        701.110
      </num>
      <head>
        Qualifying minimum cost of restoration.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          69 FR 10302
        </aref>
        , Mar. 4, 2004; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          69 FR 22377
        </aref>
        , Apr. 26, 2004. Redesignated and amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 70088
        </aref>
        , Nov. 17, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='110' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.110
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Qualifying minimum cost of restoration.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To qualify for assistance under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='701' sect='103' psec='#a' tq='N'>
                701.103(a)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , the eligible damage must be so costly that Federal assistance is
            or will be required to return the land to productive agricultural
            use or to provide emergency water for livestock.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Deputy Administrator shall establish the minimum qualifying
            cost of restoration. Each affected State may be allowed to establish
            a higher minimum qualifying cost of restoration.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A producer may request a waiver of the qualifying minimum cost of
            restoration. The waiver request shall document how failure to grant
            the waiver will result in environmental damage or hardship to the
            producer and how the waiver will accomplish the goals of the
            program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            69 FR 10302
          </aref>
          , Mar. 4, 2004; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            69 FR 22377
          </aref>
          , Apr. 26, 2004. Redesignated and amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 70088
          </aref>
          , Nov. 17, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6522'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:B:701.111
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        701.111
      </num>
      <head>
        Prohibition on duplicate payments.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          69 FR 10302
        </aref>
        , Mar. 4, 2004, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          71 FR 30265
        </aref>
        , May 26, 2006. Redesignated at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 70088
        </aref>
        , Nov. 17, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='111' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.111
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Prohibition on duplicate payments.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Duplicate payments.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Participants are not eligible to receive funding under the ECP for
            land on which the participant has or will receive funding under:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Wetland Reserve Program (WRP) provided for in 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1467' tq='N'>
                1467
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Emergency Wetland Reserve Program (EWRP) provided for in 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='623' tq='N'>
                623
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Emergency Watershed Protection Program (EWP), provided for in 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='624' tq='N'>
                624
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , for the same or similar expenses.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any other program that covers the same or similar expenses so as to
            create duplicate payments, or, in effect, a higher rate of cost
            share than is allowed under this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Refund.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Participants who receive any duplicate funds, payments, or benefits
            shall refund any ECP payments received.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            69 FR 10302
          </aref>
          , Mar. 4, 2004, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            71 FR 30265
          </aref>
          , May 26, 2006. Redesignated at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 70088
          </aref>
          , Nov. 17, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6523'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:B:701.112
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        701.112
      </num>
      <head>
        Eligible ECP practices.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          69 FR 10302
        </aref>
        , Mar. 4, 2004. Redesignated and amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 70088
        </aref>
        , Nov. 17, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='112' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.112
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Eligible ECP practices.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Cost-share assistance may be offered for ECP practices to replace
            or restore farmland, fences, or conservation structures to a
            condition similar to that existing before the natural disaster. No
            relief under this subpart shall be allowed to address conservation
            problems existing before the disaster.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The practice or practices made available when the ECP is
            implemented shall be only those practices authorized by FSA for
            which cost-share assistance is essential to permit accomplishment of
            the program goals.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Cost-share assistance may be provided for permanent vegetative
            cover, including establishment of the cover where needed, only in
            conjunction with eligible structures or installations where cover is
            needed to prevent erosion and/or siltation or to accomplish some
            other ECP purpose.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Practice specifications shall represent the minimum levels of
            performance needed to address the ECP need.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            69 FR 10302
          </aref>
          , Mar. 4, 2004. Redesignated and amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 70088
          </aref>
          , Nov. 17, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6524'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:B:701.113-701.116
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        701.113-701.116
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='113-701' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.113-701
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .116
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6525'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:B:701.117
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        701.117
      </num>
      <head>
        Average adjusted gross income limitation.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          72 FR 45880
        </aref>
        , Aug. 16, 2007. Redesignated at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 70088
        </aref>
        , Nov. 17, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='117' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.117
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Average adjusted gross income limitation.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          To be eligible for payments issued from the $16 million provided under
          the U.S. Troop Readiness, Veterans&apos; Care, Katrina Recovery, and
          Iraq Accountability Appropriations Act, 2007 (
          <aref target='_blank' title='Pub. L. 110-28' alt='Pub. L. 110-28' href='http://www.gpo.gov/fdsys/pkg/PLAW-110publ28/html/PLAW-110publ28.htm'>
            Pub. L. 110-28
          </aref>
          , 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            section 9003
          </aref>
          ), each applicant must meet the provisions of the Adjusted Gross
          Income Limitations at 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR part 
            <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
              1400
            </subref>
          </aref>
           subpart G.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            72 FR 45880
          </aref>
          , Aug. 16, 2007. Redesignated at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 70088
          </aref>
          , Nov. 17, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6526'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:B:701.118-701.125
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        701.118-701.125
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='118-701' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.118-701
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .125
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6527'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:B:701.126
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        701.126
      </num>
      <head>
        Maximum cost-share percentage.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          69 FR 10302
        </aref>
        , Mar. 4, 2004. Redesignated and amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 70088
        </aref>
        , Nov. 17, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='126' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.126
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Maximum cost-share percentage.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In addition to other restrictions that may be applied by FSA, an
            ECP participant shall not receive more than 
            <PRTPAGE P='16' />
            75 percent of the lesser of the participant&apos;s total actual cost
            or of the total allowable costs, as determined by this part, to
            perform the practice.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             However, notwithstanding paragraph (a) of this section, a qualified
            limited resource producer that participates in the ECP may receive
            no more than 90 percent of the participant&apos;s actual cost to
            perform the practice or 90 percent of the total allowable costs for
            the practice as determined under this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In addition to other limitations that apply, in no case shall the
            ECP payment exceed 50 percent of what the Deputy Administrator has
            determined is the agricultural value of the affected land.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            69 FR 10302
          </aref>
          , Mar. 4, 2004. Redesignated and amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 70088
          </aref>
          , Nov. 17, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6528'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:B:701.127
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        701.127
      </num>
      <head>
        Maximum ECP payments per person or legal entity.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 7088
        </aref>
        , Nov. 17, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='127' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.127
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Maximum ECP payments per person or legal entity.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          A person or legal entity, as defined in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
              1400 of this title
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , is limited to a maximum ECP cost-share of $200,000 per person or
          legal entity, per natural disaster.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 7088
          </aref>
          , Nov. 17, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6529'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:B:701.128-701.149
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        701.128-701.149
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='128-701' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.128-701
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .149
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6530'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:B:701.150
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        701.150
      </num>
      <head>
        2005 hurricanes.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          71 FR 30265
        </aref>
        , May 26, 2006. Redesignated and amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 70088, 70089
        </aref>
        , Nov. 17, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='150' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.150
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          2005 hurricanes.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          In addition benefits elsewhere allowed by this part, claims related to
          calendar year 2005 hurricane losses may be allowed to the extent
          provided for in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='150' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.150
            </subref>
          </aref>
           through 701.157. Such claims under those sections will be limited to
          losses in counties that were declared disaster counties by the
          President or the Secretary because of 2005 hurricanes and to losses to
          oyster reefs. Claims under 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='151' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.151
            </subref>
          </aref>
           through 701.157 shall be subject to all normal ECP limitations and
          provisions except as explicitly provided in those sections.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            71 FR 30265
          </aref>
          , May 26, 2006. Redesignated and amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 70088, 70089
          </aref>
          , Nov. 17, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6531'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:B:701.151
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        701.151
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          71 FR 30265
        </aref>
        , May 26, 2006. Redesignated and amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 70088, 70089
        </aref>
        , Nov. 17, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='151' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.151
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The following definitions apply to 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='152' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.152
            </subref>
          </aref>
           through 701.157:
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Above-ground irrigation
          </E>
           facilities means irrigation pipes, sprinklers, pumps, emitters, and
          any other integral part of the above ground irrigation system.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Barn
          </E>
           means a structure used for the housing of animals or farm equipment.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Commercial forest land
          </E>
           means forest land with trees intended to be harvested for commercial
          purposes that has a productivity potential greater than or equal to 20
          cubic feet per year of merchantable timber.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Date of loss
          </E>
           means the date the hurricane damage occurred in calendar year 2005.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Eligible county
          </E>
           means any county that was declared a disaster county by the President
          or the Secretary because of a calendar year 2005 hurricane, that
          otherwise meets the eligibility requirements of this part.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Forest management plan
          </E>
           means a plan of action and direction on forest lands to achieve a set
          of results usually specified as goals or objectives consistent with
          program policies prepared or approved by a natural resource
          professional, such as a State forestry agency representative.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Poultry house
          </E>
           means a building used to house live poultry for the purpose of
          commercial food production.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Private non-industrial forest land
          </E>
           means rural commercial forest lands with existing tree cover, or
          which are suitable for growing trees, that are owned by a private
          non-industrial forest landowner as defined in this section.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Private non-industrial forest landowner
          </E>
           means, for purposes of the ECP for forestry, an individual, group,
          association, corporation, Indian tribe, or other legal private entity
          owning non-industrial private forest land or who receives concurrence
          from the landowner for making the claim in lieu of the owner, and for
          practice implementation and who holds a lease on the land for a
          minimum of 10 years. Owners or lessees principally engaged in the
          primary processing of raw wood products are excluded from this
          definition. Owners of land leased to lessees who would be excluded
          under the previous sentence are also excluded.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Shade house
          </E>
           means a metal or wood structure covered by a material used for shade
          purposes.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            71 FR 30265
          </aref>
          , May 26, 2006. Redesignated and amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 70088, 70089
          </aref>
          , Nov. 17, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6532'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:B:701.152
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        701.152
      </num>
      <head>
        Availability of funding.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          71 FR 30265
        </aref>
        , May 26, 2006. Redesignated and amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 70088
        </aref>
        , Nov. 17, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='17' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='152' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.152
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Availability of funding.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Payments under 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1701' sect='53' psec='' tq='N'>
              1701.53
            </subref>
          </aref>
           through 701.157 are subject to the availability of funds under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 109-148' alt='Public Law 109-148' href='http://www.gpo.gov/fdsys/pkg/PLAW-109publ148/html/PLAW-109publ148.htm'>
            Public Law 109-148
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            71 FR 30265
          </aref>
          , May 26, 2006. Redesignated and amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 70088
          </aref>
          , Nov. 17, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6533'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:B:701.153
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        701.153
      </num>
      <head>
        Debris removal and water for livestock.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          71 FR 30265
        </aref>
        , May 26, 2006. Redesignated and amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 70088, 70089
        </aref>
        , Nov. 17, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='153' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.153
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Debris removal and water for livestock.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Subject to the other eligibility provisions of this part, an ECP
          participant addressing damage in an eligible county from hurricanes
          during calendar year 2005 may be allowed up to 90 percent of the
          participant&apos;s actual cost or of the total allowable cost for
          cleaning up structures such as barns, shade houses and above-ground
          irrigation facilities, for removing poultry house debris, including
          carcasses, and for providing water for livestock.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            71 FR 30265
          </aref>
          , May 26, 2006. Redesignated and amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 70088, 70089
          </aref>
          , Nov. 17, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6534'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:B:701.154
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        701.154
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='154' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.154
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6535'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:B:701.155
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        701.155
      </num>
      <head>
        Nursery.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          71 FR 30265
        </aref>
        , May 26, 2006. Redesignated and amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 70088, 70089
        </aref>
        , Nov. 17, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='155' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.155
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Nursery.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subject to the other eligibility provisions of this part except as
            provided explicitly in this section, assistance may be made
            available in an eligible county under this section for the cost of
            removing nursery debris such as nursery structures, shade houses,
            and above ground irrigation facilities, where such debris was
            created in calendar year 2005 by a 2005 hurricane.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notwithstanding 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='701' sect='126' psec='' tq='N'>
                701.126
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , an otherwise eligible ECP participant may be allowed up to 90
            percent of the participant&apos;s actual cost or of the total
            allowable cost for losses described in paragraph (a) of this
            section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            71 FR 30265
          </aref>
          , May 26, 2006. Redesignated and amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 70088, 70089
          </aref>
          , Nov. 17, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6536'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:B:701.156
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        701.156
      </num>
      <head>
        Poultry.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          71 FR 30265
        </aref>
        , May 26, 2006. Redesignated at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 70088
        </aref>
        , Nov. 17, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='156' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.156
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Poultry.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subject to the other eligibility provisions of this part except as
            provided explicitly in this section, assistance may be allowed under
            this section for uninsured losses in calendar year 2005 to a poultry
            house in an eligible county due to a 2005 hurricane.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Claimants under this section may be allowed an amount up to the
            lesser of:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The lesser of 50 percent of the participant&apos;s actual or the
            total allowable cost of the reconstruction or repair of a poultry
            house, or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             $50,000 per poultry house.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The total amount of assistance provided under this section and any
            indemnities for losses to a poultry house paid to a poultry grower,
            may not exceed 90 percent of the total costs associated with the
            reconstruction or repair of a poultry house.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Poultry growers must provide information on insurance payments on
            their poultry houses. Copies of contracts between growers and
            poultry integrators may be required.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Assistance under this section is limited to amounts necessary for
            reconstruction and/or repair of a poultry house to the same size as
            before the hurricane.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Assistance is limited to poultry houses used to house poultry for
            commercial enterprises. A commercial poultry enterprise is one with
            a dedicated structure for poultry and a number of poultry that
            exceeds actual non-commercial uses of poultry and their products at
            all times, and from which poultry or related products are actually,
            and routinely, sold in commercial quantities for food, fiber, or
            eggs. Unless otherwise approved by FSA, a commercial quantity is a
            quantity per week that would normally exceed $100 in sales.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Poultry houses with respect to which claims are made under this
            section must be reconstructed or repaired to meet current building
            standards.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            71 FR 30265
          </aref>
          , May 26, 2006. Redesignated at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 70088
          </aref>
          , Nov. 17, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6537'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:B:701.157
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        701.157
      </num>
      <head>
        Private non-industrial forest land.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          71 FR 30265
        </aref>
        , May 26, 2006. Redesignated and amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 70088, 70089
        </aref>
        , Nov. 17, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='157' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.157
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Private non-industrial forest land.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subject to the other eligibility provisions of this part except as
            provided explicitly in this section, assistance made available under
            this section with respect to private, non-industrial forest land in
            an eligible county for costs related to reforestations,
            rehabilitation, and related measures undertaken because of losses in
            calendar year 2005 caused by a 2005 hurricane. To be eligible, a
            non-industrial private forest landowner must have suffered a 
            <PRTPAGE P='18' />
            loss of, or damage to, at least 35 percent of forest acres on
            commercial forest land of the forest landowner in a designated
            disaster county due to a 2005 hurricane or related condition. The 35
            percent loss shall be determined based on the value of the land
            before and after the hurricane event.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             During the 5-year period beginning on the date of the loss, the
            eligible private non-industrial forest landowner must:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Reforest the eligible damaged forest acres in accordance with a
            forest management plan approved by FSA that is appropriate for the
            forest type where the forest management plan is developed by a
            person or legal entity with appropriate forestry credentials, as
            determined by the Deputy Administrator;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Use the best management practices included in the forest management
            plan; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Exercise good stewardship on the forest land of the landowner while
            maintaining the land in a forested state.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notwithstanding 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='701' sect='126' psec='' tq='N'>
                701.126
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , an ECP participant shall not receive under this section more than
            75 percent of the participant&apos;s actual cost or of the total
            allowable cost of reforestation, rehabilitation, and related
            measures.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payments under this section shall not exceed a maximum of $150 per
            acre for any acre.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Requests will be prioritized based upon planting tree species best
            suited to the site as stated in the forest management plan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            71 FR 30265
          </aref>
          , May 26, 2006. Redesignated and amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 70088, 70089
          </aref>
          , Nov. 17, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6538'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:C:701.200-701.202
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        701.200-701.202
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='200-701' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.200-701
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .202
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6539'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:C:701.203
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        701.203
      </num>
      <head>
        Scope.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='203' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.203
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Scope.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subject to the availability of funds and only for areas, natural
            disasters, and time periods for the natural disaster and
            rehabilitation approved by the Deputy Administrator, FSA will
            provide financial assistance to owners of nonindustrial private
            forest land who carry out emergency measures to restore land damaged
            by a natural disaster on or after January 1, 2010, as determined by
            FSA.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The objective of EFRP is to make financial assistance available to
            eligible participants on eligible land for certain practices to
            restore nonindustrial private forest land that has been damaged by a
            natural disaster.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6540'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:C:701.204
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        701.204
      </num>
      <head>
        Participant eligibility.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='204' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.204
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Participant eligibility.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be eligible to participate in EFRP, a person or legal entity
            must be an owner of nonindustrial private forest land affected by a
            natural disaster, and must be liable for or have the expense that is
            the subject of the financial assistance. The owner must be a person
            or legal entity (including an Indian tribe) with full
            decision-making authority over the land, as determined by FSA, or
            with such waivers as may be needed from lenders or others as may be
            required, to undertake program commitments.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Federal agencies and States, including all agencies and political
            subdivisions of a State, are ineligible for EFRP.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An application may be denied for any reason.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6541'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:C:701.205
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        701.205
      </num>
      <head>
        Land eligibility.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='205' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.205
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Land eligibility.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For land to be eligible, it must be nonindustrial private forest
            land and must, as determined by FSA:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Have existing tree cover or have had tree cover immediately before
            the natural disaster and be suitable for growing trees;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Have damage to natural resources caused by a natural disaster,
            which occurred on or after January 1, 2010, that, if not treated,
            would impair or endanger the natural resources on the land and would
            materially affect future use of the land; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be physically located in a county in which EFRP has been
            implemented.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land is ineligible for EFRP if FSA determines that the land is any
            of the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Owned or controlled by the United States; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Owned or controlled by States, including State agencies or
            political subdivisions of a State.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6542'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:C:701.206-701.209
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        701.206-701.209
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='19' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='206-701' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.206-701
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .209
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6543'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:C:701.210
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        701.210
      </num>
      <head>
        Qualifying minimum cost of restoration.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='210' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.210
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Qualifying minimum cost of restoration.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FSA will establish the minimum qualifying cost of restoration,
            which may vary by State or region.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An applicant may request a waiver of the qualifying minimum cost of
            restoration. The waiver request must document how failure to grant
            the waiver will result in environmental damage or hardship to the
            person or legal entity, and how the waiver will accomplish the goals
            of the program.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6544'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:C:701.211
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        701.211
      </num>
      <head>
        Prohibition on duplicate payments.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='211' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.211
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Prohibition on duplicate payments.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Participants are not eligible to receive funding under EFRP for
            land on which FSA determines that the participant has or will
            receive funding for the same or similar expenses under:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Emergency Conservation Program provided for in subpart B of
            this part;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Wetland Reserve Program (WRP) provided for in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1467' tq='N'>
                1467 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Emergency Wetland Reserve Program (EWRP) provided for in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='623' tq='N'>
                623 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Emergency Watershed Protection Program (EWP), provided for in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='624' tq='N'>
                624 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any other program that covers the same or similar expenses so as to
            create duplicate payments, or, have the effect of creating in total,
            otherwise, a higher rate of financial assistance than is allowed on
            its own under this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Participants who receive any duplicate funds, payments, or benefits
            must refund any EFRP payments received, except the Deputy
            Administrator may reduce the refund amount to the amount determined
            appropriate by the Deputy Administrator to ensure that the total
            amount of assistance received by the owner of the land under all
            programs does not exceed an amount otherwise allowed in this part.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6545'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:C:701.212
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        701.212
      </num>
      <head>
        Eligible EFRP practices.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='212' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.212
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Eligible EFRP practices.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Financial assistance may be offered to eligible persons or legal
            entities for EFRP practices to restore forest health and
            forest-related resources on eligible land.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Practice specifications must represent the minimum level of
            performance needed to restore the land to the applicable FSA, NRCS,
            Forest Service, or State forestry standard.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6546'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:C:701.213-701.225
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        701.213-701.225
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='213-701' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.213-701
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .225
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6547'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:701:C:701.226
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        701.226
      </num>
      <head>
        Maximum financial assistance.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='701' sect='226' psec='' tq='N'>
              701.226
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Maximum financial assistance.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In addition to other restrictions that may be applied by FSA, an
            EFRP participant will not receive more than 75 percent of the lesser
            of the participant&apos;s total actual cost or of the total
            allowable costs, as determined by this subpart, to perform the
            practice.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A person, as defined in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
                1400 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , is limited to a maximum cost-share of $500,000 per person or legal
            entity, per disaster.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Deputy Administrator may waive the provisions of this section
            on a case by case basis to address unusually large losses. Such
            relief is solely at the discretion of the Deputy Administrator, and
            the failure to provide such relief is not subject to administrative
            review or appeal under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              parts 
              <subref title='7' part='11' tq='N'>
                11
              </subref>
               or 
              <subref title='7' part='780' tq='N'>
                780 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>