<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol4'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:C:277
    </extid>
    <num>
      277
    </num>
    <head>
      PAYMENTS OF CERTAIN ADMINISTRATIVE COSTS OF STATE AGENCIES
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='2011-203' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/2011-203.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 2011-203
            </subref>
          </aref>
          6.
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          Amdt. 188, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            45 FR 85702
          </aref>
          , Dec. 30, 1980, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
      <EDNOTE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Editorial Note:
        </HD>
        <P>
          OMB control numbers relating to this 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='277' tq='N'>
              277
            </subref>
          </aref>
           are contained in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='271' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              271.8
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </EDNOTE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='4961'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:C:277:-:277.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        277.1
      </num>
      <head>
        General purpose and scope.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='277' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              277.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General purpose and scope.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Purpose.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This part establishes uniform requirements for the management of
            administrative funds provided to State agencies and sets forth
            principles for claiming costs of activities paid with administrative
            funds under the Food Stamp Program, and the Food Distribution
            Program and Food Stamp Program on Indian Reservations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Scope and applicability.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon compliance with the provisions of this part, payments to State
            agencies will be made for cost(s) incurred for administration of the
            Food Stamp Program and for administration of the Food Distribution
            Program on Indian Reservations. To ensure maximum practical
            uniformity, deviation(s) by a State agency from this part may be
            authorized only when necessary to meet program objectives, to
            conserve program funds, or when essential to the public interest.
            However, any deviations from this part must be authorized by the
            Administrator of FNS.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4962'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:C:277:-:277.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        277.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='277' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              277.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          For the purpose of this part the term:
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Accrued expenditures
          </E>
           means the charges incurred by the State agency during a given period
          for liabilities incurred, benefits received or for goods and services
          used during this period.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Accrued income
          </E>
           means the net value of earnings during a given period resulting from
          services and goods provided whether or not payment has been realized.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Acquisition cost
          </E>
           refers to nonexpendable personal property acquired by purchase and
          means the net invoice price of the property including any attachments,
          accessories or auxiliary apparatus necessary to make the property
          usable for the purpose for which it was acquired. Ancillary charges
          such as taxes, duty, protection in-transit insurance, freight or
          installation shall be included in or excluded from acquisition cost in
          accordance with the State agency&apos;s regular accounting practices.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Approval or authorization by FNS
          </E>
           means documentation evidencing consent prior to incurring specific
          costs.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Applicable credits
          </E>
           refer to those receipts or reduction of expenditure-type transactions
          which offset or reduce expense items allocable to programs as direct
          or indirect costs. Examples of such transactions are: Purchase
          discounts; rebates or allowances; recoveries or indemnities on losses;
          sale of publications, equipment, and scrap; income from personal or
          incidental services; and adjustments of overpayments or erroneous
          charges.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Disbursements
          </E>
           refers to the transfer of funds by the state agency to pay for
          Program costs resulting from purchased or expired goods and services.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Expendable personal property
          </E>
           means all tangible personal property other than nonexpendable
          property.
          <PRTPAGE P='969' />
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Program funds
          </E>
           means money, or property provided in lieu of money, paid for or
          furnished by FNS to a State agency.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Funds available to the State agency
          </E>
           may include contributions from third parties including other Federal
          agencies.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            In-kind contributions
          </E>
           refers to the value of noncash contributions. Only when authorized by
          Federal legislation may property purchased with Federal funds be
          considered as a State agency&apos;s in-kind contribution. In-kind
          contributions may be for the value of real and/or nonexpendable
          personal property or the value of goods and services provided
          specifically to the project or program.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Nonexpendable personal property
          </E>
           means tangible personal property having a useful life of more than
          one year and an acquisition cost of more than $300 per unit. A State
          agency may use its own definition of nonexpendable personal property
          provided that such definition would at least include all tangible
          personal property as defined herein.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Obligations
          </E>
           are the amounts of orders placed, contracts awarded, services
          received, and similar transactions during a given period which require
          payment.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Offset
          </E>
           means a method to recover funds due FNS through use of the Letter of
          Credit system. Recovery is accomplished by accounting adjustments to
          increase Federal funds on hand or disbursed.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            OMB
          </E>
           means the Office of Management and Budget.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Personal property
          </E>
           means property of any kind except real property. It may be tangible
          (having physical existence) or intangible (having no physical
          existence) such as patents, inventions and copyrights.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Program
          </E>
           means both the Food Stamp Program and the Food Distribution Program
          on Indian Reservations.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Program closeout
          </E>
           means the process by which FNS determines that all applicable
          administrative and financial processes have been completed by the
          State agency and FNS terminates the program in the affected project
          area or areas.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Project costs
          </E>
           are allowable costs as set forth in this part.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Real property
          </E>
           means land, land improvements, structure and appurtenances thereto,
          excluding movable machinery and equipment.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State agency
          </E>
           means the organization as defined in 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR 
            <subref title='7' part='271' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              271.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State agency costs
          </E>
           means the State agency outlays from its funds available for program
          administration. Unless authorized by Federal legislation, costs
          charged to other Federal grants or to other Federal contracts may not
          be considered as State agency costs reimbursable under this authority.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Subagency
          </E>
           means the organization or person to which a State agency makes any
          payment for acquisition of goods, materials or services for use in
          administering the program and which is accountable to the State agency
          for the use of funds provided.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Terms and conditions
          </E>
           means legal requirements imposed by the Federal Government under
          statute, regulations, contracts, agreements or otherwise.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Unliquidated obligation
          </E>
           represents the amount of obligations not yet paid.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Unobligated balance
          </E>
           means the portion of the Federal funds authorized less all allowable
          costs and unpaid obligations of the State agency.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4963'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:C:277:-:277.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        277.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Budgets and budget revision procedures.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='277' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              277.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Budgets and budget revision procedures.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The preparation, content, submittal, and revision requirements for the
          State Food Stamp Program Budget shall be as specified in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='272' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              272.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
          . The application for funds and budget requirements for the Food
          Distribution Program on Indian Reservations shall be as specified in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='283' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
              283.9
            </subref>
          </aref>
          . State agencies must submit a budget to FNS as part of the State Plan
          each fiscal year. Upon approval of the budget by FNS, administrative
          funds will be provided.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4964'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:C:277:-:277.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        277.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Funding.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [Amdt. 188, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          45 FR 85702
        </aref>
        , Dec. 30, 1980]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='277' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              277.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Funding.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This section sets allowable cost standards for activities of State
            agencies in administering the Food Stamp Program and Food
            Distribution Program on Indian Reservations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Federal reimbursement rate.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The base percentage for Federal payment shall be 50 percent of
            State agencies&apos; 
            <PRTPAGE P='970' />
            allowable Food Stamp Program administrative costs. This rate
            includes reimbursement for food stamp informational activities but
            not for recruitment activities. Recruitment activities are those
            activities designed to persuade an individual who has made an
            informed choice not to apply for food stamps to change his or her
            decision and apply.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Funding of demonstration projects approved by FNS will be at a rate
            agreed to by FNS in accordance with the requirements outlined in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='282' tq='N'>
                282
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The reimbursement of administrative costs to State agencies
            administering the program on Indian reservations shall be in
            accordance with the requirements of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              parts 
              <subref title='7' part='281' tq='N'>
                281
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='283' tq='N'>
                283
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             the federally funded share of administrative costs, as identified
            in paragraph (b) of this section may be decreased based upon its
            payment error rate as described in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='275' sect='23' psec='' tq='N'>
                275.23
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . The rates of Federal funding for the activities identified in
            paragraphs (b)(1) and (b)(2) of this section shall not be reduced
            based upon the agency&apos;s payment error rate.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Employment and training program grants, as outlined in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='273' sect='7' psec='#d' tq='N'>
                273.7(d)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             shall be 100 percent federally-funded.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Matching costs.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State agency costs for Federal matching funds may consist of:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Charges reported on a cash or accrual basis by the State agency as
            project costs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Project costs financed with cash contributed or donated to the
            State agency by other non-Federal public agencies and institutions.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Project costs represented by services and real or personal property
            donated by other non-Federal public agencies and institutions.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All cash or in-kind contributions except as provided in paragraph
            (e) of this section shall be allowable as part of the State
            agency&apos;s share of program costs when such contributions:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Are verifiable;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Are not contributed for another federally-assisted program, unless
            authorized by Federal legislation;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Are necessary and reasonable for accomplishment of project
            objectives;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Are charges that would be allowable under this part;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Are not paid by the Federal Government under another assistance
            agreement unless authorized under the other agreement and its
            subject laws and regulations; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Are in the approved budget.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The value of services rendered by volunteers or the value of goods
            contributed by third parties, exclusive of the State and Federal
            agencies, are unallowable for reimbursement purposes under the Food
            Stamp Program. The value of services rendered by volunteers shall be
            allowable only to meet any matching administrative costs
            requirements for the Food Distribution Program on Indian
            Reservations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The expenses (e.g. travel, lodging, meals) of persons working with
            volunteer or nonprofit organizations which receive training and
            assistance pursuant to 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='272' sect='4' psec='#d_2' tq='N'>
                272.4(d)(2)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             are not allowable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Investigations of authorized retail or wholesale food concerns when
            performed in coordination with the USDA Office of Inspector General
            and FNS shall be funded at the 50 percent Federal reimbursement
            rate.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [Amdt. 188, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            45 FR 85702
          </aref>
          , Dec. 30, 1980]
        </CITA>
        <EDNOTE>
          <HD SOURCE='HED'>
            Editorial Note:
          </HD>
          <P>
            For 
            <E T='04'>
              Federal Register
            </E>
             citations affecting 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='277' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
                277.4
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , see the List of CFR Sections Affected, which appears in the
            Finding Aids section of the printed volume and at 
            <E T='03'>
              www.fdsys.gov
            </E>
            .
          </P>
        </EDNOTE>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4965'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:C:277:-:277.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        277.5
      </num>
      <head>
        Methods of payment.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='277' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              277.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Methods of payment.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This section sets forth FNS methods for authorizing funds for State
            agencies.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The “Letter of Credit” (LOC) (SF-1193A) is the document by which an
            official of FNS authorizes a State agency to draw funds from the
            United States Treasury. This shall be the preferred method of
            payment for State agencies which receive at least $120,000 per year
            and meet the requirements prescribed in OMB Circular A-102,
            Attachment J.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State agencies shall request payment(s) by submitting Request for
            Payment on Letter of Credit and Status of Funds Report (Treasury
            Form SF-183) to the appropriate United States Treasury Regional
            Disbursing Office with a copy to FNS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State agencies not meeting the requirements for the LOC method of 
            <PRTPAGE P='971' />
            payment or failing to meet LOC reporting requirements, including
            those requiring adjustments to cash balances to liquidate amounts
            owed to FNS, shall be provided funds by Treasury check in accordance
            with the provisions of Department of the Treasury Circular 1075.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payments for proper charges incurred by State agencies will not be
            withheld unless such payments are suspended or disallowed pursuant
            to 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='277' sect='16' psec='' tq='N'>
                277.16
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . When a payment is withheld, payment adjustments will be made in
            accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='277' sect='16' psec='' tq='N'>
                277.16
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . When FNS collects an indebtedness, whether due to a disallowance
            or an offset for amounts which the State agency has been billed but
            which it has failed to pay without cause acceptable to FNS, FNS
            shall provide reasonable notice to the State agency, and shall
            require appropriate accounting adjustment to cash balances for which
            the State agency is accountable to the Federal government to
            liquidate the indebtedness.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4966'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:C:277:-:277.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        277.6
      </num>
      <head>
        Standards for financial management systems.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='277' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              277.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Standards for financial management systems.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This section prescribes standards for financial management systems
            in administering program funds by the State agency and its
            subagencies or contractors.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Responsibilities.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Financial management systems for program funds in the State agency
            shall provide for:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Accurate, current, and complete disclosure of the financial results
            of program activities in accordance with Federal reporting
            requirements.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Records which identify the source and application of funds for FNS
            or State agency activities supporting the administration of the
            Program. These records shall show authorizations, obligations,
            unobligated balances, assets, liabilities, outlays and income of the
            State agency, its sub- agencies and agents.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Records which identify unallowable costs and offsets resulting from
            FNS or other determinations as specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='277' sect='16' psec='' tq='N'>
                277.16
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and the disposition of these amounts. Accounting procedures must be
            in effect to prevent a State agency from claiming these costs under
            ongoing program administrative cost reports.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Effective control and accountability by the State agency for all
            program funds, property, and other assets acquired with program
            funds. State agencies shall adequately safeguard all such assets and
            shall assure that they are used solely for program authorized
            purposes unless disposition has been made in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='277' sect='13' psec='' tq='N'>
                277.13
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Controls which minimize the time between the receipt of Federal
            funds from the United States Treasury and their disbursement for
            program costs. In the Letter of Credit system, the State agency
            shall make drawdowns from the U.S. Treasury through a U.S. Treasury
            Regional Disbursing Office as nearly as possible to the time of
            making the disbursements.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Procedures to determine the reasonableness, allowability, and
            allocability of costs in accordance with the applicable provisions
            prescribed in appendix A to this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Support and source documents for costs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An audit trail including identification of time periods, initial
            and summary accounts, cost determination and allocation procedures,
            cost centers or other accounting procedures to support any costs
            claimed for program administration.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Periodic audits by qualified individuals who are independent of
            those who maintain Federal program funds as prescribed in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='277' sect='17' psec='' tq='N'>
                277.17
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Methods to resolve audit findings and recommendations and to follow
            up on corrective or preventive actions.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The standards in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='277' sect='6' psec='#b' tq='N'>
                277.6(b)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             apply to subagencies or contractors involved with program funding.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4967'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:C:277:-:277.7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        277.7
      </num>
      <head>
        Cash depositories.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='277' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              277.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Cash depositories.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The term “cash depositories” refers to banks or other institutions
            which maintain accounts where Food Stamp Program funds are deposited
            and from which withdrawals are made to meet administrative costs of
            the State agency.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State agencies are encouraged to use minority owned banks to expand
            opportunities for minority enterprises.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS shall not:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Require physical segregation in a cash depository of program funds
            from other State agency funds.
            <PRTPAGE P='972' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Establish any eligibility requirements for cash depositories in
            which program funds are deposited by the State agency.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4968'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:C:277:-:277.8
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        277.8
      </num>
      <head>
        Bonding and insurance.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='277' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              277.8
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Bonding and insurance.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In administering FNS program funds, State agencies shall observe
            their regular requirements and practices with respect to bonding and
            insurance. FNS will not impose additional bonding and insurance
            requirements, including fidelity bonding, above those normally
            required by the State agency.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Loan guarantees.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS makes no guarantee of any loan or payment of money borrowed by
            a State agency for administering the program. State agencies shall
            not make any assurances to any lender or contractor that FNS will
            furnish funds for loan payments.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4969'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:C:277:-:277.9
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        277.9
      </num>
      <head>
        Administrative costs principles.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [Amdt. 188, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          45 FR 85702
        </aref>
        , Dec. 30, 1980, as amended by Amdt. 385, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          65 FR 33440
        </aref>
        , May 24, 2000]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='277' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
              277.9
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Administrative costs principles.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This section prescribes specific policies and procedures governing
            State agencies for funding under this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The incremental cost of certifying TANF households for Food Stamp
            Program benefits are allowable costs for FNS reimbursement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When costs for administering the program are claimed for
            reimbursement, the audit trail must identify the specific
            activities, locations, or time periods as defined in this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Direct cost.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Allowable direct costs may be charged to the Food Stamp Program at
            the 50 percent or higher funding level as specified in this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Indirect cost.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Allowable indirect costs may also be claimed at the 50 percent or
            higher reimbursement funding level as specified in this part and
            appendix A.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Direct and indirect costs claimed for program cost reimbursement
            must be incurred for the time periods, the activities or for the
            locations for which the rates are approved by FNS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All State agency Cost Allocation Plans for determining the costs of
            administering the program must be approved by the cognizant Federal
            agency. All Cost Allocation Plans involving program funds shall be
            submitted to FNS for review.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [Amdt. 188, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            45 FR 85702
          </aref>
          , Dec. 30, 1980, as amended by Amdt. 385, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            65 FR 33440
          </aref>
          , May 24, 2000]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4970'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:C:277:-:277.10
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        277.10
      </num>
      <head>
        Program income.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='277' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
              277.10
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Program income.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Program income is gross income resulting from activities financed
            with program funds. Such earnings exclude interest income but
            include income from service fees, usage or rental fees, sale of
            assets purchased with program funds, and royalties on patents and
            copyrights.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Interest earned on advances of program administrative funds shall
            be remitted to FNS except for interest earned on advances to States
            or instrumentalities of a State as provided by the Intergovernmental
            Cooperation Act of 1968 (Pub. L. 90-577) and advances to tribal
            organizations under the Indian Self-Determination Act (
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              sections 102
            </aref>
             through 104).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Income resulting from the sale of real and personal property whose
            acquisition cost was borne in whole or in part with Program funds
            shall be remitted to FNS or applied to the Federal share of current
            program costs in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='277' sect='13' psec='' tq='N'>
                277.13
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . All other sales proceeds will be handled in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='277' sect='13' psec='' tq='N'>
                277.13
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Unless there is a prior agreement between FNS and the State agency,
            the State agency shall have no obligation to FNS with respect to
            royalties received from copyrights or patents produced as a result
            of activities financed with program administrative funds.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any other income earned under activities supported by program
            administrative funds may be retained by the State agency if they are
            deducted from the gross program administrative costs for the
            purposes of determining net costs and FNS&apos;s share of net cost.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State agencies shall record the receipt and expenditure of revenues
            such as taxes, special assessments, levies, fines, etc., as a part
            of program fund transactions when such revenues are specifically
            earmarked for program fund projects.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4971'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:C:277:-:277.11
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        277.11
      </num>
      <head>
        Financial reporting requirements.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [Amdt. 188, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          45 FR 85702
        </aref>
        , Dec. 30, 1980, as amended by Amdt. 385, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          65 FR 33440
        </aref>
        , May 24, 2000]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='973' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='277' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
              277.11
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Financial reporting requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This section prescribes requirements for the State agencies to
            report financial information to FNS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Authorized forms and instructions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Only forms specified by this part, or other forms authorized by
            FNS, may be used for obtaining financial information from State
            agencies for the program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All instructions for use in connection with the form specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='277' sect='11' psec='#c' tq='N'>
                277.11(c)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             shall be followed. FNS may prescribe supplementary instructions.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State agencies shall submit the original and two copies of forms
            required by this section unless FNS approves a waiver of this
            requirement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The forms and instructions in this part shall be available to the
            State agency and to the public upon request to FNS Regional Offices
            as set out in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='271' sect='6' psec='#b' tq='N'>
                271.6(b)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Financial status report—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Form.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State agencies shall use the standard Financial Status Report (Form
            SF-269) to report program costs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Frequency.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The report (Form SF-269) shall be required quarterly.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Exceptions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Those State agencies that receive payments under the U.S. Treasury
            check system shall submit to FNS a Quarterly Report of Federal Cash
            Transactions (Form SF-272).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Due dates.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Quarterly reports shall be due April 30 (for the period January
            through March), July 30 (April through June), October 30 (July
            through September), January 30 (October through December). Final
            reports are due December 30 for all completed Federal fiscal years
            (October 1 through September 30) or 90 days after termination of
            Federal financial support. Requests from State agencies for
            extension of reporting due dates may be approved, if necessary.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Time limit for State agencies to file claims.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             After the deadline in paragraph (c)(4) of this section for the
            final SF-269 report, State agencies shall use the form specified by
            FNS as needed within three years of the end of the Federal fiscal
            year to amend a prior expenditure report pertaining to such Federal
            fiscal year. The three-year reporting deadline may be extended by
            FNS if litigation, an audit, or a claim is unresolved at the end of
            the three-year period. The reporting form shall be used to amend
            prior expenditure reports, and to request reimbursement for any
            additional funding due, or to pay back to FNS any inadvertent prior
            overclaim. Requests for reimbursement will only be honored if the
            claim is filed within the timeframe in paragraph (d)(2) of this
            section. FNS reserves the right to bill State agencies for amounts
            due FNS resulting from an overclaim, even if no reporting form has
            been submitted.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subject to the availability of funds from the appropriation for the
            year in which the expenditure was incurred, FNS may reimburse State
            agencies for an allowable expenditure only if the State agency files
            a claim with FNS for that expenditure within two years after the
            calendar quarter in which the State agency (or local agency)
            incurred the cost. FNS will consider non-cash expenditures such as
            depreciation to have been made in the quarter the expenditure was
            recorded in the accounting records of the State agency in accordance
            with generally accepted accounting principles.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For Automated Data Processing (ADP) expenditures approved under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='277' sect='18' psec='#c' tq='N'>
                277.18(c)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , subject to the availability of funds and required FNS approval
            related to the Advance Planning Document, FNS may reimburse State
            agencies for allowable expenditures at the appropriate rate in
            effect at the time the equipment or service was received only if the
            State agency files for a claim with FNS within two years after the
            calendar quarter in which the cost was incurred. FNS will consider
            non-cash expenditures such as depreciation to have been made in the
            quarter the expenditure was recorded in the accounting records of
            the State agency in accordance with generally accepted accounting
            principles.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             States wishing to request an extension of the deadline in
            paragraphs (d)(2) and (d)(3) of this section must submit the request
            in writing to FNS prior to the applicable deadline. The State
            agency&apos;s request for an extension must include a specific
            explanation, justification, and documentation of why the claim will
            be late and when the claim will be filed.
            <PRTPAGE P='974' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The time limits in paragraphs (d)(2) and (d)(3) of this section
            will not apply to any of the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_5_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any claim for an adjustment to prior year costs previously claimed
            under an interim rate concept;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_5_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any claim arising from an audit exception as defined in this
            section. An audit exception means a proposed adjustment by the
            Department to any expenditure claimed by a State agency by virtue of
            a Federal-or State-initiated audit. The audit must comply with the
            requirements of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='277' sect='17' psec='' tq='N'>
                277.17
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3015' tq='N'>
                3015
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , and must have been started within 3 years of the date of
            submission of the final SF-269 of the relevant Federal fiscal year
            to which it applies.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_5_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any claim resulting from a court-ordered retroactive payment.
            However, this provision does not bind FNS to a State or Federal
            court decision when FNS was not a party to the action;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_5_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any claim for which FNS determines there was good cause for the
            State agency&apos;s not filing it within the time limit. Good cause
            is lateness due to circumstances beyond the State agency&apos;s
            control such as Acts of God or documented action or inaction of the
            Federal Government. It does not include neglect or administrative
            inadequacy on the part of the State, State agency, legislature, or
            any of their offices or employees.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [Amdt. 188, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            45 FR 85702
          </aref>
          , Dec. 30, 1980, as amended by Amdt. 385, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            65 FR 33440
          </aref>
          , May 24, 2000]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4972'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:C:277:-:277.12
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        277.12
      </num>
      <head>
        Retention and custody of records.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='277' sect='12' psec='' tq='N'>
              277.12
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Retention and custody of records.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Retention period.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All financial records, supporting documents, statistical records,
            negotiated contracts, and all other records pertinent to program
            funds shall be maintained for three years from the date of
            submission of the annual financial status report of the relevant
            fiscal year to which they apply except that:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If any litigation, claim, or audit is started before the expiration
            of the three-year period, the applicable records shall be retained
            until these have been resolved.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the case of a payment by a State agency to a subagency or
            contractor using program funds, the State agency, USDA, the
            Comptroller General of the United States, or any of their duly
            authorized representatives, shall have access to any book,
            documents, papers and records of the subagency or contractor which
            the State agency, USDA, or the Comptroller General of the United
            States or any of their duly authorized representatives, determine
            are pertinent to administration of the specific FNS program funds,
            for the purpose of making audit, examination, excerpts, and
            transcripts.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Restrictions on public access.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Unless required by laws, FNS will not place restrictions on State
            agencies which limit public access to their records or the records
            of their subagencies or contractors that are pertinent to the
            administrative funding provided by FNS except when the State agency
            can demonstrate that such records must be kept confidential and
            would have been excepted from disclosure pursuant to the Freedom of
            Information Act (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='5' sect='552' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/5/552.html'>
                5 U.S.C. 552
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) if the records had belonged to FNS.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4973'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:C:277:-:277.13
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        277.13
      </num>
      <head>
        Property.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='277' sect='13' psec='' tq='N'>
              277.13
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Property.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This section prescribes policies and procedures governing title,
            use, disposition of real and personal property for which acquisition
            costs were borne, in whole or in part, as a direct charge to FNS
            funds, and ownership rights or intangible personal property
            developed, in whole or in part, with FNS funds. State agencies may
            follow their own property management policies and procedures
            provided they observe the requirements of this section. With respect
            to property covered by this section, FNS may not impose on State
            agencies any requirement (including property reporting requirements)
            not authorized by this section unless specifically required by
            Federal laws.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Nonexpendable personal property—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Title.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Title to nonexpendable personal property whose acquisition cost is
            borne, in whole or in part, by FNS shall vest in the State agency
            upon acquisition, and shall be subject to the restrictions on use
            and dispositions set forth in this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Use.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall use the property in the program as long as 
            <PRTPAGE P='975' />
            there is a need for such property to accomplish the purpose of the
            program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When there is no longer a need for the property to accomplish the
            purpose of the program, the State agency shall use the property
            where needed in administration of other programs in the following
            order of priority:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='b_2_ii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Other federally-funded programs of FNS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='b_2_ii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Other federally-funded programs of USDA.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='b_2_ii_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Other federally-funded programs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When the State agency no longer has need for such property in any
            of its federally financed activities, the property may be used for
            the State agency&apos;s own official activities in accordance with
            the following standards:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='b_2_iii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the property had a total acquisition cost of less than $1,000,
            the State agency may use the property without reimbursement to FNS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='b_2_iii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For all such property not covered under paragraph (b)(2)(iii)(A) of
            this section, the State agency may retain the property for its own
            use, provided a fair compensation is made to FNS for the FNS share
            of the property. The amount of compensation shall be computed by
            applying the percentage of FNS participation in the cost of the
            property to the current fair market value of the property.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Disposition.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the State agency has no need for the property, disposition of
            the property shall be made as follows:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the property had a total acquisition cost of less than $1,000
            per unit, the State agency may sell the property and retain the
            proceeds.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the property had an acquisition cost of $1,000 or more per unit,
            the State agency shall:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='b_3_ii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If instructed to ship the property elsewhere, the State agency
            shall be reimbursed with an amount which is computed by applying the
            percentage of the State agency&apos;s participation in the cost of
            the property to the current fair market value of the property, plus
            any shipping or interim storage costs incurred.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='b_3_ii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If instructed to otherwise dispose of the property, the State
            agency shall be reimbursed by FNS for the cost incurred in such
            disposition.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='b_3_ii_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If disposition or other instructions are not issued by FNS within
            120 days of a request from the State agency, the State agency shall
            sell the property and reimburse FNS an amount which is computed by
            applying the percentage of FNS participation in the cost of the
            property to the sales proceeds. The State agency may, however,
            deduct and retain from FNS&apos;s share $100 or 10 percent of the
            proceeds, whichever is greater, for the State agency selling and
            handling expenses.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Transfer of title to certain property.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Where FNS determines that an item of nonexpendable personal
            property with an acquisition cost of $1,000 or more which is to be
            wholly borne by FNS is unique, difficult, or costly to replace, FNS
            may reserve the right to require the State agency to transfer title
            of the property to the Federal Government or to a third party named
            by FNS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Such reservation shall be subject to the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The right to require transfer of title may be reserved only by
            means of an expressed special condition under which funds were
            authorized for acquisition of the property, or, if approval for the
            acquisition of the property is given after the funds are awarded, by
            means of a written stipulation at the time such approval is given.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The property must be sufficiently described to enable the State
            agency to determine exactly what property is involved.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS may not exercise the right to reserve until the State agency no
            longer needs the property in the activity for which it was acquired.
            Such need shall be assumed to end with termination of the activity
            in which the property was used unless the State agency continues to
            use the property in other program-related activities after the
            termination date and demonstrates to FNS a continued need for such
            use in the program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To exercise the right, FNS must issue disposition instructions to
            the State agency not later than 120 days after the State agency no
            longer needs the property in the activity for which it was acquired.
            If instructions are not issued within that time, FNS&apos;s right
            shall lapse, and the State agency shall 
            <PRTPAGE P='976' />
            act in accordance with the applicable standards in paragraphs (b)(2)
            and (b)(3) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall be entitled to reimbursement with an amount
            which is computed by applying the percentages of the State
            agency&apos;s participation in the acquisition cost of the property
            to the current fair market value of the property, and for any
            reasonable shipping and interim storage costs it incurs pursuant to
            FNS&apos;s disposition instructions.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Property management standards.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State agencies&apos; property management standards for
            nonexpendable personal property covered by this section shall
            include the following procedural requirements:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Property records shall be maintained accurately and provide for:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A description of the property.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Manufacturer&apos;s serial number or other identification number.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Acquisition date and cost.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Source of the property.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Percentage of FNS funds used in the acquisition of the property, or
            sufficient information to be able to compute the percentage, if and
            when the property is disposed of.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Location, use and condition of the property.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_vii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Ultimate disposition data including sales price or the method used
            to determine current fair market value if the State agency
            reimburses FNS for its share.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_viii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (viii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Trade-in value of any property purchased with Federal funds where
            their trade-in value reduces the acquisition cost of new property.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A physical inventory of property shall be taken and the results
            reconciled with the property records at least once every two years
            to verify the existence, current utilization, and continued need for
            the property.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A control system shall be in effect to ensure adequate safeguards
            to prevent loss, damage, or theft to the property. Any loss, damage,
            or theft of nonexpendable personal property shall be investigated
            and properly documented.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Adequate maintenance procedures shall be implemented to keep the
            property in good condition.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Proper sales procedures shall be implemented to keep the property
            in good condition.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Expendable personal property—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Title.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Title to expendable personal property, whose acquisition cost was
            borne in whole or in part by FNS, shall vest in the State agency.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Use.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall use the property in the program as long as
            there is a need for such property to accomplish the purpose of the
            program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Disposition.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When there is no longer a need for the property in the program and
            there is a residual inventory exceeding $1,000 the State agency
            shall:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Use the property in other federally sponsored projects or programs;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Retain the property for use on non-federally sponsored activities;
            or,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Sell it.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Compensation.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS must be compensated for its share if the alternative in
            paragraph (e)(3)(i) of this section is not followed. The amount of
            compensation shall be computed in the same manner as for
            nonexpendable personal property.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Patents and inventions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If any program activity produced patents, patent rights, processes
            or inventions in the course of work aided by FNS, such fact shall be
            promptly and fully reported to FNS. Unless there is prior agreement
            between the State agency and FNS on disposition of such items, FNS
            shall determine whether protection on such invention or discovery
            shall be sought and how the rights in the invention or
            discovery—including rights under any patent issued thereon—shall be
            disposed of and administered in order to protect the public interest
            consistent with “Government Patent Policy” (President&apos;s
            Memorandum for Heads of Excecutive Departments and Agencies, August
            23, 1971), and State of Government Patent Policy as printed in title
            37 CFR, chapters I and II.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Copyrights.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When a program activity results in a book or other copyrightable
            materials, the author or State agency is free to copyright the work,
            but FNS reserves a royalty-free, nonexclusive and irrevocable right
            to reproduce, publish or otherwise use and to authorize others to
            use the work for government purposes. This includes 
            <PRTPAGE P='977' />
            copyrights on ADP software as specified in appendix A.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4974'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:C:277:-:277.14
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        277.14
      </num>
      <head>
        Procurement standards.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='277' sect='14' psec='' tq='N'>
              277.14
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Procurement standards.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This section establishes standards and guidelines for the
            procurement of supplies, equipment, construction and other services
            whose cost is borne in whole or in part by FNS program funds. These
            standards ensure that such materials are obtained in an effective
            and economical manner and in compliance with the provisions of
            applicable Federal law and Executive orders. No additional
            procurement standards will be imposed by FNS upon State agencies
            unless specifically required by Federal law, or Executive orders, or
            authorized by the Administrator for Federal Procurement Policy,
            Office of Management and Budget.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             These standards do not relieve the State agency of any contractual
            responsibilities under its contracts. The State agency is
            responsible, in accordance with good administrative practice and
            sound business judgment, for the settlement of all contractual and
            administrative issues arising out of procurements entered into in
            support of the program. These include but are not limited to sources
            evaluations, protests, disputes and claims. FNS shall not substitute
            its judgment for that of the State agency unless the matter is
            primarily a Federal concern. Violations of laws shall be referred to
            the local, State or Federal authority having jurisdiction.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State agencies shall use their own procurement procedures provided
            that procurements paid in whole or in part with FNS program funds
            meet the standards set forth in this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Review of proposed contracts.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State agencies shall submit proposed contracts and related
            procurement documents to FNS for preaward review and approval when:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The procurement is expected to exceed $10,000 and is to be awarded
            without competition or only one bid or offer is received in response
            to solicitation;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The procurement expected to exceed $10,000 specifies a “brand name”
            product; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS has determined that the State agency&apos;s procurement
            procedures or operation fails to comply with one or more significant
            aspects of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Code of conduct.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall maintain a written code or standards of
            conduct which shall govern the performance of its officers,
            employees, or agents engaged in the award and administration of
            contracts borne in whole or in part with FNS program funds. No
            employee, officer, or agent of the State agency shall participate in
            the selection, or in the award or administration of a contract
            supported in whole or in part by FNS program funds if a conflict of
            interest, real or apparent, would be involved. Such conflict would
            arise when:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The employee, officer, or agent;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any member of his/her immediate family;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             His or her partner; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An organization which employs, or is about to employ, any of the
            above, has a financial or other interest in the firm selected for
            award. The State agency&apos;s officers, employees, or agents shall
            neither solicit nor accept gratuities, favors, or anything of
            monetary value from contractors, potential contractors, or parties
            to subagreements. State agencies may set minimum rules where the
            financial interest is not substantial or the gift is an unsolicited
            item of nominal intrinsic value. To the extent permitted by State or
            local law or regulations, such standards of conduct shall provide
            for penalties, sanctions, or other disciplinary actions for
            violations of such standards by the State agency&apos;s officers,
            employees, or agents, or by contractors or their agents.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Procurement procedures.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall establish procurement procedures which
            provide that proposed procurement actions shall be reviewed by State
            agency officials to avoid the purchase of unnecessary or duplicative
            items. Consideration should be given to consolidation or dividing
            the purchase into smaller units, to obtain a more economical
            purchase. Where appropriate, an analysis shall be made of lease
            versus purchase alternatives, and any other appropriate analyses, to
            determine which approach would be the most economical. To foster
            greater economy and efficiency, State agencies 
            <PRTPAGE P='978' />
            are encouraged to enter into State and local intergovernmental
            agreements for procurement or use of common goods and services.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Contracting with small and minority firms, women&apos;s business
              enterprises and labor surplus area firms.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             It is FNS policy to award a fair share of contracts to small and
            minority business firms. State agencies must take affirmative steps
            to assure that small and minority businesses are utilized when
            possible as sources of supplies, equipment, construction and
            services. State agency affirmative steps shall include the
            following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Including qualified small and minority businesses on solicitation
            lists.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Assuring that small and minority businesses are solicited whenever
            they are potential sources.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When economically feasible, dividing total requirements into
            smaller tasks or quantities so as to permit maximum small and
            minority business participation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Where the requirement permits, establishing delivery schedules
            which will encourage participation by small and minority business.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_1_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Using the services and assistance of the Small Business
            Administration, the Office of Minority Business Enterprise of the
            Department of Commerce and the Community Services Administration, as
            appropriate.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_1_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If any subcontracts are to be let, requiring the prime contractor
            to take the affirmative steps in paragraphs (e)(1) (i) through (v)
            of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State agencies shall take similar appropriate affirmative action in
            support of women&apos;s business enterprises.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State agencies are encouraged to procure goods and services from
            labor surplus areas, as defined by the Department of Labor.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS shall impose no additional regulations or requirements in the
            foregoing areas unless specifically mandated by law or Executive
            order.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Selection procedures.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All State agency procurement transactions shall be conducted in a
            manner that provides maximum open and free competition with this
            section. Procurement procedures shall not contain features which
            restrict or eliminate competition. The State agency shall have
            written selection procedures which shall provide, as a minimum, the
            following procedural requirements:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Solicitation of offers, whether by competitive sealed bid or
            competitive negotiation, shall contain a clear and accurate
            description of the technical requirements for the material, product,
            or service desired. Descriptions shall not, in competitive
            procurements, contain features which unduly restrict competition.
            Descriptions may include a statement of the qualitative nature of
            the material, product or service desired and, when necessary, shall
            set forth those minimum essential characteristics and standards to
            which it must conform if it is to satisfy its intended use. When it
            is impractical or uneconomical to describe clearly and accurately
            the technical requirements, a “brand name or equal” description may
            be used to define the performance or requirements of the material,
            product or service desired. The specific features of the named brand
            which must be met by offerors shall be clearly stated. State
            agencies shall clearly set forth all requirements which offerors
            must fulfill and all other factors to be used in evaluating bids or
            proposals.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State agencies shall make awards only to responsible contractors
            that possess the potential ability to perform successfully under the
            terms and conditions of a proposed procurement. Consideration shall
            be given to such matters as contractor integrity, compliance with
            public policy, record of past performance, and financial and
            technical resources.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Procurement methods.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State agency procurements made in whole or in part with program
            funds shall be by one of the following methods:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Small purchase procedures
            </E>
             are those relatively simple and informal procurement methods that
            are sound and appropriate for a procurement of services, supplies,
            or other property, costing in the aggregate not more than $10,000.
            State agencies shall comply with State or local small purchase
            dollar limits under $10,000. If small purchase procedures are used
            for a procurement under the program, price or rate quotations shall
            be obtained from an adequate number of qualified sources.
            <PRTPAGE P='979' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In 
            <E T='03'>
              competitive sealed bids
            </E>
             (formal advertising), sealed bids are publicly solicited and a
            firm-fixed-price contract (lump sum or unit price) is awarded to the
            responsible bidder whose bid, conforming with all the material terms
            and conditions of the invitation for bids, is lowest in price.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In order for the State agency to use this method of procurement the
            following conditions, as a minimum, must prevail:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_vi_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A complete, adequate, and realistic specification or purchase
            description is available.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_vi_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Two or more responsible suppliers are willing and able to compete
            effectively for the State agency&apos;s business.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_vi_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The procurement lends itself to a firm-fixed-price contract, and
            selection of the successful bidder can appropriately be made
            principally on the basis of price.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If formal advertising is used for a procurement under a grant, the
            following requirements shall apply:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_ii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A sufficient time prior to the date set for opening of bids, bids
            shall be solicited from an adequate number of known suppliers. In
            addition, the invitation shall be publicly advertised.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_ii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The invitation for bids, including specifications and pertinent
            attachments, shall clearly define the items or services needed in
            order for the bidders to properly respond to the invitation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_ii_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All bids shall be opened publicly at the time and place stated in
            the invitation for bids.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_ii_D'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (D)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A firm-fixed-price contract award shall be made by written notice
            by the State agency to that responsible bidder whose bid, conforming
            to the invitation for bids, is lowest. Where specified in the
            bidding documents, factors such as discounts, transportation costs
            and life cycle costs shall be considered in determining which bid is
            lowest. Payment discounts may only be used to determine low bid when
            prior experience of the State agency indicates that such discounts
            are generally taken.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_ii_E'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (E)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any or all bids may be rejected by the State agency when there are
            sound documented business reasons in the best interest of the
            program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In 
            <E T='03'>
              competitive negotiation,
            </E>
             proposals are requested from a number of sources and the Request
            for Proposal is publicized, negotiations are normally conducted with
            more than one of the sources submitting offers, and either a
            fixed-price or cost-reimbursable type contract is awarded, as
            appropriate. Competitive negotiation may be used if conditions are
            appropriate for the use of formal advertising. If competitive
            negotiation is used for procurement under a grant, the following
            requirements shall apply:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Proposals shall be solicited from an adequate number of qualified
            sources to permit reasonable competition consistent with the nature
            and requirements of the procurement. The Request for Proposals shall
            be publicized and reasonable requests by other sources to compete
            shall be honored to the maximum extent practicable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Request for Proposal shall identify all significant evaluation
            factors, including price or cost where required and their relative
            importance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall provide procedures for technical evaluation
            of the proposals received, determinations of responsible offerors
            for the purpose of written or oral discussions, and selection for
            contract award.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_3_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Award may be made to the responsible offeror whose proposal will be
            most advantageous to the State agency, price and other factors
            considered. Unsuccessful offerors should be notified promptly.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_3_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State agencies may utilize competitive negotiation procedures for
            procurement of architectural/engineering professional services
            whereby competitors&apos; qualifications are evaluated and the most
            qualified competitor is selected subject to negotiation of fair and
            reasonable compensation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Noncompetitive negotiation
            </E>
             is procurement through solicitation of a proposal from only one
            source, or after solicitation of a number of sources, competition is
            determined inadequate. Noncompetitive negotiation may be used when
            the award of a contract is infeasible under small purchase,
            competitive bidding (formal advertising) or competitive negotiation
            procedures. Awards of contracts by noncompetitive negotiation are
            limited to the following:
            <PRTPAGE P='980' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_4_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The item is available only from a single source;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_4_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Public exigency or emergency when the urgency for the requirement
            will not permit a delay incident to competitive procurement;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_4_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS authorizes noncompetitive procurement; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_4_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             After solicitation of a number of sources, competition is
            determined inadequate.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Contract pricing.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The cost plus a percentage of cost and percentage of construction
            cost method(s) of contracting may not be used by a State agency.
            State agencies shall perform some form of cost or price analysis in
            connection with every procurement action including contract
            modifications. Costs or prices based on estimated costs for
            contracts, paid in whole or in part by FNS program funds, shall be
            allowed only to the extent that costs incurred or cost estimates
            included in negotiated prices are consistent with Federal cost
            principles.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              State agency procurement records.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State agencies shall maintain records sufficient to detail the
            significant history of a procurement. These records shall include,
            but are not necessarily limited to, information pertinent to the
            rationale for the method of procurement, the selection of contract
            type, the contract selection or rejection, and the basis for the
            cost or price.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Contract provisions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In addition to provisions defining a sound and complete procurement
            contract, State agencies shall include the following contract
            provisions or conditions in all procurement contracts and
            subcontracts as required by this provision, Federal law, or FNS:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Contracts other than small purchases shall contain provisions or
            conditions which will allow for administrative, contractual, or
            legal remedies in instances where contractors violate or breach
            contract terms, and provide for such sanctions and penalties as may
            be appropriate.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All contracts in excess of $10,000 shall contain suitable
            provisions for termination by the State agency including the manner
            by which it will be effected and the basis for settlement. In
            addition, such contracts shall describe conditions under which the
            contract may be terminated for default as well as conditions where
            the contract may be terminated because of circumstances beyond the
            control of the contractor.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All contracts awarded in excess of $10,000 by State agencies and
            their contractors or subagencies shall contain a provision requiring
            compliance with Executive Order 11246, entitled “Equal Employment
            Opportunity,” as amended by Executive Order 11375, and as
            supplemented in Department of Labor regulations (
            <aref type='CFR'>
              29 CFR part 
              <subref title='29' part='60' tq='N'>
                60
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All contracts and subcontracts for construction or repair shall
            include a provision for compliance with the Copeland “Anti-Kickback”
            Act (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='18' sect='874' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/18/874.html'>
                18 U.S.C. 874
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) as supplemented in Department of Labor regulations (
            <aref type='CFR'>
              29 CFR part 
              <subref title='29' part='3' tq='N'>
                3
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ). This Act provides that each contractor or subagency shall be
            prohibited from inducing, by any means, any person employed in the
            construction, completion, or repair of public work, to give up any
            part of the compensation to which he is otherwise entitled. The
            State agency shall report all suspected or reported violations to
            FNS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Where applicable, all contracts awarded by State agencies and
            subagencies in excess of $2,000 for construction contracts in excess
            of $2,500 for other contracts which involve the employment of
            mechanics or laborers shall include a provision for compliance with 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              sections 103 and 107 of
            </aref>
             the Contract Work Hours and Safety Standards Act (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='40' sect='327' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/40/327.html'>
                40 U.S.C. 327
              </subref>
            </aref>
             through 330) as supplemented by Department of Labor regulations (
            <aref type='CFR'>
              29 CFR part 
              <subref title='29' part='5' tq='N'>
                5
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ). Under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 103 of
            </aref>
             the Act, each contractor shall be required to compute the wages of
            every mechanic and laborer on the basis of a standard work day of 8
            hours and a standard work week of 40 hours. Work in excess of the
            standard work day or work week is permissible provided that the work
            is compensated at a rate of not less than 1
            <FR>
              1/2
            </FR>
             times the basic rate for all hours worked in excess of 8 hours in
            any calendar day or 40 hours in the work week. 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              Section 107 of
            </aref>
             the Act is applicable to construction work and provides that no
            laborer or mechanic shall be required to work in surroundings or
            under working conditions which are unsanitary, hazardous, or
            dangerous to 
            <PRTPAGE P='981' />
            his health and safety as determined under construction, safety, and
            health standards promulated by the Secretary of Labor. These
            requirements do not apply to the purchases of supplies or materials
            or articles ordinarily available on the open market, or contracts
            for transportation or transmission of intelligence.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The contract shall include notice of FNS requirements and
            regulations pertaining to reporting and print rights under any
            contract involving research, developmental, experimental, or
            demonstration work with respect to any discovery or invention which
            arises or is developed in the course of or under such contract, and
            of FNS requirements and regulations pertaining to copyrights and
            rights to data so derived.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All negotiated contracts (except those awarded by small purchases
            procedures) awarded by State agencies shall include a provision to
            the effect that the State agency, FNS, the Comptroller General of
            the United States, or any of their duly authorized representatives,
            shall have access to any books, documents, papers, and records of
            the contractor which are directly pertinent to that specific
            contract, for the purpose of making audit, examination, excerpts,
            and transcriptions. State agencies shall require contracts to
            maintain all required records for three years after the State agency
            makes final payments or all other pending matters are closed,
            whichever is last.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Contracts, subcontracts, and subgrants of amounts in excess of
            $100,000 shall contain a provision which requires compliance with
            all applicable standards, orders, or requirements issued under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 306 of
            </aref>
             the Clean Air Act, 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 508 of
            </aref>
             the Clean Water Act, Executive Order 11738, and Environmental
            Protection Agency (EPA) regulations, which prohibit the use under
            nonexempt Federal contract, grants, or loans of facilities included
            on the EPA List of Violating Facilities. The provision shall require
            reporting of violations to the FNS and to the USEPA Assistant
            Administrator for Enforcement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Contracts shall recognize mandatory standards and policies relating
            to energy efficiency which are contained in the State energy
            conservation plan issued in compliance with the Energy Policy and
            Conservation Act (
            <aref target='_blank' title='Pub. L. 94-165' alt='Pub. L. 94-165' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d94:./list/bd/d94pl.lst:165%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Pub. L. 94-165
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Contract administration.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State agencies shall maintain a contract administration system
            insuring that contractors perform in accordance with the terms,
            conditions, and specifications of their contracts or purchase
            orders.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4975'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:C:277:-:277.15
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        277.15
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='277' sect='15' psec='' tq='N'>
              277.15
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4976'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:C:277:-:277.16
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        277.16
      </num>
      <head>
        Suspension, disallowance and program closeout.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [Amdt. 188, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          45 FR 85702
        </aref>
        , Dec. 30, 1980, as amended by Amdt. 342, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          59 FR 2733
        </aref>
        , Jan. 19, 1994]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='277' sect='16' psec='' tq='N'>
              277.16
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Suspension, disallowance and program closeout.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Suspension.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When a State agency has materially failed to comply with any of the
            provisions contained in the Act, regulations, or FNS-approved State
            Plan of Operation, FNS may, after written notification to the State
            agency, temporarily withhold some or all Federal reimbursements for
            costs of administration of the Food Stamp Program in accordance with
            
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='276' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
                276.4
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . Adjustments will be made either by adjusting the Letter of Credit
            authorization or by not allowing the State agency to withdraw funds.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Disallowance.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS may disallow costs in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='276' tq='N'>
                276
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and effect nonpayment for some or all costs incurred by a State
            agency which are normally allowable but are determined by FNS to be
            nonreimbursable because the State agency has failed to comply with
            any of the provisions contained in the Act, regulations, or
            FNS-approved State Plan of Operation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS may also disallow costs and institute recovery of Federal funds
            when a State agency fails to adhere to the cost principles of this
            part and appendix A.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Offsets to the Letter of Credit.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS may recover funds when owed by the State agency to FNS through
            offsets to the Letter of Credit. Offsets shall include:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Costs determined by FNS to be disallowed under the provisions of
            this part;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Unallowable costs resulting from audit or investigation findings;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Amounts owed which have been billed to the State agency and which
            the State agency has failed to pay without cause acceptable to FNS;
            or
            <PRTPAGE P='982' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Amounts owed to FNS for title IV reimbursements and recipient
            claims collections which were reported on the FNS-209 and which the
            State agency has failed to pay.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The amounts recovered through the offset procedure should be in one
            lump sum. If recovery of funds through the offset procedure is not
            possible in one lump sum, FNS shall make appropriate adjustments to
            recover the funds in not more than three fiscal years.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Program transfer or termination.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When termination or transfer of a State program has been agreed
            upon by FNS, the following closeout procedure shall be observed:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon request, FNS shall make or arrange for prompt payment to the
            State agency for allowable costs not covered by previous payments.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall immediately refund to FNS any unobligated
            balance of cash withdrawn by the State agency for the administration
            of the program in the affected State or Indian reservation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall submit to FNS within 90 days after the date
            of termination of the program, all required financial, performance,
            and other reports. FNS may grant extensions when requested by the
            State agency.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS shall adjust the amount authorized by the Letter of Credit in
            order to effect payment of any amounts due the State agency, and if
            appropriate, shall bill the State agency for any amounts due to FNS.
            The amounts of such billings shall be promptly remitted to FNS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the event a final audit has not been performed prior to the
            closeout of the program, FNS shall retain the right to disallow
            costs or recover funds resulting from the final audit findings.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='277' sect='13' psec='' tq='N'>
                277.13
              </subref>
            </aref>
             apply for any property acquired with program funds or received from
            the Federal Government in connection with the program and which was
            in use in the affected project area or areas.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [Amdt. 188, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            45 FR 85702
          </aref>
          , Dec. 30, 1980, as amended by Amdt. 342, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            59 FR 2733
          </aref>
          , Jan. 19, 1994]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4977'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:C:277:-:277.17
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        277.17
      </num>
      <head>
        Audit requirements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='277' sect='17' psec='' tq='N'>
              277.17
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Audit requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This section sets forth the audit requirements for State agencies
            that receive FNS program funds. Audits shall be conducted on an
            organization-wide basis. Such audits are to determine whether:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Financial operations are conducted properly;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The financial statements are presented fairly;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The organization has complied with laws and regulations affecting
            the expenditure of Federal funds;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Internal procedures have been established to meet the objectives of
            federally assisted programs; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Financial reports to the Federal Government contain accurate and
            reliable information.
          </text>
        </P>
        <FP>
          Except where required by law, no additional requirements for audit
          will be imposed by FNS unless approved by the Office of Management and
          Budget (OMB). The provisions of this section do not limit the
          authority of FNS to make audits of State agencies, their subdivisions,
          and subcontracts. However, if independent audits arranged for by State
          agencies meet the requirements prescribed herein, FNS shall rely on
          them, and any additional audit work already done.
        </FP>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Audit standards.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State agencies shall use their own procedures to arrange for
            independent audits, and to prescribe the scope of audits, provided
            that the audits comply with the requirements set forth in this
            section. Where contracts are awarded for audit services, the
            contracts shall include a reference to OMB Circular A-102,
            Attachment P.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Audits shall be made in accordance with the General Accounting
            Office “Standards for Audit of Governmental Organizations, Programs,
            Activities, and Functions, the Guidelines for Financial and
            Compliance Audits of Federally Assisted Program,” and any compliance
            supplements approved by OMB, and generally accepted auditing
            standards established by the American Institute of Certified Public
            Accountants.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Purpose of audit.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Audits will include, at a minimum, an examination of the systems of
            internal control, systems established to ensure compliance 
            <PRTPAGE P='983' />
            with laws and regulations affecting the expenditure of Federal
            funds, financial transactions and accounts, and financial statements
            and reports of State agencies. These examinations are to determine
            whether:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             There is effective control over and proper accounting for revenues
            expenditures, assets, and liabilities.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The financial statements are presented fairly in accordance with
            generally accepted accounting principles.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Federal financial reports (including Financial Status Reports,
            Cash Reports, and claims for advances and reimbursements) contain
            accurate and reliable financial data; and are presented in
            accordance with the terms of applicable agreements, and in
            accordance with Attachment H of OMB Circular A-102.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Federal funds are being expended in accordance with the terms of
            applicable agreements and those provisions of Federal law or
            regulations that could have a material effect on the financial
            statements or on the awards tested.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Audit coverage.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A representative number of charges to Federal funds shall be
            tested. The test shall be representative of:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The universe of Federal funds received, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All cost categories that materially affect the award. The test is
            to determine whether the charges:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Are necessary and reasonable for the proper administration of the
            program;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Conform to any limitations or exclusions in the award;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Were given consistent accounting treatments and applied uniformly
            to both federally assisted and other activities of the State agency;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Were net of applicable credits;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Did not include costs property chargeable to other federally
            assisted programs;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Were properly recorded (i.e., correct amount, date) and supported
            by source documentation;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_vii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Were approved in advance, if subject to prior approval in
            accordance with Financial Management Circular 74-4;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_viii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (viii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Were incurred in accordance with competitive purchasing procedures,
            if covered by OMB Circular A-102, Attachment O; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_ix'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ix)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Were allocated equitably to benefiting activities, including
            non-Federal activities.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Audits usually will be made annually, but not less frequently than
            every two years.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the auditors become aware of irregularities in the State agency,
            subagency or subcontractor, the auditor shall promptly notify the
            cognizant agency and State agency management officials above the
            level of involvement. Irregularities include such matters as
            conflict of interest, falsification of records or reports, and
            misappropriation of funds and other assets.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Audit report.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The audit report shall include:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Financial statements, including footnotes, of the State agency,
            subagency, or subcontractor organization.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The auditor&apos;s comments on the financial statements which
            should:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Identify the statements examined and the period covered.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Identify the various programs under which the organization received
            Federal funds, and the amounts received for each program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State that the audit was done in accordance with paragraph (d) of
            this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_2_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Express an opinion as to whether the financial statements are
            fairly presented in accordance with generally accepted accounting
            principles. If an unqualified opinion cannot be expressed, state the
            nature of the qualification.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The auditor&apos;s comments on compliance and internal control
            which should:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Include comments on weaknesses in and noncompliance with the
            systems of internal control, separately identifying material
            weaknesses.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Identify the nature and impact of any noted instances of
            noncompliance with the terms of agreements and those provisions of
            Federal law or regulation that could have a material effect on the
            financial statements and reports.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Contain an expression of positive assurance with respect to
            compliance with requirements for tested items, and negative
            assurance for untested items.
            <PRTPAGE P='984' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Comments on the accuracy and completeness of financial reports and
            claims for advances or reimbursements to Federal agencies.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Comments on corrective action taken or planned by the State agency.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Record retention.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Work paper and reports shall be retained for a minimum of three
            years from the date of the audit report unless the auditor is
            notified in writing by the cognizant agency of the need to extend
            the retention period. The audit workpapers shall be made available
            upon request to the cognizant agency or its designees and the
            General Accounting Office or its designees.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Cognizant agency responsibilities.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The cognizant agency shall have the following responsibilities:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Obtain or make quality assessment reviews of the work of
            non-Federal audit organizations, and provide the results to other
            interested audit agencies. If a non-Federal audit organization is
            responsible for audits of State agencies that have different
            cognizant audit agencies, a single quality assessment review will be
            arranged.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Assure that all audit reports of State agencies that affect
            federally assisted programs are received, reviewed, and distributed
            to appropriate Federal audit officials. These officials will be
            responsible for distributing audit reports to their program
            officials.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whenever significant inadequacies in an audit are disclosed, the
            State agency will be advised and the auditor will be called upon to
            take corrective action. If corrective action is not taken, the
            cognizant agency shall notify the State agency and Federal awarding
            agencies of the facts and its recommendation. Major inadequacies or
            repetitive substandard performance of independent auditors shall be
            referred to appropriate professional bodies.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Assure that satisfactory audit coverage is provided in a timely
            manner and in accordance with the provisions of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provide technical advice and act as a liaison between Federal
            agencies, independent auditors and State agencies.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Maintain a followup system on audit findings and investigative
            matters to assure that audit findings are resolved.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Inform other affected audit agencies of irregularities uncovered.
            The audit agencies, in turn, shall inform all appropriate officials
            in their agencies. State or local government law enforcement and
            prosecuting authorities shall also be informed of irregularities
            within their jurisdiction.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Recipients shall require subrecipients that are local governments
            of Indian tribal governments to adopt the requirements in paragraphs
            (d) through (f) of this section. The recipient shall ensure that the
            subrecipient audit reports are received as required, and shall
            submit the reports to the cognizant agency. The cognizant agency
            will have the responsibility for those reports described in
            paragraph (g) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4978'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:C:277:-:277.18
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        277.18
      </num>
      <head>
        Establishment of an Automated Data Processing (ADP) and Information
        Retrieval System.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [Amdt. 319, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          55 FR 4355
        </aref>
        , Feb. 7, 1990, as amended by Amdt. 345, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          57 FR 11259
        </aref>
        , Apr. 1, 1992; Amdt. 342, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          59 FR 2733
        </aref>
        , Jan. 19, 1994; Amdt. 368, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          61 FR 33643
        </aref>
        , June 28, 1996; Amdt. 385, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          65 FR 33440
        </aref>
        , May 24, 2000]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='277' sect='18' psec='' tq='N'>
              277.18
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Establishment of an Automated Data Processing (ADP) and Information
          Retrieval System.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Scope and application.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This section establishes conditions for initial and continuing
            authority to claim Federal financial participation (FFP) for the
            costs of the planning, development, acquisition, installation and
            implementation of ADP equipment and services used in the
            administration of the Food Stamp Program. Due to the nature of the
            procurement of ADP equipment and services, current State agency
            approved cost allocation plans for ongoing operational costs shall
            not apply to ADP system development costs under this section unless
            documentation required under paragraph (c) of this section is
            submitted to and approvals are obtained from FNS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Definitions:
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Acceptance Documents
          </E>
           means written evidence of satisfactory completion of an approved
          phase of work or contract, and acceptance thereof by the State agency.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Advance Planning Document for Project Implementation
          </E>
           or 
          <E T='03'>
            Implementation APD
          </E>
           means a written plan of action requesting Federal financial
          participation (FFP) to acquire and implement ADP services and/or
          equipment.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Advance Planning Document for Project Planning
          </E>
           or 
          <E T='03'>
            Planning APD
          </E>
           means a 
          <PRTPAGE P='985' />
          brief written plan of action that requests FFP to accomplish the
          planning necessary for a State agency to determine the need for and
          plan the acquisition of ADP equipment and/or services, and to acquire
          information necessary to prepare an Implementation APD.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Advance Planning Document Update (APDU)
          </E>
           means an annual self-certification by the State agency on the status
          of project development activities and expenditures in relation to the
          approved Planning APD or Implementation APD. An APDU may also be
          submitted as needed to request funding approval for project
          continuation whenever significant project changes occur or are
          anticipated.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Automated Data Processing
          </E>
           or 
          <E T='03'>
            ADP
          </E>
           means data processing performed by a system of electronic or
          electrical machines so interconnected and interacting as to minimize
          the need for human assistance or intervention.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Automated Data Processing Equipment
          </E>
           or 
          <E T='03'>
            hardware
          </E>
           means:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Electronic digital computers, regardless of size, capacity, or
            price, that accept data input, store data, perform calculations, and
            other processing steps, and prepare information;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All peripheral or auxiliary equipment used in support of electronic
            digital computers whether selected and acquired with the computer or
            separately;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Data transmission or communications equipment that is selected and
            acquired solely or primarily for use with a configuration of ADP
            equipment which includes an electronic digital computer; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Data input equipment used to enter directly or indirectly into an
            electronic digital computer, peripheral or auxiliary equipment, or
            data transmission, or communication equipment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Automated Data Processing Services
          </E>
           means:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Services to operate ADP equipment, either by private sources, or by
            employees of the State agency, or by State or local organizations
            other than the State agency; and/or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Services provided by private sources or by employees of the State
            agency or by State and local organizations other than the State
            agency to perform such tasks as feasibility studies, system studies,
            system design efforts, development of system specifications, system
            analysis, programming and system implementation. This includes
            system training, systems development, site preparation, data entry,
            and personal services related to automated systems development and
            operations that are specifically identified as part of a Planning
            APD or Implementation APD.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Data Processing
          </E>
           means the preparation of source media containing data or basic
          elements of information and the use of such source media according to
          precise rules of procedures to accomplish such operations as
          classifying, sorting, calculating, summarizing, recording, and
          transmitting.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Emergency situation
          </E>
           means a situation where:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency can demonstrate to FNS an immediate need to
            acquire ADP equipment or services in order to continue operation of
            the Food Stamp Program; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency can clearly document that the need could not have
            been anticipated or planned for and the need prevents the State from
            following the prior approval requirements of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='277' sect='18' psec='#c' tq='N'>
                277.18(c)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Feasibility Study
          </E>
           means a preliminary study to determine whether it is sufficiently
          probable that effective and efficient use of ADP equipment or systems
          would warrant a substantial investment of staff, time, and money being
          requested, and whether the plan can be accomplished successfully.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Functional Requirements Specification
          </E>
           means an initial definition of the proposed system, which documents
          the goals, objectives, user or programmatic requirements, the
          operating environment, and the proposed design methodology, e.g.,
          centralized or distributed. This document details what the new system
          and/or hardware should do, not how it is to do it. The Specification
          document shall be based upon a clear and accurate description of the
          functional requirements for the project, and shall not, in competitive
          procurements, lead to requirements which unduly restrict competition.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            General Systems Design
          </E>
           means a combination of narrative and diagrams describing the generic
          architecture of a 
          <PRTPAGE P='986' />
          system as opposed to the detailed architecture of the system. A
          general systems design may include a systems diagram; narrative
          identifying overall logic flow and systems functions; a description of
          equipment needed (including processing, data transmission and storage
          requirements); a description of other resource requirements which will
          be necessary to operate the system; a description of system
          performance requirements; and a description of the environment in
          which the system will operate, including how the system will function
          within that environment.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Regular funding
          </E>
           or 
          <E T='03'>
            regular FFP rate
          </E>
           means any Federal reimbursement rate authorized by 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='277' sect='4' psec='#b' tq='N'>
              277.4(b)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Request for Proposal
          </E>
           or 
          <E T='03'>
            RFP
          </E>
           means the document used for public solicitations of competitive
          proposals from qualified sources as outlined in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='277' sect='14' psec='#g_3' tq='N'>
              277.14(g)(3)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Service Agreement
          </E>
           means the document, described in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='277' sect='18' psec='#f' tq='N'>
              277.18(f)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , signed by the State or local agency and the State or local central
          data processing facility whenever a central data processing facility
          provides ADP services to the State or local agency.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Software
          </E>
           means a set of computer programs, procedures, and associated
          documentation used to operate the hardware.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            System specifications
          </E>
           means information about the new ADP systems, such as: Workload
          descriptions, input data, information to be maintained and processed,
          data processing techniques, and output data, which is required to
          determine the ADP equipment and software necessary to implement the
          system design.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            System study
          </E>
           means the examination of existing information flow and operational
          procedures within an organization. The study consists of three basic
          phases: Data gathering or investigation of the present system and new
          information requirements; analysis of the data gathered in the
          investigation; and synthesis, or refitting, of the parts and
          relationships uncovered through the analysis into an efficient system.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General acquisition requirements—(1) Requirement for prior FNS
              approval.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A State agency shall obtain prior written approval from FNS as
            specified in paragraph (c)(2) of this section when it plans to
            acquire ADP equipment or services with proposed FFP that it
            anticipates will have total acquisition costs of $5 million or more
            in Federal and State funds. This applies to both competitively bid
            and sole source acquisitions. A State agency shall also obtain prior
            written approval from FNS of its justification for a sole source
            acquisition when it plans to acquire ADP equipment or services
            non-competitively from a nongovernmental source which has a total
            State and Federal acquisition cost of more than $1 million but no
            more than $5 million. The State agency shall request prior FNS
            approval by submitting the Planning APD, the Implementation APD or
            the justification for the sole source acquisition signed by the
            appropriate State official to the FNS Regional Office. However, a
            State agency shall obtain prior written approval from FNS for the
            acquisition of ADP equipment or services to be utilized in an EBT
            system regardless of the cost of the acquisition.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Specific prior approval requirements.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For ADP equipment and services acquisitions which require prior
            approval as specified in paragraph (c)(1) of this section, the State
            agency shall obtain the prior written approval of FNS for:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_i_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Planning APD prior to entering into contractual agreements or
            making any other commitment for acquiring the necessary planning
            services;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_i_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Implementation APD prior to entering into contractual
            agreements or making any other commitment for the acquisition of ADP
            equipment or services.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For ADP equipment and services acquisitions requiring prior
            approval as specified in paragraph (c)(1) of this section, prior
            approval of the following documents associated with such
            acquisitions is also required:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_ii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             RFP&apos;s; unless specifically exempted by FNS, the State agency
            shall obtain prior written approval of the RFP before the RFP may be
            released. However, RFPs costing up to $5 million for competitive
            procurements and up to $1 million for noncompetitive acquisitions
            from non-governmental sources and which are an integral part of the
            approved APD need not be submitted 
            <PRTPAGE P='987' />
            to FNS. States will be required to submit RFPs under this threshold
            amount on an exception basis or if the procurement strategy is not
            adequately described and justified in an APD. The State agency shall
            obtain prior written approval from FNS for Request for Proposals
            which are associated with an EBT system regardless of the cost.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_ii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Contracts; unless specifically exempted by FNS, the State agency
            shall obtain prior written approval before the contract may be
            signed by the State agency. However, contracts costing up to $5
            million for competitive procurements and up to $1 million for
            noncompetitive acquisitions from nongovernmental sources, and which
            are an integral part of the approved APD need not be submitted to
            FNS. States will be required to submit contracts under this
            threshold amount on an exception basis or if the procurement
            strategy is not adequately described and justified in an APD. The
            State agency shall obtain prior written approval from FNS for
            contracts which are associated with an EBT system regardless of the
            cost.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_ii_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Contract amendments; unless specifically exempted by FNS, the State
            agency shall obtain prior written approval before the contract
            amendment may be signed by the State agency. However, contract
            amendments involving cost increases of up to $1 million or time
            extensions of up to 120 days, and which are an integral part of the
            approved APD need not be submitted to FNS. States will be required
            to submit contract amendments under these threshold amounts on an
            exception basis or if the contract amendment is not adequately
            described and justified in an APD. Amendments to contracts for EBT
            systems shall be permitted within the approved funding cap. State
            agencies shall submit copies of any contract amendments or contract
            extensions to FNS with an accompanying analysis of the impact the
            changes would have upon the approved issuance cap.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency must obtain prior written approval from FNS as
            specified in paragraphs (c)(2) (i) and (ii) of this section in order
            to claim and receive reimbursement for the associated costs of the
            ADP acquisition.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Approval requirements.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For ADP equipment and service acquisitions requiring prior approval
            as specified in paragraph (c)(1) of this section, the State agency
            shall submit the following documents to FNS for approval:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_3_iii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Feasibility studies, when specifically required by FNS as a
            condition of approving the Planning APD. When required by FNS for
            approval, the State agency shall submit the feasibility study no
            later than 90 days after its completion.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_3_iii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             APD Updates, as required by paragraph (e) of this section, on an
            annual or as needed basis.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency must obtain FNS approval of the documents
            specified in paragraph (c)(3)(i) of this section in order to claim
            and receive reimbursement for the associated costs of the ADP
            acquisition.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Approval by the State agency.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Approval by the State agency is required for all documents
            specified in this regulation prior to submission for FNS approval.
            In addition, State agency approval is also required for those
            acquisitions of ADP equipment and services not requiring prior
            approval by FNS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Prompt action on requests for prior approval.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS will reply promptly to State requests for prior approval. If
            FNS has not provided written approval, disapproval or a request for
            additional information within 60 days of FNS&apos; letter
            acknowledging receipt of the State&apos;s request, the request will
            be deemed to have provisionally met the prior approval requirement
            in paragraph (c) of this section. However, provisional approval will
            not exempt a State from having to meet all other Federal
            requirements which pertain to the acquisition of ADP equipment and
            services. Such requirements remain subject to Federal audit and
            review.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              APD content requirements—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Planning APD.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency may request FFP for the costs of determining the
            need for and planning the acquisition of ADP equipment or services
            through the submission of the Planning APD. The State agency may
            request FFP for the costs of planning activities beginning with
            initial project inception through the performance of necessary
            systems and alternatives analyses, selection and design, 
            <PRTPAGE P='988' />
            including the completion of a general systems design. The Planning
            APD shall contain the following information:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency&apos;s description of the programmatic and
            organizational needs and/or problems to be addressed by the proposed
            ADP acquisition and the specific objectives to be accomplished under
            the Planning APD;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency&apos;s commitment to complete the following, where
            appropriate, as part of project planning activities: a functional
            requirements specification document, feasibility study, alternatives
            analysis, cost-benefit analysis, and a general system design. If an
            existing ADP system is to be transferred, the State agency may plan
            to use the general system design of the transferred system.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency&apos;s description of the organization, required
            State and contractual resources and availability of those resources,
            and the assignments of roles and responsibilities for project
            planning activities. The State agency shall include a description of
            resources to be procured and procurement methods;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency&apos;s schedule of activities and deliverables
            during project planning, including a description and schedule of
            procurement activities to be undertaken in support of the planning
            project; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A proposed budget which shall identify costs for project planning
            activities by Federal fiscal year. The budget shall include an
            estimate of prospective cost distribution to participating Federal
            agencies and the method for cost allocation. The State agency shall
            also include an estimate of the total project costs, including both
            the cost of the planning project and the cost of any eventual ADP
            equipment and/or services acquisition, which will be used only for
            determining whether the threshold of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='277' sect='18' psec='#c_1' tq='N'>
                277.18(c)(1)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             is met. An estimate of total project cost for an EBT system shall
            not be required to be incorporated into the Planning APD budget.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Implementation APD.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency may request FFP to acquire ADP equipment and
            services through the submission of the Implementation APD. The State
            agency may request FFP for the necessary activities to develop,
            acquire, install and implement the proposed ADP system or
            acquisition. The Implementation APD shall contain the following
            information, where appropriate:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall complete and submit a functional
            requirements specification document;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall submit a feasibility study and associated
            alternatives analyses, which include the transfer or modification of
            an existing system from a similar State or jurisdiction in the
            examination of alternatives. State agencies which reject the
            transfer or modification of an existing system must provide an
            analysis describing the barriers to system transfer as part of the
            feasibility study. The analysis of barriers to system transfer shall
            include a comparison of the costs of overcoming the problem in
            transferring an operational system to the costs of developing a new
            system;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall submit the new or transferred general
            systems design and shall also document the intended approaches,
            plans and techniques to develop or modify specific aspects of the
            proposed ADP system or acquisition including hardware, software,
            telecommunications, system testing, and data security;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall describe the anticipated resource
            requirements for implementation of the ADP project, the resources
            planned to be available for the project, and plans for augmenting
            resources to meet resource requirements;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall indicate the principal events and schedule
            of activities, milestones, and deliverables during implementation of
            the project;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall submit a proposed budget which identifies
            costs for intended project development and implementation activities
            by Federal fiscal year and shall include a consideration of all
            possible Implementation APD activity costs (e.g., system conversion,
            computer capacity planning, supplies, training, and miscellaneous
            ADP expenses). The budget shall contain an estimate of prospective
            cost distribution and methods for allocating costs to participating
            Federal agencies;
            <PRTPAGE P='989' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_vii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall document the scope, methodology, evaluation
            criteria and results of cost-benefit analyses for evaluating the
            selected design and alternatives. The cost-benefit analysis shall
            include a statement indicating the period of time the State agency
            intends to use the proposed equipment or system; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_viii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (viii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall describe the security and interface
            requirements to be employed and the backup and contingency
            procedures available.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              APD Budget.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The proposed budget for both the Planning APD and the
            Implementation APD shall include cost distribution plans containing
            the bases for proposed rates, both direct and indirect, for costs
            associated with system planning, development, acquisition or
            implementation, as appropriate. The budget proposals accompanying
            the Implementation APD shall also include proposed cost distribution
            plans and the bases of proposed rates for the operation of the ADP
            system. The budget activities shall be presented on a Federal fiscal
            year basis in a clear fashion to associate costs with each planned
            activity. The budgets must identify all development costs separately
            from any ongoing operational costs. Costs must be distinguished by
            developmental projects and developmental time periods. Actual costs
            claimed must be reconciliable to projected costs as proposed and
            approved by FNS in the APD.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              APD Update—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General submission requirements.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall submit an APD Update for FNS approval for
            all approved Planning and Implementation APD&apos;s when total
            acquisition costs exceed $5 million. The APD Update shall be
            submitted to the FNS Regional Office within 90 days after the annual
            anniversary date of the original APD approval, unless the submission
            date is specifically altered by FNS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Content requirements.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The APD Update represents a self-certification by the State agency
            of project status in relation to the provisions of the approved
            Planning APD and Implementation APD. The Annually Updated APD shall
            include:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Project activity status. (A) The status of all major tasks and
            milestones in the approved Planning APD, Implementation APD or
            previous APD Update&apos;s for the past year. The APD Update shall
            include all major tasks and milestones completed in the past year
            and degree of completion for unfinished tasks.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_viii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The status of all project deliverables completed in the past year
            and degree of completion for unfinished products.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_viii_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Reports of past and/or anticipated problems or delays in meeting
            target dates in the approved Planning APD, Implementation APD or
            previous APD Update&apos;s for the remainder of the project. The
            Annually Updated APD shall include an explanation of the need to
            extend any major project target dates.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Project expenditures. (A) A detailed accounting for all
            expenditures for project development over the past year.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_ii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An explanation of differences between projected expenses in the
            approved Planning or Implementation APD, or previous APD
            Update&apos;s, and actual expenditures for the past year. If changes
            in costs are reported, FNS may require the submission of a revised
            cost-benefit analysis as a condition for approval of the APD Update.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_ii_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Changes to the allocation basis in the approved APD&apos;s cost
            allocation methodology.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Changes to the approved APD.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_iii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Revised language for all changes to the approved APD or previous
            APD Updates shall be submitted as part of the APD Update, unless
            submitted separately by the State agency as the changes occurred
            throughout the year.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_iii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Changes in project management and/or contractor services.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Submission as needed.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In addition to the requirement for approval of an APD Update on an
            annual basis, as specified in paragraph (e)(1) of this section, the
            State agency may submit an APD Update on a more frequent or as
            needed basis, in order to obtain a commitment of FFP whenever
            significant project changes occur. Without such approval, the State
            agency is at risk for funding of project activities which are not in
            compliance with the terms and conditions of the approved APD 
            <PRTPAGE P='990' />
            and subsequently approved APD Updates, until such time as approval
            is specifically granted by FNS. At a minimum, the State agency
            should consider submission of an APD Update whenever any of the
            following changes occur or are anticipated:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A significant increase ($1 million or more) in total project costs;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A significant schedule extension (60 days or more) for major
            milestones;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A significant change in procurement approach, and/or scope of
            procurement activities beyond that approved in the APD;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_3_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A change in system concept, or a change to the scope of the
            project; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_3_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A change to the approved cost allocation methodology.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Service agreements.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall execute service agreements when data
            processing services are to be provided by a State central data
            processing facility or another State or local agency. Service
            agreements shall be kept on file by the State agency and be
            available for Federal review, and shall:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Identify the ADP services that will be provided;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Include, preferably as an amendable attachment, a schedule of
            charges for each identified ADP service, and a certification that
            these charges apply equally to all users;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Include a description of the method(s) of accounting for the
            services rendered under the agreement and computing services
            charges;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Include assurances that services provided will be timely and
            satisfactory;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Include assurances that information in the computer system as well
            as access, use and disposal of ADP data will be safeguarded in
            accordance with provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='272' sect='1' psec='#c' tq='N'>
                272.1(c)
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='277' sect='13' psec='' tq='N'>
                277.13
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Require the provider to obtain prior approval pursuant to 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='277' sect='18' psec='#c_1' tq='N'>
                277.18(c)(1)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             from FNS for ADP equipment and ADP services that are acquired from
            commercial sources primarily to support the Food Stamp Program and
            requires the provider to comply with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='277' sect='14' psec='' tq='N'>
                277.14
              </subref>
            </aref>
             for procurements related to the service agreement. ADP equipment
            and services are considered to be primarily acquired to support the
            Food Stamp Program when the Program may reasonably be expected to
            either be billed for more than 50 percent of the total charges made
            to all users of the ADP equipment and services during the time
            period covered by the service agreement, or directly charged for the
            total cost of the purchase or lease of ADP equipment or services;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Include the beginning and ending dates of the period of time
            covered by the service agreement; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Include a schedule of expected total charges to the Program for the
            period of the service agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Conditions for receiving FFP—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A State agency may receive FFP at the 50 percent reimbursement rate
            for the costs of planning, design, development or installation of
            ADP and information retrieval systems if the proposed system will:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Assist the State agency in meeting the requirements of the Food
            Stamp Act;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Meet the program standards specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='272' sect='10' psec='#b_1' tq='N'>
                272.10(b)(1), (b)(2), and (b)(3)
              </subref>
               of this chapter
            </aref>
            , except for the requirements in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='272' sect='10' psec='#b_2_vi' tq='N'>
                272.10(b)(2)(vi), (b)(2)(vii), and (b)(3)(ix)
              </subref>
               of this chapter
            </aref>
             to eventually transmit data directly to FCS;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be likely to provide more efficient and effective administration of
            the program; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be compatible with such other systems utilized in the
            administration of State agency plans under the program of Temporary
            Assistance for Needy Families (TANF).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State agencies seeking FFP for the planning, design, development or
            installation of automated data processing and information retrieval
            systems shall develop Statewide systems which are integrated with
            TANF. In cases where a State agency can demonstrate that a local,
            dedicated, or single function (issuance or certification only)
            system will provide for more efficient and effective administration
            of the program, FNS may grant an exception to the Statewide
            integrated requirement. These exceptions will be based on an
            assessment of the proposed system&apos;s ability to meet the State
            agency&apos;s need for automation. Systems funded as exceptions to
            this rule, however, should be capable to the extent necessary, of an
            automated data exchange with the State agency system 
            <PRTPAGE P='991' />
            used to administer TANF. In no circumstances will funding be
            available for systems which duplicate other State agency systems,
            whether presently operational or planned for future development.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Emergency acquisition requirements.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency may request FFP for the costs of ADP equipment and
            services acquired to meet emergency situations which preclude the
            State agency from following the prior approval requirements of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='277' sect='18' psec='#c' tq='N'>
                277.18(c)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . FNS may provide FFP in emergency situations if the following
            conditions are met:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency must submit a written request to FNS prior to the
            acquisition of any ADP equipment or services. The written request
            must be sent by registered mail and shall include:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A brief description of the ADP equipment and/or services to be
            acquired and an estimate of their costs;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A brief description of the circumstances which result in the State
            agency&apos;s need to proceed with the acquisition prior to
            obtaining formal FNS approval; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A description of the adverse impact which would result if the State
            agency does not immediately acquire the ADP equipment and/or
            services.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon receipt of a written request for emergency acquisition FNS
            shall provide a written response to the State agency within 14 days.
            The FNS response shall:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Inform the State agency that the request has been disapproved and
            the reason for disapproval; or,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Inform the State agency that FNS recognizes that an emergency
            situation exists and the State agency must submit a formal request
            for approval by FNS which includes the information specified at 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='277' sect='18' psec='#d_2' tq='N'>
                277.18(d)(2)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             within 90 days from the date of the State agency&apos;s initial
            written request.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If FNS approves the request submitted under paragraph (h)(1) of
            this section, FFP will be available from the date the State agency
            acquires the ADP equipment and services.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Cost determination and claiming costs—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Cost determination.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Actual costs must be determined in compliance with an FNS approved
            budget and appendix A to this part, and must be reconcilable with
            the FNS funding level. There shall be no payments pursuant to this
            section to the extent that a State agency is reimbursed for such
            costs pursuant to any other Federal program or uses ADP systems for
            purposes not connected with the Food Stamp Program. The State agency
            approved cost allocation plan must be amended to disclose the
            methods which will be used to identify and classify costs to be
            claimed. This methodology must be submitted to FNS as part of the
            request for FNS approval of funding as required in paragraph (d)(3)
            of this section. Any costs funded pursuant to these regulations
            shall be excluded in determining the State agency&apos;s
            administrative costs under any other section of this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Cost identification for purposes of FFP claims.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State agencies shall assign and claim the costs incurred under an
            approved APD in accordance with the following criteria:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Development costs.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Using its normal departmental accounting system, the State agency
            shall specifically identify what items of costs constitute
            development costs, assign these costs to specific project cost
            centers, and distribute these costs to funding sources based on the
            specific identification, assignment and distribution outlined in the
            approved APD. The methods for distributing costs set forth in the
            APD should provide for assigning identifiable costs, to the extent
            practicable, directly to program/functions. The State agency shall
            amend the cost allocation plan required by 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='277' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
                277.9
              </subref>
            </aref>
             to include the approved APD methodology for the identification,
            assignment and distribution of the development costs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Operational costs.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Costs incurred for the operation of an ADP system shall be
            identified and assigned by the State agency to funding sources in
            accordance with the approved cost allocation plan required by 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='277' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
                277.9
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Service agreement costs.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             States that operate a central data processing facility shall use
            their approved central service cost allocation plan required by OMB
            Circular A-87 to identify and assign costs incurred under service
            agreements with the State agency. The State agency shall then
            distribute these costs to funding 
            <PRTPAGE P='992' />
            sources in accordance with paragraphs (i)(2)(i) and (i)(2)(ii) of
            this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Capital expenditures.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall charge the costs of ADP equipment having
            unit acquisition costs or total aggregate costs, at the time of
            acquisition, of more than $25,000 by means of depreciation or use
            allowance, unless a waiver is specifically granted by FNS. If the
            equipment acquisition is part of an APD that is subject to the prior
            approval requirements of paragraph (c)(2) of this section, the State
            agency may submit the waiver request as part of the APD.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Claiming costs.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Prior to claiming funding under this section the State agency shall
            have complied with the requirements for obtaining approval and prior
            approval of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='277' sect='18' psec='#c' tq='N'>
                277.18(c)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Budget authority.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS approval of requests for funding shall provide notification to
            the State agency of the budget authority and dollar limitations
            under which such funding may be claimed. FNS shall provide this
            amount as a total authorization for such funding which may not be
            exceeded unless amended by FNS. FNS&apos;s determination of the
            amount of this authorization shall be based on the budget submitted
            by the State agency. Activities not included in the approved budget,
            as well as continuation of approved activities beyond scheduled
            deadlines in the approved plan, shall require FNS approval of an
            amended State budget for payment. Requests to amend the budget
            authorization approved by FNS shall be submitted to FNS prior to
            claiming such expenses.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Procurement requirements.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Procurements of ADP equipment and services are subject to the
            procurement standards prescribed by 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='277' sect='14' psec='' tq='N'>
                277.14
              </subref>
            </aref>
             regardless of any conditions for prior approval, except the
            requirements of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='277' sect='14' psec='#b_1' tq='N'>
                277.14(b)(1) and (2)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             regarding review of proposed contracts. Those standards include a
            requirement for maximum practical open and free competition
            regardless of whether the procurement is formally advertised or
            negotiated.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The standards prescribed by 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='277' sect='14' psec='' tq='N'>
                277.14
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , as well as the requirement for prior approval, apply to ADP
            services and equipment acquired by a State or local agency, and the
            ADP services and equipment acquired by a State or local central data
            processing facility primarily to support the Food Stamp Program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The competitive procurement policy prescribed by 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='277' sect='14' psec='' tq='N'>
                277.14
              </subref>
            </aref>
             shall be applicable except for ADP services provided by the agency
            itself, or by other State or local agencies.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Access to the system and records.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Access to the system in all aspects, including but not limited to
            design, development, and operation, including work performed by any
            source, and including cost records of contractors and
            subcontractors, shall be made available by the State agency to FNS
            or its authorized representatives at intervals as are deemed
            necessary by FNS, in order to determine whether the conditions for
            approval are being met and to determine the efficiency, economy and
            effectiveness of the system. Failure to provide full access by
            appropriate State and Federal representatives to all parts of the
            system shall result in suspension and/or termination of Food Stamp
            Program funds for the costs of the system and its operation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='l'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (l)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Ownership rights—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='l_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Software
            </E>
            (i) The State or local government shall include a clause in all
            procurement instruments which provides that the State or local
            government shall have all ownership rights in any software or
            modifications thereof and associated documentation designed,
            developed or installed with FFP under this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='l_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS reserves a royalty-free, nonexclusive, and irrevocable license
            to reproduce, publish, or otherwise use and to authorize others to
            use for Federal Government purposes, such software, modifications,
            and documentation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='l_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Proprietary operating/vendor software packages (e.g., ADABAS or
            TOTAL) which are provided at established catalog or market prices
            and sold or leased to the general public shall not be subject to the
            ownership provisions in paragraphs (l)(1)(i) and (l)(1)(ii) of this
            section. FFP is not available for proprietary applications software
            developed specifically for the Food Stamp Program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='l_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Automated data processing equipment.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The policies and procedures governing title, use and disposition of
            property purchased with Food Stamp Program funds, which appear at 7
            CFR 
            <PRTPAGE P='993' />
            277.13 are applicable to automated data processing equipment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='m'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (m)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Use of ADP systems.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             ADP systems designed, developed or installed with FFP shall be used
            for the period of time specified in the APD, unless FNS determines
            that a shorter period is justified.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='n'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (n)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Basis for continued Federal financial participation.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS will continue FFP at the levels approved in the Planning APD
            and the Implementation APD provided that project development
            proceeds in accordance with the conditions and terms of the approved
            APD and that ADP resources are used for the purposes authorized. FNS
            will use the APD Update to monitor ADP project development. The
            submission of the report prescribed in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='277' sect='18' psec='#e' tq='N'>
                277.18(e)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             for the duration of project development is a condition for
            continued FFP. In addition, periodic onsite reviews of ADP project
            development and State and local agency ADP operations may be
            conducted by or for FNS to assure compliance with approved
            APD&apos;s, proper use of ADP resources, and the adequacy of State
            or local agency ADP operations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='o'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (o)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Disallowance of Federal financial participation.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If FNS finds that any ADP acquisition approved under the provisions
            of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='277' sect='18' psec='#c' tq='N'>
                277.18(c)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             fails to comply with the criteria, requirements, and other
            undertakings described in the approved or modified APD, payment of
            FFP may be disallowed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='p'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (p)
            </enum>
            <head>
              ADP system security requirements and review process—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='p_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              ADP system security requirements.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State and local agencies are responsible for the security of all
            ADP projects under development, and operational systems involved in
            the administration of the Food Stamp Program. State and local
            agencies shall determine appropriate ADP security requirements based
            on recognized industry standards or standards governing security of
            Federal ADP systems and information processing.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='p_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              ADP security program.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State agencies shall implement and maintain a comprehensive ADP
            Security Program for ADP systems and installations involved in the
            administration of the Food Stamp Program. ADP Security Programs
            shall include the following components.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='p_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Determination and implementation of appropriate security
            requirements as prescribed in paragraph (p)(1) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='p_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Establishment of a security plan and, as appropriate, policies and
            procedures to address the following areas of ADP security:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='p_2_ii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Physical security of ADP resources;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='p_2_ii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Equipment security to protect equipment from theft and unauthorized
            use;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='p_2_ii_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Software and data security;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='p_2_ii_D'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (D)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Telecommunications security;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='p_2_ii_E'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (E)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Personnel security;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='p_2_ii_F'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (F)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Contingency plans to meet critical processing needs in the event of
            short- or long-term interruption of service;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='p_2_ii_G'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (G)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Emergency preparedness; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='p_2_ii_H'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (H)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Designation of an Agency ADP Security Manager.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='p_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Periodic risk analyses. State agencies shall establish and maintain
            a program for conducting periodic risk analyses to ensure that
            appropriate, cost-effective safeguards are incorporated into new and
            existing systems. In addition, risk analyses shall be performed
            whenever significant system changes occur.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='p_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              ADP system security reviews.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State agencies shall review the ADP system security of
            installations involved in the administration of the Food Stamp
            Program on a biennial basis. At a minimum, the reviews shall include
            an evaluation of physical and data security, operating procedures,
            and personnel practices. State agencies shall maintain reports of
            their biennial ADP system security reviews, together with pertinent
            supporting documentation, for Federal on-site review.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='p_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Applicability.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The security requirements of this section apply to all ADP systems
            used by State and local governments to administer the Food Stamp
            Program.
            <PRTPAGE P='994' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='p_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Costs.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Costs incurred for complying with the provisions of paragraphs
            (p)(1) through (p)(3) of this section are considered regular
            administrative costs which are funded at the regular FFP level.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [Amdt. 319, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            55 FR 4355
          </aref>
          , Feb. 7, 1990, as amended by Amdt. 345, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            57 FR 11259
          </aref>
          , Apr. 1, 1992; Amdt. 342, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            59 FR 2733
          </aref>
          , Jan. 19, 1994; Amdt. 368, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            61 FR 33643
          </aref>
          , June 28, 1996; Amdt. 385, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            65 FR 33440
          </aref>
          , May 24, 2000]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>