<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol3'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:G:170
    </extid>
    <num>
      170
    </num>
    <head>
      USDA FARMERS MARKET
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='5' sect='301' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/5/301.html'>
              5 U.S.C. 301
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='1621-162' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1621-162.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 1621-162
            </subref>
          </aref>
          7.
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            70 FR 76131
          </aref>
          , Dec. 23, 2005, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='4270'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:G:170:-:170.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        170.1
      </num>
      <head>
        To which farmers markets does this rule apply?
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='170' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              170.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          To which farmers markets does this rule apply?
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          This rule applies only to the USDA Farmers Market at headquarters on
          the corner of 12th Street &amp; Independence Avenue, SW., Washington,
          DC.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4271'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:G:170:-:170.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        170.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Is the USDA Farmers Market a producer-only market?
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='170' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              170.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Is the USDA Farmers Market a producer-only market?
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Yes. A producer-only market is one that does not offer agricultural
          products that are commercially made, created, or produced, and only
          allows agricultural products that are grown by a principal farmer. A
          producer-only market offers raw agricultural products such as fruits,
          vegetables, flowers, bedding plants, and potted plants. The USDA
          Farmers Market is a producer-only market since only farmers who may
          sell products that they grow or produce will be selected for
          participation. It also allows the sale of value-added products and
          other specialized non-produce items.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4272'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:G:170:-:170.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        170.3
      </num>
      <head>
        What products may be sold at the USDA Farmers Market?
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='170' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              170.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          What products may be sold at the USDA Farmers Market?
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Products that may be sold at the market include, but are not limited
          to, fresh, high-quality fruits, vegetables, herbs, honey, jams and
          jellies, cheese, vinegars, cider, maple syrup, fish, flowers, bedding
          plants, and potted plants. USDA inspected meats and poultry items also
          may be sold.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4273'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:G:170:-:170.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        170.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Who may participate in the USDA Farmers Market?
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='170' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              170.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Who may participate in the USDA Farmers Market?
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Members of three groups may participate in the USDA Farmers Markets:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Principal farmers or producers who sell their own agricultural
              products.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The principal farmer must be in full control and supervision of the
            individual steps of production of crops including tilling, planting,
            cultivating, fertilizer and pesticide applications (if applicable),
            harvesting and post-harvest handling on its own farm with its own
            machinery and labor.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Principal farmer or producers who sell their own value-added
              agricultural products.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Value-added products may include agricultural products that have
            been enhanced through a modification of the product, such as
            braiding, weaving, hulling, extracting, handcrafting, and the like.
            It also may result from growing the product in a way that is
            acknowledged as safer. Farmers and vendors selling these types of
            products must prepare them predominately with material they have
            grown or gathered.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Nonproduce vendors.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A limited number of non-produce vendors may be selected by market
            management to sell specialized products that enhance the market
            atmosphere and historically attract customers to a farmers market.
            These specialized vendors, such as bakers, may be exempted from the
            reselling restrictions that apply to the farmers and vendors
            described in paragraphs (a) and (b) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4274'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:G:170:-:170.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        170.5
      </num>
      <head>
        Is there a fee to participate in the USDA Farmers Market?
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='311' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='170' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              170.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Is there a fee to participate in the USDA Farmers Market?
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          No, there are no fees charged to participate in the market.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4275'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:G:170:-:170.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        170.6
      </num>
      <head>
        How are potential market participants identified for the USDA Farmers
        Market?
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='170' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              170.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          How are potential market participants identified for the USDA Farmers
          Market?
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Potential market participants are recruited by AMS market management
          through local farm organizations in the Washington DC metropolitan
          area State Departments of Agriculture from the mid-Atlantic region
          including, Virginia, West Virginia, Maryland, Delaware, and
          Pennsylvania. Upon receiving a list of potential farmers and vendors
          from the organizations and the State Departments of Agriculture, an
          information packet, which includes an application and this rule, will
          be mailed to each potential participant identified by the contacts.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4276'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:G:170:-:170.7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        170.7
      </num>
      <head>
        Can I apply if I am not recruited?
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='170' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              170.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Can I apply if I am not recruited?
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Yes. Interested persons may call or write USDA to request an
          information packet even if they are not recruited. Those interested
          may write USDA/AMS/TM/MSB, Room 2646-South Building, 1400 Independence
          Avenue, SW., Washington, DC, 20250, or call (202) 720-8317. They may
          also call the USDA Farmers Market Hotline at 1-800-384-8704 to leave a
          message to have a packet mailed or faxed. They may also visit the web
          site at 
          <E T='03'>
            http://www.ams.usda.gov/farmersmarkets/
          </E>
           to review the selection criteria, the operating rules, and to receive
          an application electronically.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4277'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:G:170:-:170.8
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        170.8
      </num>
      <head>
        What are the application procedures?
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='170' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              170.8
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          What are the application procedures?
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          In January of each year, prospective and returning participants must
          submit to USDA a completed application for participation in the
          upcoming market season. Each application will include a copy of this
          rule, which includes the selection criteria and operating guidelines.
          Each applicant also will certify that each is the owner or
          representative of the farm or business submitting the application.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4278'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:G:170:-:170.9
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        170.9
      </num>
      <head>
        What type of information does the application require?
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='170' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
              170.9
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          What type of information does the application require?
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The application for participation in the USDA Farmers Market will
          provide market management with information on contacts, farm location,
          type of farming operation, types of products grown, and business
          practices, including insurance coverage.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4279'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:G:170:-:170.10
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        170.10
      </num>
      <head>
        Must a participant in the market have insurance?
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='170' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
              170.10
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Must a participant in the market have insurance?
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          There is no requirement for a participant to have insurance; however,
          USDA asks that participants with insurance provide insurance
          information for our records.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4280'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:G:170:-:170.11
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        170.11
      </num>
      <head>
        How are farmers and vendors selected for participation in the USDA
        Farmers Market?
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='170' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
              170.11
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          How are farmers and vendors selected for participation in the USDA
          Farmers Market?
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          USDA reviews all applications and selects participants based primarily
          on the type of farmer or vendor (i.e., fruit, vegetable, herb, baker)
          and secondly, on the specific types of products to be sold. The
          selection of the participants is conducted by the market management to
          ensure a balanced product mix of fruits, vegetables, herbs,
          value-added products, and baked goods.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4281'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:G:170:-:170.12
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        170.12
      </num>
      <head>
        What are the selection criteria for participation in the USDA Farmers
        Market?
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='170' sect='12' psec='' tq='N'>
              170.12
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          What are the selection criteria for participation in the USDA Farmers
          Market?
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The selection criteria are designed to ensure a consistently high
          level of quality and diverse products are available at the market,
          while operating in the constraints of space available at the market
          site. The criteria are:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Member of one of the three participant groups specified in 
              <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
                § 
                <subref title='7' part='170' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
                  170.4
                </subref>
                 of this part
              </aref>
              .
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The participant must be a producer-only farmer or producer, seller
            of value-added products, or specialized non-produce vendor.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Participant offers a product that adds to a product mix.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Market management will ensure that a balanced mix of fresh fruits
            and vegetables will be maintained throughout the season. Final
            selection of fruit and vegetable producers will be made based on
            their ability to ensure a wide range of fresh farm products
            throughout the season.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Willingness to Glean.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Participants should commit to supporting the USDA food
            gleaning/food recovery initiative. 
            <PRTPAGE P='312' />
            This commitment requires farmers and vendors to donate surplus food
            and food products at the end of each market day to a local nonprofit
            organization identified by USDA. Questions about tax deductions for
            gleaning should be referred to the Internal Revenue Service or a tax
            advisor. Receipts for donated foods may be obtained from the
            receiving nonprofit organization.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Commitment to market.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Participants must commit to the entire market season and be willing
            to participate on a regular basis.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Grandfather provision.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Market management reserves the right to select several farmers or
            vendors based on previous participation in the program, consistency
            in providing quality products, and compliance with operating
            guidelines.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4282'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:G:170:-:170.13
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        170.13
      </num>
      <head>
        What are the operating guidelines for the USDA Farmers Market?
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='170' sect='13' psec='' tq='N'>
              170.13
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          What are the operating guidelines for the USDA Farmers Market?
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Market Operation.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Market will be held in parking court #9 of the USDA
            Headquarters Complex located on the corner of 12th Street and
            Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC. Selling will not begin
            before 10 a.m. and will end promptly at 2 p.m. each market day. All
            participants must be in place, setup and ready to sell by 10 a.m.
            Due to space restrictions at the site, late arrivals will be located
            at market management&apos;s discretion. All vehicles must vacate the
            market site no later than 3 p.m.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Notification of Attendance.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each participant must call USDA within 48 hours of a market day if
            they cannot attend. Failure to provide proper and timely
            notification may result in termination of participation in the
            market.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Participant Space.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             One vehicle is permitted per space; all other vehicles must be
            removed from the immediate market premises. One space is 16w × 17d
            feet, and all trucks must fit within that area. There is only room
            for 15 spaces.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Signage.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Participants must clearly display the name of their farm/business
            and post prices for all items being sold.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Clean-up.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Participants are responsible for cleaning all trash and waste
            within and around their allotted space. Garbage bins are provided on
            the market site for this purpose.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Cooperative Marketing.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Participants are permitted to share space with another participant
            or sell another&apos;s products if the arrangement is deemed by
            market management as beneficial to the market. A co-op must be
            pre-approved by market management and will not be accepted if
            similar products are already sold by existing farmers or vendors.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Farm/Business Visits.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Market management may visit farm/business locations to verify
            compliance with market criteria and guidelines. Participants should
            submit a map and directions to their farm/businesses with their
            market applications.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Conduct on Federal Property:
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Participants must comply with 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              Subpart 20.3 of
            </aref>
             the Federal Property Management Regulations, “Conduct on Federal
            Property,” 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              41 CFR 
              <subref title='41' part='20' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
                20.3
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4283'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:G:170:-:170.14
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        170.14
      </num>
      <head>
        What circumstances will prevent participation in the USDA Farmers
        Market?
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='170' sect='14' psec='' tq='N'>
              170.14
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          What circumstances will prevent participation in the USDA Farmers
          Market?
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Efforts will be made to accommodate all who apply to participate in
            the market. However, market management may deny participation in the
            market because of insufficient space or excess supply of the
            products to sell, failure to meet the stated criteria, or the
            participant&apos;s noncompliance with the operating guidelines or
            regulations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Participants who sell before the 10 a.m. opening time will be
            restricted from participating in the market following their second
            violation. A written warning will be given to the participant for
            the first violation of this guideline. After the second violation
            occurs, a letter of reprimand will be given to the participant
            restricting their participation for the next immediate market day.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Participants who arrive after the 10 a.m. opening time may be
            restricted from participating in the market following their second
            violation. A written warning may be given to the participant for the
            first violation of this guideline. After the second violation
            occurs, a letter of reprimand may be given to the participant
            restricting their participation for the next immediate market day.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>