<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol2'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:B:48
    </extid>
    <num>
      48
    </num>
    <head>
      REGULATIONS OF THE SECRETARY OF AGRICULTURE FOR THE ENFORCEMENT OF THE
      PRODUCE AGENCY ACT
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            Sec. 3, 44
          </aref>
          , Stat. 1355, as amended; 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='494' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/494.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 494
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            24 FR 7127
          </aref>
          , Sept. 3, 1959, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='2057'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:B:48:-:48.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        48.1
      </num>
      <head>
        Meaning of words.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='48' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              48.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Meaning of words.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Words in this part in the singular form shall be deemed to import the
          plural, and vice versa, as the case may demand.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='2058'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:B:48:-:48.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        48.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='48' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              48.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Unless the context otherwise requires, the following terms shall be
          construed as follows:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Act
            </E>
             means “An act to prevent the destruction or dumping, without good
            and sufficient cause therefor, of farm produce received in
            interstate commerce by commission merchants and others, and to
            require them truly and correctly to account for all farm produce
            received by them,” approved March 3, 1927 (
            <aref target='_blank' href='http://frwebgate.access.gpo.gov/cgi-bin/getpage.cgi?dbname=71_statutes2_at_large&amp;position=all&amp;page=1355'>
              44 Stat. 1355
            </aref>
            ; 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='491-497' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/491-497.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 491-497
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Person
            </E>
             means an individual, partnership, association or corporation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Secretary
            </E>
             means the Secretary of Agriculture of the United States, or any
            officer or employee of the Department to whom authority has
            heretofore been delegated, or to whom authority may hereafter be
            delegated, to act in his stead.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Service
            </E>
             means the Consumer and Marketing Service, United States Department
            of Agriculture.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Deputy Administrator
            </E>
             means the Deputy Administrator for Marketing Services, or any
            officer or employee of the Service, to whom authority has heretofore
            lawfully been delegated, or to whom authority may hereafter lawfully
            be delegated, to act in his stead.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Director
            </E>
             means the Director of the Fruit and Vegetable Division of the
            Service, or any officer or employee of the Division to whom
            authority has heretofore lawfully been delegated, or to whom
            authority may hereafter lawfully be delegated by the Director to act
            in his stead.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Produce
            </E>
             means all fresh fruits and fresh vegetables generally considered by
            the trade as perishable fruits and vegetables, melons, dairy or
            poultry products, or any perishable farm products of any kind or
            character.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Truly and correctly to account
            </E>
             means, unless otherwise stipulated by the parties, that the
            consignee of produce shall, within ten days after the final sale is
            made of any produce received for sale on consignment in interstate
            commerce or in the District of Columbia, render to the consignor
            thereof a true and correct itemized statement of the gross sales as
            well as all selling charges and all other charges or expenses paid
            and a statement of the net proceeds or deficit, and make full
            payment to the consignor of the net proceeds so received together
            with a full explanation of the disposition of any and all produce
            not sold.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Good and sufficient cause
            </E>
             means, with respect to destroyed, abandoned, discarded, or dumped
            produce, that the produce so dealt with had no commercial value, or
            that some other legal justification for so dealing with such produce
            existed, such as an order of condemnation by a health officer or
            definite authority from the shipper.
            <PRTPAGE P='307' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Commercial value
            </E>
             means any value that the produce may have for any purpose that can
            be ascertained in the exercise of due diligence by the consignee
            without unreasonable expense on loss of time.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='2059'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:B:48:-:48.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        48.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Director.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='48' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              48.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Director.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The Director shall perform, for and under the supervision of the
          Secretary and the Deputy Administrator, such duties as the Secretary
          or the Deputy Administrator may require in enforcing the provisions of
          the Act and the regulations issued thereunder.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='2060'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:B:48:-:48.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        48.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Destroying or dumping.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='48' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              48.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Destroying or dumping.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Any person receiving produce in interstate commerce or in the District
          of Columbia for or on behalf of another who, without good and
          sufficient cause, shall destroy or abandon, discard as refuse, or dump
          any produce, directly or indirectly or through collusion with any
          person, shall be considered to have violated the Act.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='2061'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:B:48:-:48.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        48.5
      </num>
      <head>
        False report or statement.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='48' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              48.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          False report or statement.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Any person receiving produce in interstate commerce or in the District
          of Columbia for or on behalf of another shall be considered to have
          violated the Act if, knowingly and with intent to defraud, he makes
          any false report or statement to the person from whom such produce was
          received concerning the handling, condition, quality, quantity, sale,
          or disposition thereof.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='2062'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:B:48:-:48.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        48.6
      </num>
      <head>
        Failure to account.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='48' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              48.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Failure to account.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Any person receiving produce in interstate commerce or in the District
          of Columbia for or on behalf of another shall be considered to have
          violated the Act if, knowingly and with intent to defraud, he fails
          truly and correctly to account to the person from whom such produce
          was received.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='2063'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:B:48:-:48.7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        48.7
      </num>
      <head>
        Evidence to justify dumping.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='48' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              48.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Evidence to justify dumping.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Any person, receiving produce in interstate commerce or in the
          District of Columbia, having reason to destroy, abandon, discard as
          refuse or dump such produce, should, prior to such destroying,
          abandoning, discarding or dumping, obtain a dumping certificate or
          other evidence of justification for such action. Certification,
          showing that the produce has no commercial value, should be obtained
          from:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An inspector authorized by the United States Department of
            Agriculture to inspect produce; or (b) a health officer, or food
            inspector of any State, county, parish, city or municipality or of
            the District of Columbia. When no inspector or health officer, as
            designated in paragraph (a) or (b) of this section is available,
            affidavits as to the condition of the produce should be obtained
            from two disinterested persons having no financial interest in the
            produce involved or in the business of a person financially
            interested therein, and who are unrelated by blood or marriage to
            any such financially interested person, and who, at the time of
            certification, and for a period of at least one year immediately
            prior thereto, have been engaged in the handling of the same general
            kind or class of produce with respect to which such affidavits are
            to be made. The certificate or affidavit obtained for justifying
            dumping should identify the produce to be dumped by giving the name
            of the shipper, any identifying marks or brands on the original
            container, the type of container, the commodity, the quantity, the
            date of inspection, and contain a short description of the condition
            of the produce to be dumped at the time of inspection. The name,
            address and title of the person or persons making such inspection
            should also be designated on the certificate or affidavit.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='2064'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:B:48:-:48.8
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        48.8
      </num>
      <head>
        Filing of complaints.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='48' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              48.8
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Filing of complaints.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Any person having reason to believe that the Act or the regulations in
          this part have been violated should submit promptly all available
          facts with respect thereto to the Director for investigation and
          appropriate action.
          <PRTPAGE P='308' />
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>