<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol4'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:C:271
    </extid>
    <num>
      271
    </num>
    <head>
      GENERAL INFORMATION AND DEFINITIONS
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='2011-203' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/2011-203.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 2011-203
            </subref>
          </aref>
          6.
        </P>
      </AUTH>
    </text>
    <section orderid='4868'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:C:271:-:271.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        271.1
      </num>
      <head>
        General purpose and scope.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [Amdt. 132, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          43 FR 47882
        </aref>
        , Oct. 17, 1982, as amended by Amdt. 216, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          47 FR 23461
        </aref>
        , May 28, 1982; Amdt. 248, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          48 FR 16832
        </aref>
        , Apr. 19, 1983; Amdt. 356, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          59 FR 29713
        </aref>
        , June 9, 1994]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='271' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              271.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General purpose and scope.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Purpose of the food stamp program.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The food stamp program is designed to promote the general welfare
            and to safeguard the health and well being of the Nation&apos;s
            population by raising the levels of nutrition among low-income
            households. 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              Section 2 of
            </aref>
             the Food Stamp Act of 1977 states, in part: 
          </text>
        </P>
        <EXTRACT>
          <P>
            Congress hereby finds that the limited food purchasing power of
            low-income households contributes to hunger and malnutrition among
            members of such households. Congress further finds that increased
            utilization of food in establishing and maintaining adequate
            national levels of nutrition will promote the distribution in a
            beneficial manner of the Nation&apos;s agricultural abundance and
            will strengthen the Nation&apos;s agricultural economy, as well as
            result in more orderly marketing and distribution of foods. To
            alleviate such hunger and malnutrition, a food stamp program is
            herein authorized which will permit low-income households to obtain
            a more nutritious diet through normal channels of trade by
            increasing food purchasing power for all eligible households who
            apply for participation.
          </P>
        </EXTRACT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Scope of the regulations.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              Part 
              <subref title='7' part='271' tq='N'>
                271
              </subref>
            </aref>
             contains general information, definitions, and other material
            applicable to all parts of this subchapter. 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              Part 
              <subref title='7' part='272' tq='N'>
                272
              </subref>
            </aref>
             sets forth policies and procedures governing State agencies which
            participate in the program. 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              Part 
              <subref title='7' part='273' tq='N'>
                273
              </subref>
            </aref>
             describes the eligibility criteria to be applied by State agencies
            and related processing requirements and standards. 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              Part 
              <subref title='7' part='274' tq='N'>
                274
              </subref>
            </aref>
             provides requirements for the issuance of coupons to eligible
            households and establishes related issuance responsibilities. 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              Part 
              <subref title='7' part='275' tq='N'>
                275
              </subref>
            </aref>
             sets forth guidelines for monitoring the food stamp program,
            analyzing the results and formulating corrective action. 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              Part 
              <subref title='7' part='276' tq='N'>
                276
              </subref>
            </aref>
             establishes State agency liability and certain Federal sanctions. 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              Part 
              <subref title='7' part='277' tq='N'>
                277
              </subref>
            </aref>
             outlines procedures for payment of administrative costs of State
            agencies. 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              Part 
              <subref title='7' part='278' tq='N'>
                278
              </subref>
            </aref>
             delineates the terms and conditions for the participation of retail
            food stores, wholesale food concerns, meal services, and insured
            financial institutions. 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              Part 
              <subref title='7' part='279' tq='N'>
                279
              </subref>
            </aref>
             establishes the procedures for administrative and judicial reviews
            requested by food retailers, food wholesalers, and meal services. 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              Part 
              <subref title='7' part='280' tq='N'>
                280
              </subref>
            </aref>
             explains procedures for issuing emergency coupon allotments to
            certain victims of disasters unable to purchase adequate amounts of
            food. 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              Part 
              <subref title='7' part='281' tq='N'>
                281
              </subref>
            </aref>
             sets forth guidelines for designating Indian tribes as State
            agencies. 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              Part 
              <subref title='7' part='282' tq='N'>
                282
              </subref>
            </aref>
             provides guidelines for initiation, selection, and operation of
            demonstration, research, and evaluation projects. 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              Part 
              <subref title='7' part='284' tq='N'>
                284
              </subref>
            </aref>
             provides for a nutrition assistance program for the Commonwealth of
            the Northern Mariana Islands (CNMI). 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              Part 
              <subref title='7' part='285' tq='N'>
                285
              </subref>
            </aref>
             describes the general terms and conditions under which grant funds
            are provided to the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [Amdt. 132, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            43 FR 47882
          </aref>
          , Oct. 17, 1982, as amended by Amdt. 216, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            47 FR 23461
          </aref>
          , May 28, 1982; Amdt. 248, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            48 FR 16832
          </aref>
          , Apr. 19, 1983; Amdt. 356, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            59 FR 29713
          </aref>
          , June 9, 1994]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4869'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:C:271:-:271.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        271.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [Amdt. 132, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          43 FR 47882
        </aref>
        , Oct. 17, 1978]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='271' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              271.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Access device
          </E>
           means any card, plate, code, account number, or other means of access
          that can be used alone, or in conjunction with another access device,
          to obtain payments, allotments, 
          <PRTPAGE P='637' />
          benefits, money, goods, or other things of value, or that can be used
          to initiate a transfer of funds under the Food Stamp Act of 1977, as
          amended.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Active case
          </E>
           means a household which was certified prior to, or during, the sample
          month and issued food stamp benefits for the sample month.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Active case error rate
          </E>
           means an estimate of the proportion of cases with an error in the
          determination of eligibility or basis of issuance. This estimate will
          be expressed as a percentage of the completed active quality control
          reviews excluding all results from cases processed by SSA personnel or
          participating in a demonstration project identified by FNS as having
          certification rules that are significantly different from standard
          requirements.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Adequate notice
          </E>
           in a periodic reporting system such as monthly reporting or quarterly
          reporting means a written notice that includes a statement of the
          action the agency has taken or intends to take; the reason for the
          intended action; the household&apos;s right to request a fair hearing;
          the name of the person to contact for additional information; the
          availability of continued benefits; and the liability of the household
          for any overissuances received while awaiting a fair hearing if the
          hearing official&apos;s decision is adverse to the household.
          Depending on the timing of a State&apos;s system and the timeliness of
          report submission by participating households, such notice may be
          received prior to agency action, at the time reduced benefits are
          received, or, if benefits are terminated, at the time benefits would
          have been received if they had not been terminated. In all cases,
          however, participants will be allowed ten days from the mailing date
          of the notice to contest the agency action and to have benefits
          restored to their previous level. If the 10-day period ends on a
          weekend or a holiday and a request is received the day after the
          weekend or holiday, the State agency shall consider the request to be
          timely.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Alien Status Verification Index (ASVI)
          </E>
           means the automated database maintained by the Immigration and
          Naturalization Service which may be accessed by State agencies to
          verify immigration status.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Allotment
          </E>
           means the total value of coupons a household is authorized to receive
          during each month or other time period.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Application form
          </E>
           means: (1) The application form designed or approved by FNS, which is
          completed by a household member or authorized representative; or
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For households consisting solely of public assistance or general
            assistance recipients, it may also mean the application form used to
            apply for public assistance or general assistance, including
            attachments approved by FNS, which is completed by a household
            member or authorized represen- tative.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Assessment
          </E>
           an in-depth evaluation of employability skills coupled with
          counseling on how and where to search for employment. If combined with
          work experience, employment search or training, an assessment of this
          nature could constitute part of an approvable employment and training
          component.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Authorization document
          </E>
           means an intermediary document issued by the State agency and used in
          an issuance system to authorize a specific benefit amount for a
          household.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Authorization to participate card (ATP)
          </E>
           means a document which is issued by the State agency to a certified
          household to show the allotment the household is authorized to receive
          on presentation of such document.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Beginning month(s)
          </E>
           in a Monthly Reporting and Retrospective Budgeting system means
          either the first month for which the household is certified for food
          stamps (where the State agency has adopted a one month accounting
          system) or the first month for which the household is certified for
          food stamps and the month thereafter (where the State agency has
          adopted a two month accounting system). Except for beginning months in
          sequence as described in the preceding sentences, a beginning month
          cannot be any month which immediately follows a month in which a
          household is certified. The month following the month of termination
          resulting from a one-month temporary change in household circumstances
          shall not be considered a beginning month.
          <PRTPAGE P='638' />
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Budget month
          </E>
           in a Monthly Reporting and Retrospective Budgeting system means the
          fiscal or calendar month from which the State agency uses income and
          other circumstances of the household to calculate the household&apos;s
          food stamp allotment to be provided for the corresponding issuance
          month.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Bulk storage point
          </E>
           means an office of the State agency or any person, partnership,
          corporation, organization, political subdivision, or other entity with
          which a State agency has contracted for, or to which it has assigned
          responsibility for, the security and storage of food coupons.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Communal dining facility
          </E>
           means a public or nonprofit private establishment, approved by FNS,
          which prepares and serves meals for elderly persons, or for
          supplemental security income (SSI) recipients, and their spouses, a
          public or private nonprofit establishment (eating or otherwise) that
          feeds elderly persons or SSI recipients, and their spouses, and
          federally subsidized housing for the elderly at which meals are
          prepared for and served to the residents. It also includes private
          establishments that contract with an appropriate State or local agency
          to offer meals at concessional prices to elderly persons or SSI
          recipients, and their spouses.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Coupon
          </E>
           means any coupon, stamp, type of certificate, authorization card,
          cash or check issued in lieu of a coupon, or access device, including
          an electronic benefit transfer card or personal identification number
          issued pursuant to the provisions of the Food Stamp Act of 1977, as
          amended, for the purchase of eligible food.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Coupon issuer
          </E>
           means any office of the State agency or any person, partnership,
          corporation, organization, political subdivision, or other entity with
          which a State agency has contracted for, or to which it has assigned
          responsibility for, the issuance of coupons to households.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Deficiency
          </E>
           means any aspect of a State&apos;s program operations determined to
          be out of compliance with the Food Stamp Act, FNS Regulations, or
          program requirements as contained in the State agency&apos;s manual,
          the State agency&apos;s approved Plan of Operation or other State
          agency plans.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Department
          </E>
           means the U.S. Department of Agriculture.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Direct access system
          </E>
           means an issuance system in which benefits are issued directly to the
          household, without the use of an intermediary document, based on the
          issuance agent&apos;s direct access to information in the
          household&apos;s individual record on the master issuance file, which
          may be a card document or an on-line computer system.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Drug addiction or alcoholic treatment and rehabilitation program
          </E>
           means any drug addiction or alcoholic treatment and rehabilitation
          program conducted by a private, nonprofit organization or institution,
          or a publicly operated community mental health center, under part B of
          title XIX of the Public Health Service Act (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='42' sect='300x' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/42/300x.html'>
              42 U.S.C. 300x
            </subref>
          </aref>
           et seq.). Under part B of title XIX of the Public Health Service Act
          is defined as meeting the criteria which would make it eligible to
          receive funds, even if it does not actually receive funding under part
          B of title XIX.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Elderly or disabled member
          </E>
           means a member of a household who: (1) Is 60 years of age or older;
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Receives supplemental security income benefits under title XVI of
            the Social Security Act or disability or blindness payments under
            titles I, II, X, XIV, or XVI of the Social Security Act;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Receives federally or State-administered supplemental benefits
            under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 1616(a) of
            </aref>
             the Social Security Act provided that the eligibility to receive
            the benefits is based upon the disability or blindness criteria used
            under title XVI of the Social Security Act;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Receives federally or State-administered supplemental benefits
            under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 212(a) of
            </aref>
            <aref target='_blank' title='Pub. L. 93-66' alt='Pub. L. 93-66' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d93:./list/bd/d93pl.lst:66%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Pub. L. 93-66
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Receives disability retirement benefits from a governmental agency
            because of a disability considered permanent under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 221(i) of
            </aref>
             the Social Security Act.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is a veteran with a service-connected or non-service-connected
            disability rated by the Veteran&apos;s Administration (VA) as total
            or paid as total by the VA under title 38 of the United States Code;
            <PRTPAGE P='639' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is a veteran considered by the VA to be in need of regular aid and
            attendance or permanently housebound under title 38 of the United
            States Code;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is a surviving spouse of a veteran and considered by the VA to be
            in need of regular aid and attendance or permanently housebound or a
            surviving child of a veteran and considered by the VA to be
            permanently incapable of self-support under title 38 of the United
            States Code;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is a surviving spouse or surviving child of a veteran and
            considered by the VA to be entitled to compensation for a
            service-connected death or pension benefits for a
            nonservice-connected death under title 38 of the United States Code 
            <E T='03'>
              and
            </E>
             has a disability considered permanent under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 221(i) of
            </aref>
             the Social Security Act. “Entitled” as used in this definition
            refers to those veterans&apos; surviving spouses and surviving
            children who are receiving the compensation or pension benefits
            stated or have been approved for such payments, but are not yet
            receiving them; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Receives an annuity payment under: 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 2(a)(1)(iv) of
            </aref>
             the Railroad Retirement Act of 1974 
            <E T='03'>
              and
            </E>
             is determined to be eligible to receive Medicare by the Railroad
            Retirement Board; or 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 2(a)(1)(v) of
            </aref>
             the Railroad Retirement Act of 1974 and is determined to be
            disabled based upon the criteria used under title XVI of the Social
            Security Act.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_11'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (11)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is a recipient of interim assistance benefits pending the receipt
            of Supplemented Security Income, a recipient of disability related
            medical assistance under title XIX of the Social Security Act, or a
            recipient of disability-based State general assistance benefits 
            <E T='03'>
              provided
            </E>
             that the eligibility to receive any of these benefits is based upon
            disability or blindness criteria established by the State agency
            which are at least as stringent as those used under title XVI of the
            Social Security Act (as set forth at 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              20 CFR part 
              <subref title='20' part='416' tq='N'>
                416
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , subpart I, Determining Disability and Blindness as defined in
            Title XVI).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Eligible foods
          </E>
           means: (1) Any food or food product intended for human consumption
          except alcoholic beverages, tobacco, and hot foods and hot food
          products prepared for immediate consumption;
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Seeds and plants to grow foods for the personal consumption of
            eligible households;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Meals prepared and delivered by an authorized meal delivery service
            to households eligible to use coupons to purchase delivered meals;
            or meals served by an authorized communal dining facility for the
            elderly, for SSI households or both, to households eligible to use
            coupons for communal dining;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Meals prepared and served by a drug addict or alcoholic treatment
            and rehabilitation center to narcotic addicts or alcoholics and
            their children who live with them;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Meals prepared and served by a group living arrangement facility to
            residents who are blind or disabled as defined in paragraphs (2)
            through (11) of the definition of “Elderly or disabled member”
            contained in this section;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Meals prepared by and served by a shelter for battered women and
            children to its eligible residents;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the case of certain eligible households living in areas of
            Alaska where access to food stores is extremely difficult and the
            households rely on hunting and fishing for subsistence, equipment
            for the purpose of procuring food for eligible households, including
            nets, lines, hooks, fishing rods, harpoons, knives, and other
            equipment necessary for subsistence hunting and fishing but not
            equipment for the purpose of transportation, clothing or shelter,
            nor firearms, ammunition or other explosives;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the case of homeless food stamp households, meals prepared for
            and served by an authorized public or private nonprofit
            establishment (e.g. soup kitchen, temporary shelter), approved by an
            appropriate State or local agency, that feeds homeless persons; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the case of homeless food stamp households, meals prepared by a
            restaurant which contracts with an appropriate State agency to serve
            meals to homeless persons at concessional (low or reduced) prices.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Employment and training (E&amp;T) component
          </E>
           a work experience, work training or job search program, as described
          in 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 6(d)(4)(B)(iv) of
          </aref>
           the Food Stamp 
          <PRTPAGE P='640' />
          Act of 1977 (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='2014' note='' psec='#2_4_B' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/2014.html#2_4_B'>
              7 U.S.C. 2014(2)(4)(B)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ) designed to help food stamp recipients move promptly into
          unsubsidized employment.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Employment and training (E&amp;T) mandatory participant
          </E>
           a Food Stamp Program applicant or participant who is required to work
          register under 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='2014' note='' psec='#d_1' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/2014.html#d_1'>
              7 U.S.C. 2014(d)(1)
            </subref>
          </aref>
           or (2) and who the State determines should not be exempted from
          participation in an employment and training program.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Employment and training (E&amp;T) program
          </E>
           a program operated by each State agency consisting of one or more
          work, training, education or job search components.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Error
          </E>
           for active cases results when a determination is made by a quality
          control reviewer that a household which received food stamp benefits
          during the sample month is ineligible or received an incorrect
          allotment. Thus, errors in active cases involve dollar loss to either
          the participant or the government. For negative cases, an “error”
          means that the reviewer determines that the decision to deny, suspend,
          or terminate a household was incorrect.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Exempted
          </E>
           for purposes of 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='273' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              273.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
           excluding paragraphs (a) and (b)—this term refers to a work
          registered person or persons excused by the State, under the
          conditions in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='273' sect='7' psec='#e' tq='N'>
              273.7(e)
            </subref>
          </aref>
           from participation in an employment and training program.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Exercises governmental jurisdiction
          </E>
           means the active exercise of the legislative, executive or judicial
          powers of government by an Indian tribal organization.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Federal fiscal year
          </E>
           means a period of 12 calendar months beginning with each October 1
          and ending with September 30 of the following calendar year.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Firm&apos;s practice
          </E>
           means the usual manner in which personnel of a firm or store accept
          food coupons as shown by the actions of the personnel at the time of
          the investigation.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            FNS
          </E>
           means the Food and Nutrition Service of the U.S. Department of
          Agriculture.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Food Stamp Act
          </E>
           means the Food Stamp Act of 1977 (
          <aref target='_blank' title='Pub. L. 95-113' alt='Pub. L. 95-113' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d95:./list/bd/d95pl.lst:113%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Pub. L. 95-113
          </aref>
          ), including any subsequent amendments thereto.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            General assistance (GA)
          </E>
           means cash or another form of assistance, excluding in-kind
          assistance, financed by State or local funds as part of a program
          which provides assistance to cover living expenses or other basic
          needs intended to promote the health or well-being of recipients.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Group living arrangement
          </E>
           means a public or private nonprofit residential setting that serves
          no more than sixteen residents that is certified by the appropriate
          agency or agencies of the State under regulations issued under 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 1616(e) of
          </aref>
           the Social Security Act or under standards determined by the
          Secretary to be comparable to standards implemented by appropriate
          State agencies under 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 1616(e) of
          </aref>
           the Social Security Act. To be eligible for food stamp benefits, a
          resident of such a group living arrangement must be blind or disabled
          as defined in paragraphs (2) through (11) of the definition of
          “Elderly or disabled member” contained in this section.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Homeless individual
          </E>
           means an individual who lacks a fixed and regular nighttime residence
          or an individual whose primary nighttime residence is: (1) A
          supervised shelter designed to provide temporary accommodations (such
          as a welfare hotel or congregate shelter);
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A halfway house or similar institution that provides temporary
            residence for individuals intended to be institutionalized;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A temporary accommodation for not more than 90 days in the
            residence of another individual; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A place not designed for, or ordinarily used, as a regular sleeping
            accommodation for human beings (a hallway, a bus station, a lobby or
            similar places).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Homeless meal provider
          </E>
           means:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A public or private nonprofit establishment (e.g., soup kitchens,
            temporary shelters) that feeds homeless persons; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A restaurant which contracts with an appropriate State agency to
            offer meals at concessional (low or reduced) prices to homeless
            persons.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            House-to-house trade route
          </E>
           means any retail food business operated from a truck, bus, pushcart,
          or other mobile vehicle.
          <PRTPAGE P='641' />
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Identification (ID) card
          </E>
           means a card which identifies the bearer as eligible to receive and
          use food coupons.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Immigration and Naturalization Service (INS)
          </E>
           means the Immigration and Naturalization Service, U.S. Department of
          Justice.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Indian tribe
          </E>
           means: (1) Any Indian tribe, Band, Nation, or other organized Indian
          group on a reservation for example, a Rancheria, Pueblo or Colony, and
          including any Alaska Native Village or regional or village corporation
          (established pursuant to the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (
          <aref target='_blank' href='http://frwebgate.access.gpo.gov/cgi-bin/getpage.cgi?dbname=92_statutes_at_large&amp;position=all&amp;page=688'>
            85 Stat. 688
          </aref>
          )), that is on a reservation and is recognized as eligible for Federal
          programs and services provided to Indians because of their status as
          Indians; or (2) any Indian tribe or Band on a reservation holding a
          treaty with a State government.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Indian tribal organization (ITO)
          </E>
           means: (1) The recognized governing body of any Indian tribe on a
          reservation; or (2) the tribally recognized intertribal organization
          which the recognized governing bodies of two or more Indian tribes on
          a reservation authorizes to operate the Food Stamp Program or a Food
          Distribution Program on their behalf.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Insured financial institution
          </E>
           means a financial institution insured by the Federal Deposit
          Insurance Corporation (FDIC) or financial institutions which are
          insured under the Federal Credit Union Act and which have retail food
          stores or wholesale food concerns in their field of membership.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Issuance month
          </E>
           in a Monthly Reporting and Retrospective Budgeting system means the
          fiscal or calendar month for which the State agency shall issue a food
          stamp allotment. Issuance is based upon income and circumstances in
          the corresponding budget month. In prospective budgeting, the budget
          month and issuance month are the same. In retrospective budgeting, the
          issuance month follows the budget month and the issuance month shall
          begin within 32 days after the end of the budget month.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Large project area
          </E>
           means those project areas/management units with monthly active
          caseloads of more than 15,000 households based on the most current
          information available at the time the large project area review
          schedule is developed.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Low-income household
          </E>
           means a household whose annual income does not exceed 125 percent of
          the Office of Management and Budget poverty guidelines.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Management Evaluation (ME) reviews
          </E>
           means reviews conducted by States at the project area level to
          determine if State agencies are administering and operating the Food
          Stamp Program in accordance with program requirements.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Management unit
          </E>
           means an area based on a welfare district, region, or other
          administrative structure designated by the State agency and approved
          by FNS to be reviewed for ME review purposes.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Master issuance file
          </E>
           means a cumulative file containing the individual records and status
          of households, and the amount of benefits, if any, each household is
          authorized to receive.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Meal delivery service
          </E>
           means a political subdivision, a private nonprofit organization, or a
          private establishment with which a State or local agency has
          contracted for the preparation and delivery of meals at concessional
          prices to elderly persons, and their spouses, and to the physically or
          mentally handicapped and persons otherwise disabled, and their
          spouses, such that they are unable to adequately prepare all of their
          meals.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Medicaid
          </E>
           means medical assistance under title XIX of the Social Security Act,
          as amended.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Medium project area
          </E>
           means those project areas/management units with monthly active
          caseloads of 2,001 to 15,000 households based on the most current
          information available at the time the medium project area review
          schedule is developed.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Minimum benefit
          </E>
           means the minimum monthly amount of food stamps that one- and
          two-person households receive. The amount of the minimum benefit shall
          be $10.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            National performance measure
          </E>
           means the sum of the products of each State agency&apos;s payment
          error rate times that State agency&apos;s proportion of the total
          value of the national allotments issued for the fiscal year using the
          most recent issuance data available at the 
          <PRTPAGE P='642' />
          time the State agency is notified of its performance error rate.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Negative case
          </E>
           means any action taken to deny, suspend, or terminate a case.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Negative case error rate
          </E>
           means an estimate of the proportion of denied, suspended, or
          terminated cases where the household was incorrectly denied,
          suspended, or terminated. This estimate will be expressed as a
          percentage of completed negative quality control reviews excluding all
          results from cases processed by SSA personnel or participating in a
          demonstration project identified by FNS as having certification rules
          that are significantly different from standard requirements.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Newly work registered
          </E>
           food stamp participants work registered at the point of application.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Nonprofit cooperative food purchasing venture
          </E>
           means any private nonprofit association of consumers whose members
          pool their resources to buy food.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Offset year
          </E>
           means the calendar year during which offsets may be made to collect
          certain recipient claims from individuals&apos; Federal income tax
          refunds.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Overissuance
          </E>
           means the amount by which coupons issued to a household exceeds the
          amount it was eligible to receive.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Overpayment error rate
          </E>
           means the percentage of the value of all allotments issued in a
          fiscal year that are either: (1) Issued to households that fail to
          meet basic program eligibility requirements, or
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Overissued to eligible households.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Payment error rate
          </E>
           means the sum of the point estimates of two component error rates: an
          overpayment error rate and an underpayment error rate. Each component
          error rate is the value of allotments either overissued or underissued
          expressed as a percentage of all allotments issued to completed active
          sample cases, excluding those cases processed by SSA personnel or
          participating in certain demonstration projects designated by FNS.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Placed in an employment and training (E&amp;T) program
          </E>
           means a State agency may count a person as “placed” in an E&amp;T
          program when the individual commences a component.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Program
          </E>
           means the food stamp program conducted under the Food Stamp Act and
          regulations.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Project area
          </E>
           means the county or similar political subdivision designated by a
          State as the administrative unit for program operations. Upon prior
          FNS approval, a city, Indian reservation, welfare district, or any
          other entity with clearly defined geographic boundaries, or any
          combination of such entities, may be designated as a project area, or
          a State as a whole may be designated as a single project area.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Prospective budgeting
          </E>
           in a Monthly Reporting and Retrospective Budgeting system means the
          computation of a household&apos;s food stamp allotment for an issuance
          month based on an estimate of income and circumstances which will
          exist in that month.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Public assistance (PA)
          </E>
           means any of the following programs authorized by the Social Security
          Act of 1935, as amended: Old-age assistance, Temporary Assistance for
          Needy Families (TANF), including TANF for children of unemployed
          fathers, aid to the blind, aid to the permanently and totally disabled
          and aid to aged, blind, or disabled.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Quality control review
          </E>
           means a review of a statistically valid sample of active and negative
          cases to determine the extent to which households are receiving the
          food stamp allotments to which they are entitled, and to determine the
          extent to which decisions to deny, suspend, or terminate cases are
          correct.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Record-for-issuance file
          </E>
           means a file which is created monthly from the master issuance file,
          which shows the amount of benefits each eligible household is to
          receive for the issuance month, and the amount actually issued to the
          household.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Regulations
          </E>
           means the provisions of this subchapter. Regulatory citations refer
          to provisions of this subchapter unless otherwise specified.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Reservation
          </E>
           means the geographically defined area or areas over which an ITO
          exercises governmental jurisdiction so long as such area or areas are
          legally recognized by the Federal or a State government as being set
          aside for the use of Indians.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Retail food store
          </E>
           means:
          <PRTPAGE P='643' />
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An establishment or house-to-house trade route that sells food for
            home preparation and consumption normally displayed in a public
            area, and either offers for sale, on a continuous basis, a variety
            of foods in sufficient quantities in each of the four categories of
            staple foods including perishable foods in at least two such
            categories (Criterion A) as set forth in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='1' psec='#b_1' tq='N'>
                278.1(b)(1)
              </subref>
               of this chapter
            </aref>
            , or has more than 50 percent of its total gross retail sales in
            staple foods (Criterion B) as set forth in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='1' psec='#b_1' tq='N'>
                278.1(b)(1)
              </subref>
               of this chapter
            </aref>
             as determined by visual inspection, marketing structure, business
            licenses, accessibility of food items offered for sale, purchase and
            sales records, counting of stockkeeping units, or other inventory or
            accounting recordkeeping methods that are customary or reasonable in
            the retail food industry as set forth in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='1' psec='#b_1' tq='N'>
                278.1(b)(1)
              </subref>
               of this chapter
            </aref>
            . Entities that have more than 50 percent of their total gross
            retail sales in hot and/or cold prepared, ready-to-eat foods that
            are intended for immediate consumption either for carry-out or
            on-premises consumption, and require no additional preparation, are
            not eligible for FSP participation as retail food stores under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='1' psec='#b_1' tq='N'>
                278.1(b)(1)
              </subref>
               of this chapter
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Public or private communal dining facilities and meal delivery
            services; private nonprofit drug addict or alcoholic treatment and
            rehabilitation programs; publicly operated community mental health
            centers which conduct residential programs for drug addicts and/or
            alcoholics; public or private nonprofit group living arrangements;
            public or private nonprofit shelters for battered women and
            children; public or private nonprofit establishments, approved by an
            appropriate State or local agency, that feed homeless persons; or a
            restaurant that contracts with an appropriate State agency to
            provide meals at concessional (low or reduced) prices to homeless
            food stamp households;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any stores selling equipment for procuring food by hunting and
            fishing to eligible households in Alaska, as specified in the
            definition of eligible foods;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any private nonprofit cooperative food purchasing venture,
            including those whose members pay for food prior to receipt of the
            food; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A farmers&apos; market.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Retrospective budgeting
          </E>
           in a Monthly Reporting and Retrospective Budgeting system means the
          computation of a household&apos;s food stamp allotment for an issuance
          month based on actual income and circumstances which existed in a
          previous month, the “budget month.”
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Review date
          </E>
           for quality control active cases means a day within the sample month,
          either the first day of the calendar or fiscal month or the day a
          certification action was taken to authorize the allotment, whichever
          is later. The “review date” for negative cases, depending on the
          characteristics of individual State systems, could be the date on
          which the eligibility worker makes the decision to suspend, deny, or
          terminate the case, the date on which the decision is entered into the
          computer system, the date of the notice to the client or the date the
          negative action becomes effective. For no case is the “review date”
          the day the quality control review is conducted.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Review period
          </E>
           means the 12-month period from October 1 of each calendar year
          through September 30 of the following calendar year.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Sample frame
          </E>
           means a list of all units from which a sample is actually selected.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Sample month
          </E>
           means the month of the sample frame from which a case is selected
          (e.g., for all cases selected from a frame consisting of households
          participating in January, the sample month is January).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Screening
          </E>
           an evaluation by the eligibility worker as to whether a person should
          or should not be referred for participation in an employment and
          training program. This activity would not be considered an approvable
          E&amp;T component.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Secretary
          </E>
           means the Secretary of the U.S. Department of Agriculture.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Shelter for battered women and children
          </E>
           means a public or private nonprofit residential facility that serves
          battered women and their children. If such a facility serves other
          individuals, a portion of the facility must be set aside on a
          long-term basis to serve only battered women and children.
          <PRTPAGE P='644' />
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Small project area
          </E>
           means those project areas/management units with monthly active
          caseloads of 2,000 households or fewer based on the most current
          information available at the time the small project area review
          schedule is developed.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            SSA processed/demonstration case
          </E>
           means a case that is participating or has been denied based upon
          processing by SSA personnel or is participating or has been
          denied/terminated based upon the rules of a demonstration project with
          significantly different certification rules (as identified by FNS).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Staple food
          </E>
           means those food items intended for home preparation and consumption
          in each of the following food categories: meat, poultry, or fish;
          bread or cereals; vegetables or fruits; and dairy products.
          Commercially processed foods and prepared mixtures with multiple
          ingredients shall only be counted in one staple food category. For
          example, foods such as cold pizza, macaroni and cheese,
          multi-ingredient soup, or frozen dinners, shall only be counted as one
          staple food item and will normally be included in the staple food
          category of the main ingredient as determined by FNS. Hot foods are
          not eligible for purchase with food stamps and, therefore, do not
          qualify as staple foods for the purpose of determining eligibility
          under 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='278' sect='1' psec='#b_1' tq='N'>
              278.1(b)(1)
            </subref>
             of this chapter
          </aref>
          . Accessory food items including, but not limited to, coffee, tea,
          cocoa, carbonated and uncarbonated drinks, candy, condiments, and
          spices shall not be considered staple foods for the purpose of
          determining eligibility of any firm. However, accessory foods that are
          offered for sale in authorized retail food stores are eligible food
          items which may be purchased with food stamp benefits.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State
          </E>
           means any one of the fifty States, the District of Columbia, Guam,
          the Virgin Islands of the United States, and the reservation of an
          Indian tribe whose ITO meets the requirements of the Food Stamp Act
          for participation as a State agency.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State agency
          </E>
           means: (1) The agency of State government, including the local
          offices thereof, which is responsible for the administration of the
          federally aided public assistance programs within the State, and in
          those States where such assistance programs are operated on a
          decentralized basis, it includes the counterpart local agencies which
          administer such assistance programs for the State agency, and (2) the
          Indian tribal organization of any Indian tribe determined by the
          Department to be capable of effectively administering a Food Stamp
          Program or a Food Distribution Program in accordance with provisions
          of the Food Stamp Act of 1977.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State Income and Eligibility Verification System (IEVS)
          </E>
           means a system of information acquisition and exchange for purposes
          of income and eligibility verification which meets the requirements of
          
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 1137 of
          </aref>
           the Social Security Act, generally referred to as the IEVS.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State Wage Information Collection Agency (SWICA)
          </E>
           means the State agency administering the State unemployment
          compensation law, another agency administering a quarterly wage
          reporting system, or a State agency administering an alternative
          system which has been determined by the Secretary of Labor, in
          consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of
          Health and Human Services, to be as effective and timely in providing
          employment related income and eligibility data as the two just
          mentioned agencies.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Sub-units
          </E>
           means the physical location of an organizational entity within a
          project area/management unit involved in the operation of the Food
          Stamp Program, excluding Post Offices.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Supplemental Security Income (SSI)
          </E>
           means monthly cash payments made under the authority of: (1) Title
          XVI of the Social Security Act, as amended, to the aged, blind and
          disabled; (2) 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 1616(a) of
          </aref>
           the Social Security Act; or (3) 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 212(a) of
          </aref>
          <aref target='_blank' title='Pub. L. 93-66' alt='Pub. L. 93-66' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d93:./list/bd/d93pl.lst:66%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Pub. L. 93-66
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Systematic Alien Verification for Entitlements (SAVE)
          </E>
           means the INS program whereby State agencies may verify the validity
          of documents provided by aliens applying for food stamp benefits by
          obtaining information from a central data file.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Thrifty food plan
          </E>
           means the diet required to feed a family of four persons consisting
          of a man and a woman 20 through 50, a child 6 through 8, and a 
          <PRTPAGE P='645' />
          child 9 through 11 years of age, determined in accordance with the
          Secretary&apos;s calculations. The cost of such diet shall be the
          basis for uniform allotments for all households regardless of their
          actual composition. In order to develop maximum food stamp allotments,
          the Secretary shall make household size and other adjustments in the
          Thrifty Food Plan taking into account economies of scale and other
          adjustments as required by law.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Trafficking
          </E>
           means the buying or selling of coupons, ATP cards or other benefit
          instruments for cash or consideration other than eligible food; or the
          exchange of firearms, ammunition, explosives, or controlled
          substances, as defined in 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 802 of
          </aref>
           title 21, United States Code, for coupons.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Underissuance
          </E>
           means the amount by which the allotment to which the household was
          entitled exceeds the allotment which the household received.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Underissuance error rate.
          </E>
           (See 
          <E T='03'>
            Underpayment error rate
          </E>
          .)
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Underpayment error rate
          </E>
           means the ratio of the value of allotments underissued to recipient
          households to the total value of allotments issued in a fiscal year by
          a State agency.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Universe
          </E>
           means all units for which information is desired.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Variance
          </E>
           means the incorrect application of policy and/or a deviation between
          the information that was used to authorize the sample month issuance
          and the verified information that should have been used to calculate
          the sample month issuance.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Wholesale food concern
          </E>
           means an establishment which sells eligible food to retail food
          stores or to meal services for resale to households.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [Amdt. 132, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            43 FR 47882
          </aref>
          , Oct. 17, 1978]
        </CITA>
        <EDNOTE>
          <HD SOURCE='HED'>
            Editorial Note:
          </HD>
          <P>
            For 
            <E T='04'>
              Federal Register
            </E>
             citations affecting 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='271' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
                271.2
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , see the List of CFR Sections Affected, which appears in the
            Finding Aids section of the printed volume and at 
            <E T='03'>
              www.fdsys.gov
            </E>
            .
          </P>
        </EDNOTE>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4870'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:C:271:-:271.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        271.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Delegations to FNS for administration.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [Amdt. 132, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          43 FR 47882
        </aref>
        , Oct. 17, 1982]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='271' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              271.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Delegations to FNS for administration.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Delegation.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Within the Department, FNS acts on behalf of the Department in the
            administration of the Food Stamp Program with the exception of those
            functions, which may be delegated to other agencies within the
            Department. The right is reserved at any time to withdraw, modify,
            or amend any delegation of authority. When authority is delegated to
            FNS, the responsibilities may be carried out by the Administrator or
            by another official of FNS, or by State agencies with respect to
            claims against households, as designated.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Claims settlement.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS shall have the power to determine the amount of and to settle
            and adjust any claim arising under the provisions of the act or this
            subchapter, and to compromise or deny all or part of any claim.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Demonstration authority.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS is authorized to undertake demonstration projects which test
            new methods designed to improve program administration and benefit
            delivery. FNS is authorized to initiate program research and
            evaluation efforts for the purposes of improving and assessing
            program administration and effectiveness. The procedure for
            initiating and conducting these projects is established in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='282' tq='N'>
                282
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [Amdt. 132, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            43 FR 47882
          </aref>
          , Oct. 17, 1982]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4871'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:C:271:-:271.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        271.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Delegations to State agencies for administration.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [Amdt. 132, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          43 FR 47882
        </aref>
        , Oct. 17, 1978, as amended by Amdt. 207, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          47 FR 52333
        </aref>
        , Nov. 19, 1982]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='271' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              271.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Delegations to State agencies for administration.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General delegation.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall be responsible for the administration of the
            program within the State, including, but not limited to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Certification of applicant households;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Issuance, control, and accountability of coupons;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Developing and maintaining complaint procedures;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Developing, conducting, and evaluating training;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Conducting performance reporting reviews;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Keeping records necessary to determine whether the program is being
            conducted in compliance with these regulations; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Submitting accurate and timely financial and program reports.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Claims delegation.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS delegates to the State agency, subject to the standards in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='273' sect='18' psec='' tq='N'>
                273.18
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , the authority to determine the amount of, and settle, adjust,
            compromise or deny all or part 
            <PRTPAGE P='646' />
            of any claim which results from fraudulent or nonfraudulent
            overissuances to participating households.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [Amdt. 132, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            43 FR 47882
          </aref>
          , Oct. 17, 1978, as amended by Amdt. 207, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            47 FR 52333
          </aref>
          , Nov. 19, 1982]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4872'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:C:271:-:271.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        271.5
      </num>
      <head>
        Coupons as obligations of the United States, crimes and offenses.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [Amdt. 132, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          43 FR 47882
        </aref>
        , Oct. 17, 1978, as amended by Amdt. 221, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          47 FR 35168
        </aref>
        , Aug. 13, 1982; Amdt. 269, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          51 FR 10782
        </aref>
        , Mar. 28, 1986; Amdt. 334, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          57 FR 3911
        </aref>
        , Feb. 3, 1992; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          59 FR 51354
        </aref>
        , Oct. 11, 1994]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='271' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              271.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Coupons as obligations of the United States, crimes and offenses.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Coupons as obligations.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Pursuant to 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 15(d) of
            </aref>
             the Food Stamp Act, coupons are an obligation of the United States
            within the meaning of 18 United States Code (U.S.C.) 8. The
            provisions of Title 18 of the United States Code, “Crimes and
            Criminal Procedure,” relative to counterfeiting, misuse and
            alteration of obligations of the United States are applicable to
            coupons.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Penalties.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any unauthorized issuance, redemption, use, transfer, acquisition,
            alteration, or possession of coupons, ATP cards, or other program
            access device may subject an individual, partnership, corporation,
            or other legal entity to prosecution under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              sections 15 (b) and (c) of
            </aref>
             the Food Stamp Act or under any other applicable Federal, State or
            local law, regulation or ordinance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              Section 15(b)(1) of
            </aref>
             the Food Stamp Act reads as follows: 
          </text>
        </P>
        <EXTRACT>
          <P>
            Subject to the provisions of paragraph (2) of this subsection,
            whoever knowingly uses, transfers, acquires, alters, or possesses
            coupons, authorization cards, or access devices in any manner
            contrary to this Act or the regulations issued pursuant to this Act
            shall, if such coupons, authorization cards, or access devices are
            of a value of $5000 or more, be guilty of a felony and shall be
            fined not more than $250,000 or imprisoned for not more than twenty
            years, or both, and shall, if such coupons or authorization cards
            are of a value of $100 or more but less than $5000 or if the item
            used, transferred, acquired, altered or possessed is an access
            device that has a value of $100 or more but less than $5000 be
            guilty of a felony and shall upon the first conviction thereof, be
            fined not more than $10,000 or imprisoned for not more than five
            years, or both, and upon the second and any subsequent conviction
            thereof, shall be imprisoned for not less than six months nor more
            than five years and may also be fined not more than $10,000 or, if
            such coupons or authorization cards are of a value of less than
            $100, or if the item used, transferred, acquired, altered, or
            possessed is an access device that has a value of less than $100,
            shall be guilty of a misdemeanor, and upon the first conviction
            thereof, shall be fined not more than $1000 or imprisoned for not
            more than one year or both, and upon the second and any subsequent
            conviction thereof, shall be imprisoned for not more than one year
            and may also be fined not more than $1000. In addition to such
            penalties, any person convicted of a felony or misdemeanor violation
            under this subsection may be suspended by the court from
            participation in the food stamp program for an additional period of
            up to eighteen months consecutive to that period of suspension
            mandated by 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 6(b)(1) of
            </aref>
             this Act.
          </P>
        </EXTRACT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              Section 15(b)(2) of
            </aref>
             the Food Stamp Act reads as follows: 
          </text>
        </P>
        <EXTRACT>
          <P>
            In the case of any individual convicted of an offense under
            paragraph (b)(1) of this section, the court may permit such
            individual to perform work approved by the court for the purpose of
            providing restitution for losses incurred by the United States and
            the State agency as a result of the offense for which such
            individual was convicted. If the court permits such individual to
            perform such work and such individual agrees thereto, the court
            shall withhold the imposition of the sentence on the condition that
            such individual perform the assigned work. Upon the successful
            completion of the assigned work the court may suspend such sentence.
          </P>
        </EXTRACT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              Section 15(c) of
            </aref>
             the Food Stamp Act reads as follows: 
          </text>
        </P>
        <EXTRACT>
          <P>
            Whoever presents, or causes to be presented, coupons for payment or
            redemption of the value of $100 or more, knowing the same to have
            been received, transferred, or used in any manner in violation of
            the provisions of this Act or the regulations issued pursuant to
            this Act, shall be guilty of a felony and, upon the first conviction
            thereof, shall be fined not more than $20,000 or imprisoned for not
            more than five years, or both, and upon the second and any
            subsequent conviction thereof, shall be imprisoned for not less than
            one year nor more than five years and may also be fined not more
            than $20,000 or if such coupons are of a value of less than $100,
            shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and, upon the first conviction
            thereof, shall be fined not more than $1,000 or imprisoned for not
            more than one year, or both, and upon the second and any subsequent
            conviction thereof, shall be imprisoned for not more than one year
            and may also be fined not more than $1,000. In addition to such
            penalties, any persons convicted of a felony or misdemeanor
            violation under this subsection may be suspended by the court from
            participation in the food stamp program for an additional period of
            up to eighteen months consecutive to that period of suspension
            mandated by 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 6(b)(1) of
            </aref>
             this Act.
          </P>
        </EXTRACT>
        <PRTPAGE P='647' />
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Security for coupons and ATP&apos;s.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All individuals, partnerships, corporations, or other legal
            entities including State agencies and their delegatees (referred to
            in this paragraph as “persons”) having custody, care and control of
            coupons and ATP&apos;s shall, at all times, take all precautions
            necessary to avoid acceptance, transfer, negotiation, or use of
            spurious, altered, or counterfeit coupons and ATP&apos;s and to
            avoid any unauthorized use, transfer, acquisition, alteration or
            possession of coupons and ATP&apos;s. These persons shall safeguard
            coupons and ATP&apos;s from theft, embezzlement, loss, damage, or
            destruction.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Coupon issuers.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any coupon issuer or any officer, employee or agent, thereof
            convicted of failing to provide the monthly reports required in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='274' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
                274.5
              </subref>
            </aref>
             or convicted of violating 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='274' tq='N'>
                274
              </subref>
            </aref>
             shall be subject to a fine of not more than $1,000, or imprisoned
            for not more than 1 year, or both.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any coupon issuer or any officer, employee or agent, thereof
            convicted of knowingly providing false information in the reports
            required under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='274' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
                274.5
              </subref>
            </aref>
             shall be subject to a fine of not more than $10,000, or imprisoned
            not more than 5 years, or both.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Forfeiture and denial of property rights—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='3'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any nonfood items, moneys, negotiable instruments, securities, or
            other things of value furnished or intended to be furnished by any
            person in exchange for food coupons, authorization cards, or other
            program benefit instruments or access devices in any manner not
            authorized by the Food Stamp Act or regulations issued pursuant to
            the Act, shall be subject to forfeiture and denial of property
            rights. Such property is deemed forfeited to the United States
            Department of Agriculture (USDA) at the time it is either exchanged
            or offered in exchange.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             These forfeiture and denial of property rights provisions shall
            apply to property exchanged or offered in exchange during
            investigations conducted by the Inspector General, USDA, and by
            other authorized Federal law enforcement agencies.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             These forfeiture and denial of property rights provisions shall not
            apply to property exchanged or intended to be exchanged during the
            course of internal investigations by retail firms, during
            investigations conducted solely by State and local law enforcement
            agencies and without the participation of an authorized Federal law
            enforcement agency, or during compliance investigations conducted by
            the Food and Nutrition Service.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Custodians and their responsibilities.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Inspector General, USDA, the Inspector General&apos;s designee,
            and other authorized Federal law enforcement officials shall be
            custodians of property acquired during investigations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon receiving property subject to forfeiture the custodian shall:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='e_2_ii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Place the property in an appropriate location for storage and
            safekeeping, or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='e_2_ii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Request that the General Services Administration (GSA) take
            possession of the property and remove it to an appropriate location
            for storage and safekeeping.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The custodian shall store property received at a location in the
            judicial district where the property was acquired unless good cause
            exists to store the property elsewhere.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_2_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Custodians shall not dispose of property prior to the fulfillment
            of the notice requirements set out in paragraph 3, or prior to the
            conclusion of any related administrative, civil, or criminal
            proceeding, without reasonable cause. Reasonable cause to dispense
            with notice requirements might exist, for example, where explosive
            materials are being stored which may present a danger to persons or
            property.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_2_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Custodians may dispose of any property in accordance with
            applicable statutes or regulations relative to disposition. The
            custodian may:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='e_2_v_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Retain the property for official use;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='e_2_v_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Donate the property to Federal, State, or local government
            facilities such as hospitals or to any nonprofit charitable
            organizations recognized as such under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 501(c)(3) of
            </aref>
             the Internal Revenue Code; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='e_2_v_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Request that GSA take custody of the property and remove it for
            disposition or sale.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_2_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Proceeds from the sale of forfeited property and any moneys
            forfeited shall be used to pay all proper 
            <PRTPAGE P='648' />
            expenses of the proceedings for forfeiture and sale including
            expenses of seizure, maintenance of custody, transportation costs,
            and any recording fees. Moneys remaining after payment of such
            expenses shall be deposited into the general fund of the United
            States Treasury.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Notice requirements.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The custodian shall make reasonable efforts to notify the actual or
            apparent owner(s) of or person(s) with possessory interests in the
            property subject to forfeiture except for the good cause exception
            if the owner cannot be notified.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The notice shall:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='e_3_ii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Include a brief description of the property;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='e_3_ii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Inform the actual or apparent owner(s) of or person(s) with
            possessory interests in the property subject to forfeiture of the
            opportunity to request an administrative review of the forfeiture;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='e_3_ii_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Inform the actual or apparent owner(s) of or person(s) with
            possessory interests in the property subject to forfeiture of the
            requirements for requesting administrative review of the forfeiture;
            and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='e_3_ii_D'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (D)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State the title and address of the official to whom a request for
            administrative review of the forfeiture may be addressed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as provided in paragraphs (e)(3) (iv) and (v) of this
            section, notice shall be given within 45 days from the date the
            United States convicts, acquits, or declines to act against the
            person who exchanged the property.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_3_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notice may be delayed if it is determined that such action is
            likely to endanger the safety of a law enforcement official or
            compromise another ongoing criminal investigation conducted by OIG,
            the United States Secret Service, the United States Postal
            Inspection Service, or other authorized Federal law enforcement
            agency.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_3_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notice need not be given to the general public.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Administrative review.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_4_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The actual or apparent owner(s) of or person(s) with possessory
            interests in the property shall have 30 days from the date of the
            delivery of the notice of forfeiture to make a request for an
            administrative review of the forfeiture.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_4_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The request shall be made in writing to the Assistant Inspector
            General for Investigations, Office of Inspector General, USDA, or to
            his/her designee, hereinafter referred to as the reviewing official.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_4_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A request for an administrative review of the forfeiture of
            property shall include the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='e_4_iii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A complete description of the property, including serial numbers,
            if any;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='e_4_iii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Proof of the person&apos;s property interest in the property; and,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='e_4_iii_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The reason(s) the property should not be forfeited.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_4_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The requestor may, at the time of his/her written request for
            administrative review, also request an oral hearing of the reasons
            the property should not be forfeited.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_4_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The burden of proof will rest upon the requestor, who shall be
            required to demonstrate, by a preponderance of the evidence, that
            the property should not be forfeited.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_4_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Should the administrative determination be in their favor, the
            actual or apparent owner(s) of or person(s) with possessory
            interests in the property subject to forfeiture may request that
            forfeited items be returned or that compensation be made if the
            custodian has already disposed of the property.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_4_vii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The reviewing official shall not remit or mitigate a forfeiture
            unless the requestor:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='e_4_vii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Establishes a valid, good faith property interest in the property
            as owner or otherwise; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='e_4_vii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Establishes that the requestor at no time had any knowledge or
            reason to believe that the property was being or would be used in
            violation of the law; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='e_4_vii_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Establishes that the requestor at no time had any knowledge or
            reason to believe that the owner had any record or reputation for
            violating laws of the United States or of any State for related
            crimes.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_4_viii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (viii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The reviewing official may postpone any decision until the
            conclusion of any related administrative, civil, or criminal
            proceeding.
            <PRTPAGE P='649' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_4_ix'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ix)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The decision of the reviewing official as to the disposition of the
            property shall be the final agency determination for purposes of
            judicial review.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [Amdt. 132, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            43 FR 47882
          </aref>
          , Oct. 17, 1978, as amended by Amdt. 221, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            47 FR 35168
          </aref>
          , Aug. 13, 1982; Amdt. 269, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            51 FR 10782
          </aref>
          , Mar. 28, 1986; Amdt. 334, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            57 FR 3911
          </aref>
          , Feb. 3, 1992; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            59 FR 51354
          </aref>
          , Oct. 11, 1994]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4873'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:C:271:-:271.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        271.6
      </num>
      <head>
        Complaint procedure.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [Amdt. 132, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          43 FR 47882
        </aref>
        , Oct. 17, 1978, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          45 FR 71350
        </aref>
        , Oct. 28, 1980; Amdt. 187, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          45 FR 85699
        </aref>
        , Dec. 30, 1980; Amdt. 211, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          47 FR 53315
        </aref>
        , Nov. 26, 1982; Amdt. 237, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          47 FR 57668
        </aref>
        , Dec. 28, 1982; Amdt. 250, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          48 FR 22130
        </aref>
        , May 17, 1983; Amdt. 269, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          51 FR 10782
        </aref>
        , Mar. 28, 1986; Amdt. 356, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          59 FR 29713
        </aref>
        , June 9, 1994; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          76 FR 27606
        </aref>
        , May 12, 2011]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='271' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              271.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Complaint procedure.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              State agency responsibility—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General scope.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall maintain a system of its choosing for
            handling program complaints filed by participants, potential
            participants, or other concerned individuals or groups. This shall
            not include complaints alleging discrimination on the basis of race,
            sex, age, religious creed, national origin, political beliefs or
            disability; such complaints shall be handled in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='272' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
                272.6
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . This procedure also need not include complaints that can be
            pursued through a fair hearing. Complaints regarding such areas as
            processing standards and service to participants and potential
            participants would generally be handled under this complaint
            procedure.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Minimum requirements.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall follow up on complaints, resolve complaints
            and take corrective action where warranted, and respond to the
            complainant on the State agency&apos;s disposition of the complaint.
            The State agency shall make information on the complaint system and
            how to file a complaint available to participants, potential
            participants and other interested persons. The State agency may make
            the information available through written materials or posters at
            certification offices or other appropriate means.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Complaint analysis.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall maintain records of complaints received and
            their disposition, and shall review records at least annually to
            assess whether patterns of problems may be present in local offices,
            project areas, or throughout the State. The results of this review
            shall be provided to the Performance Reporting System coordinator
            for appropriate action, and for inclusion, if appropriate, in the
            State Corrective Action Plan in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='275' sect='16' psec='' tq='N'>
                275.16
              </subref>
               of this chapter
            </aref>
            . The information provided to the Performance Reporting System
            Coordinator shall include the identification, if any, of potential
            or actual patterns of deficiencies in local offices, project areas,
            or throughout the State, and any identification of causes of these
            problems.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Monitoring.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS shall monitor State compliance with these requirements through
            the Performance Reporting System.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Regional office responsibility.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Persons or agencies desiring program information or wishing to file
            a complaint may contact the appropriate FNS Regional Office.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For Delaware, the District of Columbia, Maryland, New Jersey,
            Pennsylvania, Puerto Rico, Virginia, the Virgin Islands of the
            United States, and West Virginia: Mid-Atlantic Regional Office, U.S.
            Department of Agriculture, Food and Nutrition Service, CN 02150,
            Trenton, NJ 08650.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For Alabama, Florida, Georgia, Kentucky, Mississippi, North
            Carolina, South Carolina, and Tennessee: Southeast Regional Office,
            U.S. Department of Agriculture, Food and Nutrition Service, 77
            Forsyth Street SW., suite 112, Atlanta, GA 30303-3427.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For Illinois, Indiana, Michigan, Minnesota, Ohio and Wisconsin:
            Midwest Regional Office, U.S. Department of Agriculture, Food and
            Nutrition Service, 77 West Jackson Blvd., 20th Floor, Chicago, IL
            60604-3507.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For Arkansas, Louisiana, New Mexico, Oklahoma, and Texas: Southwest
            Regional Office, U.S. Department of Agriculture, Food and Nutrition
            Service, 1100 Commerce Street, suite 5-C-30, Dallas, TX 75242.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For Alaska, Arizona, California, Guam, Hawaii, Idaho, Nevada,
            Oregon and Washington: Western Regional Office, U.S. Department of
            Agriculture, Food and Nutrition Service, 550 Kearny Street, room
            400, San Francisco, CA 94108.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For Connecticut, Maine, Massachusetts, New Hampshire, New York,
            Rhode Island, and Vermont: Northeast Regional Office, U.S.
            Department of Agriculture, Food and Nutrition Service, 10 Causeway
            St., Boston, MA 02222-1069.
            <PRTPAGE P='650' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_vii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For Colorado, Iowa, Kansas, Missouri, Montana, Nebraska, North
            Dakota, South Dakota, Utah, and Wyoming: Mountain Plains Regional
            Office, U.S. Department of Agriculture, Food and Nutrition Service,
            1244 Speer Blvd., suite 903, Denver, CO 80204-3581.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Complainants shall be advised of the appropriate State complaint
            handling and fair hearing procedures. Upon household request, other
            complaints shall be pursued by the Department rather than the State
            agency, unless the complaint is one upon which the complainant
            wishes to request a fair hearing.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [Amdt. 132, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            43 FR 47882
          </aref>
          , Oct. 17, 1978, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            45 FR 71350
          </aref>
          , Oct. 28, 1980; Amdt. 187, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            45 FR 85699
          </aref>
          , Dec. 30, 1980; Amdt. 211, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            47 FR 53315
          </aref>
          , Nov. 26, 1982; Amdt. 237, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            47 FR 57668
          </aref>
          , Dec. 28, 1982; Amdt. 250, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            48 FR 22130
          </aref>
          , May 17, 1983; Amdt. 269, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            51 FR 10782
          </aref>
          , Mar. 28, 1986; Amdt. 356, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            59 FR 29713
          </aref>
          , June 9, 1994; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 27606
          </aref>
          , May 12, 2011]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4874'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:C:271:-:271.7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        271.7
      </num>
      <head>
        Allotment reduction procedures.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [Amdt. 146, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          46 FR 1426
        </aref>
        , Jan. 6, 1981, as amended by Amdt. 207, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          47 FR 52333
        </aref>
        , Nov. 19, 1982; Amdt. 211, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          47 FR 53315
        </aref>
        , Nov. 26, 1982; Amdt. 233, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          47 FR 53830
        </aref>
        , Nov. 30, 1982; Amdt. 269, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          51 FR 10782
        </aref>
        , Mar. 28, 1986; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          54 FR 24154
        </aref>
        , June 6, 1989; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          56 FR 63596
        </aref>
        , Dec. 4, 1991; Amdt. 356, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          59 FR 29713
        </aref>
        , June 9, 1994]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='271' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              271.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Allotment reduction procedures.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General purpose.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This section sets forth the procedures to be followed if the
            monthly food stamp allotments determined in accordance with the
            provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='273' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
                273.10
              </subref>
            </aref>
             must be reduced, suspended, or cancelled to comply with 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 18 of
            </aref>
             the Food Stamp Act of 1977, as amended. The best available data
            pertaining to the number of people participating in the program and
            the amounts of benefits being issued shall be used in deciding
            whether such action is necessary.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Nature of reduction action.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Action to comply with 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 18 of
            </aref>
             the Food Stamp Act of 1977, as amended, may be a suspension or
            cancellation of allotments for one or more months, a reduction in
            allotment levels for one or more months or a combination of these
            three actions. If a reduction in allotments is deemed necessary,
            allotments shall be reduced by reducing maximum food stamp
            allotments amounts for each household size by the same percentage.
            This results in all households of a given size having their benefits
            reduced by the same dollar amount. The dollar reduction would be
            smallest for one-person households and greatest for the largest
            households. Since the dollar amount would be the same for all
            households of the same size, the rate of reduction would be lowest
            for zero net income households and greatest for the highest net
            income households. All one- and two-person households affected by a
            reduction action shall be guaranteed the minimum benefit unless the
            action is a cancellation of benefits, a suspension of benefits, or a
            reduction of benefits of 90 percent or more of the total amount of
            benefits projected to be issued in the affected month.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Reduction method.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a reduction in allotments is deemed necessary, the maximum food
            stamp allotments amounts for all household sizes shall be reduced by
            a percentage specified by FNS. For example, if it is determined that
            a 25 per cent reduction in the maximum food stamp allotments amount
            is to be made, the reduction for all four-person households would be
            calculated as follows: The maximum food stamp allotments amount for
            a four-person household ($209 in November 1980) would be reduced by
            25% to $157. Then 30 percent of the household&apos;s net food stamp
            income would be deducted from the reduced maximum food stamp
            allotments amount. For example, 30 per cent of a net food stamp
            income of $200, $60, would be deducted from the reduced maximum food
            stamp allotments amount ($157), resulting in a reduced allotment of
            $97.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Implementation of allotment reductions—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Reductions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='3'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a decision is made to reduce monthly food stamp allotments, FNS
            shall notify State agencies of the date the reduction is to take
            effect and by what percentage maximum food stamp allotments amounts
            are to be reduced.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon receiving notification that a reduction is to be made in an
            upcoming month&apos;s allotment, State agencies shall act
            immediately to implement the reduction. Such action could differ
            from State to State depending on the nature of the issuance system
            in use. Where there are computerized issuance systems, the program
            used for calculating allotments shall be altered to reflect the
            appropriate percentage reduction in the maximum food stamp
            allotments for each household size and the computer program shall be
            adjusted to allow for the minimum benefit for one- 
            <PRTPAGE P='651' />
            and two-person households. The computer program shall also be
            adjusted to provide for the rounding of benefit levels of $1, $3 and
            $5 to $2, $4 and $6, respectively. FNS will provide State agencies
            with revised issuance tables reflecting the percentage reductions to
            be made in the maximum food stamp allotments amounts and reduce
            maximum food stamp allotments levels. In States where manual
            issuance is used, State agencies shall reproduce the issuance tables
            provided by FNS and distribute them to issuance personnel. State
            agencies shall ensure that the revised issuance tables are
            distributed to issuance agents and personnel in time to allow
            benefit reductions during the month ordered by FNS. In an HIR card
            system State agencies have the option of enacting the reduction in
            benefits either by changing all HIR cards before issuance activity
            for the affected month begins or by adjusting allotments at the
            point of issuance as each household appears at the issuance office.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Suspensions and cancellations.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a decision is made to suspend or cancel the distribution of food
            stamp benefits in a given month, FNS shall notify State agencies of
            the date the suspension or cancellation is to take effect. In the
            event of a suspension or cancellation of benefits, the provision for
            the minimum benefit for households with one or two members only
            shall be disregarded and all households shall have their benefits
            suspended or cancelled. Upon receiving notification that an upcoming
            month&apos;s issuance is to be suspended or cancelled, State
            agencies shall take immediate action to effect the suspension or
            cancellation. This action would involve making necessary computer
            adjustments, and notifying issuance agents and personnel.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon being notified by FNS that a suspension of benefits is over,
            State agencies shall act immediately to resume issuing benefits to
            certified households and shall resume benefit issuance as soon as
            practicable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Affected allotments.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whenever a reduction of allotments is ordered for a particular
            month, reduced benefits shall be calculated for all households for
            the designated month. However, any household with one or two members
            whose reduced benefits would be less than the minimum benefit shall
            receive the minimum benefit except as provided in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='273' sect='10' psec='#e_2' tq='N'>
                273.10(e)(2)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . Allotments or portions of allotments representing restored or
            retroactive benefits for a prior unaffected month would not be
            reduced, suspended, or cancelled even though they are issued during
            an affected month.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Notification of eligible households.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Reductions, suspensions and cancellations of allotments shall be
            considered to be Federal adjustments to allotments. As such, State
            agencies shall notify households of reductions, suspensions and
            cancellations of allotments in accordance with the notice provisions
            of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='273' sect='12' psec='#e_1' tq='N'>
                273.12(e)(1)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , except that State agencies shall not provide notices of adverse
            action to households affected by reductions, suspensions or
            cancellations of allotments.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Restoration of benefits.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Households whose allotments are reduced or cancelled as a result of
            the enactment of these procedures are not 
            <E T='03'>
              entitled
            </E>
             to the restoration of the lost benefits at a future date. However,
            if there is a surplus of funds as a result of the reduction or
            cancellation, FNS shall direct State agencies to provide affected
            households with restored benefits unless the Secretary determines
            that the amount of surplus funds is too small to make this
            practicable. The procedures implemented by State agencies for
            reducing and cancelling benefits shall be designed so that in the
            event FNS directs the restoration of benefits, such benefits are
            issued promptly.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Effects of reductions, suspensions and cancellations on the
              certification of eligible households.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as provided in paragraph (e)(2) of this section,
            determinations of the eligibility of applicant households shall not
            be affected by reductions, suspensions or cancellations of
            allotments. State agencies shall accept and process applications
            during a month(s) in which a reduction, suspension or cancellation
            is in effect in accordance with the requirements of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='273' tq='N'>
                273
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . Determinations of eligibility shall also be made according to the
            provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='273' tq='N'>
                273
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . If an applicant is found to be eligible for benefits and a
            reduction is in effect, 
            <PRTPAGE P='652' />
            the amount of benefits shall be calculated by reducing the maximum
            food stamp allotments amount by the appropriate percentage for the
            applicant&apos;s household size and then deducting 30 percent of the
            household&apos;s net food stamp income from the reduced maximum food
            stamp allotments amount. If an applicant is found to be eligible for
            benefits while a suspension or cancellation is in effect, no
            benefits shall be issued to the applicant until issuance is again
            authorized by FNS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Expedited service.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Households eligible to receive expedited processing who apply for
            program benefits during months in which reductions or suspensions
            are in effect, shall have their cases processed in accordance with
            the expedited processing provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='273' sect='2' psec='#i' tq='N'>
                273.2(i)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_ii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Those households that receive expedited service in months in which
            reductions are in effect and that are determined to be eligible
            shall be issued allotments that are reduced in accordance with the
            reduction in effect. These reduced allotments shall be made
            available to the households within the benefit delivery timeframe
            specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='273' sect='2' psec='#i' tq='N'>
                273.2(i)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_ii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Those households that receive expedited service in months in which
            suspensions are in effect and that are determined to be eligible
            shall have benefits issued to them within the timeframe specified in
            
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='273' sect='2' psec='#i' tq='N'>
                273.2(i)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . However, if the suspension is still in effect at the time issuance
            is to be made, the issuance shall be suspended until the suspension
            is ended.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Households eligible to receive expedited processing who apply for
            Program benefits during months in which cancellations are in effect
            shall receive expedited service. However, the deadline for
            completing the processing of such cases shall be five calendar days
            or the end of the month of application, whichever date is later. All
            other rules pertaining to expedited service, contained in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='273' sect='2' psec='#i' tq='N'>
                273.2(i)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , shall be applicable to these cases.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The reduction, suspension or cancellation of allotments in a given
            month shall have no effect on the certification periods assigned to
            households. Those participating households whose certification
            periods expire during a month in which allotments have been reduced,
            suspended or cancelled shall be recertified according to the
            provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='273' sect='14' psec='' tq='N'>
                273.14
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . Households found eligible to participate during a month in which
            allotments have been reduced, suspended or cancelled shall have
            certification periods assigned in accordance with the provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='273' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
                273.10
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Fair hearings.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any household that has its allotment reduced, suspended or
            cancelled as a result of an order issued by FNS in accordance with
            these rules may request a fair hearing if it disagrees with the
            action, subject to the following conditions. State agencies shall
            not be required to hold fair hearings unless the request for a fair
            hearing is based on a household&apos;s belief that its benefit level
            was computed incorrectly under these rules or that the rules were
            misapplied or misinterpreted. State agencies shall be allowed to
            deny fair hearings to those households who are merely disputing the
            fact that a reduction, suspension or cancellation was ordered.
            Furthermore, since the reduction, suspension or cancellation would
            be necessary to avoid an expenditure of funds beyond those
            appropriated by Congress, households do not have a right to a
            continuation of benefits pending the fair hearing. A household may
            receive retroactive benefits in an appropriate amount if it is
            determined that its benefits were reduced by more than the amount by
            which the State agency was directed to reduce benefits.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Issuance services.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State agencies must have issuance services available to serve
            housholds receiving restored or retroactive benefits for a prior,
            unaffected month.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Penalties.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notwithstanding any other provision of this subchapter, FNS may
            take one or more of the following actions against a State agency
            that fails to comply with a directive to reduce, suspend or cancel
            allotments in a particular month.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If FNS ascertains that a State agency does not plan to comply with
            a directive to reduce, suspend or cancel allotments for a particular
            month, a warning will be issued advising the State agency that if it
            does not comply, FNS may cancel 100 percent of the 
            <PRTPAGE P='653' />
            Federal share of the State agency&apos;s administrative costs for
            the affected month(s). If, after receiving such a warning, a State
            agency does not comply with a directive to reduce, suspend or cancel
            allotments, FNS may cancel 100 percent of the Federal share of the
            State agency&apos;s administrative costs for the affected month(s).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If FNS ascertains after warning a State agency as provided in
            paragraph (h)(1) of this section, that the State agency does not
            plan to comply with a directive to reduce, suspend or cancel
            allotments, a court injunction may be sought to compel compliance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a State agency fails to reduce, suspend or cancel allotments as
            directed, FNS will bill the State agency for all over issuances that
            result. If a State agency fails to remit the billed amount to FNS
            within a prescribed period of time the funds will be recovered
            through offsets against the Federal share of the State agency&apos;s
            administrative costs, or any other means available under law.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [Amdt. 146, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            46 FR 1426
          </aref>
          , Jan. 6, 1981, as amended by Amdt. 207, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            47 FR 52333
          </aref>
          , Nov. 19, 1982; Amdt. 211, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            47 FR 53315
          </aref>
          , Nov. 26, 1982; Amdt. 233, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            47 FR 53830
          </aref>
          , Nov. 30, 1982; Amdt. 269, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            51 FR 10782
          </aref>
          , Mar. 28, 1986; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            54 FR 24154
          </aref>
          , June 6, 1989; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            56 FR 63596
          </aref>
          , Dec. 4, 1991; Amdt. 356, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            59 FR 29713
          </aref>
          , June 9, 1994]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4875'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:C:271:-:271.8
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        271.8
      </num>
      <head>
        Information collection/recordkeeping—OMB assigned control numbers.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          50 FR 2660
        </aref>
        , Jan. 18, 1985, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          54 FR 7002
        </aref>
        , Feb. 15, 1989; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          54 FR 24527
        </aref>
        , June 7, 1989; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          56 FR 55059
        </aref>
        , Oct. 24, 1991; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          67 FR 41603
        </aref>
        , June 19, 2002]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='271' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              271.8
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Information collection/recordkeeping—OMB assigned control numbers.
        </SUBJECT>
        <table class='gpotable' CDEF='s25,10' COLS='2' OPTS='L2'>
          <caption />
          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th>
                7 CFR section where requirements are described
              </th>
              <th>
                Current OMB control no.
              </th>
            </tr>
          </thead>
          <tfoot />
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                271.7 (d)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0064
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                272.1 (d)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0274
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                272.1 (f)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0009
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22' />
              <td>
                0584-0010
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22' />
              <td>
                0584-0015
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22' />
              <td>
                0584-0022
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22' />
              <td>
                0584-0025
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22' />
              <td>
                0584-0034
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22' />
              <td>
                0584-0037
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22' />
              <td>
                0584-0052
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22' />
              <td>
                0584-0053
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22' />
              <td>
                0584-0064
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22' />
              <td>
                0584-0069
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22' />
              <td>
                0584-0074
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22' />
              <td>
                0584-0080
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22' />
              <td>
                0584-0081
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22' />
              <td>
                0584-0083
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22' />
              <td>
                0584-0124
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22' />
              <td>
                0584-0274
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22' />
              <td>
                0584-0285
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22' />
              <td>
                0584-0299
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22' />
              <td>
                0584-0301
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22' />
              <td>
                0584-0303
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22' />
              <td>
                0584-0333
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22' />
              <td>
                0584-0334
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22' />
              <td>
                0584-0336
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22' />
              <td>
                0584-0339
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                272.2 (a), (c), (d), (e), (f)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0083
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                272.5 (c)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0083
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                272.3 (a), (b), (c)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0083
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                272.6 (g), (h)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0025
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                272.7 (f), (g), (h), (i), (j), (k), (m)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0064
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                273.1 (f), (g)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0064
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                273.2 (b), (c), (f), (g), (h), (i), (j), (k)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0064
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                273.4 (e)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0274
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                273.5 (b)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0064
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                273.6 (a), (b), (g)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0064
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                273.7 (a), (d), (e)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0339
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                273.7 (c)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0064
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22' />
              <td>
                0584-0083
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22' />
              <td>
                0584-0339
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                273.7 (f)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0064
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                273.7 (m)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0285
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                273.8 (b), (c), (e), (g), (h), (i)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0064
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                273.9 (d)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0064
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                273.10 (a), (c), (e), (f), (g)(1)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0064
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                273.10 (g)(3)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0124
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                273.11 (a), (b), (c), (d), (e), (f), (h)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0064
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                273.11 (g)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0334
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                273.11 (i) (1)-(4)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0080
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22' />
              <td>
                0584-0081
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                273.11 (i)(5)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0009
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22' />
              <td>
                0584-0081
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                273.11 (i)(6)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0009
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22' />
              <td>
                0584-0080
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22' />
              <td>
                0584-0081
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                273.12 (a), (b), (c), (d), (e), (f)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0064
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                273.13 (a)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0064
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                273.14 (a), (b), (c)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0064
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                273.15 (a), (c), (d), (f), (i), (k), (l), (m), (q)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0064
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                273.16 (a), (b), (d), (e), (f), (g), (h), (i)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0064
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                273.17 (h)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0301
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                273.18 (a), (c), (d), (e), (f), (g), (k)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0064
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                273.18 (h)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0069
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                273.18 (i)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0053
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                273.21 (a), (c), (e), (f), (g), (h), (i), (j), (m), (p), (q)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0064
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                274.1 (c)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0009.
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                274.3 (d)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0009, 0584-0069, 0584-0080.
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                274.4 (a)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0080.
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                274.4 (b)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0009, 0584-0015, 0584-0080, 0584-0081.
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                274.4 (f)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0009, 0584-0053.
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                274.6 (a), (b) and (e)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0080, 0584-0081.
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                274.7 (a)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0009.
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                274.7 (c)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0022.
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                274.8 (a)-(c)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0009.
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                274.8 (e)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0053.
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                274.9 (a)-(d)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0009.
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                274.11
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0009.
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                275.2 (a)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0010
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22' />
              <td>
                0584-0303
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                275.4 (a)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0010
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22' />
              <td>
                0584-0303
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                275.4 (b)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0010
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                275.4 (c)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0034
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22' />
              <td>
                0584-0074
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22' />
              <td>
                0584-0299
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                275.5 (a), (b)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0010
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                275.6 (b)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0010
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                275.8 (a)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0010
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                275.9 (b), (g)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0010
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                275.10 (a)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0074
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22' />
              <td>
                0584-0299
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22' />
              <td>
                0584-0303
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                275.11 (a)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0303
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                275.12 (b), (c), (d), (e)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0074
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                275.12 (f), (g)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0299
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                275.13 (b), (d), (e)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0034
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                275.14 (c), (d)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0034
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22' />
              <td>
                0584-0074
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22' />
              <td>
                0584-0299
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                275.16 (b), (c), (d)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0010
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                275.17 (a), (b)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0010
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                275.18 (a), (b)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0010
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                275.19 (a), (b), (c)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0010
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                275.20 (a)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0010
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                275.21 (b)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0034
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22' />
              <td>
                0584-0074
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22' />
              <td>
                0584-0299
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                275.21 (c), (d), (e)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0034
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                275.22 (a), (b)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0010
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                275.23
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0010
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22' />
              <td>
                0584-0034
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22' />
              <td>
                0584-0074
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22' />
              <td>
                0584-0299
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                276.2 (b)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0015.
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                277.12 (a)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0341
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                277.14 (b), (c), (d), (h), (i), (j), (k)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0341
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                277.15 (c)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0064
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                277.17 (a), (b), (c), (d), (e), (f), (g)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0341
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                277.18 (a), (c), (d), (e), (g), (h)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0083
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                278.1 (a), (b), (l)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0008
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                278.1 (e), (f)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0064
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                278.4 (b), (c)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0085
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                278.5 (a)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0085
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22' />
              <td>
                0584-0314
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                278.5 (c), (d), (f)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0008
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                278.6 (b)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0008
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                278.7 (b), (c)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0008
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                278.8 (a)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0008
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                280.7 (c), (d), (g)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0336
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                280.9 (b)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0009
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22' />
              <td>
                0584-0037
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                280.10 (a)
              </td>
              <td>
                0584-0336
              </td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            50 FR 2660
          </aref>
          , Jan. 18, 1985, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            54 FR 7002
          </aref>
          , Feb. 15, 1989; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            54 FR 24527
          </aref>
          , June 7, 1989; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            56 FR 55059
          </aref>
          , Oct. 24, 1991; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            67 FR 41603
          </aref>
          , June 19, 2002]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>