<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol10'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1499
    </extid>
    <num>
      1499
    </num>
    <head>
      FOOD FOR PROGRESS PROGRAM
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='1736o' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1736o.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 1736o
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; and 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='15' sect='714b' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/15/714b.html'>
              15 U.S.C. 714b
            </subref>
             and 
            <subref title='15' sect='714c' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/15/714c.html'>
              714c
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            74 FR 13066
          </aref>
          , Mar. 26, 2009, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='13257'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1499:-:1499.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1499.1
      </num>
      <head>
        General statement.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1499' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              1499.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General statement.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This part sets forth the general terms and conditions governing the
            donation of commodities by the Commodity Credit Corporation (CCC) to
            participants in the Food for Progress Program (FFPr). Under FFPr,
            participants use the donated commodities or proceeds from the sale
            of such commodities to implement activities in a foreign country
            pursuant to an agreement with CCC. The Foreign Agricultural Service
            (FAS) of the Department of Agriculture (USDA) administers FFPr on
            behalf of CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In addition to the provisions of this part, other regulations of
            general application issued by USDA, including the regulations set
            forth in Chapter 30 of this title, are applicable to the FFPr. All
            provisions of the CCC Charter Act (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='15' sect='714' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/15/714.html'>
                15 U.S.C. 714
              </subref>
            </aref>
             et seq.) and any other statutory provisions that are generally
            applicable to CCC are applicable to FFPr and the regulations set
            forth in this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This part shall not apply to a donation by CCC to a foreign
            government or an intergovernmental agency or organization (such as
            the United Nations&apos; World Food Program) under FFPr.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13258'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1499:-:1499.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1499.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1499' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              1499.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The following definitions are applicable to this part:
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Activity
          </E>
           means a project to be carried out by a participant, directly or
          through a subrecipient, to fulfill the objectives of an agreement.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Agreement
          </E>
           means a legally binding agreement entered into between CCC and a
          participant to implement activities under FFPr.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            CCC
          </E>
           means the Commodity Credit Corporation and includes any official of
          the United States delegated the responsibility to act on behalf of
          CCC.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            CCC-provided funds
          </E>
           means U.S. dollars provided under an agreement to a participant for
          expenses for the internal transportation, storage and handling of the
          donated commodities, expenses involved in the administration and
          monitoring of the activities under the agreement, and technical
          assistance related to the monetization of donated commodities.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Commodities
          </E>
           mean U.S. agricultural commodities or products of U.S. agricultural
          commodities.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Donated commodities
          </E>
           means the commodities donated by CCC to a participant under an
          agreement. The term may include donated commodities that are used to
          produce a further processed product for use under the agreement.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            FAS
          </E>
           means the Foreign Agricultural Service acting on behalf of CCC.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            FFPr
          </E>
           means the Food for Progress Program.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Force majeure
          </E>
           is a common clause in contracts, exempting the parties for
          non-fulfillment of their obligations as a result of conditions beyond
          their control, such as earthquakes, floods or war.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Income
          </E>
           means interest earned on sale proceeds and other resources received
          by a participant, other than sale proceeds, as a result of carrying
          out an agreement. The term may include resources from VAT refunds,
          activity fees, interest on loans, and other sources.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Participant
          </E>
           means an entity with which CCC has entered into an agreement.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Subrecipient
          </E>
           means a legal entity that receives donated commodities, income, sale
          proceeds or other resources from a participant for the purpose of
          implementing in the targeted country activities described in a FFPr
          agreement and that is accountable to such participant for the use of
          such commodities, funds, or resources. The term may include foreign or
          international organizations 
          <PRTPAGE P='1012' />
          (such as agencies of the United Nations) at the discretion of FAS.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Sale proceeds
          </E>
           mean funds received by a participant from the sale of donated
          commodities.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Targeted country
          </E>
           means the country in which activities are implemented under an
          agreement.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13259'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1499:-:1499.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1499.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Eligibility determination.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1499' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              1499.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Eligibility determination.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An entity will be eligible to become a participant only after FAS
            determines that the entity has:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Organizational experience in implementing and managing awards, and
            the capability and personnel to develop, implement, monitor, report
            on, and provide accountability for activities in accordance with
            this part;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Experience working in the proposed targeted country;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An adequate financial framework to implement the activities the
            entity proposes to carry out under FFPr. In order to determine
            whether the entity is financially responsible, FAS may require it to
            submit corporate policies and financial materials that have been
            audited or otherwise reviewed by a third party;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A person or agent located in the United States with respect to
            which service of judicial process may be obtained by FAS on behalf
            of the entity; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An operating financial account in the proposed targeted country, or
            a satisfactory explanation for not having such an account and a
            description of how a FFPr agreement would be administered without
            such an account.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In determining whether an entity will be eligible to be a
            participant, FAS may consider the entity&apos;s previous compliance
            or noncompliance with the provisions of this part and 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1599' tq='N'>
                1599 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . FAS may consider matters such as whether the entity corrected
            deficiencies in the implementation of an agreement in a timely
            manner and whether the entity has timely and accurately filed
            reports and other submissions that are required to be filed with FAS
            and other agencies of the United States.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13260'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1499:-:1499.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1499.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Application process.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1499' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              1499.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Application process.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An entity seeking to enter into an agreement with CCC shall submit
            an application, in accordance with this section, that sets forth its
            proposal to carry out activities under FFPr in the proposed targeted
            country. An application shall contain the items specified in
            paragraph (b) of this section and shall be submitted electronically
            to FAS at the address set forth at 
            <E T='03'>
              http://www.fas.usda.gov
            </E>
            . An entity that has not yet met the eligibility requirements in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1499' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
                1499.3
              </subref>
            </aref>
             may submit an application, but FAS will not enter into an agreement
            with an entity until FAS had made a determination of eligibility
            under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1499' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
                1499.3
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An applicant shall include the following items in its application:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A completed Form SF-424, which is a standard application for
            Federal assistance;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An introduction that contains the elements specified in paragraph
            (c) of this section; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A plan of operation that contains the elements specified in
            paragraph (d) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The introduction shall include:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An explanation of the need for the food aid in the targeted country
            and how the applicant&apos;s proposed activities would address that
            need;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Information regarding the applicant&apos;s ability to become
            registered and operate in the targeted country;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Information about the applicant&apos;s past food aid projects; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A budget that details the amount of any sale proceeds, income, and
            CCC-provided funds that the applicant proposes to use to fund:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_4_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Administrative costs;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_4_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Inland transportation, storage and handling costs; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_4_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Activity costs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A plan of operation shall include:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The name of the targeted country where the proposed activities
            would be implemented;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The kind, quantity, and proposed use of the commodities requested,
            and any commodities that would be acceptable substitutions therefor,
            and the proposed delivery schedule;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If monetization or barter is proposed:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The quantity of the requested commodities that would be sold or
            bartered;
            <PRTPAGE P='1013' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The amount of sale proceeds anticipated;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The amount of income expected to be generated;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_3_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The anticipated monetization completion date;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_3_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The goods or services to be generated from the barter of the
            requested commodities; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_3_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The value of the goods or services anticipated to be generated from
            the barter of the requested commodities.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A list of each of the activities that would be implemented, with a
            brief statement of the objectives to be accomplished under each
            activity;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For each proposed activity, the targeted geographic area,
            anticipated beneficiaries, and methods that the applicant would use
            to choose such beneficiaries, including obtaining and considering
            statistics on poverty levels, food deficits, and any other required
            items set forth on the FAS Web site at 
            <E T='03'>
              http://www.fas.usda.gov
            </E>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For each proposed activity:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_6_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An explanation of whether the activity would be carried out through
            the distribution or barter of the requested commodities or funded by
            sale proceeds, income, or a combination thereof; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_6_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The amount of commodities requested and of any sale proceeds and
            income expected to be generated to carry out such activity; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_6_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A detailed description of the activity, including the steps
            involved in its implementation and the anticipated completion date;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any cash or non-cash contributions that the applicant expects to
            receive from non-CCC sources that:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_7_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Are critical to the implementation of the proposed activities; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_7_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Enhance the implementation of the activities;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any subrecipient that would be involved and a description of each
            subrecipient&apos;s responsibilities and its capability to perform
            responsibilities;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any governmental or nongovernmental entities that would be involved
            and the extent to which FFPr will strengthen or increase the
            capabilities of such entities to further economic development in the
            targeted country;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The method by which the applicant intends to inform beneficiaries
            of an activity about the source of the requested commodities or
            funding for the activity and, where the beneficiaries will be
            receiving the commodities directly, how to prepare and use them
            properly;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_11'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (11)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Established baselines, a timeline, and proposed outcomes that would
            enable FAS to measure the applicant&apos;s progress towards
            achieving the objectives of the proposed activities;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_12'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (12)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the proposed activities would involve the use of sale proceeds
            or income:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_12_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The process that the applicant would use to sell the requested
            commodities, including steps the applicant would take to use, to the
            extent possible, the private sector in the monetization process; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_12_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The procedures that the applicant would use to assure that sale
            proceeds and income are received and deposited into a separate,
            interest-bearing account and disbursed from such account for use
            only in accordance with the agreement;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_13'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (13)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A description of any port, transportation, storage, and warehouse
            facilities that would be used with sufficient detail to demonstrate
            that they would be adequate to handle the requested commodities
            without undue spoilage or waste, and, in cases where the applicant
            proposes to distribute some or all of the requested commodities, a
            description of how they would be transported from the receiving port
            to the point at which distribution would be made to the
            beneficiaries;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_14'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (14)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any reprocessing or repackaging of the requested commodities that
            would take place prior to the distribution, sale or barter by the
            applicant;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_15'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (15)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The action the applicant would take to ensure that any commodities
            to be distributed to beneficiaries, rather than sold, would be
            imported and distributed free from all customs, duties, tolls, and
            taxes;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_16'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (16)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A plan that shows how the requested commodities could be imported
            and distributed without a disruptive impact upon production, prices
            and marketing of the same or like products in the country where they
            will be delivered, and the extent to which any sale or barter of the
            requested commodities would displace or interfere with any 
            <PRTPAGE P='1014' />
            sales that may otherwise be made by the applicant or any other
            entity in the country where they will be delivered; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_17'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (17)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any additional required items set forth on the FAS Web site at 
            <E T='03'>
              http://www.fas.usda.gov
            </E>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13261'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1499:-:1499.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1499.5
      </num>
      <head>
        Agreements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1499' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              1499.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Agreements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             After FAS approves an applicant&apos;s proposal, FAS will develop
            an agreement in consultation with the applicant. The agreement will
            set forth the obligations of CCC and the participant. A participant
            must comply with the terms of the agreement to receive assistance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A participant shall not use donated commodities, sale proceeds,
            income or CCC-provided funds for any activity or any expenses
            incurred by the participant prior to the date of the agreement or
            after the agreement is suspended or terminated, except as approved
            by FAS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The agreement will include a budget that sets forth the maximum
            amounts of sale proceeds and CCC-provided funds that may be expended
            for various purposes under the agreement. A participant may make
            adjustments to this budget without prior approval from FAS only as
            specified in the agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Prior to providing any donated commodities or CCC-provided funds to
            a participant under an agreement, FAS may require the participant to
            complete a training program administered by FAS that is designed to
            ensure that the participant is aware of, and has the capacity to
            complete, all required reporting and audit functions set forth in
            this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A participant will be prohibited from using CCC-provided funds to
            acquire goods and services, either directly or indirectly through
            another party, from certain countries that will be specified in the
            agreement. Any violation of this provision of the agreement will be
            a basis for immediate termination by CCC of the agreement, in
            addition to the imposition of any other applicable civil and
            criminal penalties.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The agreement will prohibit the sale or transshipment of the
            donated commodities to a country not specified in the agreement for
            as long as such donated commodities are controlled by the
            participant.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC may enter into a multicountry agreement in which donated
            commodities are delivered to one country and activities are carried
            out in another.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC may provide donated commodities and CCC-provided funds under a
            multiyear agreement contingent upon the availability of commodities
            and funds.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13262'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1499:-:1499.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1499.6
      </num>
      <head>
        Payments.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1499' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              1499.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Payments.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the participant arranges for transportation in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1499' sect='7' psec='#b_2' tq='N'>
                1499.7(b)(2)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , and the participant seeks payment directly, the participant shall,
            as specified in the agreement, either submit to FAS, or maintain on
            file and make available to FAS, the following documents:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A signed copy of the completed Form CCC-512;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The original, or a true copy of, each on-board bill of lading
            indicating the freight rate and signed by the originating carrier;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For all non-containerized cargoes:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A signed copy of the Federal Grain Inspection Service (FGIS)
            Official Stowage Examination Certificate (Vessel Hold Certificate);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A signed copy of the National Cargo Bureau Certificate of Readiness
            (Vessel Hold Inspection Certificate); and,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A signed copy of the National Cargo Bureau Certificate of Loading;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For all containerized cargoes, a copy of the FGIS Container
            Condition Inspection Certificate;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A signed copy of the liner booking note or charter party covering
            ocean transportation of the cargo;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the case of charter shipments, a signed notice of arrival at the
            first discharge port, unless FAS has determined that circumstances
            of force majeure have prevented the vessel&apos;s arrival at the
            first port of discharge;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A request by the participant for reimbursement of freight, survey
            costs other than at load port, and other expenses approved by CCC,
            indicating the amount due and accompanied by a certification from
            the carrier or other parties that payments have been received from
            the participant; and
            <PRTPAGE P='1015' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A document on letterhead and signed by an officer or agent of the
            participant specifying the name of the entity to receive payment;
            the bank ABA number to which payment is to be made; the account
            number for the deposit at the bank; the participant&apos;s taxpayer
            identification number; and the type of the account into which the
            payment will be deposited.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the participant arranges for transportation in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1499' sect='7' psec='#b_2' tq='N'>
                1499.7(b)(2)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , and the participant has used a freight forwarder, the participant
            shall cause the freight forwarder to submit the documents specified
            in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1499' sect='6' psec='#a' tq='N'>
                1499.6(a)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             in order to receive payment from CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In no case will CCC reimburse a participant for demurrage costs or
            pay demurrage to any other entity.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If FAS has agreed to pay the costs of transporting, storing, and
            distributing the donated commodities from the designated port or
            point of entry, the participant will be reimbursed in the manner set
            forth in the agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the agreement authorizes the payment of CCC-provided funds, CCC
            will pay these funds to the participant on a reimbursement for
            expenses basis, except as provided in paragraph (f)(1) of this
            section. The participant shall request the payment of CCC-provided
            funds to reimburse it for authorized expenses in the manner set
            forth in the agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A participant may request an advance of the amount of funds
            specified in the agreement. FAS will not approve any request for an
            advance if:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             It is received earlier than 60 days after the date of a previous
            advance made in connection with the same agreement; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any required reports, as specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1499' sect='13' psec='' tq='N'>
                1499.13
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and in the agreement, are more than six months in arrears.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as may otherwise be provided in the agreement, the
            participant shall deposit and maintain in a bank account located in
            the United States all funds advanced by CCC. The account shall be
            interest-bearing, unless the exceptions in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='3019' sect='22' psec='#k' tq='N'>
                3019.22(k)
              </subref>
               of this title
            </aref>
             apply, or FAS determines that this requirement would constitute an
            undue burden. The participant shall remit semi-annually to CCC any
            interest earned on the advanced funds. The participant shall, no
            later than 10 days after the end of each calendar quarter, submit a
            financial statement to FAS accounting for all funds advanced and all
            interest earned.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The participant shall return to CCC any funds that are advanced by
            CCC if such funds have not been obligated as of the 180th day after
            the advance was made. Such funds and interest shall be transferred
            to FAS within 30 days of such date.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a participant is required to pay funds to CCC in connection with
            an agreement, the participant shall make such payment in U.S.
            dollars, unless otherwise approved in advance by FAS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Suppliers of commodities shall seek payment according to the
            purchase contract with CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13263'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1499:-:1499.7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1499.7
      </num>
      <head>
        Transportation of goods.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1499' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              1499.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Transportation of goods.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Shipments of donated commodities are subject to the requirements of
            
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='46' sect='55305' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/46/55305.html'>
                46 U.S.C. 55305
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='46' sect='55314' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/46/55314.html'>
                55314
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , regarding carriage on U.S.-flag vessels.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Transportation of donated commodities and other goods such as bags
            that may be provided by CCC under FFPr will be acquired under a
            specific agreement in the manner determined by FAS. Such
            transportation will be acquired by:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC in accordance with the Federal Acquisition Regulations (FAR),
            USDA&apos;s procurement regulations set forth in chapter 4 of title
            48 of the Code of Federal Regulations (the AGAR), and directives
            issued by the Director, Office of Procurement and Property
            Management, USDA; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The participant, with reimbursement by CCC, in the manner specified
            in the agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A participant that acquires transportation in accordance with
            paragraph (b)(2) of this section may only use the services of a
            freight forwarder that is licensed by the FMC and that would not
            have a conflict of interest in carrying out the freight forwarder
            duties. To assist FAS in determining whether there is a potential
            conflict of interest, the participant must submit to FAS a
            certification indicating that the freight forwarder:
            <PRTPAGE P='1016' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is not engaged in, and will not engage in, supplying commodities or
            furnishing ocean transportation or ocean transportation-related
            services for commodities provided under any FFPr agreement to which
            the participant is a party; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is not affiliated with the participant and has not made
            arrangements to give or receive any payment, kickback, or illegal
            benefit in connection with its selection as an agent of the
            participant.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A participant that is responsible for transportation under
            paragraph (b)(2) of this section shall declare in the transportation
            contract the point at which the ocean carrier will take custody of
            commodities to be transported.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13264'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1499:-:1499.8
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1499.8
      </num>
      <head>
        Entry and handling of commodities.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1499' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              1499.8
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Entry and handling of commodities.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The participant shall make all necessary arrangements for receiving
            the donated commodities in the targeted country, including obtaining
            appropriate approvals for entry and transit. The participant shall
            store and maintain the donated commodities in good condition from
            the time of delivery at the port of entry or the point of receipt
            from the originating carrier until their distribution, sale or
            barter.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The participant shall, as provided in the agreement, arrange for
            transporting, storing, and distributing the donated commodities from
            the designated point and time where title to the commodities passes
            to the participant by contracting directly with suppliers of
            services, as set forth in the agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a participant arranges for the packaging or repackaging of
            donated commodities that are to be distributed, the participant
            shall ensure that the packaging:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is plainly labeled in the language of the targeted country;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Contains the name of the donated commodities;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Includes a statement indicating that the donated commodities are
            furnished by the people of the United States of America; and,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Includes a statement indicating that the donated commodities shall
            not be sold, exchanged or bartered.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a participant arranges for the reprocessing and repackaging of
            donated commodities that are to be distributed, the participant
            shall ensure that the packaging:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is plainly labeled in the language of the targeted country;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Contains the name of the reprocessed product;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Includes a statement indicating that the reprocessed product was
            made with commodities furnished by the people of the United States
            of America; and,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Includes a statement indicating that the reprocessed product shall
            not be sold, exchanged or bartered.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a participant distributes donated commodities that are not
            packaged, the participant shall, to the extent practicable, display:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Banners, posters or other media informing the public of the name
            and source of the donated commodities; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A statement that the donated commodities may not be sold,
            exchanged, or bartered.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A participant shall arrange with the government of the targeted
            country that all donated commodities to be distributed will be
            imported and distributed free from all customs, duties, tolls, and
            taxes. A participant is encouraged to make similar arrangements,
            where possible, with the government of the country where donated
            commodities to be sold or bartered are delivered.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13265'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1499:-:1499.9
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1499.9
      </num>
      <head>
        Damage to or loss of commodities.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1499' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
              1499.9
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Damage to or loss of commodities.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FAS will be responsible for the donated commodities prior to the
            transfer of title to the commodities to the participant. The
            participant will be responsible for the donated commodities
            following the transfer of title to the commodities to the
            participant. The title will transfer as specified in the agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A participant shall inform FAS, in the manner and within the time
            period set forth in the agreement, of any damage to or loss of the
            donated commodities that occurs following the transfer of title to
            the commodities to the participant. The participant shall take all
            steps necessary to protect its interests and the interests of CCC
            with 
            <PRTPAGE P='1017' />
            respect to any damage to or loss of the donated commodities that
            occurs after title has been transferred to the participant. The
            agreement will specify whether the participant is responsible for
            obtaining a survey in the event that the donated commodities are
            damaged or lost following the transfer of title to the commodities
            to the participant.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the donated commodities are damaged or lost during the time that
            they are in the care of the carrier:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             And either FAS or the participant engages the services of an
            independent cargo surveyor, the surveyor will provide to FAS and the
            participant any report, narrative chronology or other commentary
            that it prepares;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FAS and the participant will provide to each other the names and
            addresses of any individuals known to be present at the time of
            discharge or during the survey who can verify the quantity of
            damaged or lost commodities;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             And the participant engages the services of the surveyor, CCC will
            reimburse the participant for the reasonable costs, as determined by
            FAS, of the survey, unless:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The participant was required by the agreement to pay for the
            survey;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The survey was a delivery survey and the surveyor did not also
            prepare a discharge survey; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The survey was not conducted contemporaneously with the discharge
            of the vessel, unless FAS determines that such action was justified
            under the circumstances;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any survey obtained by the participant shall, to the extent
            practicable, be conducted jointly by the surveyor, the participant,
            and the carrier, and the survey report shall be signed by all
            parties;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             And the damage or loss occurred with respect to a bulk grain
            shipment, if the agreement provides that the participant is
            responsible for survey and outturn reports, the participant shall
            engage the services of an independent cargo surveyor to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_5_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Observe the discharge of the cargo;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_5_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Report on discharging methods, including scale type, calibrations
            and any other factor that may affect the accuracy of scale weights,
            and, if scales are not used, state the reason therefor and describe
            the actual method used to determine weight;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_5_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Estimate the quantity of cargo, if any, lost during discharge
            through carrier negligence;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_5_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Advise on the quality of sweepings;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_5_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Obtain copies of port or vessel records, if possible, showing the
            quantity discharged; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_5_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notify the participant immediately if the surveyor has reason to
            believe that the correct quantity was not discharged or if
            additional services are necessary to protect the cargo; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             And the damage or loss occurred with respect to a container
            shipment, if the agreement provides that the participant is
            responsible for survey and outturn reports, the participant shall
            engage the services of an independent cargo surveyor to list the
            container numbers and seal numbers shown on the containers, indicate
            whether the seals were intact at the time the containers were
            opened, and note whether the containers were in any way damaged.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the participant has title to the donated commodities, and the
            value of any damaged donated commodities is in excess of $1,000, the
            participant shall immediately arrange for an inspection by a public
            health official or other competent authority approved by FAS and
            provide to FAS a certification by such public health official or
            other competent authority regarding the exact quantity and condition
            of the damaged commodities. The value of damaged donated commodities
            shall be determined on the basis of the commodity acquisition,
            transportation, and related costs incurred by CCC with respect to
            such commodities. The participant shall inform FAS of the results of
            the inspection and indicate whether the damaged commodities are:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Fit for the use authorized in the agreement and, if so, whether
            there has been a diminution in quality; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Unfit for the use authorized in the agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the participant has title to the donated commodities, the
            participant shall arrange for the recovery of 
            <PRTPAGE P='1018' />
            that portion of the donated commodities designated as suitable for
            the use authorized in the agreement. The participant shall dispose
            of donated commodities that are unfit for such use in the following
            order of priority:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Sale for the most appropriate use, 
            <E T='03'>
              i.e.
            </E>
            , animal feed, fertilizer, industrial use, or another use approved
            by FAS, at the highest obtainable price;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Donation to a governmental or charitable organization for use as
            animal feed or for other non-food use; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Destruction of the commodities if they are unfit for any use, in
            such manner as to prevent their use for any purpose.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The participant shall arrange for all U.S. Government markings to
            be obliterated or removed before the donated commodities are
            transferred by sale or donation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A participant may retain any proceeds generated by the disposal of
            the donated commodities in accordance with paragraph (e)(1) of this
            section and shall use the proceeds for expenses related to the
            disposal of the donated commodities and for activities specified in
            the agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The participant shall notify FAS immediately and provide detailed
            information about the actions taken in accordance with paragraph
            (e)(1) of this section, including the quantities, values, and
            dispositions of commodities determined to be unfit.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13266'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1499:-:1499.10
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1499.10
      </num>
      <head>
        Claims for damage to or loss of commodities.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1499' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
              1499.10
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Claims for damage to or loss of commodities.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FAS will be responsible for claims arising out of damage to or loss
            of a quantity of the donated commodities prior to the transfer of
            title to the commodities to the participant.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the participant has title to the donated commodities, and the
            value of the damaged or lost donated commodities is estimated to be
            $20,000 or greater, the participant will be responsible for:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Initiating a claim arising out of such damage or loss, including
            actions relating to collections pursuant to commercial insurance
            contracts; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notifying FAS immediately and providing detailed information about
            the circumstances surrounding such damage or loss, the quantity of
            damaged or lost donated commodities, and the value of the damage or
            loss.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the participant has title to the donated commodities, and the
            value of the damaged or lost donated commodities is estimated to be
            less than $20,000, the participant will be responsible for providing
            detailed information about the damage or loss in the next report
            required to be filed under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1499' sect='13' psec='#c_1' tq='N'>
                1499.13(c)(1) or (2)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and shall not be required to initiate a claim collection action.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The value of a claim for lost donated commodities shall be
            determined on the basis of the commodity acquisition,
            transportation, and related costs incurred by CCC with respect to
            such commodities.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The value of a claim for damaged donated commodities shall be
            determined on the basis of the commodity acquisition,
            transportation, and related costs incurred by CCC with respect to
            such commodities, less any funds generated if such commodities are
            sold in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1499' sect='9' psec='#e_1' tq='N'>
                1499.9(e)(1)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If FAS determines that a participant is not exercising due
            diligence in the pursuit of a claim, FAS may require the participant
            to assign its rights to pursue the claim to FAS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The participant may retain any funds obtained as a result of a
            claims collection action initiated by it in accordance with this
            section, or recovered pursuant to any insurance policy or other
            similar form of indemnification, but such funds shall only be
            expended for purposes approved in advance by FAS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FAS will retain any funds obtained as a result of a claims
            collection action initiated by it under this section; provided,
            however, that if the participant paid for the freight or a portion
            thereof, FAS will use a portion of such funds to reimburse the
            participant for such expense on a prorated basis.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13267'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1499:-:1499.11
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1499.11
      </num>
      <head>
        Use of commodities and sale proceeds.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1499' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
              1499.11
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Use of commodities and sale proceeds.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A participant must use the donated commodities in accordance with
            the agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A participant shall not permit the distribution, handling, or
            allocation of 
            <PRTPAGE P='1019' />
            donated commodities on the basis of political affiliation,
            geographic location, or the ethnic, tribal or religious identity or
            affiliation of the potential consumers or beneficiaries.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A participant shall not permit the distribution, handling, or
            allocation of donated commodities by the military forces or any
            government or insurgent group without the specific authorization of
            FAS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A participant may sell or barter donated commodities only if such
            sale or barter is provided for in the agreement or the participant
            is disposing of damaged commodities as specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1499' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
                1499.9
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . The participant shall sell the donated commodities at a reasonable
            market price in the economy where the sale occurs. The participant
            shall use any sale proceeds, income, or goods or services derived
            from the sale or barter of the donated commodities only as provided
            in the agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The participant shall deposit all sale proceeds and income into a
            separate, interest-bearing account unless the exceptions in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='3019' sect='22' psec='#k' tq='N'>
                3019.22(k)
              </subref>
               of this title
            </aref>
             apply, the account is in a country where the laws or customs
            prohibit the payment of interest, or FAS determines that this
            requirement would constitute an undue burden.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A participant may use sale proceeds or income to purchase real or
            personal property only if local law permits the participant to
            retain title to such property. However, the participant shall not
            use sale proceeds or income to pay for the acquisition, development,
            construction, alteration or upgrade of real property that is:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Owned or managed by a church or other organization engaged
            exclusively in religious pursuits; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Used in whole or in part for sectarian purposes, except that a
            participant may use sale proceeds or income to pay for repairs to or
            rehabilitation of a structure located on such real property to the
            extent necessary to avoid spoilage or loss of donated commodities,
            but only if such structure is not used in whole or in part for any
            religious or sectarian purposes while the donated commodities are
            stored in it. If such use is not specifically provided for in the
            agreement, such use may only occur after receipt of written approval
            from FAS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A participant shall endeavor to comply with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='3019' sect='41' psec='' tq='N'>
                3019.41
              </subref>
            </aref>
             through 3019.43 of this title when procuring goods and services and
            when engaging in construction work to implement the agreement. The
            participant shall also establish procedures to prevent fraud. As
            provided for in the agreement, the participant shall enter into a
            written contract with each provider of goods, services or
            construction work that requires the provider to maintain adequate
            records to account for all donated commodities or funds or both
            provided to the provider by the participant and to submit periodic
            reports to the participant. The participant shall submit a copy of
            the signed contracts to FAS.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13268'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1499:-:1499.12
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1499.12
      </num>
      <head>
        Subrecipients.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1499' sect='12' psec='' tq='N'>
              1499.12
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Subrecipients.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If provided for in the agreement, a participant may utilize the
            services of a subrecipient to implement activities under this
            agreement. The participant shall enter into a written subagreement
            with the subrecipient, and provide a copy of such subagreement to
            FAS, in the manner set forth in the agreement, prior to the transfer
            of any donated commodities, sale proceeds, income or CCC-provided
            funds to the subrecipient. Such written subagreement shall require
            the subrecipient to pay to the participant the value of any donated
            commodities, sale proceeds, income, or CCC-provided cash funds that
            are not used in accordance with the subagreement or are lost,
            damaged, or misused as a result of the subrecipient&apos;s failure
            to exercise reasonable care.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a participant demonstrates to FAS that it is not feasible to
            enter into a subagreement with a subrecipient, FAS may grant
            approval to proceed without a subagreement; provided, however, that
            the participant must obtain such approval from FAS prior to
            transferring any donated commodities, sale proceeds, income, or
            CCC-provided funds to the subrecipient.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The participant shall monitor the actions of a subrecipient as
            necessary to ensure that donated commodities or funds provided to
            the subrecipient are 
            <PRTPAGE P='1020' />
            used for authorized purposes in compliance with applicable laws and
            regulations and the agreement and that performance goals are
            achieved. The participant shall provide in the subagreement that the
            subrecipient must comply with applicable provisions of the
            regulations set forth in Chapter XXX of this title.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13269'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1499:-:1499.13
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1499.13
      </num>
      <head>
        Recordkeeping and reporting requirements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1499' sect='13' psec='' tq='N'>
              1499.13
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Recordkeeping and reporting requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A program participant shall retain records and permit access to
            records in accordance with the requirements of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='3019' sect='53' psec='' tq='N'>
                3019.53
              </subref>
               of this title
            </aref>
            . The date of submission of the final expenditure report, as
            referenced in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='3019' sect='53' psec='#b' tq='N'>
                3019.53(b)
              </subref>
               of this title
            </aref>
            , shall be the final date of submission of the forms required by
            paragraphs (c)(1) and (2) of this section as prescribed by FAS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A participant shall, within 30 days after export of all or a
            portion of the donated commodities, submit evidence of such export
            to FAS, in the manner set forth in the agreement. The evidence may
            be submitted through an electronic media approved by FAS or by
            providing the carrier&apos;s on board bill of lading. The evidence
            of export must show the kind and quantity of commodities exported,
            the date of export, and the country where commodities were
            delivered.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A participant shall submit to FAS information, using a form as
            prescribed by FAS, covering the receipt, handling and disposition of
            the donated commodities. Such report shall be submitted to FAS, by
            the dates and for the reporting periods specified in the agreement,
            until all of the donated commodities have been distributed, sold or
            bartered and such disposition has been reported to FAS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the agreement authorizes the sale or barter of donated
            commodities, the participant shall submit to FAS information, using
            a form as prescribed by FAS, covering the receipt and use of sale
            proceeds and income, and, in the case of bartered commodities,
            covering the services and goods derived from the barter of donated
            commodities. Such reports shall be submitted to FAS, by the dates
            and for the reporting periods specified in the agreement, until all
            of the sale proceeds and income have been disbursed and reported to
            FAS. When reporting financial information, the participant shall
            include the amounts in U.S. dollars and the exchange rate.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The participant shall report, in the manner specified in the
            agreement, its progress, measured against established baselines,
            towards achieving the objectives of the activities under the
            agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The participant shall retain copies of and make available to FAS
            all barter receipts, contracts or other documents related to the
            barter of the donated commodities and the services or goods derived
            from such barter, for a minimum of two years after the agreement has
            been closed out.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The participant shall provide to FAS additional information or
            reports relating to the agreement if requested by FAS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A participant shall submit to FAS, in the manner specified in the
            agreement, an annual audit in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='3019' sect='26' psec='' tq='N'>
                3019.26
              </subref>
               of this title
            </aref>
            . If FAS requires an annual financial audit with respect to a
            particular agreement, and CCC provides funds for this purpose, the
            participant shall arrange for such audit and submit it to FAS, in
            the manner specified in the agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A participant shall, as provided in the agreement, submit to FAS
            interim and final evaluations of the implementation of the
            agreement. Unless otherwise provided in the agreement, the
            evaluations shall be submitted at the mid-point and end-point of the
            implementation period. The participant shall arrange for the
            evaluations to be conducted by an independent third party that:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is financially and legally separate from the participant&apos;s
            organization;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Has staff with demonstrated knowledge, analytical capability,
            language skills and experience in conducting evaluations of
            development programs involving agriculture, education, and
            nutrition;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Uses acceptable analytical frameworks such as comparison with
            non-project areas, surveys, involvement of stakeholders in the
            evaluation, and statistical analyses;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Uses local consultants, as appropriate, to conduct portions of the
            evaluation; and,
            <PRTPAGE P='1021' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_1_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provides a detailed outline of the evaluation, major tasks, and
            specific schedules prior to initiating the evaluation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Receipt by FAS of the evaluations referred to in paragraph (e)(1)
            of this section is a condition for the participant to retain any
            funds provided by CCC to carry out the evaluations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A participant shall submit to FAS the financial reports and
            information outlined in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='3019' sect='52' psec='' tq='N'>
                3019.52
              </subref>
               of this title
            </aref>
            . The agreement will specify the acceptable forms and time
            requirements for submission.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13270'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1499:-:1499.14
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1499.14
      </num>
      <head>
        Noncompliance with an agreement.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1499' sect='14' psec='' tq='N'>
              1499.14
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Noncompliance with an agreement.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          If a participant fails to comply with a term of an agreement, FAS may
          take one or more of the enforcement actions set forth in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3019' sect='62' psec='' tq='N'>
              3019.62
            </subref>
             of this title
          </aref>
           and, if appropriate, initiate a claim against the participant. FAS
          may also initiate a claim against a participant if the donated
          commodities are damaged or lost or the sale proceeds, income, or
          CCC-provided funds are lost due to an action or omission of the
          participant.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13271'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1499:-:1499.15
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1499.15
      </num>
      <head>
        Suspension, termination, and closeout of agreements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1499' sect='15' psec='' tq='N'>
              1499.15
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Suspension, termination, and closeout of agreements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An agreement may be suspended or terminated by CCC if it determines
            that:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The continuation of the assistance provided under the agreement is
            no longer necessary or desirable; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Storage facilities are inadequate to prevent spoilage or waste, or
            distribution of the donated commodities will result in substantial
            disincentive to, or interference with, domestic production or
            marketing in the targeted country.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An agreement may be terminated in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='3019' sect='61' psec='' tq='N'>
                3019.61
              </subref>
               of this title
            </aref>
            . If an agreement is terminated, the participant shall:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be responsible for the safety of any undistributed donated
            commodities and dispose of such commodities only as agreed to by
            FAS; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Follow the closeout procedures in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='3019' sect='71' psec='' tq='N'>
                3019.71
              </subref>
            </aref>
             through 3019.73 of this title.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An agreement will be considered completed when CCC and the
            participant have fulfilled their responsibilities under the
            agreement or the agreement has been terminated. The procedures in
            sections 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='3019' sect='71' psec='' tq='N'>
                3019.71
              </subref>
            </aref>
             through 3019.73 of this title will apply to the closeout of a
            completed agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13272'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1499:-:1499.16
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1499.16
      </num>
      <head>
        Appeals.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1499' sect='16' psec='' tq='N'>
              1499.16
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Appeals.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          A participant may appeal a determination arising under this part to
          FAS. Such appeal will be in writing and submitted to the FAS official
          and in the manner set forth in the agreement. The participant will be
          given an opportunity to have a hearing before a final decision is made
          regarding its appeal.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13273'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1499:-:1499.17
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1499.17
      </num>
      <head>
        Paperwork Reduction Act.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1499' sect='17' psec='' tq='N'>
              1499.17
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Paperwork Reduction Act.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The information collection requirements contained in this regulation
          have been approved by the Office of Management and Budget under
          provisions of 44 U.S.C. Chapter 35 and have been assigned OMB Number
          0551-0035.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>