<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol5'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:III:-:318
    </extid>
    <num>
      318
    </num>
    <head>
      STATE OF HAWAII AND TERRITORIES QUARANTINE NOTICES
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='7701-777' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/7701-777.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 7701-777
            </subref>
          </aref>
          2 and 7781-7786; 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR 
            <subref title='7' part='2' sect='22' psec='' tq='N'>
              2.22
            </subref>
            , 
            <subref title='7' part='2' sect='80' psec='' tq='N'>
              2.80
            </subref>
            , and 
            <subref title='7' part='371' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              371.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            24 FR 10777
          </aref>
          , Dec. 29, 1959, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='5303'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:III:-:318:lii80:318.13-1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        318.13-1
      </num>
      <head>
        Notice of quarantine.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          74 FR 2775
        </aref>
        , Jan 16, 2009, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          74 FR 15641
        </aref>
        , Apr. 7, 2009]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='318' sect='13-1' psec='' tq='N'>
              318.13-1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Notice of quarantine.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Under the authority of 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 412 of
            </aref>
             the Plant Protection Act, the Secretary of Agriculture may prohibit
            or restrict the movement in interstate commerce of any plant or
            plant product if the Secretary determines that the prohibition or
            restriction is necessary to prevent the introduction into the United
            States or the dissemination within the United States of a plant pest
            or noxious weed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Secretary has determined that it is necessary to prohibit the
            interstate movement of cut flowers and fruits and vegetables and
            plants and portions of plants from Hawaii, Puerto Rico, the U.S.
            Virgin Islands, Guam, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana
            Islands except as provided in this subpart or as provided in
            “Subpart—Territorial Cotton, Cottonseed, and Cottonseed Products and
            “Subpart—Sand, Soil, or Earth, with Plants from Territories and
            Districts”” in this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            74 FR 2775
          </aref>
          , Jan 16, 2009, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            74 FR 15641
          </aref>
          , Apr. 7, 2009]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5304'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:III:-:318:lii80:318.13-2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        318.13-2
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='318' sect='13-2' psec='' tq='N'>
              318.13-2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Administrator.
          </E>
           The Administrator of the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service
          (APHIS), U.S. Department of Agriculture, or any other employee of
          APHIS to whom authority has been delegated to act in the
          Administrator&apos;s stead.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service.
          </E>
           The Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service (APHIS) of the U.S.
          Department of Agriculture.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Approved growing media.
          </E>
           Agar or other translucent tissue culture media, buckwheat hulls,
          clean ocean sand, excelsior, exfoliated vermiculite, ground cork,
          ground peat, ground rubber, paper, polymer stabilized cellulose,
          quarry gravel, sawdust, wood shavings, cork shavings, sphagnum moss,
          tree fern slab (approved only for orchids), and vegetable fiber (free
          of pulp) including coconut and osmunda, but excluding cotton and
          sugarcane.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Certification (certified).
          </E>
           A type of authorization, issued by an inspector, evidencing freedom
          from infestation, to allow the movement of certain regulated articles
          in accordance with the regulations in this subpart. “Certified” shall
          be construed accordingly.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Commercial consignment.
          </E>
           A lot of fruits or vegetables that an inspector identifies as having
          been produced for sale or distribution in mass markets. Such
          identification will be based on a variety of indicators, including,
          but not limited to: Quantity of produce, type of packaging,
          identification of grower and packinghouse on the packaging, and
          documents consigning the fruits or vegetables to a wholesaler or
          retailer.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Compliance agreement.
          </E>
           Any agreement to comply with stipulated conditions as prescribed
          under 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='318' sect='13-3' psec='' tq='N'>
              318.13-3
            </subref>
          </aref>
           or 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='318' sect='13-4' psec='' tq='N'>
              318.13-4
            </subref>
          </aref>
           or 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='305' sect='34' psec='' tq='N'>
              305.34
            </subref>
             of this chapter
          </aref>
          , executed by any person to facilitate the interstate movement of
          regulated articles under this subpart.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Consignment.
          </E>
           A quantity of plants, plant products, and/or other articles,
          including fruits or vegetables, being moved from one country to
          another and covered, when required, by a single certificate or limited
          permit (a consignment may be composed of one or more commodities or
          lots).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Continental United States.
          </E>
           The 48 contiguous States, Alaska, and the District of Columbia.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Cut flower.
          </E>
           Any cut blooms, fresh foliage, and dried decorative plant material
          customarily used in the florist trade and not for planting; and being
          the severed portion of a plant, including the inflorescence, and any
          parts of 
          <PRTPAGE P='183' />
          the plant attached thereto, in a fresh state.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Disinfection (disinfect and disinfected).
          </E>
           The application to parts or all of a ship, vessel, other surface
          craft, or aircraft of a treatment that may be designated by the
          inspector as effective against such plant pests as may be present.
          (“Disinfect” and “disinfected” shall be construed accordingly.)
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Fruits and vegetables.
          </E>
           A commodity class for fresh parts of plants intended for consumption
          or processing and not planting.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Inspector.
          </E>
           A State agricultural inspector or any individual authorized by the
          Administrator of APHIS or the Commissioner of Customs and Border
          Protection, Department of Homeland Security, to enforce the
          regulations in this subpart.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Interstate.
          </E>
           From one State into or through any other State; or within the
          District of Columbia, Guam, the Virgin Islands of the United States,
          or any other territory or possession of the United States.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Limited permit.
          </E>
           A document issued by an inspector or a person operating under a
          compliance agreement for the interstate movement of regulated articles
          to a specified destination for:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Consumption, limited utilization or processing, or treatment; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Movement into or through the continental United States in
            conformity with a transit permit.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Lot.
          </E>
           A number of units of a single commodity, identifiable by its
          homogeneity of composition and origin, forming all or part of a
          consignment.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Means of conveyance.
          </E>
           A ship, truck, aircraft, or railcar.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Moved (move and movement).
          </E>
           Shipped, offered for shipment to a common carrier, received for
          transportation or transported by a common carrier, or carried,
          transported, moved, or allowed to be moved, directly or indirectly,
          from Hawaii, Puerto Rico, Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern
          Marina Islands, or the U.S. Virgin Islands into or through the
          continental United States or any other State or territory of the
          United States (or from or into or through other places as specified in
          this subpart). “Move” and “movement” shall be construed accordingly.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Packing materials.
          </E>
           Any plant or plant product, soil, or other substance associated with
          or accompanying any commodity or consignment to serve for filling,
          wrapping, ties, lining, mats, moisture retention, protection, or any
          other auxiliary purpose. The word “packing,” as used in the expression
          “packing materials,” includes the presence of such materials within,
          in contact with, or accompanying a consignment.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Person.
          </E>
           Any individual, partnership, corporation, association, joint venture,
          or other legal entity.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Plant debris.
          </E>
           Detached leaves, twigs, or other portions of plants, or plant litter
          or rubbish as distinguished from approved parts of clean fruits and
          vegetables, or other commercial articles.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Plant pests.
          </E>
           Any living stage of any of the following that can directly or
          indirectly injure, cause damage to, or cause disease in any plant or
          plant product: A protozoan, nonhuman animal, parasitic plant,
          bacterium, fungus, virus or viroid, infectious agent or other
          pathogen, or any article similar to or allied with any of those
          articles.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Plant Protection and Quarantine (PPQ).
          </E>
           The Plant Protection and Quarantine program of APHIS.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Regulated articles.
          </E>
           Fruits or vegetables in the raw or unprocessed state; cut flowers;
          seeds; and plants or plant products for nonpropagative or propagative
          use.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Sealed (sealable) container.
          </E>
           A completely enclosed container designed for the storage and/or
          transportation of commercial air, sea, rail, or truck cargo, and
          constructed of metal or fiberglass, or other similarly sturdy and
          impenetrable material, providing an enclosure accessed through doors
          that are closed and secured with a lock or seal. Sealed (sealable)
          containers used for sea consignments are distinct and separable from
          the means of conveyance carrying them when arriving in and in transit
          through the continental United States. Sealed (sealable) containers
          used for air consigments are distinct and separable from the means of
          conveyance carrying them before any transloading in the continental
          United States. Sealed (sealable) containers used for air consignments
          after transloading in the continental United 
          <PRTPAGE P='184' />
          States or for overland consignments in the continental United States
          may either be distinct and separable from the means of conveyance
          carrying them, or be the means of conveyance itself.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Soil.
          </E>
           The loose surface material of the earth in which plants grow, in most
          cases consisting of disintegrated rock with an admixture of organic
          material and soluble salts.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State.
          </E>
           Any of the several States of the United States, the Commonwealth of
          the Northern Mariana Islands, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the
          District of Columbia, Guam, the Virgin Islands of the United States,
          or any other territory or possession of the United States.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Transit permit.
          </E>
           A written authorization issued by the Administrator for the movement
          of fruits and vegetables en route to a foreign destination that are
          otherwise prohibited movement by this subpart into the continental
          United States. Transit permits authorize one or more consignments over
          a designated period of time.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Transloading.
          </E>
           The transfer of cargo from one sealable container to another, from
          one means of conveyance to another, or from a sealable container
          directly into a means of conveyance.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            United States.
          </E>
           All of the States.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5305'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:III:-:318:lii80:318.13-3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        318.13-3
      </num>
      <head>
        General requirements for all regulated articles.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          74 FR 2775
        </aref>
        , Jan. 16, 2009, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 4249
        </aref>
        , Jan. 26, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='318' sect='13-3' psec='' tq='N'>
              318.13-3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General requirements for all regulated articles.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          All regulated articles that are allowed movement under this subpart
          must be moved in accordance with the following requirements, except as
          specifically provided otherwise in this subpart.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Freedom from plant debris.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All regulated articles moved under this subpart must be free from
            plant debris.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Certification.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Certification may be issued for the movement of regulated articles
            under the following conditions:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Certification on basis of inspection or nature of lot involved.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Regulated articles may be certified when they have been inspected
            by an inspector and found apparently free from infestation and
            infection, or without such inspection when the inspector determines
            that the lot for consignment is of such a nature that no danger of
            infestation or infection is involved.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Persons intending to move any articles that may be certified must
            contact the local Plant Protection and Quarantine office as far as
            possible in advance of the contemplated date of shipment in order to
            request an inspection.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Persons intending to move any articles that may be certified must
            prepare, handle, and safeguard such articles from infestation or
            reinfestation, and assemble them at such points as the inspector may
            designate, placing them so that inspection may be readily made.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Certification on basis of treatment.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Regulated articles for which treatments are approved under
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='305' tq='N'>
                305 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
             may be certified if such treatments have been applied in accordance
            with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='305' tq='N'>
                305 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and if the articles were handled after such treatment in accordance
            with a compliance agreement executed by the applicant for
            certification or under the supervision of an inspector.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Regulated articles certified after treatment in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='305' tq='N'>
                305 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
             that are taken aboard any ship, vessel, other surface craft, or
            aircraft must be segregated and protected in a manner as required by
            the inspector.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Limited permits.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Limited permits 
            <SU>
              1
            </SU>
            <FTREF />
             may be issued by an inspector for the movement of certain
            noncertified regulated articles to restricted destinations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <FTNT>
          <P>
            <SU>
              1
            </SU>
             Limited permits can be obtained from each State or territory&apos;s
            local Plant Protection and Quarantine office.
          </P>
        </FTNT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Limited permits may be issued by an inspector for the movement of
            regulated articles that would otherwise be prohibited movement under
            this subpart, if the articles are to be moved in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='318' sect='13-6' psec='' tq='N'>
                318.13-6
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except when the regulations specify that an inspector must issue
            the limited permit, limited permits may be issued by a person
            operating under a compliance agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Compliance agreements.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             As a condition for the movement of regulated articles for which a
            compliance agreement is required, the person entering the compliance
            agreement must agree to the following:
            <PRTPAGE P='185' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             That he or she will use any permit or certification issued to him
            or her in accordance with the provisions in the permit, the
            requirements in this subpart, and the compliance agreement;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             That he or she will maintain at his or her establishment such
            safeguards against the establishment and spread of infestation and
            infection and comply with such conditions as to the maintenance of
            identity, handling (including post-treatment handling), and
            interstate movement of regulated articles and the cleaning and
            treatment of means of conveyance and containers used in such
            movement of the articles, as may be required by the inspector in
            each specific case to prevent the spread of infestation or
            infection; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             That he or she will allow inspectors to inspect the establishment
            and its operations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Attachment of limited permit or verification of certification.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as otherwise provided for certain air cargo and
            containerized cargo on ships moved in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='318' sect='13-10' psec='' tq='N'>
                318.13-10
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , each box, bale, crate, or other container of regulated articles
            moved under certification or limited permit shall have the limited
            permit attached to the outside of the container or bear a U.S.
            Department of Agriculture stamp or inspection sticker verifying that
            the consignment has been certified in accordance with paragraph (b)
            of this section: 
            <E T='03'>
              Provided
            </E>
            , That if a limited permit or certification is issued for a
            consignment of more than one container or for bulk products,
            certification shall be stamped on or the limited permit shall be
            attached to the accompanying waybill, manifest, or bill of lading.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Withdrawal of certification, transit permits, limited permits, or
              compliance agreements.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any certification, transit permit, limited permit, or compliance
            agreement which has been issued or authorized may be withdrawn by an
            inspector orally or in writing, if such inspector determines that
            the holder thereof has not complied with all conditions under the
            regulations for the use of such document. If the cancellation is
            oral, the decision and the reasons for the withdrawal shall be
            confirmed in writing as promptly as circumstances allow. Any person
            whose certification, transit permit, limited permit, or compliance
            agreement has been withdrawn may appeal the decision in writing to
            the Administrator within 10 days after receiving the written
            notification of the withdrawal. The appeal shall state all of the
            facts and reasons upon which the person relies to show that the
            certification, transit permit, limited permit, or compliance
            agreement was wrongfully withdrawn. The Administrator shall grant or
            deny the appeal, in writing, stating the reasons for such decision,
            as promptly as circumstances allow. If there is a conflict as to any
            material fact, a hearing shall be held to resolve such conflict.
            Rules of practice concerning such a hearing will be adopted by the
            Administrator.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Container marking and identity.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as provided in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='318' sect='13-6' psec='#c' tq='N'>
                318.13-6(c)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , consignments of regulated articles moved in accordance with this
            subpart must have the following information clearly marked on each
            container or on the waybill, manifest, or bill of lading
            accompanying the articles: Nature and quantity of contents; name and
            address of shipper, owner, or person shipping or forwarding the
            articles; name and address of consignee; shipper&apos;s identifying
            mark and number; and the certification stamp or number of the
            limited permit authorizing movement, if one was issued.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Refusal of movement.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An inspector may refuse to allow the interstate movement of a
            regulated article if the inspector finds that the regulated article
            is prohibited, is not accompanied by required documentation, is so
            infested with a plant pest or noxious weed that, in the judgment of
            the inspector, it cannot be cleaned or treated, or contains soil or
            other prohibited contaminants.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Costs and charges.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Services of the inspector during regularly assigned hours of duty
            at the usual places of duty shall be furnished without cost to the
            one requesting such services. APHIS will not assume responsibility
            for any costs or charges, other than those indicated in this
            section, in connection with the inspection, treatment, conditioning,
            storage, forwarding, or any other operation of any character 
            <PRTPAGE P='186' />
            incidental to the physical movement of regulated articles or plant
            pests.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
            <head>
              APHIS not responsible for damage.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             APHIS assumes no responsibility for any damage to regulated
            articles that results from the application of treatment or other
            measures required under this subpart (or under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='305' tq='N'>
                305 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) to protect against the dissemination of plant pests within the
            United States.
          </text>
        </P>
        <APPRO>
          (Approved by the Office of Management and Budget under control number
          0579-0346)
        </APPRO>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            74 FR 2775
          </aref>
          , Jan. 16, 2009, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 4249
          </aref>
          , Jan. 26, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5306'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:III:-:318:lii80:318.13-4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        318.13-4
      </num>
      <head>
        Approval of certain fruits and vegetables for interstate movement.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='318' sect='13-4' psec='' tq='N'>
              318.13-4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Approval of certain fruits and vegetables for interstate movement.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Determination by the Administrator.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Administrator has determined that the application of one or
            more of the designated phytosanitary measures cited in paragraph (b)
            of this section to certain fruits and vegetables mitigates the risk
            posed by those commodities, and that such articles may be moved
            interstate subject to one or more of those measures, as provided in
            paragraphs (c) and (d) of this section. The name and origin of all
            fruits and vegetables authorized movement under this section, as
            well as the applicable requirements for their movement, may be found
            on the Internet at 
            <E T='03'>
              http://www.aphis.usda.gov/import_export/plants/manuals/ports/downloads/hawaii.pdf
            </E>
             or 
            <E T='03'>
              http://www.aphis.usda.gov/import_export/plants/manuals/ports/downloads/puerto_rico.pdf
            </E>
            . Fruits or vegetables that require phytosanitary measures other
            than one or more of the designated phytosanitary measures cited in
            paragraph (b) of this section may only be moved in accordance with
            applicable requirements in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='318' sect='13-3' psec='' tq='N'>
                318.13-3
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and regulated article-specific requirements contained elsewhere in
            this subpart.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Designated phytosanitary measures.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The fruits and vegetables are inspected in the State of origin or
            in the first State of arrival.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The fruits and vegetables originated from a pest-free area in the
            State of origin and the grower from which the fruit or vegetable
            originated has entered into a compliance agreement with the
            Administrator.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The fruits and vegetables are treated in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='305' tq='N'>
                305 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and the treatment is certified by an inspector.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The fruits and vegetables articles are inspected and certified in
            the State of origin by an inspector and have been found free of one
            or more specific quarantine pests identified by risk analysis as
            likely to follow the pathway.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The fruits and vegetables are moved as commercial consignments
            only.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The fruits and vegetables may be distributed only within a defined
            area and the boxes or containers in which the fruit or vegetables
            are distributed must be marked to indicate the applicable
            distribution restrictions.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Fruits and vegetables authorized for interstate movement under
              this section—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Previously approved fruits and vegetables.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Fruits and vegetables that were authorized movement under this
            subpart either administratively or by specific regulation as of
            February 17, 2009 and that were subject only to one or more of the
            designated phytosanitary measures cited in paragraph (b) of this
            section and the general requirements of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='318' sect='13-3' psec='' tq='N'>
                318.13-3
              </subref>
            </aref>
             may continue to be moved interstate under the same requirements
            that applied before February 17, 2009, except as provided in
            paragraph (d) of this section. The interstate movement conditions
            for those fruits and vegetables that were authorized movement under
            this subpart subject to additional measures beyond the designated
            measures in paragraph (b) of this section can be found in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='318' sect='13-16' psec='' tq='N'>
                318.13-16
              </subref>
            </aref>
             or one of the commodity-specific sections in this subpart.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Other fruits and vegetables.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Fruits and vegetables that do not meet the criteria in paragraph
            (c)(1) of this section may be authorized movement under this section
            as follows:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Pest risk analysis.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The risk posed by the particular article from a specified State has
            been evaluated and publicly communicated as follows:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_i_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Availability of pest risk analysis.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             APHIS published in the 
            <E T='04'>
              Federal Register,
            </E>
             for a public comment period of 60 days, a notice announcing the
            availability of a pest risk analysis that evaluated the risks
            associated with the 
            <PRTPAGE P='187' />
            movement of the particular fruit or vegetable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_i_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Determination of risk; factors considered.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Administrator determined, and announced in the notice referred
            to in the previous paragraph, that, based on the information
            available, the application of one or more of the designated
            phytosanitary measures described in paragraph (b) of this section is
            sufficient to mitigate the risk that plant pests or noxious weeds
            could be introduced into or disseminated elsewhere within the United
            States by the fruit or vegetable. In order for the Administrator to
            make the determination described in this paragraph, he or she must
            conclude based on the information presented in the risk analysis for
            the fruit or vegetable that the risk posed by each quarantine pest
            associated with the fruit or vegetable in the State of origin is
            mitigated by one or more of the following factors:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          (
          <E T='03'>
            1
          </E>
          ) 
          <E T='03'>
            Inspection.
          </E>
           A quarantine pest is associated with the fruit or vegetable in the
          State of origin, but the pest can be easily detected via inspection in
          the State of origin or in the State of first arrival;
        </P>
        <P>
          (
          <E T='03'>
            2
          </E>
          ) 
          <E T='03'>
            Pest freedom.
          </E>
           No quarantine pests are known to be associated with the fruit or
          vegetable in the State of origin, or a quarantine pest is associated
          with the fruit or vegetable in the State of origin but the fruit or
          vegetable originates from an area that meets the requirements of 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='318' sect='13-5' psec='' tq='N'>
              318.13-5
            </subref>
          </aref>
           for pest freedom;
        </P>
        <P>
          (
          <E T='03'>
            3
          </E>
          ) 
          <E T='03'>
            Effectiveness of treatment.
          </E>
           A quarantine pest is associated with the fruit or vegetable in the
          State of origin, but the risk posed by the pest can be reduced by
          applying an approved post-harvest treatment to the fruit or vegetable;
        </P>
        <P>
          (
          <E T='03'>
            4
          </E>
          ) 
          <E T='03'>
            Predeparture inspection.
          </E>
           A quarantine pest is associated with the fruit or vegetable in the
          State of origin, but the fruit or vegetable is subject to predeparture
          inspection;
        </P>
        <P>
          (
          <E T='03'>
            5
          </E>
          ) 
          <E T='03'>
            Commercial consignments.
          </E>
           A quarantine pest is associated with the fruit or vegetable in the
          State of origin, but the risk posed by the pest can be reduced by
          commercial practices.
        </P>
        <P>
          (
          <E T='03'>
            6
          </E>
          ) 
          <E T='03'>
            Limited distribution.
          </E>
           A quarantine pest is associated with the fruit or vegetable in the
          State of origin, but the risk posed by the pest can be reduced by
          limiting distribution of the fruit or vegetable and labeling boxes
          containing the fruit or vegetable with those distribution
          instructions.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Administrator&apos;s decision.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Administrator will announce his or her decision in a subsequent
            
            <E T='04'>
              Federal Register
            </E>
             notice. If appropriate, APHIS would begin allowing the interstate
            movement of the fruits or vegetables subject to requirements
            specified in the notice because:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_ii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No comments were received on the pest risk analysis;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_ii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The comments on the pest risk analysis revealed that no changes to
            the pest risk analysis were necessary; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_ii_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Changes to the pest risk analysis were made in response to public
            comments, but the changes did not affect the overall conclusions of
            the analysis and the Administrator&apos;s determination of risk.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Amendment of interstate movement requirements.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If, after February 17, 2009, the Administrator determines that one
            or more of the designated phytosanitary measures is not sufficient
            to mitigate the risk posed by any fruit or vegetable authorized
            interstate movement under this section, APHIS will prohibit or
            further restrict the interstate movement of the fruit or vegetable
            pending resolution of the situation. If APHIS concludes that a
            permanent change to the interstate movement requirements of a
            particular fruit or vegetable is necessary, APHIS will also publish
            a notice in the 
            <E T='04'>
              Federal Register
            </E>
             advising the public of its finding. The notice will specify the
            amended interstate movement requirements, provide an effective date
            for the change, and invite public comment on the subject.
          </text>
        </P>
        <APPRO>
          (Approved by the Office of Management and Budget under control number
          0579-0346)
        </APPRO>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5307'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:III:-:318:lii80:318.13-5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        318.13-5
      </num>
      <head>
        Pest-free areas.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='318' sect='13-5' psec='' tq='N'>
              318.13-5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Pest-free areas.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Certain fruits or vegetables may be moved interstate provided that the
          fruits or vegetables originate from an area that is free of a specific
          pest or pests. In some cases, fruits or vegetables may only be moved
          interstate if the area of origin is free of all plant 
          <PRTPAGE P='188' />
          pests that attack the fruits or vegetables. In other cases, fruits or
          vegetables may be moved interstate if the area of origin is free of
          one or more plant pests that attack the fruit or vegetable and the
          risk posed by the remaining plant pests that attack the fruit or
          vegetable is mitigated by other specific phytosanitary measures
          contained in the regulations in this subpart.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Application of standards for pest-free areas.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             APHIS will make a determination of an area&apos;s pest-free status
            based on information provided by the State. The information used to
            make this determination will include trapping and surveillance data,
            survey protocols, and protocols for actions to be performed upon
            detection of a pest.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Survey protocols.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             APHIS must approve the survey protocol used to determine and
            maintain pest-free status, as well as protocols for actions to be
            performed upon detection of a pest. Pest-free areas are subject to
            audit by APHIS to verify their status.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Determination of pest freedom.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For an area to be considered free of a specified pest for the
            purposes of this subpart, the Administrator must determine, and
            announce in a notice published in the 
            <E T='04'>
              Federal Register
            </E>
             for a public comment period of 60 days, that the area meets the
            criteria of paragraphs (a) and (b) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Administrator will announce his or her decision in a subsequent
            
            <E T='04'>
              Federal Register
            </E>
             notice. If appropriate, APHIS will allow movement of the regulated
            article from a pest-free area because:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No comments were received on the notice or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The comments on the notice did not affect the overall conclusions
            of the notice and the Administrator&apos;s determination of risk.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Decertification of pest-free areas; reinstatement.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a pest is detected in an area that is designated as free of that
            pest, APHIS will publish in the 
            <E T='04'>
              Federal Register
            </E>
             a notice announcing that the pest-free status of the area in
            question has been withdrawn and that interstate movement of host
            crops for the pest in question is subject to application of an
            approved treatment for the pest. If a treatment for the pest is not
            available, interstate movement of the host crops would be
            prohibited. In order for a decertified pest-free area to be
            reinstated, it would have to meet the criteria of paragraphs (a)
            through (c) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General requirements for the interstate movement of regulated
              articles from pest-free areas—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Labeling.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each box of fruits or vegetables that is moved interstate from a
            pest-free area under this subpart must be clearly labeled with:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The name of the orchard or grove of origin, or the name of the
            grower; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The name of the municipality and State or territory in which the
            fruits or vegetables were produced; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The type and amount of fruits or vegetables the box contains.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Compliance agreement.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Persons wishing to move fruits or vegetables from a pest-free area
            in Hawaii, Puerto Rico, Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern
            Mariana Islands, or the U.S. Virgin Islands must enter into a
            compliance agreement with APHIS in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='318' sect='13-3' psec='#d' tq='N'>
                318.13-3(d)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Safeguarding.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If fruits or vegetables are moved from a pest-free area into or
            through an area that is not free of that pest, the fruits or
            vegetables must be safeguarded during the time they are present in a
            non-pest-free area by being covered with insect-proof mesh screens
            or plastic tarpaulins, including while in transit to the
            packinghouse and while awaiting packaging. If fruits or vegetables
            are moved through an area that is not free of that pest during
            transit to a port, they must be packed in insect-proof cartons or
            containers or be covered by insect-proof mesh or plastic tarpaulins
            during transit to the port and subsequent movement into or through
            the United States. These safeguards described in this section must
            remain intact until the fruits or vegetables reach their final
            destination.
          </text>
        </P>
        <APPRO>
          (Approved by the Office of Management and Budget under control number
          0579-0346)
        </APPRO>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5308'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:III:-:318:lii80:318.13-6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        318.13-6
      </num>
      <head>
        Transit of fruits and vegetables from Hawaii or the territories into or
        through the continental United States.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='189' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='318' sect='13-6' psec='' tq='N'>
              318.13-6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Transit of fruits and vegetables from Hawaii or the territories into
          or through the continental United States.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Fruits and vegetables from Hawaii, Puerto Rico, Guam, the Commonwealth
          of the Northern Mariana Islands, or the U.S. Virgin Islands that are
          otherwise prohibited interstate movement into the continental United
          States by this subpart may transit the continental United States en
          route to a foreign destination when moved in accordance with this
          section.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Transit permit.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A transit permit is required for the arrival, unloading, and
            movement through the continental United States of fruits and
            vegetables otherwise prohibited by this subpart from being moved
            through the continental United States from Hawaii, Puerto Rico,
            Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, or the U.S.
            Virgin Islands. Application for a transit permit may be made in
            writing or with PPQ Form 586. 
            <SU>
              2
            </SU>
            <FTREF />
             The transit permit application must include the following
            information:
          </text>
        </P>
        <FTNT>
          <P>
            <SU>
              2
            </SU>
             PPQ Form 586 can be obtained from PPQ Permit Services or at 
            <E T='03'>
              http://www.aphis.usda.gov/plant_health/permits/transit.shtml
            </E>
             . Applications for transit permits should be submitted to USDA,
            APHIS, PPQ Permit Services, 4700 River Road Unit 136, Riverdale, MD
            20737 or through e-permits 
            <E T='03'>
              http://www.aphis.usda.gov/permits/learn_epermits.shtml
            </E>
            .
          </P>
        </FTNT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The specific types of fruits and vegetables to be shipped (only
            scientific or English common names are acceptable);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The means of conveyance to be used to transport the fruit or
            vegetable through the continental United States;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The port of arrival in the continental United States, and the
            location of any subsequent stop;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The location of, and the time needed for, any storage in the
            continental United States;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any location in the continental United States where the fruits or
            vegetables are to be transloaded;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The means of conveyance to be used for transporting the fruits or
            vegetables from the port of arrival in the continental United States
            to the port of export;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_vii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The estimated time necessary to accomplish exportation, from
            arrival at the port of arrival in the continental United States to
            exit at the port of export;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_viii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (viii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The port of export; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_ix'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ix)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The name and address of the applicant and, if the applicant&apos;s
            address is not within the territorial limits of the continental
            United States, the name and address in the continental United States
            of an agent whom the applicant names for acceptance of service of
            process.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A transit permit will be issued only if the following conditions
            are met:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             APHIS inspectors are available at the port of arrival, port of
            export, and any locations at which transloading of cargo will take
            place and, in the case of air consignments, at any interim stop in
            the continental United States, as indicated on the application for
            the transit permit;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The application indicates that the proposed movement would comply
            with the provisions in this section applicable to the transit
            permit; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             During the 12 months prior to receipt of the application by APHIS,
            the applicant has not had a transit permit withdrawn under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='318' sect='13-3' psec='#f' tq='N'>
                318.13-3(f)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , unless the transit permit has been reinstated upon appeal.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Limited permit.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Fruits or vegetables shipped from Hawaii, Puerto Rico, Guam, the
            Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, or the U.S. Virgin
            Islands through the continental United States under this section
            must be accompanied by a limited permit, a copy of which must be
            presented to an inspector at the port of arrival and the port of
            export in the continental United States, and at any other location
            in the continental United States where an air consignment is
            authorized to stop or where overland consignments change means of
            conveyance. An inspector will issue a limited permit if the
            following conditions are met:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The inspector determines that the specific type and quantity of the
            fruits or vegetables being shipped are accurately described by
            accompanying documentation, such as the accompanying manifest,
            waybill, and bill of lading. (Only scientific or English common 
            <PRTPAGE P='190' />
            names are acceptable.) The fruits or vegetables shall be assembled
            at whatever point and in whatever manner the inspector designates as
            necessary to comply with the requirements of this section; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The inspector establishes that the consignment of fruits or
            vegetables has been prepared in compliance with the provisions of
            this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Marking requirements.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each of the smallest units, including each of the smallest bags,
            crates, or cartons, containing regulated articles for transit
            through the continental United States under this section must be
            conspicuously marked, prior to the locking and sealing of the
            container in the State of origin, with a printed label that includes
            a description of the specific type and quantity of the fruits or
            vegetables (only scientific or English common names are acceptable),
            the transit permit number under which the regulated articles are to
            be shipped, and, in English, the State in which they were grown and
            the statement “Distribution in the United States is Prohibited.”
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Handling of fruits and vegetables.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Fruits or vegetables shipped through the United States from Hawaii,
            Puerto Rico, Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands,
            or the U.S. Virgin Islands in accordance with this section may not
            be commingled in the same sealed container with fruits or vegetables
            that are intended for entry and distribution in the United States.
            The fruits or vegetables must be kept in sealed containers from the
            time the limited permit required by paragraph (b) of this section is
            issued, until the fruits or vegetables exit the United States,
            except as otherwise provided in the regulations in this section.
            Transloading must be carried out in accordance with the requirements
            of paragraphs (a), (h), and (i) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Area of movement.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The port of arrival, the port of export, ports for air stops, and
            overland movement within the continental United States of fruits or
            vegetables shipped under this section is limited to a corridor that
            includes all States of the continental United States except Alabama,
            Arizona, California, Florida, Georgia, Kentucky, Louisiana,
            Mississippi, Nevada, New Mexico, North Carolina, South Carolina,
            Tennessee, Texas, and Virginia, except that movement is allowed
            through Dallas/Fort Worth, TX, as an authorized stop for air cargo,
            or as a transloading location for consignments that arrive by air
            but that are subsequently transloaded into trucks for overland
            movement from Dallas/Fort Worth, TX, into the designated corridor by
            the shortest route. Movement through the United States must begin
            and end at locations staffed by APHIS inspectors.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Movement of regulated articles.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Transportation through the continental United States shall be by
            the most direct route to the final destination of the consignment in
            the country to which it is exported, as determined by APHIS based on
            commercial shipping routes and timetables and set forth in the
            transit permit. No change in the quantity of the original
            consignment from that described in the limited permit is allowed. No
            remarking is allowed. No diversion or delay of the consignment from
            the itinerary described in the transit permit and limited permit is
            allowed unless authorized by an APHIS inspector upon determination
            by the inspector that the change will not significantly increase the
            risk of plant pests or diseases in the United States, and unless
            each port to which the consignment is diverted is staffed by APHIS
            inspectors.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Notification in case of emergency.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the case of an emergency such as an accident, a mechanical
            breakdown of the means of conveyance, or an unavoidable deviation
            from the prescribed route, the person in charge of the means of
            conveyance must, as soon as practicable, notify the APHIS office at
            the port where the cargo arrived in the United States.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Consignments by sea.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as authorized by this paragraph, consignments arriving in
            the United States by sea from Hawaii, Puerto Rico, Guam, the
            Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, or the U.S. Virgin
            Islands may be transloaded once from a ship to another ship or,
            alternatively, once to a truck or railcar at the port of arrival and
            once from a truck or railcar to a ship at the port of export, and 
            <PRTPAGE P='191' />
            must remain in the original sealed container, except under
            extenuating circumstances and when authorized by an inspector upon
            determination by the inspector that the transloading would not
            significantly increase the risk of the introduction of plant pests
            or diseases into the United States, and provided that APHIS
            inspectors are available to provide supervision. No other
            transloading of the consignment is allowed, except under extenuating
            circumstances (
            <E T='03'>
              e.g.
            </E>
             , equipment breakdown) and when authorized by an inspector upon
            determination by the inspector that the transloading would not
            significantly increase the risk of the introduction of plant pests
            or diseases into the continental United States, and provided that
            APHIS inspectors are available to provide supervision.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Consignments by air.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Consignments arriving in the United States by air from Hawaii,
            Puerto Rico, Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands,
            or the U.S. Virgin Islands may be transloaded only once in the
            United States. Transloading of air consignments must be carried out
            in the presence of an APHIS inspector. Consignments arriving by air
            that are transloaded may be transloaded either into another aircraft
            or into a truck trailer for export by the most direct route to the
            final destination of the consignment through the designated corridor
            set forth in paragraph (e) of this section. This may be done at
            either the port of arrival in the United States or at the second air
            stop within the designated corridor, as authorized in the transit
            permit and as provided in paragraph (i)(2) of this section. No other
            transloading of the consignment is allowed, except under extenuating
            circumstances (
            <E T='03'>
              e.g.
            </E>
            , equipment breakdown) and when authorized by an APHIS inspector
            upon determination by the inspector that the transloading would not
            significantly increase the risk of the introduction of plant pests
            or diseases into the United States, and provided that APHIS
            inspectors are available to provide supervision. Transloading of air
            consignments will be authorized only if the following conditions are
            met:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The transloading is done into sealable containers;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The transloading is carried out within the secure area of the
            airport (
            <E T='03'>
              i.e.
            </E>
            , that area of the airport that is open only to personnel authorized
            by the airport security authorities);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The area used for any storage is within the secure area of the
            airport; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             APHIS inspectors are available to provide the supervision required
            by paragraph (i)(1) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as authorized by paragraph (f) of this section, consignments
            that continue by air from the port of arrival in the continental
            United States may be authorized by APHIS for only one additional
            stop in the continental United States, provided the second stop is
            within the designated corridor set forth in paragraph (e) of this
            section and is staffed by APHIS inspectors. As an alternative to
            transloading a consignment arriving in the United States into
            another aircraft, consignments that arrive by air may be transloaded
            into a truck trailer for export by the most direct route to the
            final destination of the consignment through the designated corridor
            set forth in paragraph (e) of this section. This may be done at
            either the port of arrival in the United States or at the second
            authorized air stop within the designated corridor. No other
            transloading of the consignment is allowed, except under extenuating
            circumstances (
            <E T='03'>
              e.g.
            </E>
            , equipment breakdown) and when authorized by an APHIS inspector
            upon determination by the inspector that the transloading would not
            significantly increase the risk of the introduction of plant pests
            or diseases into the United States, and provided that APHIS
            inspectors are available to provide supervision.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Duration and location of storage.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any storage in the United States of fruits or vegetables shipped
            under this section must be for a duration and in a location
            authorized in the transit permit required by paragraph (a) of this
            section. Areas where such fruits or vegetables are stored must be
            either locked or guarded at all times the fruits and vegetables are
            present. Cargo shipped under this section must be kept in a sealed
            container while 
            <PRTPAGE P='192' />
            stored in the continental United States.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Temperature requirement.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except for time spent on aircraft and except during storage and
            transloading of air consignments, the temperature in the sealed
            containers containing fruits and vegetables moved under this section
            must be 60 °F or lower from the time the regulated articles leave
            Hawaii, Puerto Rico, Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana
            Islands, the U.S. Virgin Islands, or any other territory or
            possession of the United States until they exit the United States.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='l'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (l)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Prohibited materials.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='l_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The person in charge of or in possession of a sealed container used
            for movement into or through the United States under this section
            must ensure that the sealed container is carrying only those fruits
            or vegetables authorized by the transit permit required under
            paragraph (a) of this section; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='l_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The person in charge of or in possession of any means of conveyance
            or container returned to the United States without being reloaded
            after being used to export fruits or vegetables from the United
            States under this section must ensure that the means of conveyance
            or container is free of materials prohibited importation into the
            United States under this chapter.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='m'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (m)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Authorization by APHIS of the movement of fruits or vegetables
            through the United States under this section does not imply that
            such fruits or vegetables are enterable into the destination
            country. Consignments returned to the United States from the
            destination country shall be subject to all applicable regulations,
            including “Subpart—Fruits and Vegetables” of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='319' tq='N'>
                319
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and “Plant Quarantine Safeguard Regulations” of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='352' tq='N'>
                352 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='n'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (n)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any restrictions and requirements with respect to the arrival,
            temporary stay, unloading, transloading, transiting, exportation, or
            other movement or possession in the United States of any fruits or
            vegetables under this section shall apply to any person who brings
            into, maintains, unloads, transloads, transports, exports, or
            otherwise moves or possesses in the United States such fruits or
            vegetables, whether or not that person is the one who was required
            to have a transit permit or limited permit for the fruits or
            vegetables or is a subsequent custodian of the fruits or vegetables.
            Failure to comply with all applicable restrictions and requirements
            under this section by such a person shall be deemed to be a
            violation of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <APPRO>
          (Approved by the Office of Management and Budget under control number
          0579-0346)
        </APPRO>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5309'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:III:-:318:lii80:318.13-7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        318.13-7
      </num>
      <head>
        Products as ships&apos; stores or in the possession of passengers or
        crew.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='318' sect='13-7' psec='' tq='N'>
              318.13-7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Products as ships&apos; stores or in the possession of passengers or
          crew.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              In the possession of passengers or crew members.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Small quantities of fruits, vegetables, or cut flowers subject to
            the quarantine and regulations in this subpart, when loose and free
            of packing materials, may be taken aboard any ship, vessel, or other
            surface craft by passengers or members of the crew without
            inspection and certification in the State of origin. However, if
            such articles are not eligible for certification under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='318' sect='13-3' psec='' tq='N'>
                318.13-3
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , they must be entirely consumed or disposed of before arrival
            within the territorial waters of the continental United States,
            Hawaii, Puerto Rico, Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana
            Islands, or the U.S. Virgin Islands.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              As ships&apos; stores or decorations.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Fruits, vegetables, or cut flowers subject to the quarantine and
            regulations in this subpart may be taken aboard a ship, vessel, or
            other surface craft in Hawaii, Puerto Rico, Guam, the Commonwealth
            of the Northern Mariana Islands, or the U.S. Virgin Islands without
            inspection or certification. Fruits, vegetables, and cut flowers
            that are so taken aboard such a carrier must be either:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Entirely consumed or removed from the ship, vessel, or other
            surface craft before arrival within the territorial waters of the
            continental United States, Hawaii, Puerto Rico, Guam, the
            Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, the U.S. Virgin
            Islands, or any other territory or possession of the United States;
            or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the case of a surface carrier, retained aboard such carrier
            under seal or otherwise disposed of subject to safeguards equivalent
            to those imposed 
            <PRTPAGE P='193' />
            on other prohibited or restricted products by paragraphs (b) and (c)
            of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='352' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
                352.10
              </subref>
               of this chapter
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5310'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:III:-:318:lii80:318.13-8
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        318.13-8
      </num>
      <head>
        Articles and persons subject to inspection.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='318' sect='13-8' psec='' tq='N'>
              318.13-8
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Articles and persons subject to inspection.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          In addition to the inspection requirements in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='318' sect='13-9' psec='' tq='N'>
              318.13-9
            </subref>
             and 
            <subref title='7' part='318' sect='13-10' psec='' tq='N'>
              318.13-10
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , persons, means of conveyance (including ships, other oceangoing
          craft, and aircraft), baggage, cargo, and any other articles, that are
          destined for movement, are moving, or have been moved from Hawaii,
          Puerto Rico, Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands,
          or the U.S. Virgin Islands to a destination elsewhere in the United
          States are subject to agricultural inspection at the port of
          departure, the port of arrival, or any other authorized port. If an
          inspector finds any article prohibited movement by the quarantine and
          regulations of this subpart, he or she, taking the least drastic
          action, shall order the return of the article to the place of origin,
          or the exportation of the article, under safeguards satisfactory to
          him or her, or otherwise dispose of it, in whole or part, to comply
          with the quarantine and regulations of this subpart.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5311'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:III:-:318:lii80:318.13-9
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        318.13-9
      </num>
      <head>
        Inspection and disinfection of means of conveyance.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='318' sect='13-9' psec='' tq='N'>
              318.13-9
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Inspection and disinfection of means of conveyance.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Inspection of aircraft prior to departure.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No person shall move any aircraft from Hawaii, Puerto Rico, Guam,
            the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, or the U.S. Virgin
            Islands to any other State unless the person moving the aircraft has
            contacted an inspector and offered the inspector the opportunity to
            inspect the aircraft prior to departure and the inspector has
            informed the person proposing to move the aircraft that the aircraft
            may depart.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Inspection of aircraft moving to Guam.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any person who has moved an aircraft from Hawaii, Puerto Rico, the
            Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, or the U.S. Virgin
            Islands to Guam shall contact an inspector and offer the inspector
            the opportunity to inspect the aircraft upon the aircraft&apos;s
            arrival in Guam.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Inspection of ships upon arrival.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any person who has moved a ship or other oceangoing craft from
            Hawaii, Puerto Rico, Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana
            Islands, or the U.S. Virgin Islands to any other State shall contact
            an inspector and offer the inspector the opportunity to inspect the
            ship or other oceangoing craft upon its arrival.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Disinfection of means of conveyance.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If an inspector finds that a means of conveyance is infested with
            or contains plant pests, and the inspector orders disinfection of
            the means of conveyance, then the person in charge or in possession
            of the means of conveyance shall disinfect the means of conveyance
            and its cargo in accordance with an approved method contained in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='305' tq='N'>
                305 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
             under the supervision of an inspector and in a manner prescribed by
            the inspector, prior to any movement of the means of conveyance or
            its cargo.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5312'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:III:-:318:lii80:318.13-10
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        318.13-10
      </num>
      <head>
        Inspection of baggage, other personal effects, and cargo.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='318' sect='13-10' psec='' tq='N'>
              318.13-10
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Inspection of baggage, other personal effects, and cargo.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Offer for inspection by aircraft passengers.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Passengers destined for movement by aircraft from Hawaii, Puerto
            Rico, Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, or the
            U.S. Virgin Islands to any other State shall offer their carry-on
            baggage and other personal effects for inspection at the place
            marked for agricultural inspections, which will be located at the
            airport security checkpoint or the aircraft boarding gate, at the
            time they pass through the checkpoint or the gate. Passengers shall
            offer their check-in baggage for inspection at agricultural
            inspection stations prior to submitting their baggage to the
            check-in baggage facility. When an inspector has inspected and
            passed such baggage or personal effects, he or she shall apply a
            U.S. Department of Agriculture stamp, inspection sticker, or other
            identification to such baggage or personal effects to indicate that
            such baggage or personal effects have been inspected and passed as
            required. Passengers shall disclose any fruits, vegetables, plants,
            plant products, or other articles that are requested to be disclosed
            by the inspector. When an inspection of a passenger&apos;s baggage
            or personal effects discloses an article in violation of the
            regulations in this 
            <PRTPAGE P='194' />
            part, the inspector shall seize the article. The passenger shall
            state his or her name and address to the inspector, and provide the
            inspector with corroborative identification. The inspector shall
            record the name and address of the passenger, the nature of the
            identification presented for corroboration, the nature of the
            violation, the types of articles involved, and the date, time, and
            place of the violation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Offer for inspection by aircraft crew.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Aircraft crew members destined for movement by aircraft from
            Hawaii, Puerto Rico, Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana
            Islands, or the U.S. Virgin Islands to any other State, shall offer
            their baggage and personal effects for inspection at the inspection
            station designated for the employing airline not less than 20
            minutes prior to the scheduled departure time of the aircraft or the
            rescheduled departure time as posted in the public areas of the
            airport. When an inspector has inspected and passed such baggage or
            personal effects, he or she shall apply a U.S. Department of
            Agriculture stamp, inspection sticker, or other identification to
            the baggage or personal effects to indicate that such baggage or
            personal effects have been inspected and passed as required.
            Aircraft crew members shall disclose any fruits, vegetables, plants,
            plant products, or other articles that are requested to be disclosed
            by the inspector. When an inspection of a crew member&apos;s baggage
            or personal effects discloses an article in violation of the
            regulations in this part, the inspector shall seize the article. The
            crew member shall state his or her name and address to the
            inspector, and provide the inspector with corroborative
            identification. The inspector shall record the name and address of
            the crew member, the nature of the identification presented for
            corroboration, the nature of the violation, the types of articles
            involved, and the date, time, and place of the violation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Baggage inspection for persons traveling to Guam on aircraft.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No person who has moved from Hawaii, Puerto Rico, or the U.S.
            Virgin Islands to Guam on an aircraft shall remove or attempt to
            remove any baggage or other personal effects from the area secured
            for customs inspections before the person has offered to an
            inspector, and has had passed by the inspector, his or her baggage
            and other personal effects. Persons shall disclose any fruits,
            vegetables, plants, plant products, or other articles that are
            requested to be disclosed by the inspector. When an inspection of a
            person&apos;s baggage or personal effects discloses an article in
            violation of the regulations in this part, the inspector shall seize
            the article. The person shall state his or her name and address to
            the inspector, and provide the inspector with corroborative
            identification. The inspector shall record the name and address of
            the person, the nature of the identification presented for
            corroboration, the nature of the violation, the types of articles
            involved, and the date, time, and place of the violation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Baggage acceptance and loading on aircraft.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No person shall accept or load any check-in aircraft baggage
            destined for movement from Hawaii, Puerto Rico, Guam, the
            Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, or the U.S. Virgin
            Islands to any other State unless the baggage bears a U.S.
            Department of Agriculture stamp, inspection sticker, or other
            indication applied by an inspector representing that the baggage has
            been inspected and certified.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Offer for inspection by persons moving by ship.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No person who has moved on any ship or other oceangoing craft from
            Hawaii, Puerto Rico, Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana
            Islands, or the U.S. Virgin Islands to any other territory, State,
            or District of the United States, shall remove or attempt to remove
            any baggage or other personal effects from the designated inspection
            area as provided in paragraph (h) of this section on or off the ship
            or other oceangoing craft unless the person has offered to an
            inspector for inspection, and has had passed by the inspector, the
            baggage and other personal effects. Persons shall disclose any
            fruits, vegetables, plants, plant products, or other articles that
            are requested to be disclosed by the inspector. When an inspection
            of a person&apos;s baggage or personal effects discloses an article
            in violation of the regulations in this part, the inspector shall
            seize the article. The person shall state his 
            <PRTPAGE P='195' />
            or her name and address to the inspector, and provide the inspector
            with corroborative identification. The inspector shall record the
            name and address of the person, the nature of the identification
            presented for corroboration, the nature of the violation, the types
            of articles involved, and the date, time, and place of the
            violation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Loading of certain cargoes.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as otherwise provided in paragraph (f)(2) of this section,
            no person shall present to any common carrier or contract carrier
            for movement, and no common carrier or contract carrier shall load,
            any cargo containing fruits, vegetables, or other articles regulated
            under this subpart that are destined for movement from Hawaii,
            Puerto Rico, Guam, or the U.S. Virgin Islands to any other State
            unless the cargo has been offered for inspection, passed by an
            inspector, and bears a U.S. Department of Agriculture stamp or
            inspection sticker, or unless a limited permit is attached to the
            cargo as specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='318' sect='13-3' psec='#e' tq='N'>
                318.13-3(e)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Cargo designated may be loaded without a U.S. Department of
            Agriculture stamp or inspection sticker attached to the cargo or a
            limited permit attached to the cargo if the cargo is moved:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             As containerized cargo on ships or other oceangoing craft or as air
            cargo;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The carrier has on file documentary evidence that a valid limited
            permit was issued for the movement or that the cargo was certified;
            and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A notation of the existence of these documents is made by the
            carrier on the waybill, manifest, or bill of lading that accompanies
            the consignment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Cargo moved in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='318' sect='13-6' psec='#b' tq='N'>
                318.13-6(b)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             that does not have a limited permit attached to the cargo must have
            a limited permit attached to the waybill, manifest, or bill of
            lading accompanying the consignment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             R
            <E T='03'>
              emoval of certain cargoes in Guam.
            </E>
             No person shall remove or attempt to remove from a designated
            inspection area as provided in paragraph (h) of this section, on or
            off the means of conveyance, any cargo moved from Hawaii, Puerto
            Rico, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, or the U.S.
            Virgin Islands to Guam containing fruits, vegetables, or other
            articles regulated under this subpart, unless the cargo has been
            inspected and passed by an inspector in Guam.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Space and facilities for baggage and cargo inspection.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Baggage and cargo inspection will not be performed until the person
            in charge or possession of the ship, other oceangoing craft, or
            aircraft provides space and facilities on the means of conveyance,
            pier, or airport that are adequate, in the inspector&apos;s
            judgment, for the performance of inspection.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5313'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:III:-:318:lii80:318.13-11
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        318.13-11
      </num>
      <head>
        Posting of warning notice and distribution of baggage declarations.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='318' sect='13-11' psec='' tq='N'>
              318.13-11
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Posting of warning notice and distribution of baggage declarations.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Before any aircraft or any ship, vessel, or other surface craft
            moving to Guam, the Commonwealth of Northern Mariana Islands, or
            American Samoa from Hawaii or any other territory or possession of
            the United States arrives in Guam, the Commonwealth of Northern
            Mariana Islands, or American Samoa, a baggage declaration, to be
            furnished by the U.S. Department of Agriculture, calling attention
            to the provisions of the Plant Protection Act and the quarantine and
            regulations in this subpart, must be distributed to each adult
            passenger. These baggage declarations shall be executed and signed
            by the passengers and shall be collected and delivered by the master
            or other responsible officer of the aircraft, ship, vessel, or other
            surface craft to the inspector on arrival at the quarantine or
            inspection area.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Every person owning or controlling any dock, harbor, or landing
            field in Hawaii, Puerto Rico, Guam, the Commonwealth of Northern
            Mariana Islands, or the U.S. Virgin Islands from which ships,
            vessels, other surface craft, or aircraft leave for ports in any
            other State shall post, and keep posted at all times, in one or more
            conspicuous places in passenger waiting rooms on or in said dock,
            harbor, or landing field a warning notice directing attention to the
            quarantine and regulations in this subpart. Every master, or other
            responsible officer of any ship, vessel, other surface craft, or
            aircraft leaving Hawaii, Puerto Rico, Guam, the Commonwealth of the
            Northern Mariana Islands, or the U.S. Virgin Islands destined to a
            port in any 
            <PRTPAGE P='196' />
            other State, shall similarly post, and keep posted at all times,
            such a warning notice in the ship, vessel, other surface craft, or
            aircraft under his charge.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5314'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:III:-:318:lii80:318.13-12
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        318.13-12
      </num>
      <head>
        Movement by the U.S. Department of Agriculture.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='318' sect='13-12' psec='' tq='N'>
              318.13-12
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Movement by the U.S. Department of Agriculture.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Notwithstanding any other restrictions of this subpart, regulated
          articles may be moved if they are moved by the U.S. Department of
          Agriculture for experimental or scientific purposes and are moved
          under conditions found by the Administrator to be adequate to prevent
          the spread of plant pests and diseases.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5315'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:III:-:318:lii80:318.13-13
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        318.13-13
      </num>
      <head>
        Movement of frozen fruits and vegetables.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='318' sect='13-13' psec='' tq='N'>
              318.13-13
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Movement of frozen fruits and vegetables.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Frozen fruits and vegetables may be certified for movement from
          Hawaii, Puerto Rico, Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana
          Islands, or the U.S. Virgin Islands, into or through any other
          territory, State, or District of the United States in accordance with 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='318' sect='13-3' psec='' tq='N'>
              318.13-3
            </subref>
          </aref>
          . Such fruits and vegetables must be held at a temperature not higher
          than 20 °F during shipping and upon arrival in the continental United
          States, and in accordance with the requirements for the interstate
          movement of frozen fruits and vegetables in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='305' tq='N'>
              305 of this chapter
            </subref>
          </aref>
          . Paragraph (b) of 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='305' sect='17' psec='' tq='N'>
              305.17
            </subref>
          </aref>
           lists frozen fruits and vegetables for which quick freezing is not an
          authorized treatment.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5316'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:III:-:318:lii80:318.13-14
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        318.13-14
      </num>
      <head>
        Movement of processed fruits, vegetables, and other products.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='318' sect='13-14' psec='' tq='N'>
              318.13-14
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Movement of processed fruits, vegetables, and other products.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Fruits, vegetables, and other products that are processed
            sufficiently as to preclude the survival of any live pests can be
            moved interstate from Hawaii, Puerto Rico, the U.S. Virgin Islands,
            Guam, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands. Those
            processed products which are approved for interstate movement from
            those States can be found in the fruits and vegetables manuals for
            those States. These manuals are available on the Internet at 
            <E T='03'>
              http://www.aphis.usda.gov/import_export/plants/manuals/ports/downloads/hawaii.pdf
            </E>
             and 
            <E T='03'>
              http://www.aphis.usda.gov/import_export/plants/manuals/ports/downloads/puerto_rico.pdf
            </E>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Consignments of processed fruits, vegetables, or other products
            that have not been processed sufficiently as to be incapable of
            harboring fruit flies are subject to the interstate movement
            requirements which apply to the fruit, vegetable, or other product
            in its unprocessed state.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5317'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:III:-:318:lii80:318.13-15
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        318.13-15
      </num>
      <head>
        Parcel post inspection.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='318' sect='13-15' psec='' tq='N'>
              318.13-15
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Parcel post inspection.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Inspectors are authorized to inspect, with the cooperation of the U.S.
          Postal Service, parcel post packages placed in the mails in Hawaii,
          Puerto Rico, Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands,
          or the U.S. Virgin Islands to determine whether such packages contain
          products whose movement is not authorized under this subpart, to
          examine any such products that are found for insect infestation, and
          to notify the postmaster in writing of any violations of this subpart
          that are found as a result of an inspection.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5318'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:III:-:318:lii80:318.13-16
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        318.13-16
      </num>
      <head>
        Regulated articles allowed interstate movement subject to specified
        conditions.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          74 FR 2775
        </aref>
        , Jan. 16, 2009, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 4249
        </aref>
        , Jan. 26, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='318' sect='13-16' psec='' tq='N'>
              318.13-16
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Regulated articles allowed interstate movement subject to specified
          conditions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The following regulated articles may be moved interstate in
            accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='318' sect='13-3' psec='' tq='N'>
                318.13-3
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and any additional requirements specified in paragraph (b) of this
            section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <table class='gpotable' CDEF='s50,r50,r50,r25,r25' COLS='5' OPTS='L2'>
          <caption />
          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th>
                State, territory, or district of origin
              </th>
              <th>
                Common name
              </th>
              <th>
                Botanical name
              </th>
              <th>
                Plant part(s)
              </th>
              <th>
                Additional
                <LI>
                  requirements
                </LI>
              </th>
            </tr>
          </thead>
          <tfoot>
            <tr>
              <td class='tnote' colspan='5'>
                <sup>
                  1
                </sup>
                 Fruit may also be moved interstate in accordance with 
                <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
                  § 
                  <subref title='7' part='318' sect='13-17' psec='' tq='N'>
                    318.13-17
                  </subref>
                </aref>
                .
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td class='tnote' colspan='5'>
                <sup>
                  2
                </sup>
                 Fruit may also be moved interstate with treatment in accordance
                with 
                <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
                  part 
                  <subref title='7' part='305' tq='N'>
                    305 of this chapter
                  </subref>
                </aref>
                .
              </td>
            </tr>
          </tfoot>
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Hawaii
              </td>
              <td>
                Bananas 
                <sup>
                  1
                </sup>
              </td>
              <td>
                <E T='03'>
                  Musa
                </E>
                 spp
              </td>
              <td>
                Fruit
              </td>
              <td>
                (b)(1)(i), (b)(2)(ii)
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22' />
              <td>
                Litchi
              </td>
              <td>
                <E T='03'>
                  Litchi chinensis
                </E>
              </td>
              <td>
                Fruit
              </td>
              <td>
                (b)(1)(ii), (b)(3)(ii)
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22' />
              <td>
                Longan
              </td>
              <td>
                <E T='03'>
                  Dimocarpus longan
                </E>
              </td>
              <td>
                Fruit
              </td>
              <td>
                (b)(1)(ii), (b)(3)(ii)
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22' />
              <td>
                Pot marigold, johnny-jump-ups, pansies, and violets
              </td>
              <td>
                <E T='03'>
                  Calendula
                </E>
                 spp
              </td>
              <td>
                Flower
              </td>
              <td>
                (b)(2)(iii)
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22' />
              <td>
                Pineapple 
                <sup>
                  2
                </sup>
              </td>
              <td>
                <E T='03'>
                  Ananas comosus
                </E>
              </td>
              <td>
                Fruit
              </td>
              <td>
                (b)(2)(i)
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Puerto Rico
              </td>
              <td>
                Cactus
              </td>
              <td>
                <E T='03'>
                  Cactaceae
                </E>
              </td>
              <td>
                Whole plant
              </td>
              <td>
                (b)(2)(iv), (b)(3)(ii)
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22' />
              <td>
                Okra
              </td>
              <td>
                <E T='03'>
                  Abelmoschus escuelentus
                </E>
              </td>
              <td>
                Fruit
              </td>
              <td>
                (b)(3)(i)
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22' />
              <td>
                Pot marigold, johnny-jump-ups, pansies, and violets
              </td>
              <td>
                <E T='03'>
                  Calendula
                </E>
                 spp
              </td>
              <td>
                Flower
              </td>
              <td>
                (b)(2)(iii)
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                U.S. Virgin Islands
              </td>
              <td>
                Cactus
              </td>
              <td>
                <E T='03'>
                  Cactaceae
                </E>
              </td>
              <td>
                Whole plant
              </td>
              <td>
                (b)(2)(iv), (b)(3)(ii)
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22' />
              <td>
                Okra
              </td>
              <td>
                <E T='03'>
                  Abelmoschus escuelentus
                </E>
              </td>
              <td>
                Fruit
              </td>
              <td>
                (b)(3)(i)
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22' />
              <td>
                Pot marigold, johnny-jump-ups, pansies, and violets
              </td>
              <td>
                <E T='03'>
                  Calendula
                </E>
                 spp
              </td>
              <td>
                Flower
              </td>
              <td>
                (b)(2)(iii)
              </td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Additional restrictions for applicable regulated articles as
            specified in paragraph (a) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Restricted movement and distribution.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Allowed movement into Alaska. Cartons must be labeled, “For
            distribution in Alaska only.”
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             May not be moved interstate into Florida. Cartons must be stamped
            “Not for movement into or distribution in FL.”
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Plant types.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Smooth cayenne variety and hybrids with 50 percent or more smooth
            cayenne parentage only.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Green bananas of the cultivars “Williams,” “Valery,” “Grand Nain,”
            and standard and dwarf “Brazilian” only.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Inflorescences only with no stems or leaves attached.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bare-rooted plants or plants rooted in approved growing media only.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Other conditions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If destined to States other than Alabama, Arizona, Arkansas,
            California, Florida, Georgia, Illinois, Kentucky, Louisiana,
            Mississippi, Missouri, Nevada, New Mexico, North Carolina, Oklahoma,
            South Carolina, Tennessee, Texas, or Virginia, the consignment must
            be treated in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='305' tq='N'>
                305 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
             unless the consignment is for immediate consumption or processing.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Must be treated in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='305' tq='N'>
                305 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            74 FR 2775
          </aref>
          , Jan. 16, 2009, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 4249
          </aref>
          , Jan. 26, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5319'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:III:-:318:lii80:318.13-17
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        318.13-17
      </num>
      <head>
        Regulated articles from Guam.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='318' sect='13-17' psec='' tq='N'>
              318.13-17
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Regulated articles from Guam.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Regulated articles, other than soil, may be moved from Guam into or
            through any other State only if they meet the strictest plant
            quarantine requirements under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='319' tq='N'>
                319 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
             for similar articles offered for entry into such States from the
            countries of East and Southeast Asia, including Cambodia, India,
            Japan, Korea, Laos, the northeastern provinces of Manchuria, the
            Philippines, Taiwan, and Vietnam, or the islands of the Central and
            South Pacific, including Micronesia, Melanesia, and Polynesia, as
            well as Australia, New Zealand, and the Malay Archipelago, except
            requirements for permits, phytosanitary certificates, notices of
            arrival, and notices of consignment from port of arrival. Soil must
            meet the requirements of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='330' sect='300' psec='' tq='N'>
                330.300
              </subref>
               of this chapter
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Regulated articles that do not meet the requirements of paragraph
            (a)(1) of this section are prohibited movement from Guam into or
            through any other State.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Regulated articles moved from Guam into or through any other State
            shall be subject to inspection at the port of first arrival in
            another part of the United States to determine whether they are free
            of plant pests and otherwise meet the requirements applicable to
            them under this subpart, and shall be subject to release, in
            accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='330' sect='105' psec='#a' tq='N'>
                330.105(a)
              </subref>
               of this chapter
            </aref>
             as if they were foreign arrivals. Such articles shall be released
            only if they meet all applicable requirements under this subpart.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A release shall be issued in writing unless the inspection involves
            small quantities of regulated articles, in which case a release may
            be issued orally by the inspector.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5320'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:III:-:318:lii80:318.13-18 — 318.13-20
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        318.13-18 — 318.13-20
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='198' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='318' sect='13-18' psec='' tq='N'>
              318.13-18
            </subref>
          </aref>
           — 318.13-20
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5321'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:III:-:318:lii80:318.13-21
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        318.13-21
      </num>
      <head>
        Avocados from Hawaii to Alaska.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='318' sect='13-21' psec='' tq='N'>
              318.13-21
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Avocados from Hawaii to Alaska.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Avocados may be moved interstate from Hawaii to Alaska without
          treatment only under the following conditions:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Distribution and marking requirements.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The avocados may be moved interstate for distribution in Alaska
            only, the boxes of avocados must be clearly marked with the
            statement “Distribution limited to the State of Alaska” and the
            consignment must be identified in accordance with the requirements
            of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='318' sect='13-3' psec='' tq='N'>
                318.13-3
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Commercial consignments.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The avocados may be moved in commercial consignments only.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Packing requirements.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The avocados must have been sealed in the packinghouse in Hawaii in
            boxes with a seal that will break if the box is opened.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Ports.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The avocados may enter the continental United States only at the
            following ports: Portland, OR; Seattle, WA; or any port in Alaska.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Shipping requirements.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The avocados must be moved either by air or ship and in a sealed
            container. The avocados may not be commingled in the same sealed
            container with articles that are intended for entry and distribution
            in any State other than Alaska. If the avocados arrive at either
            Portland, OR, or Seattle, WA, they may be transloaded only under the
            following conditions:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Consignments by sea.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The avocados may be transloaded from one ship to another ship at
            the port of arrival, provided they remain in the original sealed
            container and that APHIS inspectors supervise the transloading. If
            the avocados are stored before reloading, they must be kept in the
            original sealed container and must be in an area that is either
            locked or guarded at all times the avocados are present.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Consignments by air.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The avocados may be transloaded from one aircraft to another
            aircraft at the port of arrival, provided the following conditions
            are met:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The transloading is done into sealable containers;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The transloading is carried out within the secure area of the
            airport (
            <E T='03'>
              i.e.
            </E>
            , that area of the airport that is open only to personnel authorized
            by the airport security authorities);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The area used for any storage of the consignment is within the
            secure area of the airport, and is either locked or guarded at all
            times the avocados are present. The avocados must be kept in a
            sealed container while stored in the continental United States en
            route to Alaska; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_2_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             APHIS inspectors supervise the transloading.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Exceptions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No transloading other than that described in paragraphs (e)(1) and
            (e)(2) of this section is allowed except under extenuating
            circumstances (such as equipment breakdown) and when authorized and
            supervised by an APHIS inspector.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Limited permit.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Consignments of avocados must be accompanied by a limited permit
            issued by an APHIS inspector in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='318' sect='13-3' psec='#c' tq='N'>
                318.13-3(c)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . The limited permit will be issued only if the inspector examines
            the consignment and determines that the consignment has been
            prepared in compliance with the provisions of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5322'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:III:-:318:lii80:318.13-22
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        318.13-22
      </num>
      <head>
        Bananas from Hawaii.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          74 FR 2775
        </aref>
        , Jan. 16, 2009, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 4249
        </aref>
        , Jan. 26, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='318' sect='13-22' psec='' tq='N'>
              318.13-22
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Bananas from Hawaii.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Green bananas (
            <E T='03'>
              Musa
            </E>
             spp.) of the cultivars “Williams,” “Valery,” “Grand Nain,” and
            standard and dwarf “Brazilian” may be moved interstate from Hawaii
            with certification in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='318' sect='13-3' psec='' tq='N'>
                318.13-3
              </subref>
            </aref>
             if the bananas meet the following conditions: 
            <SU>
              3
            </SU>
            <FTREF />
          </text>
        </P>
        <FTNT>
          <P>
            <SU>
              3
            </SU>
             Bananas from Hawaii may also be moved to Alaska under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='318' sect='13-16' psec='' tq='N'>
                318.13-16
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </P>
        </FTNT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The bananas must be picked while green and packed for shipment
            within 24 hours after harvest. If the green bananas will be stored
            overnight during that 24-hour period, they must be stored in a
            facility that prevents access by fruit flies;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No bananas from bunches containing prematurely ripe fingers (
            <E T='03'>
              i.e.
            </E>
            , individual yellow bananas in a cluster of otherwise green bananas)
            may be harvested or packed for shipment;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The bananas must be inspected by an inspector and found free of
            plant pests as well as any of the following defects: Prematurely
            ripe fingers, fused fingers, or exposed flesh (not including 
            <PRTPAGE P='199' />
            fresh cuts made during the packing process); and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To safeguard from fruit fly infestation, the bananas must be
            covered with insect-proof packaging, such as insect-proof mesh
            screens or plastic tarpaulins, from the time that they are packaged
            for shipment until they reach the port of arrival on the mainland
            United States.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bananas of any cultivar or ripeness that do not meet the conditions
            of paragraph (a) of this section may also be moved interstate from
            Hawaii in accordance with the following conditions:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The bananas are irradiated in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='305' tq='N'>
                305 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
             for the Mediterranean fruit fly (
            <E T='03'>
              Ceratitis capitata
            </E>
            ), the melon fruit fly (
            <E T='03'>
              Bactrocera curcurbitae
            </E>
            ), the Oriental fruit fly (
            <E T='03'>
              Bactrocera dorsalis
            </E>
            ), and the green scale (
            <E T='03'>
              Coccus viridis
            </E>
            ) and are inspected, after removal from the stalk, in Hawaii and
            found to be free of the banana moth (
            <E T='03'>
              Opogona sacchari
            </E>
             (Bojen)) by an inspector before or after undergoing irradiation
            treatment; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The bananas are irradiated in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='305' tq='N'>
                305 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
             for the Mediterranean fruit fly (
            <E T='03'>
              Ceratitis capitata
            </E>
            ), the melon fruit fly (
            <E T='03'>
              Bactrocera curcurbitae
            </E>
            ), and the Oriental fruit fly (
            <E T='03'>
              Bactrocera dorsalis
            </E>
            ) and are inspected, after removal from the stalk, in Hawaii and
            found to be free of the green scale (
            <E T='03'>
              Coccus viridis
            </E>
            ) and the banana moth (
            <E T='03'>
              Opogona sacchari
            </E>
             (Bojen)) before or after undergoing irradiation treatment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Untreated bananas from Hawaii may be moved interstate for treatment
            on the mainland United States under a limited permit issued by an
            inspector. To be eligible for a limited permit under this paragraph,
            bananas from Hawaii must be inspected prior to interstate movement
            from Hawaii and found free of banana moth if they are to be treated
            in accordance with the requirements of paragraph (b)(1) of this
            section or inspected and found free of banana moth and green scale
            if they are to be treated in accordance with the requirements of
            paragraph (b)(2) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            74 FR 2775
          </aref>
          , Jan. 16, 2009, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 4249
          </aref>
          , Jan. 26, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5323'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:III:-:318:lii80:318.13-23
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        318.13-23
      </num>
      <head>
        Cut flowers from Hawaii.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='318' sect='13-23' psec='' tq='N'>
              318.13-23
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Cut flowers from Hawaii.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except for cut blooms and leis of mauna loa and jade vine and
            except for cut blooms of gardenia not grown in accordance with
            paragraph (b) of this section, cut flowers may be moved interstate
            from Hawaii under limited permit, to a destination specified in the
            permit, directly from an establishment operated in accordance with
            the terms of a compliance agreement executed by the operator of the
            establishment, if the articles have not been exposed to infestation
            and they are not accompanied by any articles prohibited interstate
            movement under this subpart.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Cut blooms of gardenia may be moved interstate from Hawaii if grown
            and inspected in accordance with the provisions of this section. 
            <SU>
              4
            </SU>
            <FTREF />
          </text>
        </P>
        <FTNT>
          <P>
            <SU>
              4
            </SU>
             Cut blooms of gardenia are also eligible for interstate movement
            with treatment in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='305' tq='N'>
                305 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </P>
        </FTNT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The grower&apos;s production area must be inspected annually by an
            inspector and found free of green scale. If green scale is found
            during an inspection, a 2-month ban will be placed on the interstate
            movement of cut blooms of gardenia from that production area. Near
            the end of the 2 months, an inspector will reinspect the
            grower&apos;s production area to determine whether green scale is
            present. If reinspection determines that the production area is free
            of green scale, shipping may resume. If reinspection determines that
            green scale is still present in the production area, another 2-month
            ban on shipping will be placed on the interstate movement of
            gardenia from that production area. Each ban will be followed by
            reinspection in the manner specified, and the production area must
            be found free of green scale prior to interstate movement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The grower must establish a buffer area surrounding gardenia
            production areas. The buffer area must extend 20 feet from the edge
            of the production area. Within the buffer area, the growing of
            gardenias and the following green scale host plants is prohibited:
            Ixora, ginger (
            <E T='03'>
              Alpinia purpurata
            </E>
            ), plumeria, coffee, rambutan, litchi, guava, citrus, anthurium,
            avocado, banana, cocoa, macadamia, celery, 
            <PRTPAGE P='200' />
            <E T='03'>
              Pluchea indica,
            </E>
             mango, orchids, and annona.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An inspector must visually inspect the cut blooms of gardenias in
            each consignment prior to interstate movement from Hawaii to the
            mainland United States. If the inspector does not detect green scale
            in the consignment, the inspector will certify the consignment in
            accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='318' sect='13-3' psec='#b' tq='N'>
                318.13-3(b)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . If the inspector finds green scale in a consignment, that
            consignment will be ineligible for interstate movement from Hawaii.
          </text>
        </P>
        <APPRO>
          (Approved by the Office of Management and Budget under control number
          0579-0198)
        </APPRO>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5324'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:III:-:318:lii80:318.13-24
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        318.13-24
      </num>
      <head>
        Sweet potatoes from Puerto Rico.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='318' sect='13-24' psec='' tq='N'>
              318.13-24
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Sweet potatoes from Puerto Rico.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Sweet potatoes from Puerto Rico may be moved interstate to Atlantic
          Coast ports north of and including Baltimore, MD, under limited permit
          if treated in accordance with 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='305' tq='N'>
              305 of this chapter
            </subref>
          </aref>
           or if the following conditions are met:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The sweet potatoes must be certified by an inspector of Puerto Rico
            as having been grown under the following conditions:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Fields in which the sweet potatoes have been grown must have been
            given a preplanting treatment with an APHIS-approved soil
            insecticide.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Before planting in such treated fields, the sweet potato draws and
            vine cuttings must have been dipped in an APHIS-approved
            insecticidal solution.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             During the growing season an approved insecticide must have been
            applied to the vines at prescribed intervals.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An inspector of Puerto Rico must certify that the sweet potatoes
            have been washed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The sweet potatoes must be graded by inspectors of Puerto Rico in
            accordance with Puerto Rican standards which do not provide a
            tolerance for insect infestation or evidence of insect injury and
            found by such inspectors to comply with such standards prior to
            movement from Puerto Rico.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The sweet potatoes must be inspected by an inspector and found to
            be free of the sweet potato scarabee (
            <E T='03'>
              Euscepes postfasciatus Fairm.
            </E>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5325'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:III:-:318:lii80:318.13-25
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        318.13-25
      </num>
      <head>
        Sweetpotatoes from Hawaii.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 4250
        </aref>
        , Jan. 26, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='318' sect='13-25' psec='' tq='N'>
              318.13-25
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Sweetpotatoes from Hawaii.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Sweetpotatoes may be moved interstate from Hawaii in accordance with
          this section only if the sweetpotatoes meet the conditions in
          paragraph (a) or paragraph (b) of this section or if the sweetpotatoes
          are fumigated with methyl bromide in accordance with 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='305' tq='N'>
              305 of this chapter
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Vapor heat treatment and inspection.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The sweetpotatoes must be treated with vapor heat in accordance
            with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='305' tq='N'>
                305 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The sweetpotatoes must be sampled, cut, and inspected and found to
            be free of the ginger weevil (
            <E T='03'>
              Elytrotreinus subtruncatus
            </E>
            ). Sampling, cutting, and inspection must be performed under
            conditions that will prevent any pests that may emerge from the
            sampled sweetpotatoes from infesting any other sweetpotatoes
            intended for interstate movement in accordance with this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The sweetpotatoes must be inspected and found to be free of the
            gray pineapple mealybug (
            <E T='03'>
              Dysmicoccus neobrevipes
            </E>
            ) and the Kona coffee-root knot nematode (
            <E T='03'>
              Meloidogyne konaensis
            </E>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Sweetpotatoes that are treated in Hawaii must be packaged in the
            following manner:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_4_i_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The cartons must have no openings that will allow the entry of the
            pests of concern and must be sealed with seals that will visually
            indicate if the cartons have been opened. They may be constructed of
            any material that prevents the entry of the pests of concern.
            <SU>
              5
            </SU>
            <FTREF />
          </text>
        </P>
        <FTNT>
          <P>
            <SU>
              5
            </SU>
             If there is a question as to the adequacy of a carton, send a
            request for approval of the carton, together with a sample carton,
            to the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service, Plant Protection
            and Quarantine, Center for Plant Health Science and Technology, 1730
            Varsity Drive, Suite 400, Raleigh, NC 27606.
          </P>
        </FTNT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_4_i_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The pallet-load of cartons must be secured before it leaves the
            treatment facility in one of the following ways:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          (
          <E T='03'>
            1
          </E>
          ) With polyethylene sheet wrap;
        </P>
        <P>
          (
          <E T='03'>
            2
          </E>
          ) With net wrapping; or
        </P>
        <P>
          (
          <E T='03'>
            3
          </E>
          ) With strapping.
          <PRTPAGE P='201' />
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_4_i_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Packaging must be labeled in a manner that allows an inspector to
            determine treatment lot numbers, packing and treatment facility
            identification and location, and dates of packing and treatment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_4_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Cartons of untreated sweetpotatoes that are moving to the mainland
            United States for treatment must be shipped in shipping containers
            sealed prior to interstate movement with seals that will visually
            indicate if the shipping containers have been opened.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_5_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Certification on basis of treatment.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Certification shall be issued by an inspector for the movement of
            sweetpotatoes from Hawaii that have been treated in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='305' tq='N'>
                305 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and handled in Hawaii in accordance with this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_5_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Limited permit.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A limited permit shall be issued by an inspector for the interstate
            movement of untreated sweetpotato from Hawaii for treatment on the
            mainland United States in accordance with this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Irradiation treatment and inspection.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The sweetpotatoes must be treated with irradiation in accordance
            with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='305' tq='N'>
                305 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Sweetpotatoes that are not treated with an irradiation dose
            approved to neutralize the ginger weevil (
            <E T='03'>
              Elytrotreinus subtruncatus
            </E>
            ) must be sampled, cut, and inspected and found to be free of the
            ginger weevil by an inspector in Hawaii. Sampling, cutting, and
            inspection must be performed under conditions that will prevent any
            pests that may emerge from the sampled sweetpotatoes from infesting
            any other sweetpotatoes intended for interstate movement in
            accordance with this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be certified for interstate movement under this paragraph,
            sweetpotato from Hawaii must be inspected in Hawaii and found free
            of the gray pineapple mealybug (
            <E T='03'>
              Dysmicoccus neobrevipes
            </E>
            ) and the Kona coffee-root knot nematode (
            <E T='03'>
              Meloidogyne konaensis
            </E>
            ) by an inspector before undergoing irradiation treatment in Hawaii.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be eligible for a limited permit under this section, untreated
            sweetpotato from Hawaii must be inspected in Hawaii and found free
            of the gray pineapple mealybug (
            <E T='03'>
              Dysmicoccus neobrevipes
            </E>
            ) and the Kona coffee-root knot nematode (
            <E T='03'>
              Meloidogyne konaensis
            </E>
            ) by an inspector.
          </text>
        </P>
        <APPRO>
          (Approved by the Office of Management and Budget under control number
          0579-0281)
        </APPRO>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 4250
          </aref>
          , Jan. 26, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5326'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:III:-:318:lii80:318.13-26
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        318.13-26
      </num>
      <head>
        Breadfruit, jackfruit, fresh pods of cowpea, dragon fruit, mangosteen,
        and moringa pods from Hawaii.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 4250
        </aref>
        , Jan. 26, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='318' sect='13-26' psec='' tq='N'>
              318.13-26
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Breadfruit, jackfruit, fresh pods of cowpea, dragon fruit, mangosteen,
          and moringa pods from Hawaii.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Breadfruit and jackfruit.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be eligible for interstate movement, breadfruit and jackfruit
            from Hawaii must be treated with irradiation in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='305' tq='N'>
                305 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be certified for interstate movement, breadfruit and jackfruit
            from Hawaii must be inspected in Hawaii and found free of spiraling
            whitefly (
            <E T='03'>
              Aleurodicus dispersus
            </E>
            ), inornate scale (
            <E T='03'>
              Aonidiella inornata
            </E>
            ), red wax scale (
            <E T='03'>
              Ceroplastes rubens
            </E>
            ), green scale (
            <E T='03'>
              Coccus viridis
            </E>
            ), gray pineapple mealybug (
            <E T='03'>
              Dysmicoccus neobrevipes
            </E>
            ), pink hibiscus mealybug (
            <E T='03'>
              Maconellicoccus hirsutus
            </E>
            ), spherical mealybug (
            <E T='03'>
              Nipaecoccus viridis
            </E>
            ), citrus mealybug (
            <E T='03'>
              Pseudococcus cryptus
            </E>
            ), melon thrips (
            <E T='03'>
              Thrips palmi
            </E>
            ), and signs of thrip damage before undergoing irradiation treatment
            in Hawaii at a dose approved to neutralize fruit flies. Fruit
            treated for fruit flies also must either receive a post-harvest dip
            in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='305' tq='N'>
                305 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
             to treat external feeders or originate from an orchard or growing
            area that was previously treated with a broad-spectrum insecticide
            during the growing season and a pre-harvest inspection of the
            orchard or growing area found the fruit free of any surface pests as
            prescribed in a compliance agreement. Post-treatment inspection in
            Hawaii is not required if the fruit undergoes irradiation treatment
            at a dose approved to neutralize all plant pests of the class 
            <E T='03'>
              Insecta
            </E>
            , except pupae and adults of the order Lepidoptera. Regardless of
            irradiation dose, the fruit must be free of stems and leaves and
            must originate from an orchard that was previously treated with a
            fungicide appropriate for the fungus 
            <E T='03'>
              Phytophthora tropicalis
            </E>
             during the growing season and the fruit must be inspected prior to
            harvest and found free of the fungus or, after irradiation
            treatment, must receive a post-
            <PRTPAGE P='202' />
            harvest fungicidal dip appropriate for 
            <E T='03'>
              Phytophthora tropicalis
            </E>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be eligible for a limited permit, breadfruit and jackfruit from
            Hawaii must be free of stems and leaves and must originate from an
            orchard that was previously treated with a fungicide appropriate for
            the fungus 
            <E T='03'>
              Phytophthora tropicalis
            </E>
             during the growing season and the fruit must be inspected prior to
            harvest and found free of the fungus or, after irradiation
            treatment, must receive a post-harvest fungicidal dip appropriate
            for 
            <E T='03'>
              Phytophthora tropicalis
            </E>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Fresh pods of cowpea.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be eligible for interstate movement, fresh pods of cowpea and
            its relatives from Hawaii must be treated with irradiation in
            accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='305' tq='N'>
                305 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be certified for interstate movement, fresh pods of cowpea and
            its relatives from Hawaii must be inspected in Hawaii and found free
            of the cassava red mite (
            <E T='03'>
              Oligonychus biharensis
            </E>
            ) and adults and pupae of the order Lepidoptera before undergoing
            irradiation treatment. The pods must be free of stems and leaves.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be eligible for a limited permit, fresh pods of cowpea and its
            relatives from Hawaii must be free of stems and leaves and must be
            inspected in Hawaii and found free of the cassava red mite (
            <E T='03'>
              Oligonychus biharensis
            </E>
            ) and adults and pupae of the order Lepidoptera.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Dragon fruit.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be certified for interstate movement, dragon fruit from Hawaii
            presented for inspection must have the sepals removed and must be
            inspected in Hawaii and found free of gray pineapple mealybug (
            <E T='03'>
              Dysmicoccus neobrevipes
            </E>
            ), pink hibiscus mealybug (
            <E T='03'>
              Maconellicoccus hirsutus
            </E>
            ), and citrus mealybug (
            <E T='03'>
              Pseudococcus cryptus
            </E>
            ) before undergoing irradiation treatment in Hawaii at a dose
            approved to neutralize fruit flies. Fruit treated for fruit flies
            also must either receive a post-harvest dip in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='305' tq='N'>
                305 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
             to treat external feeders or originate from an orchard or growing
            area that was previously treated with a broad-spectrum insecticide
            during the growing season and a pre-harvest inspection of the
            orchard or growing area found the fruit free of any surface pests as
            prescribed in a compliance agreement. Post-treatment inspection in
            Hawaii is not required if the fruit undergoes irradiation treatment
            at a dose approved to neutralize all plant pests of the class 
            <E T='03'>
              Insecta
            </E>
            , except pupae and adults of the order Lepidoptera. Regardless of
            irradiation dose, the fruit must be free of stems and leaves.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Mangosteen.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be certified for interstate movement, mangosteen from Hawaii
            must have the sepals removed and must be inspected in Hawaii and
            found free of gray pineapple mealybug (
            <E T='03'>
              Dysmicoccus neobrevipes
            </E>
            ), pink hibiscus mealybug (
            <E T='03'>
              Maconellicoccus hirsutus
            </E>
            ), citrus mealybug (
            <E T='03'>
              Pseudococcus cryptus
            </E>
            ), and 
            <E T='03'>
              Thrips florum
            </E>
             before undergoing irradiation treatment in Hawaii at a dose
            approved to neutralize fruit flies. Fruit treated for fruit flies
            also must either receive a post-harvest dip in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='305' tq='N'>
                305 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
             to treat external feeders or originate from an orchard or growing
            area that was previously treated with a broad-spectrum insecticide
            during the growing season and a pre-harvest inspection of the
            orchard or growing area found the fruit free of any surface pests as
            prescribed in a compliance agreement. Post-treatment inspection in
            Hawaii is not required if the fruit undergoes irradiation treatment
            at a dose approved to neutralize all plant pests of the class 
            <E T='03'>
              Insecta
            </E>
            , except pupae and adults of the order Lepidoptera. Regardless of
            irradiation dose, the fruit must be free of stems and leaves.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Melon.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be certified for interstate movement, melon from Hawaii must be
            inspected in Hawaii and found free of spiraling whitefly (
            <E T='03'>
              Aleurodicus dispersus
            </E>
            ) before undergoing irradiation treatment in Hawaii at a dose
            approved to neutralize fruit flies. Fruit treated for fruit flies
            also must either receive a post-harvest dip in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='305' tq='N'>
                305 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
             to treat external feeders or originate from an orchard or growing
            area that was previously treated with a broad-spectrum insecticide
            during the growing season and a pre-harvest inspection of the
            orchard or growing area found the fruit free of any surface pests as
            prescribed 
            <PRTPAGE P='203' />
            in a compliance agreement. Post-treatment inspection in Hawaii is
            not required if the fruit undergoes irradiation treatment at a dose
            approved to neutralize all plant pests of the class 
            <E T='03'>
              Insecta
            </E>
            , except pupae and adults of the order Lepidoptera. Regardless of
            irradiation dose, melons must be washed to remove dirt and must be
            free of stems and leaves.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Moringa pods.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be certified for interstate movement, moringa pods from Hawaii
            must be inspected in Hawaii and found free of spiraling whitefly (
            <E T='03'>
              Aleurodicus dispersus
            </E>
            ), inornate scale (
            <E T='03'>
              Aonidiella inornata
            </E>
            ), green scale (
            <E T='03'>
              Coccus viridis
            </E>
            ), and citrus mealybug (
            <E T='03'>
              Pseudococcus cryptus
            </E>
            ) before undergoing irradiation treatment in Hawaii at a dose
            approved to neutralize fruit flies. Fruit treated for fruit flies
            also must either receive a post-harvest dip in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='305' tq='N'>
                305 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
             to treat external feeders or originate from an orchard or growing
            area that was previously treated with a broad-spectrum insecticide
            during the growing season and a pre-harvest inspection of the
            orchard or growing area found the fruit free of any surface pests as
            prescribed in a compliance agreement. Post-treatment inspection in
            Hawaii is not required if the fruit undergoes irradiation treatment
            at a dose approved to neutralize all plant pests of the class 
            <E T='03'>
              Insecta
            </E>
            , except pupae and adults of the order Lepidoptera.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 4250
          </aref>
          , Jan. 26, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5327'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:III:-:318:lii81:318.47
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        318.47
      </num>
      <head>
        Notice of quarantine.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          24 FR 10777
        </aref>
        , Dec. 29, 1959, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          66 FR 21054
        </aref>
        , Apr. 27, 2001]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='318' sect='47' psec='' tq='N'>
              318.47
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Notice of quarantine.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Secretary of Agriculture having previously quarantined Hawaii
            and Puerto Rico on account of the pink bollworm of cotton
            (Pectinophora gossypiella Saunders) and the cotton blister mite
            (Eriophyes gossypii Banks), insect pests new to and not widely
            prevalent or distributed within and throughout the United States,
            now determines that it is necessary to extend the quarantine to
            prevent the spread of these insects from the Virgin Islands of the
            United States, where they are known to occur.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Under the authority of 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              sections 411, 412, 414, and 434 of
            </aref>
             the Plant Protection Act (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='7711' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/7711.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 7711
              </subref>
              , 
              <subref title='7' sect='7712' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/7712.html'>
                7712
              </subref>
              , 
              <subref title='7' sect='7714' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/7714.html'>
                7714
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , and 7754), Hawaii, Puerto Rico, and the Virgin Islands of the
            United States are quarantined to prevent the spread of the
            aforementioned insect pests.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All parts and products of plants of the genus Gossypium, such as
            seeds including seed cotton; cottonseed; cotton lint, linters, and
            other forms of cotton fiber; cottonseed hulls, cake, meal, and other
            cottonseed products, except oil; cotton waste; and all other
            unmanufactured parts of cotton plants; and all second-hand burlap
            and other fabric which have been used, or are of the kinds
            ordinarily used, for wrapping or containing cotton, are hereby
            prohibited movement from the Hawaii, Puerto Rico, and the Virgin
            Islands of the United States into or through any other State,
            Territory or District of the United States, in manner or method or
            under conditions other than those prescribed in the regulations
            hereinafter made or amendments thereto: 
            <E T='03'>
              Provided,
            </E>
             That whenever the Deputy Administrator of the Plant Protection and
            Quarantine Programs shall find that existing conditions as to the
            pest risk involved in the movement of the articles to which the
            regulations supplemental hereto apply, make it safe to modify, by
            making less stringent, the restrictions contained in any such
            regulations, he shall set forth and publish such findings in
            administrative instructions, specifying the manner in which the
            regulations should be made less stringent, whereupon such
            modification shall become effective.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             As used in this subpart, unless the context otherwise requires, the
            term 
            <E T='03'>
              State, Territory, or District of the United States
            </E>
             means State, the District of Columbia, Alaska, Guam, Hawaii, Puerto
            Rico, or the Virgin Islands of the United States.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            24 FR 10777
          </aref>
          , Dec. 29, 1959, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            66 FR 21054
          </aref>
          , Apr. 27, 2001]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5329'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:III:-:318:lii81:318.47-1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        318.47-1
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='318' sect='47-1' psec='' tq='N'>
              318.47-1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          For the purpose of the regulations in this subpart the following
          words, names, and terms shall be construed, respectively, to mean:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Cotton.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Parts and products of plants of the genus Gossypium, including seed
            cotton; cottonseed; cotton lint, linters and other forms of cotton
            fiber; cottonseed hulls, cake, meal, and other cottonseed products,
            except oil; cotton waste; and all other unmanufactured parts of
            cotton plants; and second-hand burlap and other fabric which have
            been used, or are of the kinds ordinarily used, for wrapping or
            containing cotton.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Seed cotton.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The unginned lint and seed admixture, just as it is picked from the
            cotton boll.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Cottonseed.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The seed of the cotton plant, either separated from the lint or as
            a component part of seed cotton.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Lint.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All forms of raw or unmanufactured ginned cotton, either baled or
            unbaled, including all cotton fiber, except linters, which has not
            been woven or spun, or otherwise manufactured.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Linters.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All forms of unmanufactured cotton fiber separated from cottonseed
            after the lint has been removed, including that form referred to as
            “hull fiber.”
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Waste.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All forms of cotton waste derived from the manufacture of cotton
            lint, in any form or under any trade designation, including gin
            waste; and waste products derived from the milling of cottonseed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Seedy waste.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Picker waste, gin waste, and oil mill waste, and any other cotton
            by-products capable of carrying a high percentage of cottonseed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Clean waste.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Wastes derived from the processing of lint in machines after the
            card machine, including card strips but not card fly.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Bale covers.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Second-hand burlap and other second-hand fabric by whatever trade
            designation, which have been used, or are of the kinds ordinarily
            used, for wrapping or otherwise containing cotton. Burlap and other
            fabric of the kinds ordinarily used for wrapping cotton, when new or
            unused, are excluded from this definition.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Certificate
            </E>
             (
            <E T='03'>
              certification, certified
            </E>
            ). A type of authorization, evidencing freedom from infestation,
            issued by the Deputy Administrator of the Plant Protection and
            Quarantine Programs to allow the movement of lint, linters, waste,
            seed cotton, cottonseed, cottonseed hulls, cake, and meal, and bale
            covers in accordance with the regulations in this subpart.
            “Certification” and “certified” shall be construed accordingly.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Permit.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A type of general authorization issued by the Deputy Administrator
            of the Plant Protection and Quarantine Programs to allow the
            movement of lint, linters, waste other than seedy waste, cottonseed
            cake and meal, and bale covers in accordance with the regulations in
            this subpart.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='l'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (l)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Fumigated.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Fumigated under the supervision of an inspector of the Plant
            Protection and Quarantine Programs in a fumigation plant approved by
            the Deputy Administrator of said Programs and in accordance with
            methods approved by him.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='m'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (m)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Moved
            </E>
             (
            <E T='03'>
              movement, move
            </E>
            ). Shipped, offered for shipment to a common carrier, received for
            transportation or transported by a common carrier, or carried,
            transported, moved, or allowed to be moved, directly or indirectly,
            from Hawaii, Puerto Rico, or the Virgin Islands of the United
            States, into or through any other State, Territory, or District of
            the United States. “Movement” and “move” shall be construed
            accordingly.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5330'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:III:-:318:lii81:318.47-2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        318.47-2
      </num>
      <head>
        Articles the movement of which is prohibited or regulated.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='318' sect='47-2' psec='' tq='N'>
              318.47-2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Articles the movement of which is prohibited or regulated.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Articles prohibited movement.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The movement of seed cotton, cottonseed, and seedy waste, when
            unfumigated, is prohibited except as provided in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='318' sect='47-3' psec='#b_2' tq='N'>
                318.47-3(b)(2)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Articles the movement of which is regulated.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Lint; linters; waste; seed cotton; cottonseed; cottonseed hulls,
            cake, and meal; and bale covers may be 
            <PRTPAGE P='205' />
            moved upon compliance with the conditions prescribed in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='318' sect='47-3' psec='' tq='N'>
                318.47-3
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5331'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:III:-:318:lii81:318.47-3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        318.47-3
      </num>
      <head>
        Conditions governing the issuance of certificates and permits.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          24 FR 10777
        </aref>
        , Dec. 29, 1959, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 4251
        </aref>
        , Jan. 26, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='318' sect='47-3' psec='' tq='N'>
              318.47-3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Conditions governing the issuance of certificates and permits.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Fumigated lint; linters; waste; seed cotton; cottonseed;
              cottonseed hulls, cake, and meal; and bale covers.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Lint; linters; waste; seed cotton; cottonseed; cottonseed hulls,
            cake, and meal; and bale covers, fumigated in the Territory or
            District of origin in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='305' tq='N'>
                305 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and so certified, are allowed unrestricted movement to any port.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Unfumigated lint, linters, waste, and bale covers.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Unfumigated Hawaiian, Puerto Rican, or Virgin Islands of the United
            States lint, linters, waste other than seedy waste, and bale covers
            will be allowed to move under permit, by all-water route, for entry
            only at the ports of Norfolk, Baltimore, New York, Boston, San
            Francisco, and Seattle, or other port of arrival designated in the
            permit, and at such designated port of arrival shall become subject
            to the regulations governing the handling of cotton imported from
            foreign countries.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Fumigation may be waived and certificates issued for lint, linters,
            and waste which have been determined by an inspector of the Plant
            Protection and Quarantine Programs to have been so manufactured or
            processed by bleaching, dyeing, or other means, as to have removed
            all seeds, or to have destroyed all insect life therein.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Cottonseed cake and meal.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Cottonseed cake and meal which have been inspected in the Territory
            or District of origin and certified by an inspector of the Plant
            Protection and Quarantine Programs as being free from contamination
            with whole, uncrushed cottonseed, will be allowed unrestricted
            movement to any port.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Hawaiian, Puerto Rican, and Virgin Islands of the United States
            cottonseed cake and meal, when neither fumigated nor inspected in
            accordance with the provisions of this section, will be allowed
            entry under permit through any port at which the services of an
            inspector are available, subject to examination by an inspector for
            freedom from contamination with uncrushed cottonseed. If found to be
            free from such contamination, the cottonseed cake or meal may be
            released from further entry restrictions. Cottonseed cake or meal
            found to be contaminated shall be refused entry or subjected as a
            condition of entry and release to such safeguards as may be
            prescribed by the inspector from such administratively approved
            methods as will, in his judgment, be necessary to eliminate
            infestations of the pink bollworm or cotton blister mite.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            24 FR 10777
          </aref>
          , Dec. 29, 1959, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 4251
          </aref>
          , Jan. 26, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5332'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:III:-:318:lii81:318.47-4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        318.47-4
      </num>
      <head>
        Shipments by the Department of Agriculture.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='318' sect='47-4' psec='' tq='N'>
              318.47-4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Shipments by the Department of Agriculture.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Cotton may be moved by the Department of Agriculture for experimental
          or scientific purposes under such conditions as may be prescribed by
          the Deputy Administrator of the Plant Protection and Quarantine
          Programs, which conditions may include clearance through the New Crops
          Research Branch of the Plant Science Research Division, Agricultural
          Research Service.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5328'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:III:-:318:lii81:318.47a
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        318.47a
      </num>
      <head>
        Administrative instructions relating to Guam.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='318' sect='47a' psec='' tq='N'>
              318.47a
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Administrative instructions relating to Guam.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The plants, products and articles specified in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='318' sect='47' psec='#c' tq='N'>
              318.47(c)
            </subref>
          </aref>
           may be moved 
          <PRTPAGE P='204' />
          from Hawaii into or through Guam without restriction under this
          subpart.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5333'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:III:-:318:lii82:318.60
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        318.60
      </num>
      <head>
        Notice of quarantine.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          24 FR 10777
        </aref>
        , Dec. 29, 1959, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          66 FR 21054
        </aref>
        , Apr. 27, 2001]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='318' sect='60' psec='' tq='N'>
              318.60
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Notice of quarantine.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Secretary of Agriculture, having previously quarantined Hawaii
            and Puerto Rico to prevent the spread to other parts of the United
            States, by means of sand, soil, or earth about the roots of plants,
            of immature stages of certain dangerous insects, including
            Phyllophaga spp. (White grubs), Phytalus sp., and Adoretus sp., and
            of several species of termites or white ants, new to and not
            heretofore widely prevalent or distributed within and throughout the
            United States, now determines that it is necessary also to
            quarantine the Virgin Islands of the United States to prevent the
            spread of such dangerous insects from said Virgin Islands.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Under the authority of 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              sections 411, 412, 414, and 434 of
            </aref>
             the Plant Protection Act (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='7711' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/7711.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 7711
              </subref>
              , 
              <subref title='7' sect='7712' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/7712.html'>
                7712
              </subref>
              , 
              <subref title='7' sect='7714' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/7714.html'>
                7714
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , and 7754), Hawaii, Puerto Rico, and the Virgin Islands of the
            United States are quarantined to prevent the spread of the
            aforementioned dangerous insects.
            <PRTPAGE P='206' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Sand (other than clean ocean sand), soil, or earth around the roots
            of plants shall not be shipped, offered for shipment to a common
            carrier, received for transportation or transported by a common
            carrier, or carried, transported, moved, or allowed to be moved by
            any person from Hawaii, Puerto Rico, or the Virgin Islands of the
            United States into or through any other State, Territory, or
            District of the United States: 
            <E T='03'>
              Provided,
            </E>
             That the prohibitions of this section shall not apply to the
            movement of such products in either direction between Puerto Rico
            and the Virgin Islands of the United States: 
            <E T='03'>
              Provided further,
            </E>
             That such prohibitions shall not prohibit the movement of such
            products by the United States Department of Agriculture for
            scientific or experimental purposes, nor prohibit the movement of
            sand, soil, or earth around the roots of plants which are carried,
            for ornamental purposes, on vessels into mainland ports of the
            United States and which are not intended to be landed thereat, when
            evidence is presented satisfactory to the inspector of the Plant
            Protection and Quarantine Programs of the Department of Agriculture
            that such sand, soil, or earth has been so processed or is of such
            nature that no pest risk is involved, or that the plants with sand,
            soil, or earth around them are maintained on board under such
            safeguards as will preclude pest escape: 
            <E T='03'>
              And provided further,
            </E>
             That such prohibitions shall not prohibit the movement of plant
            cuttings or plants that have been (1) freed from sand, soil, and
            earth, (2) subsequently potted and established in sphagnum moss or
            other packing material approved under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='319' sect='37-16' psec='' tq='N'>
                319.37-16
              </subref>
            </aref>
             that had been stored under shelter and had not been previously used
            for growing or packing plants, (3) grown thereafter in a manner
            satisfactory to an inspector of the Plant Protection and Quarantine
            Programs to prevent infestation through contact with sand, soil, or
            earth, and (4) certified by an inspector of the Plant Protection and
            Quarantine Programs as meeting the requirements of paragraphs (c)
            (1), (2), and (3) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             As used in this section, the term 
            <E T='03'>
              State, Territory, or District of the United States
            </E>
             means “Guam, Hawaii, Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands of the United
            States, or the continental United States.”
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            24 FR 10777
          </aref>
          , Dec. 29, 1959, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            66 FR 21054
          </aref>
          , Apr. 27, 2001]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>