<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol15'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXV:-:2502
    </extid>
    <num>
      2502
    </num>
    <head>
      AGRICULTURAL CAREER AND EMPLOYMENT (ACE) GRANTS PROGRAM
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='2008q-1' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/2008q-1.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 2008q-1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 69117
          </aref>
          , Nov. 8, 2011, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='15895'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXV:-:2502:A:2502.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2502.1
      </num>
      <head>
        Applicability of regulations.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2502' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              2502.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Applicability of regulations.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This part contains program-specific definitions for the ACE Grants
            Program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subpart B establishes the criteria to be used in determining
            eligibility for an ACE grant award and the requirements for the
            delivery of program benefits and services, including who is
            considered eligible to receive such benefits and services and what
            the responsibilities are of ACE grantees.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subpart C establishes that, unless otherwise provided herein, the
            procedures for applying for ACE grants, the processes to be followed
            by OAO in evaluating grant proposals and awarding program funds, and
            the procedures for post-award administration of ACE grants are those
            set forth in a rule proposed ON DATE to codify provisions at 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='2500' tq='N'>
                2500
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , subparts A, B, C, D, and E.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15896'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXV:-:2502:A:2502.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2502.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2502' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              2502.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          As used in this part (unless otherwise indicated):
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Agency
          </E>
           means the Office of Advocacy and Outreach (OAO), an agency of the
          United States Department of Agriculture (USDA) or a successor agency.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Agricultural Employer
          </E>
           means any person or entity which employs, as defined in the Migrant
          and Seasonal Agricultural Worker Protection Act, 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='29' sect='1802' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/29/1802.html'>
              29 U.S.C. 1802
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , individuals engaged in agricultural employment and may include
          farmers, ranchers, dairy operators, agricultural cooperatives, and
          farm labor contractors.
          <PRTPAGE P='75' />
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Agricultural Employment
          </E>
           means any service or activity as defined in the Migrant and Seasonal
          Agricultural Worker Protection Act, 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='29' sect='1802' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/29/1802.html'>
              29 U.S.C. 1802
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , including any activity defined as “agriculture” in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            Section 3(f)
          </aref>
           or the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938, 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='29' sect='203' note='' psec='#f' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/29/203.html#f'>
              29 U.S.C. 203(f)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , any activity defined as “agricultural labor” in 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='26' sect='3121' note='' psec='#g' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/26/3121.html#g'>
              26 U.S.C. 3121(g)
            </subref>
          </aref>
           (the Internal Revenue Code); as well as the handling, planting,
          drying, packing, packaging, processing, freezing, or grading prior to
          delivery for storage of any agricultural or horticultural commodity in
          its unmanufactured state. Authorized Departmental Officer (ADO) means
          the individual, acting within the scope of delegated authority, who is
          responsible for executing and administering awards on behalf of the
          U.S. Department of Agriculture.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Community-based organization
          </E>
           means a non-governmental organization with a well-defined
          constituency that includes all or part of a particular community.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Consortium
          </E>
           means a group formed by entities with similar goals and objectives
          for the purpose of pooling resources to undertake a project that would
          otherwise be reasonably beyond the capabilities of any one member.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Eligible entity,
          </E>
           as described in 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 379C(a) of
          </aref>
           the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='2008q' note='' psec='#a' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/2008q.html#a'>
              7 U.S.C. 2008q(a)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ), means a non-profit organization, or a consortium of nonprofit
          organizations, agribusinesses, State and local governments,
          agricultural labor organizations, farmer or rancher cooperatives, and
          community-based organizations with the capacity to train farm workers.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Farmworker
          </E>
           means an individual hired to perform agricultural employment,
          including migrant, seasonal, and hired family farm workers. The term
          farmworker includes individuals who are not currently employed as a
          farmworker but who are actively seeking work as such. The term does
          not include agricultural employers or individuals who are
          self-employed.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Grantee
          </E>
           means the organization designated in the grant award document as the
          responsible legal entity to which a grant is awarded.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Legally present in the United States
          </E>
           shall have the same meaning as the term “lawfully present” in the
          United States as defined at 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            8 CFR 
            <subref title='8' part='103' sect='12' psec='#a' tq='N'>
              103.12(a)
            </subref>
          </aref>
           (addressing eligibility for Title II Social Security benefits under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Pub. L. 104-193' alt='Pub. L. 104-193' href='http://www.gpo.gov/fdsys/pkg/PLAW-104publ193/html/PLAW-104publ193.htm'>
            Pub. L. 104-193
          </aref>
          ).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Notice of Funding Availability (NOFA)
          </E>
           means a notice published in the 
          <E T='04'>
            Federal Register
          </E>
           announcing the availability of money for the grants program which
          lists the application deadlines, eligibility requirements and
          locations where interested parties can get help in applying.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Office of Advocacy and Outreach (OAO)
          </E>
           means the Office of Advocacy and Outreach, an office within the
          USDA&apos;s Departmental Management.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Request for Proposal (RFP)
          </E>
           refers to a grant competition and is used interchangeably with the
          phrase grant application notice and solicitation for grant
          applications (SFA).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Retaining an agricultural job
          </E>
           means continuing agricultural employment, including upgraded
          employment.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Returning from an agricultural job
          </E>
           means returning to a home area from a position in agricultural
          employment.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Secretary
          </E>
           means the Secretary of Agriculture and any other officer or employee
          of the United States Department of Agriculture to whom the authority
          involved is delegated.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Securing an agricultural job
          </E>
           means obtaining agricultural employment.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State
          </E>
           means any of the States of the United States, the District of
          Columbia, the Virgin Islands, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and
          Guam.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            United States worker (U.S. worker)
          </E>
           shall have the same meaning as the term U.S. worker defined by the
          Department of Labor at 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            20 CFR 
            <subref title='20' part='655' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              655.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Upgrading an agricultural job
          </E>
           means advancement to a position in agricultural employment which
          offers more hours of work and/or better terms and conditions of
          employment and/or an increase in wages.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15897'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXV:-:2502:A:2502.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2502.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Deviations.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2502' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              2502.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Deviations.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Any request by the applicant or grantee for a waiver or deviation from
          any provision of this part shall be submitted to the ADO identified in
          the agency specific requirements. OAO shall review the request and
          notify the applicant/grantee whether the request to deviate has been
          approved within 30 calendar days from the date of receipt 
          <PRTPAGE P='76' />
          of the deviation request. If the deviation request is still under
          consideration at the end of 30 calendar days, OAO shall inform the
          applicant/grantee in writing of the date when the applicant/grantee
          may expect the decision.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15898'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXV:-:2502:B:2502.4.
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2502.4.
      </num>
      <head>
        Program eligibility.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2502' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              2502.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Program eligibility.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Entities eligible to apply for and receive a grant under this part
            include:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A non-profit organization;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A consortium of nonprofit organizations; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A consortium which includes a non-profit organization(s) and one or
            more of the following: agribusinesses, State and local governments,
            agricultural labor organizations, farmer or rancher cooperatives,
            and community-based organizations with the capacity to train farm
            workers.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Additional information about eligible entities may be included in
            the RFP. In addition, the RFP will specify the criteria by which an
            entity&apos;s capacity to train farm workers will be evaluated, but
            at a minimum, the entity shall be required to demonstrate that it
            has:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An understanding of the issues facing hired farmworkers and
            conditions under which they work;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Familiarity with the agricultural industry in the geographic area
            to be served, including agricultural labor needs and existing
            services for farmworkers; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The capacity to effectively administer a program of services and
            benefits authorized by the ACE program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An applicant will be required to submit information to OAO, as
            specified in the RFP and/or FOA as part of the grant application.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15899'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXV:-:2502:B:2502.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2502.5
      </num>
      <head>
        Program benefits and services.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2502' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              2502.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Program benefits and services.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The ACE grants program will be centrally administered by the USDA
            in a manner consistent with these regulations, as well as the
            pertinent requirements of 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3015' tq='N'>
                3015, 7
              </subref>
            </aref>
             CFR 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='3016' tq='N'>
                3016
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3018' tq='N'>
                3018, 7
              </subref>
            </aref>
             CFR 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='3019' tq='N'>
                3019
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR 3052
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Office of Advocacy and Outreach (OAO) has been designated as
            the organizational unit responsible for administering the ACE
            program, including, among other things, determining the number and
            amount of grants to be awarded, the purposes for the grants to be
            awarded, as well as the criteria for the evaluation and award of
            grants.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Services and benefits provided under the ACE grants program are
            limited to those which will assist eligible farmworkers in securing,
            retaining, upgrading or returning from agricultural jobs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Such services will include the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Agricultural labor skills development
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provision of agricultural labor market information:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Transportation:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Short-term housing while in transit to an agricultural worksite;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Workplace literacy and assistance with English as a second
            language;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Health and safety instruction, including ways of safeguarding the
            food supply of the United States;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Such other services as the Secretary deems appropriate.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Grant funds shall not be used to deliver or replace any services or
            benefits which an agricultural employer, association, contractor, or
            any other entity is legally obliged to provide.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15900'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXV:-:2502:B:2502.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2502.6
      </num>
      <head>
        Recipients of program benefits or services.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2502' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              2502.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Recipients of program benefits or services.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Those eligible to receive program services or benefits under the
            ACE program are farmworkers who meet the definition of “United
            States Workers” as set forth in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='2502' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
                2502.2
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Grantees shall be responsible for verifying the employment of
            farmworkers who are actively employed and are seeking to participate
            in program services or benefits. Unemployed farmworkers seeking to
            participate shall be required to certify to grantees that they are
            eligible for program services and benefits as provided herein.
            Additional eligibility requirements may be included in the RFP.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15901'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXV:-:2502:B:2502.7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2502.7
      </num>
      <head>
        Responsibilities of grantees.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2502' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              2502.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Responsibilities of grantees.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Each grantee is responsible for providing services and/or benefits
          authorized by this program in accord with a service delivery strategy
          described in 
          <PRTPAGE P='77' />
          its approved grant plan. The services must reflect the needs of the
          relevant farmworker population in the area to be served and be
          consistent with the goals of assisting farmworkers in securing,
          retaining, upgrading, or returning from agricultural jobs. The
          necessary components of a service delivery strategy and grant plan
          will be fully set forth in an RFP but the plan shall include, at a
          minimum, the following:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The employment and education needs of the farmworker population to
            be served;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The manner in which the proposed services to be delivered will
            assist agricultural employers and farmworkers in securing,
            retaining, upgrading or returning from agricultural jobs;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The manner in which the proposed services will be coordinated with
            other available services;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The number of participants the grantee expects to serve for each
            service provided, the results expected and the anticipated
            expenditures for each category of service.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15902'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXV:-:2502:C:2502.8
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2502.8
      </num>
      <head>
        Pre-award, award, and post-award procedures and administration of
        grants.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2502' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              2502.8
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Pre-award, award, and post-award procedures and administration of
          grants.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Unless otherwise provided in this rule, the requirements governing
            pre-award solicitation and submission of proposals and/or
            applications, the review and evaluation of such, the award of grant
            funds, and post-award and close-out procedures are those set forth
            at 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='2500' tq='N'>
                2500
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , subparts A, B, C, D, and E.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For purposes of the ACE Grants Program, the provisions of Subpart
            E, at 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR 
              <subref title='7' part='2500' sect='49' psec='' tq='N'>
                2500.49
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , “Prior Approvals,” shall not apply. In lieu of that provision, the
            following requirements shall apply: Awardees may not subcontract
            more than 20 percent of the award to other parties without prior
            written approval of the ADO. To request approval, a justification
            for the proposed subcontract, a performance statement, and a
            detailed budget for the subcontract must be submitted in writing to
            the ADO.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>