<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol15'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIII:-:3300
    </extid>
    <num>
      3300
    </num>
    <head>
      AGREEMENT ON THE INTERNATIONAL CARRIAGE OF PERISHABLE FOODSTUFFS AND ON
      THE SPECIAL EQUIPMENT TO BE USED FOR SUCH CARRIAGE (ATP); INSPECTION,
      TESTING, AND CERTIFICATION OF SPECIAL EQUIPMENT
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            Sec. 4
          </aref>
          , 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Pub. L. 97-325' alt='Pub. L. 97-325' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d97:./list/bd/d97pl.lst:325%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Pub. L. 97-325
          </aref>
          , International Carriage of Perishable Foodstuffs Act (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='4403' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/4403.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 4403
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ).
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            51 FR 33879
          </aref>
          , Sept. 24, 1986, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='16378'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIII:-:3300:A:3300.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3300.1
      </num>
      <head>
        Scope of authority and purpose.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3300' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              3300.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Scope of authority and purpose.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The International Carriage of Perishable Foodstuffs Act assigns to the
          Secretary of Agriculture the responsibility for implementation of the
          Agreement on the International Carriage of Perishable Foodstuffs and
          on the Special Equipment to be Used for Such Carriage (ATP). The
          purpose of this rule is to establish procedures for the inspection,
          testing, and certification of insulated, refrigerated, mechanically
          refrigerated, and heated transport equipment in accordance with the
          Act and the standards specified in the Agreement. In the process, the
          intent is to utilize existing industry organizations and facilities
          for testing and inspection of equipment. The Secretary is the sole
          authority to issue certificates of compliance.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16379'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIII:-:3300:A:3300.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3300.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3300' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              3300.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Administrator
          </E>
           means the Administrator, Office of Transportation, U.S. Department of
          Agriculture, whose address is: 1405 Auditors Building, 201 14th
          Street, SW., Washington, DC 20250.
          <PRTPAGE P='334' />
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            ATP
          </E>
           means the Agreement on the International Carriage of Perishable
          Foodstuffs and on the Special Equipment to be Used for Such Carriage
          (ATP), and the annexes and appendices thereto, done at Geneva,
          September 1, 1970, under the auspices of the Economic Commission for
          Europe, and any subsequent amendments thereto. 
          <SU>
            1
          </SU>
          <FTREF />
        </P>
        <FTNT>
          <P>
            <SU>
              1
            </SU>
             A copy of the agreement can be obtained by request to the ATP
            Manager, Office of Transportation, U.S. Department of Agriculture,
            1405 Auditors Building, 201 14th Street, SW., Washington, DC 20250.
          </P>
        </FTNT>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            ATP manager
          </E>
           means the person designated by the Administrator to manage the
          program established by this rule, whose address is: ATP Manager,
          Office of Transportation, U.S Department of Agriculture, 1405 Auditors
          Building, 201 14th Street, SW., Washington, DC 20250.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Contracting party
          </E>
           means a country which is signatory to the ATP.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Domestic owner
          </E>
           means an organization incorporated or chartered under the laws of,
          and with principal office in, the United States, and to which one of
          the following applies:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The organization owns and operates the equipment directly.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The organization owns and operates the equipment through a wholly
            owned subsidiary in a foreign country.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The organization is a lessee or bailee of the equipment, and a
            written lease or bailment provides that the organization is
            responsible for any inspection, testing, and certification of the
            equipment with respect to the ATP rule.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Equipment
          </E>
           means the special transport equipment that meets the definitions and
          standards set forth in ATP, Annex 1, including, but not limited to,
          railcars, trucks, trailers, semitrailers, and intermodal freight
          containers that have an insulated body only, or an insulated body
          equipped with a refrigerating, mechanically refrigerating, or heating
          appliance.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Equipment manufacturer
          </E>
           means an organization which producers or assembles the complete unit
          of equipment, that is, the insulated body with the thermal appliance
          installed.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Foreign owner
          </E>
           means an organization registered under the laws of, or with principal
          office in, a country outside the United States, and which owns or
          operates the equipment.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Foreign-ATP certificate
          </E>
           means a certificate issued by a foreign country which is a
          contracting party to the ATP, attesting that the equipment listed in
          the certificate complies with pertinent standards in the ATP.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Identical mechanical refrigerating appliance
          </E>
           means an appliance which is of the same model number and design as
          the reference mechanical refrigerating appliance.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Insulated body
          </E>
           means the six-sided structural component of equipment, consisting of
          insulated doors, sidewalls, roof, floor, and endwall, inside which
          perishable foodstuffs are carried.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            International carriage
          </E>
           means transportation of perishable foodstuffs if such foodstuffs are
          loaded in equipment or the equipment containing them is loaded onto a
          rail or road vehicle, in the territory of any country and such
          foodstuffs are, or the equipment containing them is, unloaded in the
          territory of another country that is a contracting party, where such
          transportation is by:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Rail,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Road,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any combination of rail and road, or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any sea crossing of less than one hundred and fifty kilometers, if
            preceded or followed by one or more land journeys as referred to in
            clauses (a), (b), and (c) of this definition, and the perishable
            foodstuffs are shipped in the same equipment used for such land
            journeys without transloading of such foodstuffs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <FP>
          In the case of any transportation that involves one or more sea
          crossings other than as specified in clause (d) of this definition,
          each land journey shall be considered separately.
        </FP>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            New equipment
          </E>
           means equipment produced or assembled on or after the effective date
          of this rule.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Perishable foodstuffs
          </E>
           means the quick deep-frozen and frozen food products listed in Annex
          2, and the chilled food products listed in Annex 3 to the ATP.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Reference equipment
          </E>
           means a unit of equipment which has passed a test in an approved
          testing station, and can thereby serve as a basis for certification of
          related serially-produced equipment.
          <PRTPAGE P='335' />
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Reference insulated body
          </E>
           means an insulated body which has passed a test in an approved
          testing station for measurement of the K-coefficient of the body, and
          can thereby serve as the basis for approval of serially-produced
          bodies in the case in which the body and the mechanical refrigerating
          appliance of the equipment are tested separately.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Reference mechanical refrigerating appliance
          </E>
           means an appliance which has passed a test in an approved testing
          laboratory, and can thereby serve as the basis for approval of
          identical mechanical refrigerating appliances in the case in which the
          appliance and the insulated body of the equipment are tested
          separately.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Serially-produced bodies
          </E>
           means insulated bodies which meet the definition in ATP, Annex 1
          Appendix 1, paragraph 2(c)(i).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Serially-produced equipment
          </E>
           means equipment of a specific type (container, semi-trailer, trailer,
          truck, or container), which meets the definition in ATP, Annex 1,
          Appendix 1, paragraphs 2(c), (i), (ii), (iii), and (iv).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Thermal appliance
          </E>
           means the refrigerating, mechanical refrigerating, or heating
          appliance which is installed in the insulated body of the equipment.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            United States
          </E>
           means the fifty States of the United States, the District of
          Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the
          Virgin Islands of the United States, the Commonwealth of the Northern
          Mariana Islands, and any other territory or possession of the United
          States.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            U.S. ATP certificate
          </E>
           means a certificate issued by the U.S. Department of Agriculture,
          attesting that the equipment listed in the certificate complies with
          pertinent standards in the ATP.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            U.S. ATP testing laboratory
          </E>
           means a facility in the United States which has been approved by the
          Administrator to conduct tests of mechanical refrigerating appliances.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            U.S. ATP testing station
          </E>
           means a facility in the United States which has been approved by the
          Administrator to conduct tests of equipment.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16380'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIII:-:3300:B:3300.7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3300.7
      </num>
      <head>
        General.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3300' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              3300.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Testing of equipment according to the ATP is basically done in two
          phases:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Measurement of the insulating capacity, that is, the K-coefficient,
            of the insulated body.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Determination of the efficiency of the thermal appliance as
            installed in the insulated body. In the case of mechanically
            refrigerated equipment, the mechanical refrigerating appliance may
            be tested separate from the body.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16381'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIII:-:3300:B:3300.10
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3300.10
      </num>
      <head>
        Measurement of the K-coefficient of an insulated body.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3300' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
              3300.10
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Measurement of the K-coefficient of an insulated body.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The K-coefficient shall be measured according to the procedures in
          ATP, Annex 1, Appendix 2, paragraphs 1-28, and the following shall
          apply:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The internal heating method shall be used.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In ATP, Annex 1, Appendix 2, paragraph 8, last line, “about +20 °C
            for the mean temperature of the walls of the body shall be
            interpreted to mean between +19 °C (+66 °F) and 21 °C (+70 °F).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A report of each test shall be completed on a form corresponding to
            the pertinent test report model prescribed in ATP, Annex 1, Appendix
            2. Report forms may be obtained by a request to the ATP manager.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16382'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIII:-:3300:B:3300.13
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3300.13
      </num>
      <head>
        Determination of the efficiency of the thermal appliances as installed
        in the insulated body.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3300' sect='13' psec='' tq='N'>
              3300.13
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Determination of the efficiency of the thermal appliances as installed
          in the insulated body.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          In determining the efficiency of a thermal appliance with respect to
          maintaining a prescribed temperature inside the body, the procedures
          in ATP, Annex 1, Appendix 2, paragraphs 31-40 and 43-47 shall be used.
          A report of each test shall be completed on a form corresponding to
          the pertinent test report model prescribed in ATP, Annex 1, Appendix
          2. Report forms may be obtained by a request to the ATP manager.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16383'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIII:-:3300:C:3300.16
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3300.16
      </num>
      <head>
        General.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3300' sect='16' psec='' tq='N'>
              3300.16
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Any public or private organization incorporated or chartered under the
          laws of, and with principal office in, the United States may apply to
          have one or more of its facilities in the United States designated as
          a U.S. ATP testing station.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16384'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIII:-:3300:C:3300.19
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3300.19
      </num>
      <head>
        Application for approval.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3300' sect='19' psec='' tq='N'>
              3300.19
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Application for approval.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          An application by an officer of the organization shall be submitted to
          the Administrator for each facility for which approval is sought.
          Copies of the Form, Application for Approval as a U.S. ATP Testing
          Station, may be obtained by a request to the ATP manager. The
          following information must be supplied in the application:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A statement that the organization is incorporated or chartered
            under the laws of, and that it has its principal office in, the
            United States, including the name, address, and telephone number of
            the principal office.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The address and telephone number of the testing station, and name
            and title of person in charge of the station.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A summary of experience at the facility which would indicate the
            capability to conduct tests of equipment according to Subpart B of
            this rule.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A general description of the station, including drawings on letter
            size (8 
            <FR>
              1/2
            </FR>
             × 11 inches) paper to show the floor plan and cross-sections of the
            test chamber, basic dimensions, location of heat exchangers and
            instruments, and any other pertinent information.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An indication of which of the following types of equipment, as
            defined in ATP, Annex 1, that the station is capable of testing:
            intermodal freight containers, semi-trailers, trailers, railcars,
            and trucks.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A statement that the ATP manager or other representative of the
            Administrator may, before a decision is made concerning the
            application, observe a test at the station of a Class “C”
            mechanically refrigerated container or semi-trailer, with Class “C”
            being defined as in ATP, Annex 1, paragraph 3.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A statement that the station will be open to public use, that is,
            to manufacturers and owners of equipment which may apply to have
            equipment tested.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A statement that the fees to be charged by the organization for
            testing will be reasonable with respect to costs involved, and that
            such fees will be payable directly to the organization by those who
            seek testing of their equipment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A statement that the station will maintain records of basic data
            developed in each test conducted under this rule, such records to be
            available for review by the ATP manager or other representative of
            the Administrator upon request. The record for each test shall be
            maintained for a period of three years.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A statement that the organization will advise the ATP manager as
            soon as practicable of its intent to conduct a test under this rule
            and that it will, as soon as possible, advise when a firm test date
            has been set so that the ATP manager or other representative of the
            Administrator may observe the test.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A statement that the organization will send to the ATP manager a
            copy of each test report for equipment tested at the station
            according to this rule, within 30 days after completion of the test.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='l'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (l)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A statement that, should any significant change occur in the
            facility with respect to structure or test equipment as a result of
            redesign or other cause during the period of approval, the
            organization will so advise the ATP manager within 30 days after
            such change.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='m'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (m)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any other pertinent information.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16385'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIII:-:3300:C:3300.22
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3300.22
      </num>
      <head>
        Response to application for approval.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3300' sect='22' psec='' tq='N'>
              3300.22
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Response to application for approval.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The Administrator will, within 30 days of receipt of the application
          and any relevant information required, advise the applicant whether or
          not the facility is approved as a testing station. Approval is for a
          5-year period.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16386'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIII:-:3300:C:3300.25
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3300.25
      </num>
      <head>
        Application for renewal of approval.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3300' sect='25' psec='' tq='N'>
              3300.25
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Application for renewal of approval.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          If an organization wishes to have an approval renewed at the end of a
          5-year 
          <PRTPAGE P='337' />
          period, it shall submit a request for renewal to the Administrator 90
          days before expiration of the existing approval. The request for
          renewal shall contain the same type of information as required in the
          original application, that is, the information called for in 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            § 3300.19 of
          </aref>
           subpart C.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16387'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIII:-:3300:C:3300.28
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3300.28
      </num>
      <head>
        Response to application for renewal of approval.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3300' sect='28' psec='' tq='N'>
              3300.28
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Response to application for renewal of approval.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The Administrator will, within 30 days of receipt of application and
          any relevant information required, advise the applicant whether or not
          approval is renewed. A renewal is good for 5 years.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16388'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIII:-:3300:C:3300.31
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3300.31
      </num>
      <head>
        Termination of approval.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3300' sect='31' psec='' tq='N'>
              3300.31
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Termination of approval.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          An approved testing station may at any time withdraw as an approved
          testing station by written notice to the Administrator. Similarly, the
          Administrator may suspend or terminate for cause the approved status
          of a testing station by written notice to the organization, setting
          forth the reasons for such action. Examples of causes for suspension
          or termination of approval of a testing station would be a change in
          equipment or operations at the station which would render the station
          incapable of performing tests according to the standards in the ATP,
          or noncompliance of the station with pertinent portions of this rule.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16389'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIII:-:3300:D:3300.34
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3300.34
      </num>
      <head>
        General.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3300' sect='34' psec='' tq='N'>
              3300.34
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          ATP, Annex 1, Appendix 2, paragraph 41, provides that approval of
          mechanically refrigerated equipment may be done on the basis of
          separate testing of the mechanical refrigerating appliance.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16390'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIII:-:3300:D:3300.37
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3300.37
      </num>
      <head>
        Testing of a mechanical refrigerating appliance.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3300' sect='37' psec='' tq='N'>
              3300.37
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Testing of a mechanical refrigerating appliance.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          For separate testing of a mechanical refrigerating appliance, the
          following shall pertain:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The calibrated-box method shall be used, as set forth in ARI
            Standard 1110, Standard for Mechanical Refrigeration Units, of the
            Air-Conditioning and Refrigeration Institute.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The appliance shall be rated according to the class, or classes, of
            service for which the appliance is intended, with classes being
            defined as in ATP, Annex 1, paragraph 3.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A report of each test shall be completed on a form corresponding to
            the pertinent test report model prescribed in ATP, Annex 1, Appendix
            2. Report forms may be obtained by a request to the ATP manager.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16391'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIII:-:3300:E:3300.40
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3300.40
      </num>
      <head>
        General.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3300' sect='40' psec='' tq='N'>
              3300.40
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Any public or private organization incorporated or chartered under the
          laws of, and with principal office in, the United States may apply to
          have one or more of its facilities in the United States designated as
          a U.S. ATP testing laboratory.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16392'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIII:-:3300:E:3300.43
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3300.43
      </num>
      <head>
        Application for approval.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3300' sect='43' psec='' tq='N'>
              3300.43
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Application for approval.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          An application by an officer of the organization shall be submitted to
          the Administrator for each facility for which approval is sought.
          Copies of the Form, Application for Approval as a U.S. ATP Testing
          Laboratory, may be obtained by a request to the ATP manager. The
          following information must be supplied in the application:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A statement that the organization is incorporated or chartered
            under the laws of, and that it has its principal office in, the
            United States, including the address and telephone number of the
            principal office.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The address and telephone number of the testing laboratory, and
            name and title of person in charge of the laboratory.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A summary of the experience at the facility which would indicate a
            capability to conduct tests of mechanical refrigerating appliances
            according to subpart D of this rule.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A general description of the laboratory, including drawings on
            letter size (8
            <FR>
              1/2
            </FR>
             × 11 inches) paper to show the floor plan and cross-section of the
            test chamber, basic dimensions, location of heat exchangers and
            instruments, and any other pertinent information.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A statement that the ATP manager or other representative of the
            Administrator may, before a decision is 
            <PRTPAGE P='338' />
            made concerning the application, observe a test at the laboratory of
            a mechanical refrigerating appliance for a Class “C” mechanically
            refrigerated container or trailer, with Class “C” as defined in ATP,
            Annex 1, paragraph 3.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A statement that the laboratory will maintain records of basic data
            developed in each test conducted under this rule, such records to be
            available for review by the ATP manager or other representative of
            the Administrator, upon request. The record for each test shall be
            maintained for a period of three years.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A statement that the organization will advise the ATP manager as
            soon as practicable of its intent to conduct a test under this rule
            and that it will, as soon as possible, advise when a firm test has
            been set so that the ATP manager or other representative of the
            Administrator may observe the test.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A statement that the organization will send to the ATP manager a
            copy of each test report for an appliance tested at the laboratory
            according to this rule, within 30 days after completion of the test.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A statement that, should any significant change occur in the
            facility with respect to structure or test equipment as a result of
            redesign or other cause during the period of approval, the
            organization will so advise the ATP manager within 30 days after
            such change.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any other pertinent information.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16393'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIII:-:3300:E:3300.46
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3300.46
      </num>
      <head>
        Response to application for approval.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3300' sect='46' psec='' tq='N'>
              3300.46
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Response to application for approval.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The Administrator will, within 30 days of receipt of an application
          and any relevant information required, advise the applicant whether or
          not the facility is approved as a testing laboratory. Approval is for
          a 5-year period from date of approval.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16394'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIII:-:3300:E:3300.49
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3300.49
      </num>
      <head>
        Application for renewal of approval.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3300' sect='49' psec='' tq='N'>
              3300.49
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Application for renewal of approval.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          If an organization wishes to have an approval renewed at the end of a
          5-year period, it shall submit a request for renewal to the
          Administrator 90 days before expiration of the existing approval. The
          request for renewal shall contain the same type of information as
          required in the original application, that is, the information called
          for in 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            § 3300.43 of
          </aref>
           subpart E.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16395'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIII:-:3300:E:3300.52
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3300.52
      </num>
      <head>
        Response to application for renewal of approval.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3300' sect='52' psec='' tq='N'>
              3300.52
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Response to application for renewal of approval.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The Administrator will, within 30 days of receipt of application and
          any relevant information required, advise the applicant whether or not
          approval is renewed. A renewal extends the period of approval for 5
          years.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16396'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIII:-:3300:E:3300.55
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3300.55
      </num>
      <head>
        Termination of approval.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3300' sect='55' psec='' tq='N'>
              3300.55
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Termination of approval.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          An approved testing laboratory may at any time withdraw as an approved
          testing laboratory by written notice to the Administrator. Similarly,
          the Administrator may suspend or terminate for cause the approved
          status of a testing laboratory by written notice to the organization,
          setting forth the reasons for such action. Examples of causes for
          suspension or termination of approval would be a change in equipment
          or operations at the laboratory which would render it incapable of
          performing tests according to the standards in the ATP, or
          noncompliance of the laboratory with pertinent portions of this rule.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16397'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIII:-:3300:F:3300.58
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3300.58
      </num>
      <head>
        General.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3300' sect='58' psec='' tq='N'>
              3300.58
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The following shall apply for certification of new equipment:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Domestic owners are eligible to receive U.S. ATP certificates for
            equipment produced or assembled in the United States or in a foreign
            country.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Foreign owners are eligible to receive U.S. ATP certificates only
            for equipment produced or assembled in the United States.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For equipment manufactured (
            <E T='03'>
              i.e.
            </E>
            , produced or assembled) in the United States:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When the complete unit of equipment is tested, the test shall be
            performed in a U.S. ATP testing station.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When the mechanical refrigerating appliance and the insulated body
            are tested separately, such tests shall be performed in approved
            testing facilities in the United States or in test facilities
            located in, and approved by, a foreign country which is a
            Contracting Party.
            <PRTPAGE P='339' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For equipment manufactured in a foreign country which is a
            Contracting Party, a domestic owner may receive a U.S. ATP
            certiticate in exchange for the Foreign-ATP certificate issued by
            the country of manufacture.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For equipment manufactured in a foreign country which is not a
            Contracting Party, tests shall be performed in approved testing
            facilities in the United States or in facilities located in and
            approved by a foreign country which is a Contracting Party.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In accordance with ATP, Annex 1, Appendix 1, paragraphs 2(a) and
            (d), the validity of a test report for a reference equipment shall
            expire at the end of a period of 3 years or at the end of the
            manufacture of 1,000 units of serially-produced equipment, whichever
            occurs first.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The validity of a test report for a reference mechanical
            refrigerating appliance shall expire at the end of a period of three
            years, or at the end of the manufacture of 1,000 identical
            mechanical refrigerating appliances, whichever occurs first.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The validity of a test report for a reference insulated body shall
            expire at the end of a period of three years, or at the end of the
            manufacture of 1,000 serially-produced bodies, whichever occurs
            first.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Serially-produced equipment shall be produced or assembled by the
            same manufacturer and at the same manufacturing plant as the
            reference equipment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Identical mechanical refrigerating appliances shall be manufactured
            by the same manufacturer and at the same manufacturing plant as the
            reference mechanical refrigerating appliance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Serially-produced bodies shall be manufactured by the same
            manufacturer and at the same manufacturing plant as the reference
            insulated body.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='l'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (l)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Equipment manufacturers shall notify the ATP manager 30 days before
            start of manufacture so that the ATP manager or other representative
            of the Administrator may observe the manufacturing operation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='m'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (m)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Owners who receive a U.S. ATP certificate have the responsibility
            to manitain the equipment in good repair and operating condition
            with the understanding that the certificate is valid only so long
            as:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='m_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The insulated body and the thermal appliance are maintained in good
            condition;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='m_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No material alteration is made to the thermal appliance which
            decreases its refrigerating capacity, and;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='m_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the thermal appliance is replaced, it is replaced by an
            appliance of equal or greater refrigerating capacity.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16398'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIII:-:3300:F:3300.61
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3300.61
      </num>
      <head>
        Testing and verification requirements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3300' sect='61' psec='' tq='N'>
              3300.61
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Testing and verification requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          In accordance with ATP, Annex 1, Appendix 1, paragraphs 1, 1(a), 2(a),
          2(b), 2(c) and 3, and Appendix 2, paragraph 41, certification of new
          equipment is based upon the following:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For a unit of equipment, a test of the equipment in an approved
            testing station.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For serially-produced equipment:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A test of one unit of equipment in an approved testing station,
            such unit to serve as the reference equipment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Verification that production of other units of equipment is in
            conformity with the reference equipment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For mechanically refrigerated equipment, certification may be based
            upon a separate test of the mechanical refrigerating appliance and a
            separate test of the insulated body.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16399'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIII:-:3300:F:3300.64
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3300.64
      </num>
      <head>
        Application for certificate for new equipment produced or assembled in
        the United States or in a foreign country which is not a contracting
        party to the ATP.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3300' sect='64' psec='' tq='N'>
              3300.64
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Application for certificate for new equipment produced or assembled in
          the United States or in a foreign country which is not a contracting
          party to the ATP.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Application for certification shall be submitted to the ATP manager by
          an officer in the organization of the owner of the equipment. In the
          case of equipment manufactured in the United States, application may
          be made by an officer in the organization of the equipment
          manufacturer, acting on behalf of the owner. Copies of the Form,
          Application for U.S. ATP Certificate for New Equipment Produced or
          Assembled in the United States or in a Foreign Country Which is not a
          Contracting Party to the ATP, may be obtained by a request to the ATP
          manager. The following information must be supplied in the
          application:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A statement whether the owner is a domestic owner or a foreign
            owner, with the name, address and telephone 
            <PRTPAGE P='340' />
            number of its principal office, and the name and title of person to
            contact.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the operator of the equipment is different from the owner, the
            name and address of the operator.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Type of equipment (intermodal freight container, semi-trailer,
            trailer, railcar, or truck).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Total number of units of equipment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Definition and distinguishing mark of the equipment for which
            certification is sought, referring to ATP, Annex 1, paragraph 3 and
            Appendix 4.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Name, address, and telephone number of the principal office of the
            equipment manufacturer, and name and title of the person to contact.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Name and address of the plant at which the equipment was
            manufactured.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the case of a unit of equipment (
            <E T='03'>
              i.e.
            </E>
            , the insulated body with its mechanical refrigerating appliance
            installed) that has been tested to serve as the reference equipment
            for serially-produced equipment:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The original or certified true copy of the test report for the
            reference equipment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For the serially-produced equipment:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The manufacturer&apos;s make and model number for the equipment,
            including a brief description of the equipment and enclosure of any
            brochure on the equipment which might be available.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The basis upon which the equipment meets the definition of
            serially-produced equipment, with respect to the reference
            equipment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A statement that the equipment was manufactured at the same plant
            at which the reference equipment was manufactured.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_2_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A statement that production of the equipment was in conformity with
            the reference equipment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the case where the mechanical refrigerating appliance and the
            insulated body have been tested separately:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For the reference mechanical refrigerating appliance:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The original or certified true copy of the test report.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             From the test report, the effective refrigerating capacity, W, in
            watts, of the appliance at an outside temperature of +30 °C and the
            inside temperature (
            <E T='03'>
              see
            </E>
             ATP, Annex 1, paragraph 3 and Appendix 4) for the class of
            equipment for which certification is sought. “W” must be equal to,
            or greater than, the increased heat transfer rate, H
            <E T='52'>
              i
            </E>
            , for the reference insulated body. See paragraph (3)(iii) below.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For the identical mechanical refrigerating appliances:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Name and address of the plant at which the identical appliances and
            reference appliance were manufactured.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The manufacturer&apos;s make, model number, and a brief description
            of the appliances with enclosure of any brochure on the appliances
            which might be available.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A statement that the appliances meet the definition of identical
            mechanical refrigerating appliances.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For the reference insulated body:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The original or certified true copy of the test report.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The total heat transfer rate of the body, H
            <E T='52'>
              t
            </E>
            =S×K×Δ T, in watts, where: “S” is the mean surface area of the body,
            from the test report; “K” is the heat transfer coefficient of the
            body, from the test report; and, “Δ T” is the difference in degrees
            Kelvin between an outside temperature of +30 °C and the inside
            temperature for the class of equipment for which certification is
            sought.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The increased beat transfer rate, H
            <E T='52'>
              i
            </E>
            , obtained by multiplying the total heat transfer rate H
            <E T='52'>
              t
            </E>
            , by the factor of 1.75.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For the serially-produced insulated bodies:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_4_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Name and address of the plant at which the serially-produced bodies
            and reference body were manufactured.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_4_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The manufacturer&apos;s make, model number, and a brief description
            of the bodies, with any brochure on the bodies which might be
            available.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_4_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The basis upon which the bodies meet the definition of
            serially-produced bodies, with respect to the reference insulated
            body.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_4_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A statement that production of the bodies was in conformity with
            the reference insulated body.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Information on the equipment after manufacture:
            <PRTPAGE P='341' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A statement that each mechanical refrigerating appliance, after it
            was installed in the body, was operated and thoroughly checked and
            that each appliance functioned properly.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A statement that each body and each appliance has affixed to it a
            manufacturer&apos;s plate or other means of identification which
            shows the items of information required by ATP, Annex 1, paragraph
            6.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A statement that each unit of equipment, before it is put into
            service, will have affixed to it a certification plate and
            distinguishing mark as specified in ATP, Annex 1, Appendix 1,
            paragraphs 4 and 5, and Appendixes 3 and 4.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A list showing, for each unit of equipment, the serial number of
            the body and the corresponding owner&apos;s equipment identification
            number.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16400'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIII:-:3300:F:3300.67
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3300.67
      </num>
      <head>
        Application for certificate for new equipment produced or assembled in a
        foreign country which is a contracting party to the ATP.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3300' sect='67' psec='' tq='N'>
              3300.67
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Application for certificate for new equipment produced or assembled in
          a foreign country which is a contracting party to the ATP.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          An application for certification of equipment shall be submitted to
          the ATP manager by an officer in the organization of the owner of the
          equipment. Copies of the Form, Application for U.S. ATP Certificate
          for New Equipment Produced or Assembled in a Foreign Country Which is
          a Contracting Party, may be obtained by a request to the ATP manager.
          The following information must be submitted in the application:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A statement that the owner is a domestic owner, with the name,
            address and telephone number of its principal office, and the name
            and title of the person to contact.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the operator of the equipment is different from the owner, the
            name and address of the operator.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The type of equipment (intermodal freight container, trailer,
            semi-trailer, railcar, or truck.)
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Total number of units of equipment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Definition of the equipment for which certification is sought,
            referring to ATP, Annex 1, paragraph 3, and Appendix 4.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Name, address, and telephone number of the manufacturer of the
            equipment, and the name and title of the person to contact.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The manufacturer&apos;s make and model number for the equipment,
            including a brief description of the equipment and any brochure on
            the equipment which might be available.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The original or certified true copy of the test report for the
            reference equipment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The original or certified true copy of the Foreign-ATP certificate
            issued for the equipment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A statement that each unit of equipment, before it is put into
            service, will have affixed to it a certification plate and
            distinguishing mark as specified in ATP, Annex 1, Appendix 1,
            paragraphs 4 and 5, and Appendixes 3 and 4.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A list showing, for each unit of equipment, the serial number of
            the body and the corresponding owner&apos;s equipment identification
            number.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16401'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIII:-:3300:F:3300.70
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3300.70
      </num>
      <head>
        Issuance of certificate.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3300' sect='70' psec='' tq='N'>
              3300.70
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Issuance of certificate.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The ATP manager will evaluate the documents received and, for
          equipment deemed qualified, will issue a U.S. ATP certificate to the
          applicant within 30 days of the receipt of an application and any
          relevant information required. The certificate will be in the format
          prescribed in ATP, Annex 1, Appendix 3. For equipment deemed not
          qualified, the applicant will be advised of the reasons for
          non-qualification within 30 days of the receipt of an application and
          any relevant information required.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16402'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIII:-:3300:F:3300.73
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3300.73
      </num>
      <head>
        Period of validity of certificates.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3300' sect='73' psec='' tq='N'>
              3300.73
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Period of validity of certificates.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          In accordance with ATP, Annex 1, Appendix 1, paragraphs 1(a) and 1(b),
          certificates issued for new equipment are valid for a period of 6
          years from date of issue.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16403'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIII:-:3300:G:3300.76
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3300.76
      </num>
      <head>
        General.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3300' sect='76' psec='' tq='N'>
              3300.76
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Only domestic owners are eligible to receive U.S. ATP certificates for
          equipment in service, with certification based upon the following:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For equipment which has not previously been certified:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For each unit of equipment, a test in a U.S. ATP testing station or
            in a testing station located in and approved by a country which is a
            Contracting 
            <PRTPAGE P='342' />
            Party, to measure the K-coefficient of the insulated body and the
            efficiency of the thermal appliance in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='3300' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
                3300.10
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              § 3300.13 of
            </aref>
             this rule.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the equipment consists of serially-produced equipment
            manufactured by a particular equipment manufacturer, and belonging
            to one owner, certification may be based upon the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A test of 1 percent of the units of equipment as prescribed in
            preceding paragraph (a)(1) of this section, the units tested to
            serve as reference equipment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An inspection of each unit of equipment, using the procedures set
            forth in ATP, Annex 1, Appendix 2, paragraphs 29 and 49. The
            inspections shall be performed by one of the following, at the
            choice of the owner:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='a_2_ii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Persons in the owner&apos;s organization whom the owner deems
            qualified to perform inspections, or;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='a_2_ii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             By an independent inspection agency which the owner deems competent
            to perform inspections. Fees charged by such inspection agency shall
            be payable directly to the agency by the owner.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A report of each inspection shall be completed on a form
            corresponding to the pertinent test report model in ATP, Annex 1,
            Appendix 2. Report forms may be obtained by a request to the ATP
            manager.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For renewal of a U.S. ATP certificate which is nearing its
            expiration date, any of the following three procedures:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For each unit of equipment, a test as prescribed in preceding
            paragraph (a)(1) of this section, or;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the equipment is serially-produced by a particular manufacturer
            and belongs to one owner, test and inspection of the equipment
            according to the procedures prescribed in preceding paragraphs
            (a)(2)(i), (ii), and (iii) of this section, or;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An inspection of each unit of equipment as prescribed in paragraphs
            (a)(2)(ii) and (iii) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For equipment which is currently certified according to a U.S. ATP
            certificate, and which has been transferred from one domestic owner
            to another, the new owner may obtain a U.S. ATP certificate by
            submitting the original or certified true copy of the certificate
            issued to the previous owner, and by performing an inspection and
            submitting an inspection report for each unit of equipment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For equipment which is currently certified according to a
            Foreign-ATP certificate, and which has been transferred from a
            foreign owner to a domestic owner, the domestic owner may obtain a
            U.S. ATP certificate by submitting the original or certified true
            copy of the test report for the reference equipment and the original
            or certified true copy of the foreign certificate, and by performing
            an inspection and submitting an inspection report for each unit of
            equipment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Owners who receive a U.S. ATP certificate have the responsibility
            to maintain equipment in good repair and operating condition with
            the understanding that the certificate is valid only so long as:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The insulated body and the thermal appliance are maintained in good
            condition;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No material alteration is made to the thermal appliance which
            decreases its refrigeration capacity, and;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the thermal appliance is replaced, it is replaced by an
            appliance of equal or greater refrigerating capacity.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16404'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIII:-:3300:G:3300.79
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3300.79
      </num>
      <head>
        Application for certificate.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3300' sect='79' psec='' tq='N'>
              3300.79
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Application for certificate.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          An application shall be submitted to the ATP manager by an officer in
          the organization of the owner of the equipment. Copies of the Form,
          Application for U.S. ATP Certificate for Equipment in Service, may be
          obtained by a request to the ATP manager. The following information is
          requested in the application:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A statement that the owner is a domestic owner, with the name,
            address, and telephone number of its principal office, and name and
            title of person to contact.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the operator of the equipment is different from the owner, the
            name and address of the operator.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The type of equipment (intermodal freight container, trailer,
            semi-trailer, railcar, or truck).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The total number of units of equipment.
            <PRTPAGE P='343' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The definition of the equipment for which certification is sought,
            referring to ATP, Annex 1, paragraph 3 and Appendix 4.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For equipment which has not been previously certified, one of the
            following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For each unit of equipment, the original or certified true copy of
            the test report, or;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the equipment is serially-produced by one manufacturer:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Name of manufacturer.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The original or certified true copy of the test report(s) of 1
            percent of the equipment which was tested to serve as reference
            equipment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A report of inspection for each unit of equipment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For renewal of a U.S. ATP Certificate which is nearing its
            expiration date:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The original or certified true copy of that certificate, and;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             One of the following, (i) (ii), or (iii):
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For each unit of equipment, the original or certified true copy of
            the test report.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the equipment is serially-produced by one manufacturer:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='g_2_ii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Name of manufacturer.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='g_2_ii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The original or certified true copy of the test report(s) of 1
            percent of the equipment which was tested to serve as reference
            equipment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='g_2_ii_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A report of inspection from each unit of equipment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A report of inspection for each unit of equipment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For equipment which is currently certified according to a U.S. ATP
            certificate, and which has been transferred from one domestic owner
            to another:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The original or certified true copy of that certificate.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A report of inspection for each unit of equipment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For equipment which is currently certified according to a
            Foreign-ATP certificate, and which has been transferred from a
            foreign owner to a domestic owner:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The original or certified true copy of the test report for the
            reference equipment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The original or certified true copy of the Foreign-ATP certificate.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A report of inspection for each unit of equipment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A statement that each unit of equipment has, or will have, affixed
            to it a certification plate and distinguishing mark as prescribed in
            ATP, Annex 1, Appendix 1, paragraphs 4 and 5, and Appendices 3 and
            4.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A list showing, for each unit of equipment, the serial number of
            the body and the corresponding owner&apos;s equipment identification
            number.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16405'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIII:-:3300:G:3300.82
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3300.82
      </num>
      <head>
        Issuance of certificate.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3300' sect='82' psec='' tq='N'>
              3300.82
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Issuance of certificate.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The ATP manager will evaluate documents received and, for equipment
          deemed qualified, will issue a U.S. ATP certificate to the applicant
          within 30 days of receipt of the application and any relevant
          information required. The certificate will be in the format prescribed
          in ATP, Annex 1, Appendix 3. For equipment deemed not qualified, the
          applicant will be advised of reasons for non-qualification within 30
          days of receipt of an application and any relevant information
          required.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16406'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIII:-:3300:G:3300.85
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3300.85
      </num>
      <head>
        Period of validity of certificates.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3300' sect='85' psec='' tq='N'>
              3300.85
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Period of validity of certificates.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          In accordance with ATP, Annex 1, Appendix 1, paragraphs 1(b), and
          Appendix 2, paragraphs 29(c) and 49(b) and (d), considered in
          combination, certificates will be valid for periods as follows:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For equipment which passes a test, 6 years.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For serially-produced equipment of which 1 percent have passed a
            test, and all units have been inspected and passed such inspection,
            6 years.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For renewal of a U.S. ATP certificate which is nearing its
            expiration date, where the equipment has passed an inspection but
            has not been tested, 3 years.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For equipment currently certified according to a U.S. ATP
            certificate, where the equipment has been transferred from one
            domestic owner to another and the equipment has passed an
            inspection, 3 years or the date of expiration of the current U.S.
            ATP certificate, whichever gives the later expiration date on the
            new U.S. ATP certificate.
            <PRTPAGE P='344' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For equipment currently certified according to a Foreign-ATP
            certificate, where the equipment has been transferred from a foreign
            owner to a domestic owner and the equipment has passed an
            inspection, 3 years or the date of expiration of the foreign
            certificate, whichever gives the later expiration date on the newly
            issued U.S. ATP certificate.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16407'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIII:-:3300:H:3300.88
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3300.88
      </num>
      <head>
        Fees for U.S. ATP certificates.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3300' sect='88' psec='' tq='N'>
              3300.88
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Fees for U.S. ATP certificates.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The fee schedule for issuance of U.S. ATP certificates by the U.S.
          Department of Agriculture will be calculated according to the criteria
          in Circular A-25 
          <SU>
            2
          </SU>
          <FTREF />
          , issued by the Office of Management and Budget. Fees may be revised
          as required on an annual basis.
        </P>
        <FTNT>
          <P>
            <SU>
              2
            </SU>
             A copy of Circular A-25 can be obtained by a request to the Office
            of Management and Budget (OMB), 17th Street and Pennsylvania Avenue,
            NW., Washington, DC 20503.
          </P>
        </FTNT>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16408'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIII:-:3300:H:3300.91
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3300.91
      </num>
      <head>
        List of approved testing stations, approved testing laboratories, and
        fees for certificates.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3300' sect='91' psec='' tq='N'>
              3300.91
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          List of approved testing stations, approved testing laboratories, and
          fees for certificates.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          A current list of U.S. ATP testing stations, U.S. ATP testing
          laboratories, and fees for issuance of U.S. ATP certificates may be
          obtained by request to the ATP manager.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16409'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIII:-:3300:H:3300.94
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3300.94
      </num>
      <head>
        Appeals.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3300' sect='94' psec='' tq='N'>
              3300.94
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Appeals.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Any organization aggrieved by an action in connection with this rule
          may obtain a review of such action by submitting pertinent information
          by letter to the Administrator. The decision of the Administrator is
          the final agency action.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>