<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol1'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:12
    </extid>
    <num>
      12
    </num>
    <head>
      HIGHLY ERODIBLE LAND AND WETLAND CONSERVATION
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='16' sect='3801' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/3801.html'>
              16 U.S.C. 3801
            </subref>
            , 
            <subref title='16' sect='3812' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/3812.html'>
              3812
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , and 3822(h).
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            61 FR 47025
          </aref>
          , Sept. 6, 1996, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='503'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:12:A:12.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        12.1
      </num>
      <head>
        General.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          61 FR 47025
        </aref>
        , Sept. 6, 1996, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          76 FR 82077
        </aref>
        , Dec. 30, 2011]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='12' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              12.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Scope.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This part sets forth the terms and conditions under which a person
            who produces an agricultural commodity on highly erodible land or
            designates such land for conservation use, plants an agricultural
            commodity on a converted wetland, or converts a wetland shall be
            determined to be ineligible for certain benefits provided by the
            United States Department of Agriculture (USDA) and agencies and
            instrumentalities of USDA.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Purpose.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The purpose of the provisions of this part are to remove certain
            incentives for persons to produce agricultural commodities on highly
            erodible land or converted wetland and to thereby—
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Reduce soil loss due to wind and water erosion;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Protect the Nation&apos;s long-term capability to produce food and
            fiber;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Reduce sedimentation and improve water quality; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Assist in preserving the values, acreage, and functions of the
            Nation&apos;s wetlands.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            61 FR 47025
          </aref>
          , Sept. 6, 1996, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 82077
          </aref>
          , Dec. 30, 2011]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='504'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:12:A:12.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        12.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          61 FR 47025
        </aref>
        , Sept. 6, 1996; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          61 FR 53491
        </aref>
        , Oct. 11, 1996; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          76 FR 4803
        </aref>
        , Jan. 27, 2011]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='12' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              12.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The following definitions shall be applicable for the purposes of
            this part:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Agricultural commodity
          </E>
           means any crop planted and produced by annual tilling of the soil,
          including tilling by one-trip planters, or sugarcane.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            CCC
          </E>
           means the Commodity Credit Corporation, a wholly-owned government
          corporation within USDA organized under the provisions of 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='15' sect='714' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/15/714.html'>
              15 U.S.C. 714
            </subref>
          </aref>
          <E T='03'>
            et seq.
          </E>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Conservation District (CD)
          </E>
           means a subdivision of a State or local government organized pursuant
          to the applicable law to develop and implement soil and water
          conservation activities or programs.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Conservation plan
          </E>
           means the document that—
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Applies to highly erodible cropland;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Describes the conservation system applicable to the highly erodible
            cropland and describes the decisions of the person with respect to
            location, land use, tillage systems, and conservation treatment
            measures and schedules; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is approved by the local soil conservation district in consultation
            with the local committees established under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 8(b)(5) of
            </aref>
             the Soil Conservation 
            <PRTPAGE P='375' />
            and Domestic Allotment Act (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='16' sect='590h' note='' psec='#b_5' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/590h.html#b_5'>
                16 U.S.C. 590h(b)(5)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) and the Natural Resources Conservation Service (NRCS) for purposes
            of compliance with this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Conservation system
          </E>
           means a combination of one or more conservation measures or
          management practices that are—
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Based on local resource conditions, available conservation
            technology, and the standards and guidelines contained in the NRCS
            field office technical guides (available from NRCS State offices);
            and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Designed for purposes of this part to achieve, in a cost-effective
            and technically practicable manner, a substantial reduction in soil
            erosion or a substantial improvement in soil conditions on a field
            or group of fields containing highly erodible cropland when compared
            to the level of erosion or soil conditions that existed before the
            application of the conservation measures and management practices.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Conservation use or set aside
          </E>
           means cropland that is designated as conservation-use acreage, set
          aside, or other similar designation for the purpose of fulfilling
          provisions under any acreage-limitation or land-diversion program
          administered by the Secretary of Agriculture requiring that the
          producer devote a specified acreage to conservation or other non-crop
          production uses.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Creation of a wetland
          </E>
           means the development of the hydrologic, geochemical, and biological
          components necessary to support and maintain a wetland where a wetland
          did not previously exist. Any wetland established on a non-hydric soil
          will be considered a created wetland.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Department
          </E>
           means the United States Department of Agriculture (USDA).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Enhancement of a wetland
          </E>
           means the alteration of an existing wetland to increase its specific
          functions and values. Enhancement actions include new capabilities,
          management options, structures, or other actions to influence one or
          several functions and values.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Erodibility index
          </E>
           means a numerical value that expresses the potential erodibility of a
          soil in relation to its soil loss tolerance value without
          consideration of applied conservation practices or management.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            FSA
          </E>
           means the Farm Service Agency, an agency of USDA which is generally
          responsible for administering commodity production adjustment and
          certain conservation programs of USDA.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Field
          </E>
           means a part of a farm that is separated from the balance of the farm
          by permanent boundaries such as fences, roads, permanent waterways, or
          other similar features. At the option of the owner or operator of the
          farm, croplines may also be used to delineate a field if farming
          practices make it probable that the croplines are not subject to
          change. Any highly erodible land on which an agricultural commodity is
          produced after December 23, 1985, and is not exempt under 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='12' sect='5' psec='#a' tq='N'>
              12.5(a)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , shall be considered part of the field in which the land was included
          on December 23, 1985, unless, to carry out this title, the owner and
          FSA agree to modify the boundaries of the field.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Highly erodible land
          </E>
           means land that has an erodibility index of 8 or more.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Hydric soils
          </E>
           means soils that, in an undrained condition, are saturated, flooded,
          or ponded long enough during a growing season to develop an anaerobic
          condition that supports the growth and regeneration of hydrophytic
          vegetation.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Hydrophytic vegetation
          </E>
           means plants growing in water or in a substrate that is at least
          periodically deficient in oxygen during a growing season as a result
          of excessive water content.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Landlord
          </E>
           means a person who rents or leases farmland to another person.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Local FSA office
          </E>
           means the county office of the Farm Service Agency serving the county
          or a combination of counties in the area in which a person&apos;s land
          is located for administrative purposes.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            NIFA
          </E>
           means the National Institute of Food and Agriculture, an agency of
          USDA which is generally responsible for coordinating the information
          and educational programs of USDA.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            NRCS
          </E>
           means the Natural Resources Conservation Service, an agency within
          USDA which is generally responsible for providing technical assistance
          in matters of natural resources conservation and for administering
          certain conservation programs of USDA.
          <PRTPAGE P='376' />
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Operator
          </E>
           means the person who is in general control of the farming operations
          on the farm during the crop year.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Owner
          </E>
           means a person who is determined to have legal ownership of farmland
          and shall include a person who is purchasing farmland under contract.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Person
          </E>
           means an individual, partnership, association, corporation,
          cooperative, estate, trust, joint venture, joint operation, or other
          business enterprise or other legal entity and, whenever applicable, a
          State, a political subdivision of a State, or any agency thereof, and
          such person&apos;s affiliates as provided in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='12' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              12.8
            </subref>
             of this part
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Restoration of a wetland
          </E>
           means the re-establishment of wetland conditions, including
          hydrologic condition or native hydrophytic vegetation, to an area
          where a wetland had previously existed.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Secretary
          </E>
           means the Secretary of USDA.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Sharecropper
          </E>
           means a person who performs work in connection with the production of
          a crop under the supervision of the operator and who receives a share
          of such crop for such labor.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Soil map unit
          </E>
           means an area of the landscape shown on a soil map which consists of
          one or more soils.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State
          </E>
           means each of the 50 states, the District of Columbia, the
          Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, the Virgin Islands of the United
          States, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana
          Islands, or the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Tenant
          </E>
           means a person usually called a “cash tenant”, “fixed-rent tenant”,
          or “standing rent tenant” who rents land from another for a fixed
          amount of cash or a fixed amount of a commodity to be paid as rent; or
          a person (other than a sharecropper) usually called a “share tenant”
          who rents land from another person and pays as rent a share of the
          crops or proceeds therefrom. A tenant shall not be considered the farm
          operator unless the tenant is determined to be the operator pursuant
          to this part and 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR part 
            <subref title='7' part='718' tq='N'>
              718
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Wetland,
          </E>
           except when such term is a part of the term “converted wetland”,
          means land that—
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Has predominance of hydric soils;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is inundated or saturated by surface or groundwater at a frequency
            and duration sufficient to support a prevalence of hydrophytic
            vegetation typically adapted for life in saturated soil conditions;
            and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Under normal circumstances does support a prevalence of such
            vegetation, except that this term does not include lands in Alaska
            identified as having a high potential for agricultural development
            and a predominance of permafrost soils.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Wetland determination
          </E>
           means a decision regarding whether or not an area is a wetland,
          including identification of wetland type and size. A wetland
          determination may include identification of an area as one of the
          following types of wetland—
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Artificial wetland
            </E>
             is an area that was formerly non-wetland, but now meets wetland
            criteria due to human activities, such as:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An artificial lake or pond created by excavating or diking land
            that is not a wetland to collect and retain water that is used
            primarily for livestock, fish production, irrigation, wildlife, fire
            control, flood control, cranberry growing, or rice production, or as
            a settling pond; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A wetland that is temporarily or incidentally created as a result
            of adjacent development activity;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Commenced-conversion wetland
            </E>
             is a wetland, farmed wetland, farmed-wetland pasture, or a
            converted wetland on which conversion began, but was not completed,
            prior to December 23, 1985.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Converted wetland
            </E>
             is a wetland that has been drained, dredged, filled, leveled, or
            otherwise manipulated (including the removal of woody vegetation or
            any activity that results in impairing or reducing the flow and
            circulation of water) for the purpose of or to have the effect of
            making possible the production of an agricultural commodity without
            further application of the manipulations described herein if:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Such production would not have been possible but for such action,
            and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Before such action such land was wetland, farmed wetland, or
            farmed-wetland pasture and was neither highly erodible land nor
            highly erodible cropland;
            <PRTPAGE P='377' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Farmed wetland
            </E>
             is a wetland that prior to December 23, 1985, was manipulated and
            used to produce an agricultural commodity, and on December 23, 1985,
            did not support woody vegetation and met the following hydrologic
            criteria:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_4_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is inundated for 15 consecutive days or more during the growing
            season or 10 percent of the growing season, whichever is less, in
            most years (50 percent chance or more), or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_4_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a pothole, playa, or pocosion, is ponded for 7 or more
            consecutive days during the growing season in most years (50 percent
            chance of more) or is saturated for 14 or more consecutive days
            during the growing season in most years (50 percent chance or more);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Farmed-wetland pasture
            </E>
             is wetland that was manipulated and managed for pasture or hayland
            prior to December 23, 1985, and on December 23, 1985, met the
            following hydrologic criteria:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_5_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Inundated or ponded for 7 or more consecutive days during the
            growing season in most years (50) percent chance or more), or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_5_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Saturated for 14 or more consecutive days during the growing season
            in most years (50 percent chance or more);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Not-inventoried land,
            </E>
             is an area for which no evaluation of soils, vegetation, or
            hydrology has been conducted to determine if wetland criteria are
            met;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Non-wetland
            </E>
             is;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_7_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land that under natural conditions does not meet wetland criteria,
            or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_7_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is converted wetland the conversion of which occurred prior to
            December 23, 1985, and on that date, the land did not meet wetland
            criteria but an agricultural commodity was not produced and the area
            was not managed for pasture or hay;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Prior-converted cropland
            </E>
             is a converted wetland where the conversion occurred prior to
            December 23, 1985, an agricultural commodity had been produced at
            least once before December 23, 1985, and as of December 23, 1985,
            the converted wetland did not support woody vegetation and met the
            following hydrologic criteria:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_8_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Inundation was less than 15 consecutive days during the growing
            season or 10 percent of the growing season, whichever is less, in
            most years (50 percent chance or more); and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_8_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a pothole, playa or pocosin, ponding was less than 7 consecutive
            days during the growing season in most years (50 percent chance or
            more) and saturation was less than 14 consecutive days during the
            growing season most years (50 percent chance or more); or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Wetland,
            </E>
             as defined above in this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Wetland delineation
          </E>
           means outlining the boundaries of a wetland determination on aerial
          photography, digital imagery, other graphic representation of the
          area, or on the land.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Terms for FSA operations.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the regulations in this part, and in all instructions, forms,
            and documents in connection therewith, all other words and phrases
            specifically relating to FSA operations shall, unless required by
            the subject matter or the specific provisions of this part, have the
            meanings assigned to them in the regulations at 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='718' tq='N'>
                718 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
             that govern reconstitutions of farms, allotments, and bases and any
            subsequent amendment thereto.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            61 FR 47025
          </aref>
          , Sept. 6, 1996; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            61 FR 53491
          </aref>
          , Oct. 11, 1996; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 4803
          </aref>
          , Jan. 27, 2011]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='505'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:12:A:12.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        12.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Applicability.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          61 FR 47025
        </aref>
        , Sept. 6, 1996, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          76 FR 82076
        </aref>
        , Dec. 30, 2011]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='12' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              12.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Applicability.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Geographic scope.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The provisions of this part shall apply to all land, including
            Indian tribal land, in the fifty States, the District of Columbia,
            the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, the Virgin Islands of the
            United States, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern
            Mariana Islands, and the Federated States of Micronesia, the
            Republic of Palau, and the Republic of the Marshall Islands.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Effective date.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The provisions of this part apply to all actions taken after July
            3, 1996, and to determinations made after or pending on July 3,
            1996, except to the extent that 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='5' psec='#a_5' tq='N'>
                12.5(a)(5)
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
                12.5
              </subref>
            </aref>
             (b)(4) through (b)(8) specify retroactive application on December
            23, 1985, and November 28, 1990, for certain actions and
            determinations regarding wetlands and converted wetlands. Actions
            taken and determinations made prior to July 3, 1996, are subject to
            regulations set forth in this part as of July 2, 1996, except as
            otherwise provided in this part. Further, to 
            <PRTPAGE P='378' />
            the extent that a person may be eligible for an exemption for an
            action taken before July 3, 1996, the action is subject to the
            provisions of this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            61 FR 47025
          </aref>
          , Sept. 6, 1996, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 82076
          </aref>
          , Dec. 30, 2011]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='506'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:12:A:12.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        12.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Determination of ineligibility.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          61 FR 47025
        </aref>
        , Sept. 6, 1996; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          61 FR 53491
        </aref>
        , Oct. 11, 1996; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          76 FR 82077
        </aref>
        , Dec. 30, 2011]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='12' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              12.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Determination of ineligibility.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Actions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as provided in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
                12.5
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , a person shall be ineligible for all or a portion of USDA program
            benefits listed in this section if:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The person produces an agricultural commodity on a field in which
            highly erodible land is predominant, or designates such a field for
            conservation use;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The person produces an agricultural commodity on wetland that was
            converted after December 23, 1985; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             After November 28, 1990, the person converts a wetland by draining,
            dredging, filling, leveling, removing woody vegetation, or other
            means for the purpose, or to have the effect, of making the
            production of an agricultural commodity possible.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Highly erodible land.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A person determined to be ineligible under paragraph (a)(1) of this
            section may be ineligible for all program benefits listed in (d) and
            (e) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Wetland conservation.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A person determined to be ineligible under paragraph (a)(2) of this
            section shall be ineligible for all or a portion of the USDA program
            benefits listed in paragraph (d) of this section for which the
            person otherwise would have been eligible during the crop year of
            the commodity that was planted on the converted wetland. A person
            determined to be ineligible under paragraph (a)(3) of this section
            for the conversion of a wetland shall be ineligible for all or a
            portion of the USDA program benefits listed in paragraph (d) of this
            section for which the person otherwise would have been eligible
            during the crop year which is equal to the calendar year during
            which the violation occurred and each subsequent crop year until the
            converted wetland is restored or the loss of wetland values,
            acreage, and functions have been mitigated prior to the beginning of
            such calendar year in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='5' psec='#b_4_i' tq='N'>
                12.5(b)(4)(i) (A) and (C)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             through (F) of this part. Ineligibility under paragraph (a)(2) or
            (a)(3) of this section may be reduced, in lieu of the loss of all
            benefits specified under paragraph (d) of this section for such crop
            year, based on the seriousness of the violation, as determined by
            the FSA Deputy Administrator for Farm Programs or designee upon
            recommendation by the FSA County Committee. Factors such as the
            information that was available to the affected person prior to the
            violation, previous land use patterns, the existence of previous
            wetland violations under this part or under other Federal, State, or
            local wetland provisions, the wetland values, acreage, and functions
            affected, the recovery time for full mitigation of the wetland
            values, acreage, and functions , and the impact that a reduction in
            payments would have on the person&apos;s ability to repay a USDA
            farm loan shall be considered to making this determination.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Programs subject to either highly erodible land or wetland
              conservation.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             USDA program benefits covered by a determination of ineligibility
            under this rule are:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Contract payments under a production flexibility contract,
            marketing assistance loans, and any type of price support or payment
            made available under the Agricultural Market Transition Act, the
            Commodity Credit Corporation Charter Act (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='15' sect='714' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/15/714.html'>
                15 U.S.C. 714
              </subref>
            </aref>
            <E T='03'>
              et seq.
            </E>
            ), or any other Act;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A farm credit program loan made or guaranteed under the
            Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='1921' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1921.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 1921
              </subref>
            </aref>
            <E T='03'>
              et seq.
            </E>
            ) or any other provision of law administered by FSA if the Secretary
            determines that the proceeds of such loan will be used for a purpose
            that contributes to the conversion of wetlands that would make
            production of an agricultural commodity possible or for a purpose
            that contributes to excessive erosion of highly erodible land (
            <E T='03'>
              i.e
            </E>
            ., production of an agricultural commodity on highly erodible land
            without a conservation plan or conservation system as required by
            this part);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A payment made pursuant to a contract entered into under the
            Environmental Quality Incentives Program under chapter 4 of subtitle
            D of the Food Security Act of 1985, as amended; or a payment under
            any other provision of Subtitle D of that Act;
            <PRTPAGE P='379' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A payment made under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 401 or 402 of
            </aref>
             the Agricultural Credit Act of 1978 (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='16' sect='2201' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/2201.html'>
                16 U.S.C. 2201
              </subref>
               or 
              <subref title='16' sect='2202' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/2202.html'>
                2202
              </subref>
            </aref>
            );
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A payment, loan, or other assistance under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 3 or 8 of
            </aref>
             the Watershed Protection and Flood Prevention Act (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='16' sect='1003' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/1003.html'>
                16 U.S.C. 1003
              </subref>
               or 
              <subref title='16' sect='1006a' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/1006a.html'>
                1006a
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Programs subject to highly erodible land only.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In addition to programs listed in paragraph (d) of this section, a
            person determined to be ineligible under paragraph (a)(1) of this
            section shall be ineligible as determined by FSA for the following
            USDA program benefits for which the person otherwise would have been
            eligible during the crop year for which the determination applies:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A farm storage facility loan made under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 4(h) of
            </aref>
             the Commodity Credit Corporation Charter Act (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='15' sect='714b' note='' psec='#h' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/15/714b.html#h'>
                15 U.S.C. 714b(h)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            );
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A disaster payment made under the Federal Agricultural Improvement
            and Reform Act, 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Pub. L. 104-127' alt='Pub. L. 104-127' href='http://www.gpo.gov/fdsys/pkg/PLAW-104publ127/html/PLAW-104publ127.htm'>
              Pub. L. 104-127
            </aref>
            , or any other act; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A payment made under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 4 or 5 of
            </aref>
             the Commodity Credit Corporation Charter Act (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='15' sect='714b' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/15/714b.html'>
                15 U.S.C. 714b
              </subref>
               or 
              <subref title='15' sect='714c' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/15/714c.html'>
                714c
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) for the storage of an agricultural commodity acquired by the
            Commodity Credit Corporation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Prior loans.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The provisions of paragraphs (a), (b), and (c) of this section do
            not apply to any loan described in paragraphs (d) or (e) of this
            section that was made prior to December 23, 1985.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Determination of ineligibility.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For the purpose of paragraph (a) of this section, a person shall be
            determined to have produced an agricultural commodity on a field in
            which highly erodible land is predominant or to have designated such
            a field for conservation use, to have produced an agricultural
            commodity on converted wetland, or to have converted a wetland if:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS has determined that—
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Highly erodible land is predominant in such field, or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All or a portion of the field is converted wetland; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FSA has determined that the person is or was the owner or operator
            of the land, or entitled to share in the crops available from the
            land, or in the proceeds thereof; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             With regard to the provisions of paragraph (a)(1) and (a)(2) of
            this section, FSA has determined that the land is or was planted to
            an agricultural commodity or was designated as conservation use
            during the year for which the person is requesting benefits.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Intent to participate in USDA programs.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Persons who wish to participate in any of the USDA programs
            described in paragraph (d) or (e) of this section are responsible
            for contacting the appropriate agency of USDA well in advance of the
            intended participated date so that Form AD-1026 can be completed.
            This contact will help assure that the appropriate determinations
            regarding highly erodible land or wetland, and conservation plans or
            conservation systems are scheduled in a timely manner. A late
            contact may not allow sufficient time for USDA to service the
            request and could result in a substantial delay in receiving a USDA
            determination of eligibility or ineligibility.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            61 FR 47025
          </aref>
          , Sept. 6, 1996; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            61 FR 53491
          </aref>
          , Oct. 11, 1996; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 82077
          </aref>
          , Dec. 30, 2011]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='507'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:12:A:12.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        12.5
      </num>
      <head>
        Exemption.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          61 FR 47025
        </aref>
        , Sept. 6, 1996; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          61 FR 53491
        </aref>
        , Oct. 11, 1996; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          76 FR 82077
        </aref>
        , Dec. 30, 2011]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='12' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              12.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Exemption.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Exemptions regarding highly erodible land—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Highly erodible cropland in production or in USDA programs during
              1981 through 1985 crop years.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             During the period beginning on December 23, 1985, and ending on the
            later of January 1, 1990, or the date that is two years after the
            date the cropland on which an agricultural commodity is produced was
            surveyed by NRCS to determine if such land is highly erodible, no
            person shall be determined to be ineligible for benefits as provided
            in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
                12.4
              </subref>
            </aref>
             as the result of the production of an agricultural commodity on any
            highly erodible land:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             That was planted to an agricultural commodity in any year 1981
            through 1985; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             That was set aside, diverted, or otherwise not cultivated in any
            such crop years under a program administered by the Secretary for
            any such crops to reduce production of an agricultural commodity.
            <PRTPAGE P='380' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Compliance with a conservation plan or conservation system.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             As further specified in this part, no person shall be ineligible
            for the program benefits described in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
                12.4
              </subref>
            </aref>
             as the result of production of an agricultural commodity on highly
            erodible land or the designation of such land for conservation use
            if such production or designation is in compliance with a
            conservation plan or conservation system approved under paragraph
            (a)(2)(i) or (a)(2)(ii) of this section. A person shall not be
            ineligible for program benefits under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
                12.4
              </subref>
            </aref>
             as the result of the production of an agricultural commodity on
            highly erodible land or as the result of designation of such land as
            conservation use if the production or designation is:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In an area within a CD, under a conservation system that has been
            approved by the CD after the CD determines that the conservation
            system is in conformity with technical standards set forth in the
            NRCS field office technical guide for such district; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In an area not within a CD, under a conservation system that has
            been approved by NRCS to be adequate for the production of such
            agricultural commodity on highly erodible land or for the
            designation of such land as conservation use.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Reliance upon NRCS determination for highly erodible land.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A person may be relieved from ineligibility for program benefits as
            the result of the production of an agricultural commodity which was
            produced on highly erodible land or for the designation of such land
            as conservation use in reliance on a determination by NRCS that such
            land was not highly erodible land, except that this paragraph shall
            not apply to any agricultural commodity that was planted on highly
            erodible land, or for the designation of highly erodible land as
            conservation use after NRCS determines that such land is highly
            erodible land, and the person is notified of such determinations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Areas of 2 acres or less.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No person shall be determined to be ineligible under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
                12.4
              </subref>
            </aref>
             for noncommercial production of agricultural commodities on highly
            erodible land on an area of 2 acres or less if it is determined by
            FSA that such production is not intended to circumvent the
            conservation requirements otherwise applicable under this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Good faith.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No person will become ineligible under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
                12.4
              </subref>
            </aref>
             as a result of the failure of such person to apply a conservation
            system on highly erodible land if all of the following apply:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_5_ii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FSA determines such person has acted in good faith and without the
            intent to violate the provisions of this part;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_5_ii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS determines that the person complies with paragraph (a)(5)(ii)
            of this section; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_5_ii_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The good faith determination of the FSA county or State committee
            has been reviewed and approved by the applicable State Executive
            Director, with the technical concurrence of the State
            Conservationist; or district director, with the technical
            concurrence of the area conservationist.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_5_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A person who otherwise meets the requirements of paragraphs
            (a)(5)(i)(A) and (a)(5)(i)(C) of this section will be allowed a
            reasonable period of time, as determined by NRCS, but not to exceed
            one year, during which to implement the measures and practices
            necessary to be considered actively applying the person&apos;s
            conservation plan, as determined by USDA. If a person does not take
            the required corrective actions, the person may be determined to be
            ineligible for the crop year during which such actions were to be
            taken, as well as any subsequent crop year.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_5_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notwithstanding the good-faith requirements of paragraph (a)(5)(i)
            of this section, if NRCS observes a possible compliance deficiency
            while providing on-site technical assistance, NRCS will provide to
            the responsible person, not later than 45 days after observing the
            possible violation, information regarding actions needed to comply
            with the plan and this subtitle. NRCS will provide this information
            in lieu of reporting the observation as a violation, if the
            responsible person attempts to correct the deficiencies as soon as
            practicable, as determined by NRCS, after receiving the information,
            but not later than one year after receiving the information. If a
            person does not take the required corrective actions, the person may
            be determined to be ineligible for the crop year during 
            <PRTPAGE P='381' />
            which the compliance deficiencies occurred, as well as any
            subsequent crop year.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_5_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A person who meets the requirements of paragraphs (a)(5)(i) and
            (a)(5)(ii) of this section will, in lieu of the loss of all benefits
            specified under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='4' psec='#d' tq='N'>
                12.4(d) and (e)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             for such crop year, be subject to a reduction in benefits by an
            amount commensurate with the seriousness of the violation, as
            determined by FSA. The dollar amount of the reduction will be
            determined by FSA and may be based on the number of acres and the
            degree of erosion hazard for the area in violation, as determined by
            NRCS, or upon such other factors as FSA determines appropriate.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_5_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any person whose benefits are reduced in a crop year under
            paragraph (a)(5) of this section may be eligible for all of the
            benefits specified under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='4' psec='#d' tq='N'>
                12.4(d) and (e)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             for any subsequent crop year if, prior to the beginning of the
            subsequent crop year, NRCS determines that such person is actively
            applying a conservation plan according to the schedule specified in
            the plan on all highly erodible land planted to an agricultural
            commodity or designated as conservation use.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Allowable variances.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notwithstanding any other provisions of this part, no person shall
            be determined to be ineligible for benefits as a result of the
            failure of such person to apply a conservation system if NRCS
            determines that—
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_6_v_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The failure is technical and minor in nature and that such
            violation has little effect on the erosion control purposes of the
            conservation plan applicable to the land on which the violation has
            occurred; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_6_v_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The failure is due to circumstances beyond the control of the
            person; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_6_v_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS grants a temporary variance from the practices specified in
            the plan for the purpose of handling a specific problem, including
            weather, pest, and disease problems, which NRCS determines cannot
            reasonably be addressed except through such variance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_6_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the person&apos;s request for a temporary variance involves the
            use of practices or measures to address weather, pest, or disease
            problems, NRCS shall make a decision on whether to grant the
            variance during the 30-day period beginning on the date of receipt
            of the request. If NRCS fails to render a decision during the
            period, the temporary variance shall be considered granted unless
            the person seeking the variance had reason to know that the variance
            would not be granted. In determining whether to grant a variance for
            natural disasters such as weather, pest, or disease problems, NRCS
            will consider such factors as:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_6_ii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The percent of a stand damaged or destroyed by the event;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_6_ii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The percent of expected crop production compared to normal
            production for that crop;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_6_ii_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The documented invasion of non-native insects, weeds, or diseases
            for which no recognized treatment exists;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_6_ii_D'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (D)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whether an event is severe or unusual based on historical weather
            records; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_6_ii_E'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (E)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Other specific circumstances caused by a natural event that
            prevented the implementation of conservation practices or systems,
            installation of structures, or planting of cover crops.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Technical and minor violations.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notwithstanding any other provisions of this part, a reduction in
            benefits in an amount commensurate with the seriousness of the
            violation, as determined by FSA, and consistent with paragraph
            (a)(5)(iv) of this section, will be applied if NRCS determines that
            a violation involving highly erodible land that would otherwise lead
            to a loss of benefits is both of the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_7_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Technical and minor in nature; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_7_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Has a minimal effect on the erosion control purposes of the
            conservation plan applicable to the land on which the violation
            occurred.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Exemptions for wetlands and converted wetlands—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General exemptions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A person shall not be determined to be ineligible for program
            benefits under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
                12.4
              </subref>
            </aref>
             as the result of the production of an agricultural commodity on
            converted wetland or the conversion of wetland if:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The land is a prior-converted cropland and meets the definition of
            a prior-converted cropland as of the date of a wetland determination
            by NRCS;
            <PRTPAGE P='382' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The land has been determined by NRCS to be a prior-converted
            cropland and such determination has been certified, and NRCS
            determines that the wetland characteristics returned after the date
            of the wetland certification as a result of—
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='b_1_ii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The lack of maintenance of drainage, dikes, levees, or similar
            structures,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='b_1_ii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The lack of management of the lands containing the wetland, or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='b_1_ii_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Circumstances beyond the control of the person;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The land was determined by NRCS to be a farmed wetland or a
            farmed-wetland pasture and—
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='b_1_iii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Such land meets wetland criteria through a voluntary restoration,
            enhancement, or creation action after that determination,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='b_1_iii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The technical determinations regarding the baseline site conditions
            and the restoration, enhancement, or creation action have been
            adequately documented by NRCS,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='b_1_iii_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The proposed conversion action is documented by the NRCS prior to
            implementation, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='b_1_iii_D'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (D)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The extent of the proposed conversion is limited so that the
            conditions will be at least equivalent to the wetland values,
            acreage, and functions that existed at the time of implementation of
            the voluntary wetland restoration, enhancement, or creation action;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS has determined that the conversion if for a purpose that does
            not make the production of an agricultural commodity possible, such
            as conversions for fish production, trees, vineyards, shrubs,
            cranberries, agricultural waste management structures, livestock
            ponds, fire control, or building and road construction and no
            agricultural commodity is produced on such land;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS has determined that the actions of the person with respect to
            the conversion of the wetland or the combined effect of the
            production of an agricultural commodity on a wetland converted by
            the person or by someone else, individually and in connection with
            all other similar actions authorized by NRCS in the area, would have
            only a minimal effect on the wetland functions and values of
            wetlands in the area;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='b_1_vi_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             After December 23, 1985, the Army Corps of Engineers issued an
            individual permit pursuant to 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 404 of
            </aref>
             the Clean Water Act, 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='33' sect='1344' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/33/1344.html'>
                33 U.S.C. 1344
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , authorizing such action and the permit required mitigation that
            adequately replaced the values, acreage, and functions of the
            wetlands converted, as determined by NRCS, or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='b_1_vi_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             After December 23, 1985, the action is encompassed under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 404 of
            </aref>
             the Clean Water Act, 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='33' sect='1344' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/33/1344.html'>
                33 U.S.C. 1344
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , by an Army Corps of Engineers nationwide or regional general
            permit and the wetland values, acreage, and functions were
            adequately mitigated, as determined by NRCS; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_vii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The land is determined by NRCS to be—
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='b_1_vii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An artificial wetland,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='b_1_vii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A wet area created by a water delivery system, irrigation,
            irrigation system, or application of water for irrigation,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='b_1_vii_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A nontidal drainage or irrigation ditch excavated in non-wetland,
            or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='b_1_vii_D'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (D)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A wetland converted by actions of persons other than the person
            applying for USDA program benefits or any of the person&apos;s
            predecessors in interest after December 23, 1985, if such conversion
            was not the result of a scheme or device to avoid compliance with
            this part. Further drainage improvement on such land is not
            permitted without loss of eligibility for USDA program benefits,
            unless NRCS determines under paragraph (b)(1)(v) of this section
            that further drainage activities applied to such land would have
            minimal effect on the wetland functions and values in the area. In
            applying this paragraph, a converted wetland shall be presumed to
            have been converted by the person applying for USDA program benefits
            unless the person can show that the conversion was caused by a third
            party with whom the person was not associated through a scheme or
            device as described under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
                12.10
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
            . In this regard, activities of a water resource district, drainage
            district, or similar entity will be attributed to all persons within
            the jurisdiction of the district or other entity who are assessed
            for the activities of the district or entity. Accordingly, where a
            person&apos;s wetland is 
            <PRTPAGE P='383' />
            converted due to the actions of the district or entity, the person
            shall be considered to have caused or permitted the drainage.
            Notwithstanding the provisions of the preceding sentences and as
            determined by FSA to be consistent with the purposes of this part,
            the activities of a drainage district or other similar entity will
            not be attributed to a person to the extent that the activities of
            the district or entity were beyond the control of the person and the
            wetland converted is not used by the person for the production of an
            agricultural commodity or a forage crop for harvest by mechanical
            means or mitigation for the converted wetland occurs in accordance
            with this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Commenced conversion wetlands.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The purpose of a determination of a commenced conversion made under
            this paragraph is to implement the legislative intent that those
            persons who had actually started conversion of a wetland or
            obligated funds for conversion prior to December 23, 1985, would be
            allowed to complete the conversion so as to avoid unnecessary
            economic hardship.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All persons who believed they had a wetland or converted wetland
            for which conversion began but was not completed prior to December
            23, 1985, must have requested by September 19, 1988, FSA to make a
            determination of commencement in order to be considered exempt under
            this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any conversion activity considered by FSA to be commenced under
            this section lost its exempt status if such activity as not
            completed on or before January 1, 1995. For purposes of this part,
            land on which such conversion activities were completed by January
            1, 1995, shall be evaluated by the same standards and qualify for
            the same exemptions as prior-converted croplands. For purposes of
            this part, land on which such conversion activities were not
            completed by January 1, 1995, shall be evaluated by the same
            standards and qualify for the same exemptions as wetlands or farmed
            wetlands, as applicable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Only those wetlands for which the construction had begun, or to
            which the contract or purchased supplies and materials related,
            qualified for a determination of commencement. However, in those
            circumstances where the conversion of wetland did not meet the
            specific requirements of this paragraph, the person could have
            requested a commencement of conversion determination from the FSA
            Deputy Administrator for Farm Programs, upon a showing that undue
            economic hardship would have resulted because of substantial
            financial obligations incurred prior to December 23, 1985, for the
            primary and direct purpose of converting the wetland.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Wetlands farmed under natural conditions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A person shall not be determined to be ineligible for program
            benefits under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
                12.4
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
             as a result of the production of an agricultural commodity on a
            wetland on which the owner or operator of a farm or ranch uses
            normal cropping or ranching practices to produce agricultural
            commodities in a manner that is consistent for the area, where such
            production is possible as a result of natural conditions, such as
            drought, and is without action by the producer that alters the
            hydrology or removes woody vegetation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Mitigation.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No person shall be determined to be ineligible under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
                12.4
              </subref>
            </aref>
             for any action associated with the conversion of a wetland if the
            wetland values, acreage, and functions are adequately mitigated, as
            determined by NRCS, through the restoration of a converted wetland,
            the enhancement of an existing wetland, or the creation of a new
            wetland, if the mitigation—
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_4_iv_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is in accordance with a mitigation plan approved by NRCS;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_4_iv_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is in advance of, or concurrent with, the wetland conversion or the
            production of an agricultural commodity, as applicable;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_4_iv_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is not at the expense of the federal government in either
            supporting the direct or indirect costs of the restoration activity
            or costs associated with acquiring or securing mitigation sites,
            except if conducted under a mitigation banking pilot program
            established by USDA;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_4_iv_D'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (D)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Occurs on lands in the same general area of the local watershed as
            the converted wetlands, provided that for purposes of this
            paragraph, lands in the same general area of the local watershed may
            include regional mitigation banks;
            <PRTPAGE P='384' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_4_iv_E'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (E)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is on lands for which the owner has granted an easement to USDA,
            recorded the easement on public land records, and has agreed to the
            maintenance of the restored, created, or enhanced wetland for as
            long as the converted wetland for which the mitigation occurred
            remains in agricultural use or is not returned to its original
            wetland classification with equivalent values, acreage, and
            functions; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_4_iv_F'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (F)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provides the equivalent values, acreage, and functions that will be
            lost as a result of the wetland conversion.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_4_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A mitigation plan is a record of decisions that document the
            actions necessary to compensate for the loss of wetland values,
            acreage, and functions that result from converting a wetland. The
            mitigation plan may be a component of a larger natural resources
            conservation plan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_4_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State Conservationist, in consultation with the State Technical
            Committee, may name certain types or classes of wetland not eligible
            for exemption under paragraph (b)(4)(i) of this section where the
            State Conservationist determines that mitigation will not achieve
            equivalent replacement of wetland values, acreage, and functions
            within a reasonable time frame or for other reasons identified by
            the State Conservationist. Any type or class of wetland that a State
            Conservationist identifies as not eligible for exemption under
            paragraph (b)(4)(i) of this section will be published in the 
            <E T='04'>
              Federal Register
            </E>
             for inclusion in this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Good faith violations.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A person who is determined under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
                12.4
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
             to be ineligible for benefits as the result of the production of an
            agricultural commodity on a wetland converted after December 23,
            1985, or as the result of the conversion of a wetland after November
            28, 1990, may regain eligibility for benefits if all of the
            following apply:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_5_iii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FSA determines that such person acted in good faith and without the
            intent to violate the wetland provisions of this part; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_5_iii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS determines that the person is implementing all practices in a
            mitigation plan within an agreed-to period, not to exceed one year;
            and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_5_iii_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The good faith determination of the FSA county or State committee
            has been reviewed and approved by the applicable State Executive
            Director, with the technical concurrence of the State
            Conservationist; or district director, with the technical
            concurrence of the area conservationist.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_5_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In determining whether a person acted in good faith under paragraph
            (b)(5)(i)(A) of this section, the FSA shall consider such factors as
            whether—
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_5_ii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The characteristics of the site were such that the person should
            have been aware that a wetland existed on the subject land,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_5_ii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS had informed the person about the existence of a wetland on
            the subject land,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_5_ii_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The person did not convert the wetland, but planted an agricultural
            commodity on converted wetland when the person should have known
            that a wetland previously existed on the subject land,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_5_ii_D'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (D)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The person has a record of violating the wetland provisions of this
            part or other Federal, State, or local wetland provisions, or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_5_ii_E'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (E)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             There exists other information that demonstrates that the person
            acted with the intent to violate the wetland provisions of this
            part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_5_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             After the requirements of paragraph (b)(5)(i) of this section are
            met, USDA may waive applying the ineligibility provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
                12.4
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Reliance upon NRCS wetland determination.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_6_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A person shall not be ineligible for program benefits as a result
            of taking an action in reliance on a previous certified wetland
            determination by NRCS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_6_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A person who may be ineligible for program benefits as the result
            of the production of an agricultural commodity on converted wetland
            or for the conversion of a wetland may seek relief under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
                12.11
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
             if such action was taken in reliance on an incorrect technical
            determination by NRCS as to the status of such land. If the error
            caused the person to make a substantial financial investment, as
            determined by the NRCS, for the conversion of a wetland, the person
            may be relieved of ineligibility for actions related to that portion
            of the converted wetland for which the substantial financial
            investment was expended in 
            <PRTPAGE P='385' />
            conversion activities. The relief available under this paragraph
            shall not apply to situations in which the person knew or reasonably
            should have known that the determination was in error because the
            characteristics of the site were such that the person should have
            been aware that a wetland existed on the subject land, or for other
            reasons.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Responsibility to provide evidence.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             It is the responsibility of the person seeking an exemption related
            to converted wetlands under this section to provide evidence, such
            as receipts, crop-history data, drawings, plans or similar
            information, for purposes of determining whether the conversion or
            other action is exempt in accordance with this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            61 FR 47025
          </aref>
          , Sept. 6, 1996; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            61 FR 53491
          </aref>
          , Oct. 11, 1996; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 82077
          </aref>
          , Dec. 30, 2011]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='508'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:12:A:12.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        12.6
      </num>
      <head>
        Administration.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          61 FR 47025
        </aref>
        , Sept. 6, 1996; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          61 FR 53491
        </aref>
        , Oct. 11, 1996; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          76 FR 4804
        </aref>
        , Jan. 27, 2011]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='12' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              12.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Administration.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A determination of ineligibility for benefits in accordance with
            the provisions of this part shall be made by the agency of USDA to
            which the person has applied for benefits. All determinations
            required to be made under the provisions of this part shall be made
            by the agency responsible for making such determinations, as
            provided in this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Administration by FSA.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The provisions of this part which are applicable to FSA will be
            administered under the general supervision of the Administrator,
            FSA, and shall be carried out in the field in part by State FSA
            committees and county FSA committees (COC).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The FSA Deputy Administrator for Farm Programs may determine any
            question arising under the provisions of this part which are
            applicable to FSA and may reverse or modify any determination of
            eligibility with respect to programs administered by FSA made by a
            State FSA committee or COC or any other FSA office or FSA official
            (except the Administrator) in connection with the provisions of this
            part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FSA shall make the following determinations which are required to
            be made in accordance with this part:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whether a person produced an agricultural commodity on a particular
            field as determined under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='5' psec='#a_1' tq='N'>
                12.5(a)(1)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The establishment of field boundaries;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whether land was planted to an agricultural commodity in any of the
            years, 1981 through 1985, for the purposes of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='5' psec='#a_1' tq='N'>
                12.5(a)(1)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whether land was set aside, diverted, or otherwise not cultivated
            under a program administered by the Secretary for any crop to reduce
            production of an agricultural commodity under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='4' psec='#g' tq='N'>
                12.4(g)
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='5' psec='#a_1' tq='N'>
                12.5(a)(1)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whether for the purposes of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
                12.9
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , the production of an agricultural commodity on highly erodible
            land or converted wetland by a landlord&apos;s tenant or
            sharecropper is required under the terms and conditions of the
            agreement between the landlord and such tenant or sharecropper;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whether the conversion of a particular wetland was commenced before
            December 23, 1985, for the purposes of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='5' psec='#b_3' tq='N'>
                12.5(b)(3)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_vii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whether the conversion of a wetland was caused by a third party
            under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='5' psec='#b_1_vii_D' tq='N'>
                12.5(b)(1)(vii)(D)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_viii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (viii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whether certain violations were made in good faith under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='5' psec='#a_5' tq='N'>
                12.5(a)(5)
              </subref>
               or 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='5' psec='#b_5' tq='N'>
                12.5(b)(5)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_ix'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ix)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The determination of the amount of reduction in benefits based on
            the seriousness of the violation, based on technical information
            provided by NRCS;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_x'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (x)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The determination of whether the application of the producer&apos;s
            conservation system would impose an undue economic hardship on the
            producer; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_xi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (xi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whether the proceeds of a farm loan made, insured, or guaranteed by
            FSA will be used for a purpose that will contribute to excessive
            erosion of highly erodible land or to the conversion of wetland.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A representative number of farms selected in accordance with
            instructions issued by the Deputy Administrator shall be inspected
            by an authorized representative of FSA to determine compliance with
            any requirement specified in this part as a prerequisite for
            obtaining program benefits.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FSA may consult with U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service on third-party
            determinations.
            <PRTPAGE P='386' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Administration by NRCS.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The provisions of this part that are applicable to NRCS shall be
            administered under the general supervision of the Deputy Chief for
            Natural Resources Conservation Programs, and shall be carried out in
            the field by the regional conservationist, state conservationist,
            area conservationist, and district conservationist or other NRCS
            representative.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An NRCS representative shall make the following determinations
            which are required to be made in accordance with this part:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whether land is highly erodible or has a wetland type or a
            converted wetland identified in accordance with the provisions of
            this part;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whether highly erodible land is predominant on a particular field
            under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='22' psec='' tq='N'>
                12.22
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whether the conservation plan that a person is applying is based on
            the local NRCS field office technical guide and is approved by—
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='c_2_iii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The CD and NRCS, or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='c_2_iii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             By NRCS;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whether the conservation system that a person is using has been
            approved by the CD under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='5' psec='#a_2' tq='N'>
                12.5(a)(2)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             or, in an area not within a CD, a conservation system approved by
            NRCS to be adequate for the production of an agricultural commodity
            on highly erodible land;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whether the actions of a person(s) with respect to the conversion
            of a wetland or production of an agricultural commodity on converted
            wetland would have only a minimal effect on the functions and values
            of wetlands in the area;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whether an approved conservation plan is being applied on highly
            erodible fields in accordance with the schedule specified therein or
            whether a failure to apply the plan is technical and minor in
            nature, due to circumstances beyond the control of the person, or
            whether a temporary variance form the requirements of the plan
            should be granted;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_vii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whether an approved conservation system is being used on a highly
            erodible field;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_viii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (viii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whether the conversion of a wetland is for the purpose or has the
            effect of making the production of an agricultural commodity
            possible;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_ix'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ix)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whether a farmed wetland or farmed-wetland pasture is abandoned;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_x'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (x)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whether the planting of an agricultural commodity on a wetland is
            possible under natural conditions;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_xi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (xi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whether maintenance of existing drainage of a wetland described in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='33' psec='' tq='N'>
                12.33
              </subref>
            </aref>
             exceeds the scope and effect of the original drainage;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_xii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (xii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whether a plan for the mitigation of a converted wetland will be
            approved and whether the mitigation of a converted wetland is
            accomplished according to the approved mitigation plan;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_xiii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (xiii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whether all technical information relating to the determination of
            a violation and severity of a violation has been provided to FSA for
            making payment-reduction determinations; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_xiv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (xiv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whether or not a commenced-conversion activity was completed by
            January 1, 1995.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS may provide such other technical assistance for implementation
            of the provisions of this part as is determined to be necessary.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A person may obtain a highly erodible land or a wetland
            scope-and-effect determination by making a written request on Form
            AD-1026. The determination will be made in writing, and a copy will
            be provided to the person.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A determination of whether or not an area meets the highly erodible
            land criteria or whether wetland criteria, identified in accordance
            with the current Federal wetland delineation methodology in use at
            the time of the determination and that are consistent with current
            mapping conventions, may be made by the NRCS representative based
            upon existing records or other information and without the need for
            an on-site determination. This determination will be made by the
            NRCS representative as soon as possible following a request for such
            a determination.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An on-site determination as to whether an area meets the applicable
            criteria shall be made by an NRCS representative if the person has
            disagreed with the determination made under paragraph (c)(5) of this
            section, or if 
            <PRTPAGE P='387' />
            adequate information is not otherwise available to an NRCS
            representative on which to make an off-site determination.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An on-site determination, where applicable, will be made by the
            NRCS representative as soon as possible following a request for such
            a determination, but only when site conditions are favorable for the
            evaluation of soils, hydrology, or vegetation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             With regard to wetland determinations, if an area is continuously
            inundated or saturated for long periods of time during the growing
            season to such an extent that access by foot to make a determination
            of predominance of hydric soils or prevalence of hydrophytic
            vegetation is not feasible, the area will be determined to be a
            wetland.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Persons who are adversely affected by a determination made under
            this section and believe that the requirements of this part were
            improperly applied may appeal, under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='12' psec='' tq='N'>
                12.12
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
            , any determination by NRCS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Administration by NIFA.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The NIFA shall coordinate the related information and education
            program for USDA concerning implementation of this rule.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Assistance of other Federal agencies.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If NRCS determines, through agreement or otherwise, that the
            purposes of this part would be furthered by the assistance of other
            Federal agencies with wetland responsibilities, NRCS may accept such
            assistance and adopt any or all such actions by these agencies as an
            action by an NRCS representative under this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            61 FR 47025
          </aref>
          , Sept. 6, 1996; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            61 FR 53491
          </aref>
          , Oct. 11, 1996; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 4804
          </aref>
          , Jan. 27, 2011]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='509'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:12:A:12.7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        12.7
      </num>
      <head>
        Certification of compliance.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='12' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              12.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Certification of compliance.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Self-certification.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In order for a person to be determined to be eligible for any of
            the benefits specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
                12.4
              </subref>
            </aref>
            :
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             It must be determined by USDA whether any field in which the person
            applying for the benefits has an interest and intends to produce an
            agricultural commodity contains highly erodible land;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The person applying for or receiving the benefits must certify in
            writing on Form AD-1026 that such person will not produce an
            agricultural commodity on highly erodible land, or designate such
            land for conservation use; or plant an agricultural commodity on a
            converted wetland; or convert a wetland to make possible the
            production of an agricultural commodity during the crop year in
            which the person is seeking such benefits, unless such actions are
            exempt, under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
                12.5
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , from the provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
                12.4
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A person may certify application of practices required by the
            person&apos;s conservation plan. NRCS shall permit a person who
            makes such a certification with respect to a conservation plan to
            revise the conservation plan in any manner, if the same level of
            conservation treatment provided for by the conservation system under
            the person&apos;s conservation plan is maintained. NRCS may not
            revise the person&apos;s conservation plan without the concurrence
            of the person;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The person applying for a FSA direct or guaranteed farm credit
            program loan must certify that such person shall not use the
            proceeds of the loan for a purpose that will contribute to excessive
            erosion on highly erodible land or to conversion of wetlands for the
            purpose, or to have the effect, of making the production of an
            agricultural commodity possible; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The person applying for the benefits must authorize and provide
            representatives of USDA access to all land in which such person has
            an interest for the purpose of verifying any such certification.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Availability to other agencies.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each agency of USDA shall make all certifications of compliance
            received by such agency and the results of investigations concerning
            such certifications of compliance available to other agencies.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Compliance.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A certification made in accordance with this section does not
            relieve any person from compliance with provisions of this part.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='510'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:12:A:12.8
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        12.8
      </num>
      <head>
        Affiliated persons.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='12' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              12.8
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Affiliated persons.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Ineligibility of affiliated persons.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Ineligibility of an individual or entity under this part for
            benefits shall also be an ineligibility for benefits for “affiliated
            persons” as defined in this section.
            <PRTPAGE P='388' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Affiliated persons of an individual.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the person requesting benefits is an individual, the affiliated
            persons are:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The spouse and minor child of such person or guardian of such
            child; except that spouses who establish to the satisfaction of the
            COC that operations of the husband and wife are maintained
            separately and independently shall not be considered affiliates;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any partnership, joint venture, or other enterprise in which the
            person or any person listed in paragraphs (b)(1) has an ownership
            interest or financial interest; unless such interest is held
            indirectly through another business enterprise; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any trust in which the individual, business enterprise, or any
            person listed in paragraph (b)(1) is a beneficiary or has a
            financial interest, unless such interest is held indirectly through
            another business enterprise.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Affiliated persons of an entity.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the person who has requested benefits from USDA is a
            corporation, partnership, or other joint venture, the affiliated
            persons are any participant or stockholder therein of the
            corporation, partnership, or other joint venture, except for persons
            who have an indirect interest through another business enterprise in
            such corporation, partnership, or other joint venture or persons
            with a 20 percent or less share in a corporation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Limitation.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any reduction in payments which results only from the application
            of the affiliation provisions of this section to a partnership,
            joint venture, trust, or other enterprise shall be limited to the
            extent of interest held in such partnership, joint venture, trust,
            or other enterprise by the person or business enterprise that
            committed the violation. However, for violations for which the
            business enterprise is considered directly responsible under the
            provisions of this part, the business enterprise shall be subject to
            a full loss of benefits, including those instances in which the
            business enterprise has an interest in the land where the violation
            occurred or where the business enterprise had an interest in the
            crops produced on the land.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Avoidance of this part.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Limitations on affiliation shall not apply as needed to correct for
            any action that would otherwise tend to defeat the purposes of this
            part.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='511'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:12:A:12.9
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        12.9
      </num>
      <head>
        Landlords and tenants.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='12' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
              12.9
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Landlords and tenants.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Landlord eligibility.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as provided in paragraph (a)(2) of this section, the
            ineligibility of a tenant or sharecropper for benefits (as
            determined under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
                12.4
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) shall not cause a landlord to be ineligible for USDA program
            benefits accruing with respect to land other than those in which the
            tenant or sharecropper has an interest.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The provisions of paragraph (a)(1) of this section shall not be
            applicable to a landlord if the production of an agricultural
            commodity on highly erodible land or converted wetland by the
            landlord&apos;s tenant or sharecropper is required under the terms
            and conditions of the agreement between the landlord and such tenant
            or sharecropper and such agreement was entered into after December
            23, 1985, or if the landlord has acquiesced in such activities by
            the tenant or sharecropper.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Tenant or renter eligibility.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The ineligibility of a tenant or renter may be limited to the
            program benefits listed in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='4' psec='#c' tq='N'>
                12.4(c)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             accruing with respect to only the farm on which the violation
            occurred if:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The tenant or renter shows that a good-faith effort was made to
            comply by developing an approved conservation plan for the highly
            erodible land in a timely manner and prior to any violation of the
            provisions of this part; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The owner of such farm refuses to apply such a plan and prevents
            the tenant or renter from implementing certain practices that are a
            part of the approved conservation plan; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FSA determines that the lack of compliance is not a part of a
            scheme or device as described in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
                12.10
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If relief is granted under paragraph (b)(1) of this section, the
            tenant or renter must actively apply those conservation treatment
            measures that are determined to be within the control of the tenant
            or renter.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='512'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:12:A:12.10
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        12.10
      </num>
      <head>
        Scheme or device.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='12' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
              12.10
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Scheme or device.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          All or any part of the benefits listed in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='12' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              12.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
           otherwise due a person from USDA may be withheld or required to 
          <PRTPAGE P='389' />
          be refunded if the person adopts or participates in adopting any
          scheme or device designed to evade, or which has the effect of
          evading, the provisions of this part. Such acts shall include, but are
          not limited to, concealing from USDA any information having a bearing
          on the application of the provisions of this part or submitting false
          information to USDA or creating entities for the purpose of concealing
          the interest of a person in a farming operation or to otherwise avoid
          compliance with the provisions of this part. Such acts shall also
          include acquiescence in, approval of, or assistance to acts which have
          the effect of, or the purpose of, circumventing these regulations.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='513'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:12:A:12.11
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        12.11
      </num>
      <head>
        Action based upon advice or action of USDA.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='12' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
              12.11
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Action based upon advice or action of USDA.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The provisions of 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            part 718 of
          </aref>
           this Title, as amended, relating to performance based upon the action
          or advice of a County Committee (COC) or State FSA Committee shall be
          applicable to the provisions of this part. In addition, if it is
          determined by the appropriate USDA agency that the action of a person
          which would form the basis of any ineligibility under this part was
          taken by such person in good-faith reliance on erroneous advice,
          information, or action of any other authorized representative of USDA,
          the appropriate agency may make such benefits available to the extent
          that similar relief would be allowed under 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR part 
            <subref title='7' part='718' tq='N'>
              718
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='514'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:12:A:12.12
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        12.12
      </num>
      <head>
        Appeals.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='12' sect='12' psec='' tq='N'>
              12.12
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Appeals.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Any person who has been or who would be denied program benefits in
          accordance with 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='12' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              12.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
           as the result of any determination made in accordance with the
          provisions of this part may obtain a review of such determination in
          accordance with the administrative appeals procedures of the agency
          which rendered such determination. Agency appeal procedures are
          contained in the Code of Federal Regulations as follows: FSA, 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='780' tq='N'>
              780 of this title
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; NRCS, 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='614' tq='N'>
              614 of this title
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; Rural Utilities Service, 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='1900' tq='N'>
              1900
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , subpart B of this title.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='515'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:12:B:12.20
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        12.20
      </num>
      <head>
        NRCS responsibilities regarding highly erodible land.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='12' sect='20' psec='' tq='N'>
              12.20
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          NRCS responsibilities regarding highly erodible land.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          In implementing the provisions of this part, NRCS shall, to the extent
          practicable:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Develop and maintain criteria for identifying highly erodible
            lands;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Prepare and make available to the public lists of highly erodible
            soil map units;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Make soil surveys for purposes of identifying highly erodible land;
            and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provide technical guidance to conservation districts which approve
            conservation plans and systems, in consultation with local county
            FSA committees, for the purposes of this part.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='516'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:12:B:12.21
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        12.21
      </num>
      <head>
        Identification of highly erodible lands criteria.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          61 FR 47025
        </aref>
        , Sept. 6, 1996; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          61 FR 53491
        </aref>
        , Oct. 11, 1996]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='12' sect='21' psec='' tq='N'>
              12.21
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Identification of highly erodible lands criteria.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Basis for identification as highly erodible.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Soil map units and an erodibility index will be used as the basis
            for identifying highly erodible land. The erodibility index for a
            soil is determined by dividing the potential average annual rate of
            erosion for each soil by its predetermined soil loss tolerance (T)
            value. The T value represents the maximum annual rate of soil
            erosion that could occur without causing a decline in long-term
            productivity. The equation for measuring erosion is described below.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The potential average annual rate of sheet and rill erosion is
            estimated by multiplying the following factors of the Universal Soil
            Loss Equation (USLE):
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Rainfall and runoff (R);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The degree to which the soil resists water erosion (K); and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The function (LS), which includes the effects of slope length (L)
            and steepness (S).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The potential average annual rate of wind erosion is estimated by
            multiplying the following factors of the Wind Erosion Equation
            (WEQ): Climatic characterization of windspeed and surface soil
            moisture (C) and the degree to which soil resists wind erosion (I).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The USLE is explained in the U.S. Department of Agriculture
            Handbook 
            <PRTPAGE P='390' />
            537, “Predicting Rainfall Erosion Losses.” The WEQ is explained in
            the paper by Woodruff, N.P., and F. H. Siddaway, 1965, “A Wind
            Erosion Equation,” Soil Science Society of America Proceedings, Vol.
            29. No. 5, pages 602-608. Values for all the factors used in these
            equations are contained in the NRCS field office technical guide and
            the references which are a part of the guide. The Universal Soil
            Loss Equation, the Revised Universal Soil Loss Equation, and the
            Wind Erosion Equation and the rules under which NRCS uses the
            equations are published at 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='610' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
                610.11
              </subref>
            </aref>
             through 610.15 of this title.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Highly erodible.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A soil map unit shall be determined to be highly erodible if either
            the RKLS/T or the CI/T value for the map unit equals or exceeds 8.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Potentially highly erodible.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whenever a soil map unit description contains a range of a slope
            length and steepness characteristics that produce a range of LS
            values which result in RKLS/T quotients both above and below 8, the
            soil map unit will be entered on the list of highly erodible soil
            map units as “potentially highly erodible.” The final determination
            of erodibility for an individual field containing these soil map
            unit delineations will be made by an on-site investigation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            61 FR 47025
          </aref>
          , Sept. 6, 1996; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            61 FR 53491
          </aref>
          , Oct. 11, 1996]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='517'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:12:B:12.22
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        12.22
      </num>
      <head>
        Highly erodible field determination criteria.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          61 FR 47025
        </aref>
        , Sept. 6, 1996; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          61 FR 53491
        </aref>
        , Oct. 11, 1996]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='12' sect='22' psec='' tq='N'>
              12.22
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Highly erodible field determination criteria.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Predominance.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Highly erodible land shall be considered to be predominant on a
            field if either:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             33.33 percent or more of the total field acreage is identified as
            soil map units which are highly erodible; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             50 or more acres in such field are identified as soil map units
            which are highly erodible.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Modification of field boundaries.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A person may request the modification of field boundaries for the
            purpose of excluding highly erodible land from a field. Such a
            request must be submitted to, and is subject to the approval of,
            FSA. FSA shall use the technical determination of NRCS in approving
            this request.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Impact of changing field boundaries.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When field boundaries are changed to include areas of land that
            were included in a field that was previously determined to be
            predominately highly erodible according to paragraph (a) of this
            section, such areas shall continue to be subject to the requirements
            for predominately highly erodible fields, except as provided in
            paragraph (b) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Small area of noncropland.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Small areas of noncropland within or adjacent to the boundaries of
            existing highly erodible crop fields such as abandoned farmsteads,
            areas around filled or capped wells, rock piles, trees, or brush
            which are converted to cropland are considered to meet the
            requirement of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='5' psec='#a_2' tq='N'>
                12.5(a)(2)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             if they are included in an approved conservation plan for the
            entire highly erodible field.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            61 FR 47025
          </aref>
          , Sept. 6, 1996; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            61 FR 53491
          </aref>
          , Oct. 11, 1996]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='518'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:12:B:12.23
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        12.23
      </num>
      <head>
        Conservation plans and conservation systems.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='12' sect='23' psec='' tq='N'>
              12.23
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Conservation plans and conservation systems.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Use of field office technical guide.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A conservation plan or conservation system developed for the
            purposes of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='5' psec='#a' tq='N'>
                12.5(a)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             must be based on, and to the extent practicable conform with, the
            NRCS field office technical guide in use at the time the plan is
            developed or revised. For highly erodible croplands which were used
            to produce agricultural commodities prior to December 23, 1985, the
            applicable conservation systems in the field office technical guide
            are designed to achieve substantial reductions in soil erosion.
            Conservation systems shall be technically and economically feasible;
            based on local resource conditions and available conservation
            technology; cost-effective; and shall not cause undue economic
            hardship on the person applying the conservation system. Any
            conservation plans or systems that were approved prior to July 3,
            1996, are deemed to be in compliance with this paragraph.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Substantial reduction in soil erosion.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For the purpose of determining whether there is a substantial
            reduction in soil erosion on a field containing highly erodible
            cropland which was used to produce an agricultural commodity 
            <PRTPAGE P='391' />
            prior to December 23, 1985, the measurement of erosion reduction
            achieved by applying a conservation plan or system shall be based on
            a comparison of the estimated annual level of erosion that is
            expected to occur on that portion of the field for which a
            conservation plan or system was developed and is being applied, to
            the estimated annual level of erosion that existed on that same
            portion of the field before the application of a conservation plan
            or system. On a field that is converted from native vegetation after
            July 3, 1996, and where any crop production will result in increased
            erosion, in no case will the required conservation plan or system
            permit a substantial increase in erosion.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Field trials.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS may allow a person to include in the person&apos;s
            conservation plan or a conservation system under the plan, on a
            field-trial basis, practices that are not currently approved but
            that NRCS considers have a reasonable likelihood of success. These
            trials must have prior approval by NRCS, and must be documented in
            the person&apos;s conservation plan specifying the limited time
            period during which the field trial is in effect. If, at the end of
            the conservation field trial period, NRCS finds that the practice
            does not meet conservation compliance requirements, the person will
            not be ineligible for USDA program benefits during the period of the
            field trial.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Highly erodible land previously under a Conservation Reserve
              Program contract.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any person who owns or operates highly erodible land that was under
            a Conservation Reserve Program contract as authorized by 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 1231 of
            </aref>
             the Food Security Act of 1985, as amended, shall have 2 years after
            the expiration of termination of the contract to fully apply a
            conservation system if the conservation plan for such land requires
            the installation of structural measures for the production of an
            agricultural commodity. NRCS officials may extend this period one
            additional year for circumstances beyond the control of the person.
            The person shall not be required to meet a higher conservation
            standard than the standard applied to other highly erodible cropland
            located within the area served by the field office technical guide
            for the area in which the field is located.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Information regarding conservation options.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS, in providing assistance to a person for the preparation or
            revision of a conservation plan under this part, will provide such
            person with information concerning cost-effective and applicable
            erosion control alternatives, crop flexibility, or other
            conservation assistance options that may be available.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Timely request for assistance.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Persons who require NRCS assistance for the development of a
            conservation plan or the installation of a conservation system are
            encouraged to request this assistance well in advance of deadline
            dates for compliance; otherwise the person may not be able to comply
            with these provisions and maintain eligibility for USDA program
            benefits.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Action by conservation districts.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Conservation districts approve or disapprove conservation plans or
            conservation systems after NRCS determines that the plans or systems
            conform to the NRCS field office technical guide. If a conservation
            district fails, without due cause, to act on a request for
            conservation plan or conservation system approval within 45 days, or
            if no conservation district exists, NRCS will approve or disapprove,
            as appropriate, the conservation plan or system in question.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Application of a conservation plan or system.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A person is considered to be applying a conservation plan for
            purposes of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='5' psec='#a' tq='N'>
                12.5(a)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             if the conservation system or plan being applied achieves or
            exceeds the substantial reduction in soil erosion as described in
            paragraph (b) which the conservation system or plan was designed to
            achieve. It is the responsibility of the person to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Certify that the conservation plan or system is being applied; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Arrange for a revision of the conservation plan with NRCS, if
            changes are made in land use, crop rotation or management,
            conservation practices, or in the original schedule of practice
            installation that would affect the achievement of substantial
            reduction in soil erosion in a given crop year.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Appeal to FSA.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Persons who are adversely affected by the determinations made under
            this subpart and believe 
            <PRTPAGE P='392' />
            that the requirements of this subpart were improperly applied may
            appeal the decision to FSA under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='12' psec='' tq='N'>
                12.12
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Undue economic hardship.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             After a technical determination has been made, the FSA county
            committee shall, if a person asserts that the application of the
            person&apos;s conservation system would impose an undue economic
            hardship on the person, make a recommendation to the State FSA
            Committee as to whether or not the application of the conservation
            system would impose an undue economic hardship. The State FSA
            Committee may provide the person with a variance on the basis of the
            hardship. Under this variance, and any conditions that may be
            required in the variance, the person will be considered to be in
            compliance with the applicable provisions of this part. The State
            FSA Committee will consider relevant factors, such as the cost of
            installation of required conservation practices and benefits earned
            through programs subject to compliance with this part, and the
            person&apos;s general economic situation.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='519'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:12:C:12.30
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        12.30
      </num>
      <head>
        NRCS responsibilities regarding wetlands.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          61 FR 47025
        </aref>
        , Sept. 6, 1996; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          61 FR 53491
        </aref>
        , Oct. 11, 1996; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          76 FR 22785
        </aref>
        , Apr. 25, 2011]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='12' sect='30' psec='' tq='N'>
              12.30
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          NRCS responsibilities regarding wetlands.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Technical and coordination responsibilities.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In carrying out the provisions of this part, NRCS shall:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Oversee the development and application of criteria to identify
            hydric soils in consultation with the National Technical Committee
            for Hydric Soils and make available to the public an approved county
            list of hydric soil map units, which is based upon the National List
            of Hydric Soils;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Coordinate with the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service and others in
            updating the National List of Plant Species that Occur in Wetlands;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Make or approve wetland determinations, delineations and
            certifications, functional assessments, mitigation plans,
            categorical minimal effects, and other technical determinations
            relative to the implementation of the wetland conservation
            provisions of this part;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Develop and utilize off-site and on-site wetland identification
            procedures;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Assure quality of service and determinations through procedures
            developed by NRCS in consultation with other Federal agencies that
            have wetland responsibilities;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Investigate complaints and make technical determinations regarding
            potential violations;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Develop a process at the state level, in coordination with the U.S.
            Fish and Wildlife Service, to ensure that these provisions are
            carried out in a technically defensible and timely manner, seek
            assistance as appropriate, and annually review the progress being
            made on implementation; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Technical assistance from others
            </E>
             In carrying out the provisions of this part, NRCS may request
            technical assistance from the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, State
            or local agencies, conservation districts, or qualified private
            entities when NRCS determines that additional staff resources or
            technical expertise are needed to address adequately the
            requirements of this part or to enhance the quality of
            implementation of this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Certification of wetland determinations and wetland delineations.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Certification of a wetland determination means that the wetland
            determination is of sufficient quality to make a determination of
            ineligibility for program benefits under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
                12.4
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
            . NRCS may certify a wetland determination without making a field
            investigation. NRCS will notify the person affected by the
            certification and provide an opportunity to appeal the certification
            prior to the certification becoming final. All wetland
            determinations made after July 3, 1996, will be done on a tract
            basis and will be considered certified wetland determinations. A
            not-inventoried designation within a certified wetland is subject to
            change when the soil, hydrology, and vegetation evaluation is
            completed and identified as to type of wetland or as a non-wetland.
            This change from a not-inventoried designation to an approved
            wetland designation will be done at the request of the landowner or
            during a formal investigation of a potential violation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The wetland determination and wetland delineation shall be
            certified 
            <PRTPAGE P='393' />
            as final by the NRCS official 30 days after providing the person
            notice of certification or, if an appeal is filed with USDA, after
            the administrative appeal procedures are exhausted.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the case of an appeal, NRCS will review and certify the accuracy
            of the determination of all lands subject to the appeal to ensure
            that the subject lands have been accurately delineated. Prior to a
            decision being rendered on the appeal, NRCS will conduct an on-site
            investigation of the subject land.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Before any benefits are withheld, an on-site investigation of a
            potential wetland violation will be made by NRCS. The affected
            person will be provided an opportunity to appeal the on-site
            determination to USDA if the on-site determination differs from the
            original determination. Such action by NRCS shall be considered a
            review of the prior determination and certification of the
            delineation. If the prior determination was a certified wetland
            determination, an appeal of the NRCS on-site determination shall be
            limited to the determination that the wetland was converted in
            violation of this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A copy of the information from the final certified wetland
            determination and the wetland delineation shall be recorded on
            official USDA aerial photography, digital imagery, or other graphic
            representation of the area.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             As long as the affected person is in compliance with the wetland
            conservation provision of this part, and as long as the area is
            devoted to the use and management of the land for production of
            food, fiber, or horticultural crops, a certification made under this
            section will remain valid and in effect until such time as the
            person affected by the certification requests review of the
            certification by NRCS. A person may request review of a
            certification only if a natural event alters the topography or
            hydrology of the subject land to the extent that the final
            certification is no longer a reliable indication of site conditions,
            or if NRCS concurs with an affected person that an error exists in
            the current wetland determination
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            61 FR 47025
          </aref>
          , Sept. 6, 1996; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            61 FR 53491
          </aref>
          , Oct. 11, 1996; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 22785
          </aref>
          , Apr. 25, 2011]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='520'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:12:C:12.31
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        12.31
      </num>
      <head>
        On-site wetland identification criteria.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          61 FR 47025
        </aref>
        , Sept. 6, 1996, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          69 FR 18803
        </aref>
        , Apr. 9, 2004; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          76 FR 82077
        </aref>
        , Dec. 30, 2011]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='12' sect='31' psec='' tq='N'>
              12.31
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          On-site wetland identification criteria.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Hydric soils.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS shall identify hydric soils through the use of published soil
            maps which reflect soil surveys completed by NRCS or through the use
            of on-site reviews. If a published soil map is unavailable for a
            given area, NRCS may use unpublished soil maps which were made
            according to the specifications of the National Cooperative Soil
            Survey or may conduct an on-site evaluation of the land.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS shall determine whether an area of a field or other parcel of
            land has a predominance of hydric soils that are inundated or
            saturated as follows:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a soil map unit has hydric soil as all or part of its name, that
            soil map unit or portion of the map unit related to the hydric soil
            shall be determined to have a predominance of hydric soils;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a soil map unit is named for a miscellaneous area that meets the
            criteria for hydric soils (i.e., riverwash, playas, beaches, or
            water) the soil map unit shall be determined to have a predominance
            of hydric soils; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a soil map unit contains inclusions of hydric soils, that
            portion of the soil map unit identified as hydric soil shall be
            determined to have a predominance of hydric soils.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              List of hydric soils.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Hydric soils are those soils which meet criteria set forth in the
            publication “Hydric Soils of the United States 1985” which was
            developed by the National Technical Committee for Hydric Soils and
            which is incorporated by reference. This publication may be obtained
            upon request by writing NRCS at U.S. Department of Agriculture, P.O.
            Box 2890, Washington, DC 20013, and is available for inspection at
            the National Archives and Records Administration (NARA). For
            information on the availability of this material at NARA, call
            202-741-6030, or go to: 
            <E T='03'>
              http://www.archives.gov/federal_register/code_of_federal_regulations/ibr_locations.html.
            </E>
             Incorporation of this publication by reference was approved by the
            Director of the Federal Register on June 24, 1986. The materials are
            incorporated as they exist on the date of the approval and a notice
            of any change in these materials will be published in the 
            <E T='04'>
              Federal Register
            </E>
            .
            <PRTPAGE P='394' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An official list of hydric soil map units shall be maintained at
            the local NRCS office and shall include—
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='a_3_ii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All soils from the National List of Hydric Soils that can be found
            in that field office area, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='a_3_ii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any soil map units or areas which the state conservationist
            determines to meet such hydric soil criteria.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any deletions of a hydric soil unit from the hydric soil map unit
            list must be made according to the established procedure contained
            in the publication “Hydric Soils of the United States 1985” for
            adding or deleting soils from the National List of Hydric Soils.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Hydrophytic vegetation.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Hydrophytic vegetation consists of plants growing in water or in a
            substrate that is at least periodically deficient in oxygen during a
            growing season as a result of excessive water content.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A plant shall be considered to be a plant species that occurs in
            wetland if such plant is listed in the National List of Plant
            Species that Occur in Wetlands. The publication may be obtained upon
            request from the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service at National Wetland
            Inventory, Monroe Bldg. Suite 101, 9720 Executive Center Drive, St.
            Petersburg, Florida 33702.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For the purposes of the definition of “wetland” in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
                12.2
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
            , land shall be determined to have a prevalence of hydrophytic
            vegetation if:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS determines through the criteria specified in paragraph (b)(3)
            of this section that under normal circumstances such land supports a
            prevalence of hydrophytic vegetation. The term “normal
            circumstances” refers to the soil and hydrologic conditions that are
            normally present, without regard to whether the vegetation has been
            removed; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the event the vegetation on such land has been altered or
            removed, NRCS will determine if a prevalence of hydrophytic
            vegetation typically exists in the local area on the same hydric
            soil map unit under non-altered hydrologic conditions.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The determination of prevalence of hydrophytic vegetation will be
            made in accordance with the current Federal wetland delineation
            methodology in use by NRCS at the time of the determination.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Mitigation wetlands.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notwithstanding the provisions of this section, wetlands which are
            created in order to mitigate the loss of other wetlands as a result
            of irrigation, recreation, municipal water, flood control, or other
            similar projects shall not be considered to be artificial wetland
            for the purposes of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='5' psec='#b_1_vii_A' tq='N'>
                12.5(b)(1)(vii)(A)
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Minimal effect determination.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For the purposes of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='5' psec='#b_1_v' tq='N'>
                12.5(b)(1)(v)
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
            , NRCS shall determine whether the effect of any action of a person
            associated with the conversion of a wetland, the conversion of
            wetland and the production of an agricultural commodity on converted
            wetland, or the combined effect of the production of an agricultural
            commodity on a wetland converted by someone else has a minimal
            effect on the functions and values of wetlands in the area. Such
            determination shall be based upon a functional assessment of
            functions and values of the wetland under consideration and other
            related wetlands in the area, and will be made through an on-site
            evaluation. A request for such determination will be made prior to
            the beginning of activities that would convert the wetland. If a
            person has converted a wetland and then seeks a determination that
            the effect of such conversion on wetland was minimal, the burden
            will be upon the person to demonstrate to the satisfaction of NRCS
            that the effect was minimal.
          </text>
        </P>
        <FP>
          The production of an agricultural commodity on any portion of a
          converted wetland in conformance with a minimal-effect determination
          by NRCS is exempt under 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='12' sect='5' psec='#b_1_v' tq='N'>
              12.5(b)(1)(v)
            </subref>
             of this part
          </aref>
          . However, any additional action of a person that will change the
          functions and values of a wetland for which a minimal-effect
          determination has been made shall be reported to NRCS for a
          determination of whether the effect continues to be minimal. The loss
          of a minimal effect determination will cause a person who produces an
          agricultural commodity on the converted wetland after such change in
          status to be ineligible, under 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='12' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              12.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , for certain program benefits. In situations where the wetland
          values, acreage, and functions are replaced by the restoration, 
          <PRTPAGE P='395' />
          enhancement or creation of a wetland in accordance with a mitigation
          plan approved by NRCS, the exemption provided by the determination
          will be effective after NRCS determines that all practices in a
          mitigation plan are being implemented.
        </FP>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Categorical Minimal Effect Exemptions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The state conservationist, in consultation with the state technical
            committee established under 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='16' sect='3861' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/3861.html'>
                16 U.S.C. 3861
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , shall identify any categories of conversion activities and
            conditions which are routinely determined by NRCS to have minimal
            effect on wetland functions and values, as described in paragraph
            (d) of this section, and recommend to the Chief, NRCS, or a
            designee, inclusion on a list of categorical minimal effect
            exemptions.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Chief, or designee, shall evaluate the conversion practices
            recommended by the state conservationists in the region to ensure
            consistency across State and regional lines, and to determine
            whether any categories of conversion activities identified pursuant
            to paragraph (e)(1) of this section, if such activities were exempt
            from the ineligibility provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
                12.4
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , would only have a minimal effect on wetland functions and values
            in a wetland system within the region.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any categories of conversion activities which meet the criteria of
            paragraph (e)(2) of this section will be published in the 
            <E T='04'>
              Federal Register
            </E>
             for inclusion in this part and shall be exempt under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='5' psec='#b_1_v' tq='N'>
                12.5(b)(1)(v)
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The NRCS local field office shall maintain a list of any activities
            and conditions which are determined by the Chief, or designee,
            exempt pursuant to this section and will provide the list to a
            person upon request.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            61 FR 47025
          </aref>
          , Sept. 6, 1996, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            69 FR 18803
          </aref>
          , Apr. 9, 2004; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 82077
          </aref>
          , Dec. 30, 2011]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='521'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:12:C:12.32
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        12.32
      </num>
      <head>
        Converted wetland identification criteria.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='12' sect='32' psec='' tq='N'>
              12.32
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Converted wetland identification criteria.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Converted wetland shall be identified by determining whether the
            wetland was altered so as to meet the definition of converted
            wetland. In making this determination, the following factors are to
            be considered:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Where hydric soils have been used for production of an agricultural
            commodity and the effect of the drainage or other altering activity
            is not clearly discernible, NRCS will compare the site with other
            sites containing the same hydric soils in a natural condition to
            determine if the hydric soils can or cannot be used to produce an
            agricultural commodity under natural conditions. If the soil on the
            comparison site could not produce an agricultural commodity under
            natural conditions, the subject wetland will be considered to be
            converted wetland.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Where woody hydrophytic vegetation has been removed from hydric
            soils for the purpose of or permitting the production of an
            agricultural commodity, the area will be considered to be converted
            wetland.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A wetland shall not be considered to be converted if:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Production of an agricultural commodity on such land is possible as
            a result of a natural condition, such as drought, and it is
            determined that the actions of the person producing such
            agricultural commodity does not permanently alter or destroy natural
            wetland characteristics. Destruction of herbaceous hydrophytic
            vegetation (i.e., plants other than woody shrubs or trees) as a
            result of the production of an agricultural commodity shall not be
            considered as altering or destroying natural wetland characteristic
            if such vegetation could return following cessation of the natural
            condition which made production of the agricultural commodity
            possible; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Such land is correctly identified as farmed wetland or
            farmed-wetland pasture.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='522'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:12:C:12.33
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        12.33
      </num>
      <head>
        Use of wetland and converted wetland.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          61 FR 47025
        </aref>
        , Sept. 6, 1996, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          76 FR 82077
        </aref>
        , Dec. 30, 2011]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='12' sect='33' psec='' tq='N'>
              12.33
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Use of wetland and converted wetland.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='32' psec='#b_2' tq='N'>
                12.32(b)(2)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             are intended to protect remaining values, acreage, and functions of
            the wetlands described therein. Persons may continue to farm such
            wetlands under natural conditions or as they did prior to December
            23, 1985. However, no action can be taken to increase effects on the
            water regime beyond that which existed on such lands on or before
            December 23, 1985, unless NRCS determines the effect on losing
            remaining wetland values would be minimal under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='5' psec='#b_1_v' tq='N'>
                12.5(b)(1)(v)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . If, after December 23, 
            <PRTPAGE P='396' />
            1985, changes due to human activity occurred in the watershed and
            resulted in an increase in the water regime on a person&apos;s land,
            the person may be allowed to adjust the existing drainage system to
            accommodate the increased water regime on the condition that the
            person affected by this additional water provides NRCS with
            appropriate documentation of the increased water regime, the causes
            thereof, and the planned changes in the existing drainage system. In
            order to maintain program eligibility, a person must provide
            sufficient documentation and receive approval from NRCS prior to
            making any changes that will have the effect of increasing the
            capacity of the existing drainage systems.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Unless otherwise provided in this part, the production of an
            agricultural commodity on land determined by NRCS to be
            prior-converted cropland is exempted by law from these regulations
            for the area which was converted. Maintenance or improvement of
            drainage systems on prior-converted croplands are not subject to
            this rule so long as the prior-converted croplands are used for the
            production of food, forage, or fiber and as long as such actions do
            not alter the hydrology of nearby wetlands or do not make possible
            the production of an agricultural commodity on these other wetlands.
            Other wetlands under this section means any natural wetland, farmed
            wetland, farmed-wetland pasture, or any converted wetland that is
            not exempt under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
                12.5
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Abandonment is the cessation for five consecutive years of
            management or maintenance operations related to the use of a farmed
            wetland or a farmed-wetland pasture. Unless the criteria for
            receiving an exemption under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='5' psec='#b_1_iii' tq='N'>
                12.5(b)(1)(iii)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             are met, such land is considered to be abandoned when the land
            meets the wetland criteria of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='31' psec='' tq='N'>
                12.31
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . In order for documentation of site conditions to be considered
            adequate under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='5' psec='#b_1_iii' tq='N'>
                12.5(b)(1)(iii)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , the affected person must provide to NRCS available information
            concerning the extent of hydrological manipulation, the extent of
            woody vegetation, and the history of use. In accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='5' psec='#b_1_iii' tq='N'>
                12.5(b)(1)(iii)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , participation in a USDA approved wetland restoration, set-aside,
            diverted acres, or similar programs shall not be deemed to
            constitute abandonment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The maintenance of the drainage capacity or any alteration or
            manipulation, including the maintenance of a natural waterway
            operated and maintained as a drainage outlet, that affects the
            circulation and flow of water made to a farmed wetland or
            farmed-wetland pasture would not cause a person to be determined to
            be ineligible under this part, provided that the maintenance does
            not exceed the scope and effect of the original alteration or
            manipulation, as determined by NRCS, and provided that the area is
            not abandoned. Any resultant conversion of wetlands is to be at the
            minimum extent practicable, as determined by NRCS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            61 FR 47025
          </aref>
          , Sept. 6, 1996, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 82077
          </aref>
          , Dec. 30, 2011]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='523'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:12:C:12.34
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        12.34
      </num>
      <head>
        Paperwork Reduction Act assigned number.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='12' sect='34' psec='' tq='N'>
              12.34
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Paperwork Reduction Act assigned number.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The information collection requirements contained in this regulation (
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR part 
            <subref title='7' part='12' tq='N'>
              12
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ) have been approved by the Office of Management and Budget under
          provisions of 44 U.S.C. chapter 35 and have been assigned OMB Number
          0560-0004.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>