<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol7'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:785
    </extid>
    <num>
      785
    </num>
    <head>
      CERTIFIED STATE MEDIATION PROGRAM
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='5' sect='301' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/5/301.html'>
              5 U.S.C. 301
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='1989' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1989.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 1989
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; and 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='5101-510' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/5101-510.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 5101-510
            </subref>
          </aref>
          4.
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            67 FR 57315
          </aref>
          , Sept. 10, 2002, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='7255'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:785:-:785.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        785.1
      </num>
      <head>
        General.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='785' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              785.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             States meeting conditions specified in this part may have their
            mediation programs certified by the Farm Service Agency (FSA) and
            receive Federal grant funds for the operation and administration of
            agricultural mediation programs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             USDA agencies participate in mediations pursuant to agency rules
            governing their informal appeals processes. Where mediation of an
            agency decision by a certified State mediation program is available
            to participants in an agency program as part of the agency&apos;s
            informal appeal process, the agency will offer a participant
            receiving notice of an agency decision the opportunity to mediate
            the decision under the State&apos;s certified mediation program, in
            accordance with the agency&apos;s informal appeals regulations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             USDA agencies making mediation available as part of the agency
            informal appeals process may execute memoranda of understanding with
            a certified mediation program concerning procedures and policies for
            mediations during agency informal appeals that are not inconsistent
            with this part or other applicable regulations. Each such memorandum
            of understanding will be deemed part of the grant agreement
            governing the operation and administration of a State certified
            mediation program receiving Federal grant funds under this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A mediator in a program certified under this part has no authority
            to make decisions that are binding on parties to a dispute.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No person may be compelled to participate in mediation provided
            through a mediation program certified under this part. This
            provision shall not affect a State law requiring mediation before
            foreclosure on agricultural land or property.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='7256'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:785:-:785.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        785.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='785' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              785.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Administrator
          </E>
           means the Administrator, FSA, or authorized designee.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Certified State mediation program
          </E>
           means a program providing mediation services that has been certified
          in accordance with 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='785' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              785.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Confidential mediation
          </E>
           means a mediation process in which the mediator will not disclose to
          any person oral or written communications provided to the mediator in
          confidence, except as allowed by 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='5' sect='574' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/5/574.html'>
              5 U.S.C. 574
            </subref>
          </aref>
           or 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='785' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
              785.9
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Covered persons
          </E>
           means producers, their creditors (as applicable), and other persons
          directly affected by actions of the USDA involving one or more of the
          following issues:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Wetlands determinations;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Compliance with farm programs, including conservation programs;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Agricultural loans (regardless of whether the loans are made or
            guaranteed by the USDA or are made by a third party);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Rural water loan programs;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Grazing on National Forest System lands;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Pesticides; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Such other issues as the Secretary may consider appropriate.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Fiscal year
          </E>
           means the period of time beginning October 1 of one year and ending
          September 30 of the next year and designated by the year in which it
          ends.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            FSA
          </E>
           means the Farm Service Agency of the U.S. Department of Agriculture,
          or a successor agency.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Mediation services
          </E>
           means all activities relating to the intake and scheduling of
          mediations; the provision of background and selected information
          regarding the mediation process; financial advisory and counseling
          services (as reasonable and necessary to prepare parties for
          mediation) performed by a person other than a State mediation program
          mediator; and mediation sessions in which a mediator assists disputing
          parties in voluntarily reaching mutually agreeable settlement of
          issues within the laws, regulations, and the agency&apos;s generally
          applicable program policies and procedures, but has no authoritative
          decision making power.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Mediator
          </E>
           means a neutral individual who functions specifically to aid the 
          <PRTPAGE P='369' />
          parties in a dispute during a mediation process.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Qualified mediator
          </E>
           means a mediator who meets the training requirements established by
          State law in the State in which mediation services will be provided
          or, where a State has no law prescribing mediator qualifications, an
          individual who has attended a minimum of 40 hours of core mediator
          knowledge and skills training and, to remain in a qualified mediator
          status, completes a minimum of 20 hours of additional training or
          education during each 2-year period. Such training or education must
          be approved by the USDA, by an accredited college or university, or by
          one of the following organizations: State Bar of a qualifying State, a
          State mediation association, a State approved mediation program, or a
          society of professionals in dispute resolution.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Qualifying State
          </E>
           means a State with a State mediation program currently certified by
          FSA.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='7257'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:785:-:785.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        785.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Annual certification of State mediation programs.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='785' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              785.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Annual certification of State mediation programs.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          To obtain FSA certification of the State&apos;s mediation program, the
          State must meet the requirements of this section.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              New request for certification.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A new request for certification of a State mediation program must
            include descriptive and supporting information regarding the
            mediation program and a certification that the mediation program
            meets certain requirements as prescribed in this subsection. If a
            State is also qualifying its mediation program to request a grant of
            Federal funds under the certified State mediation program, the State
            must submit with its request for certification additional
            information in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='785' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
                785.4
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Description of mediation program.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State must submit a narrative describing the following with
            supporting documentation:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A summary of the program;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An identification of issues available for mediation under the
            program;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Management of the program;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Mediation services offered by the program;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Program staffing and staffing levels;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Uses of contract mediation services in the program describing both
            services provided by contractors and costs of such services;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_vii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State statutes and regulations in effect that are applicable to the
            State&apos;s mediation program; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_viii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (viii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A description of the State program&apos;s education and training
            requirements for mediators including:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='a_1_viii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Training in mediation skills and in USDA programs;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='a_1_viii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Identification and compliance with any State law requirements; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='a_1_viii_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Other steps by the State&apos;s program to recruit and deploy
            qualified mediators.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_ix'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ix)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any other information requested by FSA;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Certification.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Governor, or head of a State agency designated by the Governor,
            must certify in writing to the Administrator that the State&apos;s
            mediation program meets the following program requirements:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             That the State&apos;s mediation program provides mediation services
            to covered persons with the aim of reaching mutually agreeable
            decisions between the parties under the program;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             That the State&apos;s mediation program is authorized or
            administered by an agency of the State government or by the Governor
            of the State;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             That the State&apos;s mediation program provides for training of
            mediators in mediation skills and in all issues covered by the
            State&apos;s mediation program;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             That the State&apos;s mediation program shall provide confidential
            mediation as defined in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='785' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
                785.2
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             That the State&apos;s mediation program ensures, in the case of
            agricultural loans, that all lenders and borrowers of agricultural
            loans receive adequate notification of the mediation program;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             That the State&apos;s mediation program ensures, in the case of
            other issues covered by the mediation program, that persons directly
            affected by actions of the USDA receive adequate notification of the
            mediation program; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_vii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             That the State&apos;s mediation program prohibits discrimination in
            its 
            <PRTPAGE P='370' />
            programs on the basis of race, color, national origin, sex,
            religion, age, disability, political beliefs, and marital or
            familial status.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Request for re-certification by qualifying State.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a State is a qualifying State at the time its request is made,
            the written request need only describe the changes made in the
            program since the previous year&apos;s request, together with such
            documents and information as are necessary concerning such changes,
            and a written certification that the remaining elements of the
            program will continue as described in the previous request.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='7258'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:785:-:785.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        785.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Grants to certified State mediation programs.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='785' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              785.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Grants to certified State mediation programs.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Eligibility.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be eligible to receive a grant, a State mediation program must:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be certified as described in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='785' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
                785.3
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Submit an application for a grant with its certification or
            re-certification request as set forth in this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Application for grant.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A State requesting a grant will submit the following to the
            Administrator:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Application for Federal Assistance, Standard Form 424 (available in
            any FSA office and on the Internet, 
            <E T='03'>
              http://www.whitehouse.gov/omb/grants/
            </E>
            );
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A budget with supporting details providing estimates of the cost of
            operation and administration of the program. Proposed direct
            expenditures will be grouped in the categories of allowable direct
            costs under the program as set forth in paragraph (c)(1) of this
            section;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Other information pertinent to the funding criteria specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='785' sect='7' psec='#b' tq='N'>
                785.7(b)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any additional supporting information requested by FSA in
            connection with its review of the grant request.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Grant purposes.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Grants made under this part will be used only to pay the allowable
            costs of operation and administration of the components of a
            qualifying State&apos;s mediation program that have been certified
            as set forth in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='785' sect='3' psec='#b_2' tq='N'>
                785.3(b)(2)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . Costs of services other than mediation services to covered persons
            within the State are not considered part of the cost of operation
            and administration of the mediation program for the purpose of
            determining the amount of a grant award.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Allowable costs.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subject to applicable cost principles as set forth or referenced in
            
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='3016' sect='22' psec='' tq='N'>
                3016.22
              </subref>
               of this title
            </aref>
            , allowable costs for operations and administration are limited to
            those that are reasonable and necessary to carry out the
            State&apos;s certified mediation program in providing mediation
            services for covered persons within the State. Specific categories
            of costs allowable under the certified State mediation program
            include, and are limited to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Staff salaries and fringe benefits;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Reasonable fees and costs of mediators;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Office rent and expenses, such as utilities and equipment rental;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Office supplies;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Administrative costs, such as workers&apos; compensation, liability
            insurance, employer&apos;s share of Social Security, and travel that
            is necessary to provide mediation services;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Education and training of participants and mediators involved in
            mediation;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_vii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Security systems necessary to assure confidentiality of mediation
            sessions and records of mediation sessions;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_viii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (viii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Costs associated with publicity and promotion of the program; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_ix'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ix)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Financial advisory and counseling services for parties requesting
            mediation (as reasonable and necessary to prepare parties for
            mediation) that are performed by a person other than a state
            mediation program mediator and as approved under guidelines
            established by the state mediation program and reported to FSA.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Prohibited expenditures.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Expenditures of grant funds are not allowed for:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Purchase of capital assets, real estate, or vehicles and repair, or
            maintenance of privately-owned property;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Political activities;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Routine administrative activities not allowable under OMB Cost
            Principles found in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='3015' tq='N'>
                3015
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , subpart T, of this title and OMB Circular No. A-87; and
            <PRTPAGE P='371' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Services provided by a State mediation program that are not
            consistent with the features of the mediation program certified by
            the State, including advocacy services on behalf of a mediation
            participant, such as representation of a mediation client before an
            administrative appeals entity of the USDA or other Federal
            Government department or Federal or State Court proceeding.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='7259'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:785:-:785.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        785.5
      </num>
      <head>
        Fees for mediation services.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='785' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              785.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Fees for mediation services.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          A requirement that non-USDA parties who elect to participate in
          mediation pay a fee for mediation services will not preclude
          certification of a certified State mediation program or its
          eligibility for a grant; however, if participation in mediation is
          mandatory for a USDA agency, a certified State mediation program may
          not require the USDA agency to pay a fee to participate in a
          mediation.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='7260'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:785:-:785.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        785.6
      </num>
      <head>
        Deadlines and address.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='785' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              785.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Deadlines and address.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Deadlines.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be a qualifying State as of the beginning of a fiscal year and
            to be eligible for grant funding as of the beginning of the fiscal
            year, the Governor of a State or head of a State agency designated
            by the Governor of a State must submit a request for certification
            and application for grant on or before August 1 of the calendar year
            in which the fiscal year begins.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Requests received after August 1.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FSA will accept requests for re-certifications and for new
            certifications of State mediation programs after August 1 in each
            calendar year; however, such requests will not be considered for
            grant funding under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='785' sect='7' psec='#c' tq='N'>
                785.7(c)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             until after March 1.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Requests for additional grant funds during a fiscal year.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any request by a State mediation program that is eligible for grant
            funding as of the beginning of the fiscal year for additional grant
            funds during that fiscal year for additional, unbudgeted demands for
            mediation services must be submitted on or before March 1 of the
            fiscal year.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Address.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The request for certification or re-certification and any grant
            request must be mailed or delivered to: Administrator, Farm Service
            Agency, U.S. Department of Agriculture, Stop 0501, 1400 Independence
            Avenue, SW., Washington, DC 20250-0501.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='7261'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:785:-:785.7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        785.7
      </num>
      <head>
        Distribution of Federal grant funds.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='785' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              785.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Distribution of Federal grant funds.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Maximum grant award.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A grant award shall not exceed 70 percent of the budgeted allowable
            costs of operation and administration of the certified State
            mediation program. In no case will the sum granted to a State exceed
            $500,000 per fiscal year.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Funding criteria.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FSA will consider the following in determining the grant award to a
            qualifying State:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Demand for and use of mediation services (historical and
            projected);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Scope of mediation services;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Service record of the State program, as evidenced by:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Number of inquiries;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Number of requests for and use of mediation services, historical
            and projected, as applicable;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Number of mediations resulting in signed mediation agreements;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Timeliness of mediation services; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Activities promoting awareness and use of mediation;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Historic use of program funds (budgeted versus actual); and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Material changes in the State program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Disbursements of grant funds.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Grant funds will be paid in advance, in installments throughout the
            Federal fiscal year as requested by a certified State mediation
            program and approved by FSA. The initial payment to a program in a
            qualifying State eligible for grant funding as of the beginning of a
            fiscal year shall represent at least one-fourth of the State&apos;s
            annual grant award. The initial payment will be made as soon as
            practicable after certification, or re-certification, after grant
            funds are appropriated and available.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payment of grant funds will be by electronic funds transfer to the
            designated account of each certified State mediation program, as
            approved by FSA.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Administrative reserve fund.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             After funds are appropriated, FSA will set aside 5 percent of the
            annual appropriation for use as an administrative reserve.
            <PRTPAGE P='372' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subject to paragraph (a) of this section and the availability of
            funds, the Administrator will allocate and disburse sums from the
            administrative reserve in the following priority order:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Disbursements to cover additional, unbudgeted demands for mediation
            services in qualifying States eligible for grant funding as of the
            beginning of the fiscal year;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Grants to qualifying States whose requests for new certification or
            re-certification were received between August 2 and March 1. A
            previously qualifying State that submits a request for
            re-certification received after August 1 may receive a grant award
            effective as of the beginning of the fiscal year. A newly qualifying
            State that submits a request for certification received after August
            1 may receive a grant award effective March 31 of the fiscal year.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any balance remaining in the administrative reserve will be
            allocated pro rata to certified State mediation programs based on
            their initial fiscal year grant awards.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All funds from the administrative reserve will be made available on
            or before March 31 of the fiscal year.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Period of availability of funds.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Certified State mediation programs receiving grant funds are
            encouraged to obligate award funds within the Federal fiscal year of
            the award. A State may, however, carry forward any funds disbursed
            to its certified State mediation program that remain unobligated at
            the end of the fiscal year of award for use in the next fiscal year
            for costs resulting from obligations in the subsequent funding
            period. Any carryover balances plus any additional obligated fiscal
            year grant will not exceed the lesser of 70 percent of the
            State&apos;s budgeted allowable costs of operation and
            administration of the certified State mediation program for the
            subsequent fiscal year, or $500,000.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Grant funds not spent in accordance with this part will be subject
            to de-obligation and must be returned to the USDA.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='7262'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:785:-:785.8
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        785.8
      </num>
      <head>
        Reports by qualifying States receiving mediation grant funds.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='785' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              785.8
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Reports by qualifying States receiving mediation grant funds.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Annual report by certified State mediation program.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No later than 30 days following the end of a fiscal year during
            which a qualifying State received a grant award under this part, the
            State must submit to the Administrator an annual report on its
            certified State mediation program. The annual report must include
            the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A review of mediation services provided by the certified State
            mediation program during the preceding Federal fiscal year providing
            information concerning the following matters:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A narrative review of the goals and accomplishments of the
            certified State mediation program in providing intake and scheduling
            of cases; the provision of background and selected information
            regarding the mediation process; financial advisory and counseling
            services, training, notification, public education, increasing
            resolution rates, and obtaining program funding from sources other
            than the grant under this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A quantitative summary for the preceding fiscal year, and for prior
            fiscal years, as appropriate, for comparisons of program activities
            and outcomes of the cases opened and closed during the reporting
            period; mediation services provided to clients grouped by program
            and subdivided by issue, USDA agency, types of covered persons and
            other participants; and the resolution rate for each category of
            issue reported for cases closed during the year;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An assessment of the performance and effectiveness of the
            State&apos;s certified mediation program considering:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Estimated average costs of mediation services per client with
            estimates furnished in terms of the allowable costs set forth in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='785' sect='4' psec='#b_1' tq='N'>
                785.4(b)(1)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Estimated savings to the State as a result of having the State
            mediation program certified including:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='a_2_ii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Projected costs of avoided USDA administrative appeals based on
            projections of the average costs of such appeals furnished to the
            State by FSA, with the assistance of the USDA National Appeals
            Division and other agencies as appropriate;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='a_2_ii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In agricultural credit mediations that do not result from a USDA
            adverse program decision, projected cost savings to the various
            parties as a result of resolution of their dispute in mediation.
            Projected cost savings will be based on such reliable statistical 
            <PRTPAGE P='373' />
            data as may be obtained from State statistical sources including the
            certified State&apos;s bar association, State Department of
            Agriculture, State court system or Better Business Bureau, or other
            reliable State or Federal sources;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Recommendations for improving the delivery of mediation services to
            covered persons, including:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='a_2_iii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Increasing responsiveness to needs for mediation services.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='a_2_iii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Promoting increases in dispute resolution rates.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='a_2_iii_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Improving assessments of training needs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='a_2_iii_D'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (D)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Improving delivery of training.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='a_2_iii_E'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (E)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Reducing costs per mediation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Such other matters relating to the program as the State may elect
            to include, or as the Administrator may require.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Audit report.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In addition to the auditing requirements of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='3015' tq='N'>
                3015
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , subpart I and 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='3016' sect='26' psec='' tq='N'>
                3016.26
              </subref>
               of this title
            </aref>
            , any qualifying State receiving a grant under this part must submit
            an audit report to the Administrator in compliance with OMB Circular
            A-133.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='7263'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:785:-:785.9
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        785.9
      </num>
      <head>
        Access to program records.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='785' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
              785.9
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Access to program records.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Notwithstanding 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3015' sect='24' psec='' tq='N'>
              3015.24
            </subref>
             of this title
          </aref>
          , the State must maintain and provide the Government access to
          pertinent records regarding services delivered by the certified State
          mediation program for purposes of evaluation, audit and monitoring of
          the certified State mediation program as follows:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For purposes of this section, pertinent records consist of: the
            names and addresses of applicants for mediation services; dates
            mediations opened and closed; issues mediated; dates of sessions
            with mediators; names of mediators; mediation services furnished to
            participants by the program; the sums charged to parties for each
            mediation service; records of delivery of services to prepare
            parties for mediation (including financial advisory and counseling
            services); and the outcome of the mediation services including
            formal settlement results and supporting documentation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State mediators will notify all participants in writing at the
            beginning of the mediation session that the USDA, including the USDA
            Inspector General, the Comptroller General of the United States, the
            Administrator, and any of their representatives will have access to
            pertinent records as necessary to monitor and to conduct audits,
            investigations, or evaluations of mediation services funded in whole
            or in part by the USDA.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All participants in a mediation must sign and date an
            acknowledgment of receipt of such notice from the mediator. The
            certified State mediation program shall maintain originals of such
            acknowledgments in its mediation files for at least 5 years.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='7264'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:785:-:785.10
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        785.10
      </num>
      <head>
        Penalty for non-compliance.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='785' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
              785.10
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Penalty for non-compliance.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Administrator is authorized to withdraw certification of a
            State mediation program, terminate or suspend the grant to such
            program, require a return of unspent grant funds, a reimbursement of
            grant funds on account of expenditures that are not allowed, and may
            impose any other penalties or sanctions authorized by law if the
            Administrator determines that:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State&apos;s mediation program, at any time, does not meet the
            requirements for certification;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The mediation program is not being operated in a manner consistent
            with the features of the program certified by the State, with
            applicable regulations, or the grant agreement;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Costs that are not allowed under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='785' sect='4' psec='#b' tq='N'>
                785.4(b)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             are being paid out of grant funds;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The mediation program fails to grant access to mediation records
            for purposes specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='785' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
                785.8
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Reports submitted by the State pursuant to 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='785' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
                785.7
              </subref>
            </aref>
             are false, contain misrepresentations or material omissions, or are
            otherwise misleading.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the event that FSA gives notice to the State of its intent to
            enforce any withdrawal of certification or other penalty for
            non-compliance, USDA agencies will cease to participate in any
            mediation conducted by the State&apos;s mediation program
            immediately upon delivery of such notice to the State.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='7265'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:785:-:785.11
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        785.11
      </num>
      <head>
        Reconsideration by the Administrator.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='785' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
              785.11
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Reconsideration by the Administrator.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A State mediation program may request that the Administrator
            reconsider any determination that a State is 
            <PRTPAGE P='374' />
            not a qualifying State under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='785' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
                785.3
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and any penalty decision made under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='785' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
                785.10
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . The decision of the Administrator upon reconsideration shall be
            the final administrative decision of FSA.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Nothing in this part shall preclude action to suspend or debar a
            State mediation program or administering entity under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='3017' tq='N'>
                3017 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
             following a withdrawal of certification of the State mediation
            program.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='7266'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:785:-:785.12
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        785.12
      </num>
      <head>
        Nondiscrimination.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='785' sect='12' psec='' tq='N'>
              785.12
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Nondiscrimination.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The provisions of 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            parts 
            <subref title='7' part='15' tq='N'>
              15, 15b
            </subref>
             and 
            <subref title='7' part='1901' tq='N'>
              1901
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , subpart E, of this title and 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            part 90 of
          </aref>
           title 45 apply to activities financed by grants made under this part.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='7267'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:785:-:785.13
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        785.13
      </num>
      <head>
        OMB Control Number.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='785' sect='13' psec='' tq='N'>
              785.13
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          OMB Control Number.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The information collection requirements in this regulation have been
          approved by the Office of Management and Budget and assigned OMB
          control number 0560-0165.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>