<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol10'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1424
    </extid>
    <num>
      1424
    </num>
    <head>
      BIOENERGY PROGRAM
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='8108' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/8108.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 8108
            </subref>
            , 
            <subref title='7' sect='15' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/15.html'>
              15
            </subref>
          </aref>
           U.S.C. 714b and 714c.
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            68 FR 24600
          </aref>
          , May 7, 2003, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='12527'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1424:-:1424.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1424.1
      </num>
      <head>
        Applicability.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1424' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              1424.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Applicability.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          This part sets out regulations for the Bioenergy Program (program). It
          sets forth, subject to the availability of funds as provided herein,
          or as may be limited by law, the terms and conditions a bioenergy
          producer must meet to obtain payments under this program and part from
          the Commodity Credit Corporation (CCC) for eligible bioenergy
          production. Additional terms and conditions may be set forth in the
          document required to request program benefits and in the program
          contract or agreement prescribed by CCC. This program is effective
          October 1, 2002, through September 30, 2006.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12528'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1424:-:1424.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1424.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Administration.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1424' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              1424.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Administration.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          This part shall be administered by the Executive Vice President, CCC,
          under the general direction and supervision of the Executive Vice
          President 
          <PRTPAGE P='599' />
          or designee. The Executive Vice President or a designee may authorize
          a waiver or modification of deadlines and other program requirements
          in cases where lateness or failure to meet such other requirements
          does not adversely affect the operation of the program, and may set
          such additional requirements as will facilitate the operation of the
          program. The funds available for the program shall be limited as set
          by this rule, otherwise announced by the Executive Vice President,
          CCC, or limited by law.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12529'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1424:-:1424.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1424.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1424' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              1424.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The definitions set forth in this section shall be applicable for all
          purposes of program administration under this subpart.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Agreement
          </E>
           means the Bioenergy Program Agreement or other form prescribed by CCC
          that must be executed for participation in the program.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Application
          </E>
           means the application form prescribed by CCC or another form that
          contains the same terms, conditions, and information required.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            ATF
          </E>
           means the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives of the
          United States Department of Justice.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Base production
          </E>
           means a biodiesel producer&apos;s current FY&apos;s biodiesel
          production from eligible commodities that is not an increase over
          biodiesel production in the previous FY to date.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Biodiesel
          </E>
           means a mono alkyl ester manufactured in the United States and its
          territories that meets the requirements of an appropriate American
          Society for Testing and Materials Standard.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Biodiesel
          </E>
           producer means a producer that produces and sells biodiesel who is
          also registered and in compliance with 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 211 (b) of
          </aref>
           the Environmental Protection Agency Clean Air Act Amendment of 1990.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Bioenergy
          </E>
           means ethanol and biodiesel produced from eligible commodities.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Conversion factor
          </E>
           means:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For ethanol production, a factor that converts the number of
            ethanol gallons back to commodity units as determined in the manner
            announced by CCC;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For biodiesel production, the factor that will treat 1.4 gallons of
            biodiesel produced as having involved the consumption of one bushel
            of soybeans in any case when the feedstock was an eligible commodity
            that has a corresponding oil or grease market price; if there is
            none, then the factor shall be as determined and announced by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Eligible commodity
          </E>
           means barley; corn; grain sorghum; oats; rice; wheat; soybeans;
          cotton seed; sunflower seed; canola; crambe; rapeseed; safflower;
          sesame seed; flaxseed; mustard seed; cellulosic crops, such as
          switchgrass and hybrid poplars; fats, oils, and greases (including
          recycled fats, oils and greases) derived from an agricultural product;
          and any animal byproduct (in addition to oils, fats and greases) that
          may be used to produce bioenergy, as CCC determines, that is produced
          in the United States and its territories.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Eligible producer
          </E>
           means a bioenergy producer who meets all requirements for program
          payments.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Ethanol
          </E>
           means anhydrous ethyl alcohol manufactured in the United States and
          its territories and sold either:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For fuel use, rendered unfit for beverage use, produced at a
            facility and in a manner approved by ATF for the production of
            ethanol for fuel; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             As denatured ethanol used by blenders and refiners and rendered
            unfit for beverage use.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Ethanol producer
          </E>
           means a person authorized by ATF to produce ethanol.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            FSA
          </E>
           means the Farm Service Agency, USDA.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            FY
          </E>
           means the fiscal year beginning each October 1 and ending September
          30 of the following calendar year.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            KCCO
          </E>
           means the FSA, Kansas City Commodity Office.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Posted County Price
          </E>
           means the same Posted County Price for different locations as is used
          under other CCC commodity programs for marketing loan gains and other
          matters.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Producer
          </E>
           is a legal entity (individual, partnership, cooperative, or
          corporation, etc.) who is a commercial bioenergy producer making
          application or otherwise involved under this program.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Quarter
          </E>
           means the respective time periods of October 1 through December 
          <PRTPAGE P='600' />
          31, January 1 through March 31, April 1 through June 30, and July 1
          through September 30 of each FY, as applicable.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Sign-up period
          </E>
           means the time period announced by CCC during which CCC will accept
          program agreements.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            USDA
          </E>
           means the United States Department of Agriculture.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12530'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1424:-:1424.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1424.4
      </num>
      <head>
        General eligibility rules.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1424' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              1424.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General eligibility rules.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An applicant must be determined eligible by KCCO and be assigned an
            agreement number.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be eligible for program payments, a producer must maintain
            records indicating for all relevant FY&apos;s and FY quarters:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The use of eligible commodities in bioenergy production;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The quantity of bioenergy produced from an eligible commodity by
            location;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The quantity of eligible commodity used by location to produce the
            bioenergy referred to in paragraph (b)(2) of this section; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All other records, needed, or required by the agreement to
            establish program eligibility and compliance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A producer must allow verification by CCC of all information
            provided. Refusal to allow CCC or any other agency of USDA to verify
            any information provided will result in a producer being determined
            not eligible.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For producers not purchasing raw commodity inputs, the production
            must equal or exceed that amount of production that would be
            calculated using the raw commodity inputs and the conversion factor
            set out in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1424' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
                1424.3
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . A producer that purchases soy oil from a soybean crushing plant
            for further refinement into biodiesel must be able to prove to
            CCC&apos;s satisfaction both soy oil purchases and biodiesel
            production for the applicable quarter. Any special conversion
            factors needed will be the province of CCC and CCC alone and
            CCC&apos;s decision will be final.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A producer must meet all other conditions set out in these
            regulations, in the agreement, or in other program documents.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12531'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1424:-:1424.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1424.5
      </num>
      <head>
        Agreement process.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1424' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              1424.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Agreement process.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To participate, an eligible producer must submit a signed agreement
            during the FY sign-up period. Agreements may be for single or
            multiple FY&apos;s. However, multiple FY agreements require
            producers to submit annual production estimate reports during each
            applicable FY sign-up period. Such reports must comply with the
            terms of the agreement and this part. In all cases, the accounting
            for compliance will be made on a per FY basis.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Sign-up each FY will be held for 30 calendar days beginning for:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FY 2003 on the date of publication of this rule;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FY 2004 and beyond on August 1 of the FY before the applicable FY.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             After agreements are submitted:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If determined eligible by KCCO, an agreement number will be
            assigned, and a notification will be mailed to the producer;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If additional information is needed for KCCO to determine
            eligibility, the producer will be contacted as soon as practicable
            and requested to provide additional supporting documentation;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If determined ineligible by KCCO, producers will be notified in
            writing that their agreement was rejected and the reason for the
            determination.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12532'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1424:-:1424.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1424.6
      </num>
      <head>
        Payment application process.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1424' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              1424.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Payment application process.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To apply for payments under this program during an FY, an eligible
            producer must:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Submit an application or eligibility report for each quarter.
            Submit the last quarterly application or report of the FY within 30
            calendar days of the end of the FY for which payment is requested.
            If the actual deadline is a non-workday, the deadline will be the
            next business day;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Certify with respect to the accuracy and truthfulness of the
            information provided;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Furnish CCC such certification, and access to such records, as CCC
            considers necessary to verify compliance with program provisions;
            and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provide documentation as requested by CCC of both the
            producer&apos;s net purchases of eligible commodities and net
            production of bioenergy compared to such production at all locations
            during the relevant periods. CCC may adjust the formulaic payments
            otherwise payable to the producer if there is a difference between
            the amount actually used and certified and 
            <PRTPAGE P='601' />
            the amount of increased commodity use calculated under the formula.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             After applications or reports are submitted, eligible producers:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Shall submit such additional supporting documentation as requested
            by KCCO when additional information is needed to determine
            eligibility;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Will be notified in writing of their ineligibility and reason for
            the determination, when the application is determined ineligible by
            KCCO; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Shall promptly refund payments when a refund to CCC is due. If a
            refund is not made promptly, CCC may establish a claim.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12533'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1424:-:1424.7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1424.7
      </num>
      <head>
        Gross payable units.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1424' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              1424.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Gross payable units.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For ethanol, producers will be eligible for payments on gross
            payable units for only their ethanol production from eligible inputs
            that exceeds, for the program year to date, their total comparable
            production at all locations as compared to the comparable portion of
            the previous year. Producers of ethanol are not eligible for base
            production payments. Producers shall not be paid twice for the same
            increase and any decline in relative production between quarters
            will require a comparable refund. For example, if at the end of the
            first quarter, a producer were to be paid for an increase of 500
            gallons of ethanol, but at the end of the second quarter, that
            producer&apos;s year-to-date production was down to a net increase
            for the year of 450 gallons, then a refund would be due for the loss
            of the corresponding 50 gallons of net extra production. Repayment
            rates shall be based on previous payment rates. Unless otherwise
            determined by CCC, the extra ethanol production from eligible inputs
            will be converted to gross payable units by dividing the gallons of
            increased ethanol by the applicable conversion factor.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Biodiesel producers will be eligible for payments on gross payable
            units for all biodiesel production from eligible inputs. For
            eligibility purposes there will be two kinds of payment: additional
            production payments (APP), and base production payments (BPP).
            Repayment rates shall be based on previous payment rates. Unless
            otherwise determined by CCC, gross payable units for biodiesel
            production from eligible inputs will be calculated as follows:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For APP, by dividing the gallons of increased biodiesel by the
            biodiesel conversion factor of 1.4. APP payments will be made on
            increases as compared with the previous FY. Producers will not be
            paid twice for the same production. Failure to maintain year to date
            biodiesel production increases between quarters will require a
            comparable APP refund as specified below. That is, for example, if a
            producer were to be paid, at the end of the first quarter, for 500
            gallons of increased biodiesel production, but by the end of the
            second quarter that producer&apos;s production, for the year to
            date, was only 450 gallons, then a refund of the APP premium would
            be due for the loss of the corresponding 50 gallons of net
            production increase.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For BPP, which will be made on production not eligible for the APP,
            by dividing the base production by the biodiesel conversion factor
            of 1.4 and multiplying the result by 0.5 in FY 2003, 0.3 in FY 2004,
            0.15 in FY 2005, or 0.0 (zero) in FY 2006 to determine base
            biodiesel production gross payable units.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Adding the APP and BPP to determine biodiesel gross payable units.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             There shall only be one eligible producer per plant location.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When producers move production from one plant to another between
            FY&apos;s, the prior FY&apos;s production for the producer for
            program payment calculations tied to increases in production shall
            be the greater of:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The production at the plant operated by the producer in the prior
            FY, or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The production in the prior FY at the plant being taken over by the
            producer in the current FY.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             New producers who are taking over a plant with prior bioenergy
            production shall assume that production history for program
            purposes. For example: in FY 2002, Producer A produced 1,000 gallons
            of bioenergy in plant 1 and Producer B produced 500,000 of bioenergy
            in plant 2. In FY 2003, Producer A assumes operation of plant 2;
            Producer B moves to plant 3, which was not in the program in FY
            2002, but with FY 2002 production of 400,000 gallons 
            <PRTPAGE P='602' />
            from eligible commodities; and Producer C assumes operations of
            plant 1. In FY 2003, for program purposes solely based on these
            respective plants, Producer A would have a prior FY production of
            500,000 gallons; Producer B would have a prior FY production of
            500,000 gallons; and Producer C would have a prior FY production of
            1,000 gallons. These examples would apply when a producer moves its
            entire operation from one plant to another. Otherwise, for purposes
            of computing whether a producer has increased production in the
            current year from the previous year, the determination will be made
            by comparing for the current year the producer&apos;s production
            figures from all locations in which the producer has an interest
            with, for the previous year, the sum of:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Production at those locations by any person including, but not
            limited to, the producer, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Additional production by the producer at any other location in that
            year.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Also, as needed to avoid frustrating the goals of the program, the
            Executive Vice President of CCC may treat producers with common
            interests, common ownership, or common facilities or arrangements as
            the same producer.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12534'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1424:-:1424.8
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1424.8
      </num>
      <head>
        Payment amounts.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1424' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              1424.8
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Payment amounts.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An eligible producer may be paid the amount specified in this
            section, subject to the availability of funds. Total available funds
            shall be as determined appropriate by CCC and shall not exceed $150
            million in any of FY&apos;s 2003 through 2006.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For agreements submitted during an FY sign-up, applicants must
            project increases in production. Based on expected commodity prices,
            using the formula set out in this section, submissions will be
            assigned an expected payment value. When the payment value of all
            timely submitted and validly executed agreements exceed available
            funding, CCC may, at its discretion, prorate payments to be made
            under such agreements based on total available funding.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When the payment value of all timely submitted applications exceed
            available funding, CCC will prorate payments based on total
            available funding.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subject to this section and conditions in the agreement, a
            producer&apos;s payment eligibility shall be adjusted at the end of
            each quarter, and calculated as follows:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Gross payable units, calculated and determined in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1424' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
                1424.7
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , shall be converted to net payable units for producers whose annual
            bioenergy production is:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Less than 65 million gallons, by dividing by 2.5;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Equal to or more than 65 million gallons, by dividing by 3.5;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Net payable units calculated under paragraph (d)(1) of this section
            shall then be converted to a gross payment by multiplying net
            payable units by the per-unit value of the commodity as of the 10th
            business day before the start of the production quarter, determined
            as follows:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For ethanol:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_ii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For those agricultural commodities with an established Posted
            County Price, CCC will use the Posted County Price that CCC
            announces daily for the county in which the plant is located and
            applicable quality factors as CCC may establish.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_ii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For agricultural commodities that CCC determines do not have Posted
            County Prices, CCC will use market data CCC determines to be
            appropriate for the applicable commodity.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For biodiesel made from:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_ii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Soybeans or soy oil, CCC will use the Posted County Price for
            soybeans for the county where the plant is located.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_ii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Eligible commodities other than soybeans or soy oil that have a
            corresponding oil or grease market price, CCC will first use the
            soybeans Posted County Price for Macon County, Illinois. Then, the
            applicable feedstock&apos;s oil or yellow grease (for animal fats
            and oils) market price, as determined by CCC, will be divided by the
            soy oil price published in the Agricultural Marketing Service&apos;s
            weekly “Soybean Crush Report” (Central Illinois (Decatur, Macon
            County, Illinois)) for the applicable date. The resulting percentage
            will be multiplied by the soybean gross payment to determine the
            producer&apos;s gross payment.
            <PRTPAGE P='603' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_ii_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Eligible commodities that do not have a corresponding oil or grease
            market price, in a manner as determined by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The gross payment calculated under paragraph (d)(2) of this section
            shall be reduced to a net payment by multiplying the gross payment
            figure by the proration factor determined under paragraph (c) of
            this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subject to other provisions of this section, producers shall be
            paid the net current payment, if positive, determined for the
            quarter, subject to the requirements and refund provisions of this
            part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             After the first quarter, adjustments shall be made based on changes
            in production. Refunds, when due, shall be due at the per unit
            values at which they were paid.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For an FY, no producer may receive more than 5 percent of the
            available funding for this program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When the commodity&apos;s conversion factor has been established,
            that factor will, as practicable, be posted on the program&apos;s
            website.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the commodity&apos;s conversion factor is not determined when
            the sign-up is announced, the conversion factor will be provided in
            a letter to producers with accepted agreements to the extent
            practicable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             After FY 2003, changes to established conversion factors shall be
            announced in a press release issued by CCC 90 calendar days before
            the applicable FY&apos;s sign-up, to the extent practicable.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12535'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1424:-:1424.9
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1424.9
      </num>
      <head>
        Reports required.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1424' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
              1424.9
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Reports required.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Once an eligible producer has submitted a payment application, that
          producer shall file cumulative and per-plant information for each
          relevant bioenergy producing facility quarterly through the end of the
          applicable FY as specified by CCC or as otherwise needed to establish
          compliance with this part.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12536'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1424:-:1424.10
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1424.10
      </num>
      <head>
        Succession and control of facilities and production.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1424' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
              1424.10
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Succession and control of facilities and production.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          A person who obtains a facility that is under contract under this part
          may request permission to succeed to the program agreement and CCC may
          grant such request if it is determined that permitting such succession
          would serve the purposes of the program. If appropriate, CCC may
          require the consent of the original party to such succession. Also,
          CCC may terminate a contract and demand full refund of payments made
          if a contracting party loses control of a facility whose increased
          production is the basis of a program payment or otherwise fails to
          retain the ability to assure that all program obligations and
          requirements will be met.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12537'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1424:-:1424.11
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1424.11
      </num>
      <head>
        Maintenance and inspection of records.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1424' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
              1424.11
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Maintenance and inspection of records.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          For the purpose of verifying compliance with the requirements of this
          part, each eligible producer shall make available at one place at all
          reasonable times for examination by representatives of USDA, all
          books, papers, records, contracts, scale tickets, settlement sheets,
          invoices, written price quotations, or other documents related to the
          program that is within the control of such entity for not less than
          three years from the payment date.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12538'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1424:-:1424.12
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1424.12
      </num>
      <head>
        Appeals.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1424' sect='12' psec='' tq='N'>
              1424.12
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Appeals.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A participant subject to an adverse determination under this part
            may appeal by submitting a written request to: Deputy Administrator,
            Commodity Operations, Farm Service Agency, United States Department
            of Agriculture, STOP 0550, 1400 Independence Avenue, SW.,
            Washington, D.C. 20250-0550. The appeal must be delivered in writing
            to the Deputy Administrator or postmarked within 30 days after the
            date the Agency decision is mailed or otherwise provided to the
            participant. The Deputy Administrator may consider a late appeal if
            determined warranted by the circumstances.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The regulations at 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='11' tq='N'>
                11
              </subref>
            </aref>
             apply to decisions made under this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Producers who believe they have been adversely affected by a
            determination by the Agency must seek review with the Deputy
            Administrator before any other review may be requested within the
            Agency.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12539'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1424:-:1424.13
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1424.13
      </num>
      <head>
        Misrepresentation and scheme or device.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1424' sect='13' psec='' tq='N'>
              1424.13
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Misrepresentation and scheme or device.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A producer shall be ineligible to receive payments under this
            program if CCC determines the producer:
            <PRTPAGE P='604' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Adopted any scheme or device that tends to defeat the purpose of
            the program in this part;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Made any fraudulent representation; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Misrepresented any fact affecting a program determination.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any funds disbursed pursuant to this part to a producer engaged in
            a misrepresentation, scheme, or device, or to any other person as a
            result of the bioenergy producer&apos;s actions, shall be refunded
            with interest together with such other sums as may become due, plus
            damages as may be determined by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any producer or person engaged in an act prohibited by this section
            and any producer or person receiving payment under this part shall
            be jointly and severally liable for any refund due under this part
            and for related charges.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The remedies provided in this part shall be in addition to other
            civil, criminal, or administrative remedies that may apply.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Late payment interest shall be assessed on all refunds in
            accordance with the provisions and rates prescribed in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1403' tq='N'>
                1403 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12540'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1424:-:1424.14
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1424.14
      </num>
      <head>
        Offsets, assignments, interest and waivers.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1424' sect='14' psec='' tq='N'>
              1424.14
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Offsets, assignments, interest and waivers.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any payment or portion thereof to any person shall be made without
            regard to questions of title under State law and without regard to
            any claim or lien against the bioenergy, or proceeds thereof, in
            favor of the owner or any other creditor except agencies of the U.S.
            Government. The regulations governing offsets and withholdings found
            in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1403' tq='N'>
                1403 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
             shall be applicable to agreement payments.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any producer entitled to any payment may assign any payments in
            accordance with regulations governing the assignment of payments
            found at 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1404' tq='N'>
                1404 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Interest charged by CCC under this part shall be at the rate of
            interest that the United States Treasury charges CCC for funds, as
            of the date CCC made such funds available. Such interest shall
            accrue from the date such payments were made available to the date
            of repayment or the date interest increases as determined in
            accordance with applicable regulations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC may waive the accrual of interest and/or damages if CCC
            determines that the cause of the erroneous determination was not due
            to any action of the bioenergy producer.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>