<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol12'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1788
    </extid>
    <num>
      1788
    </num>
    <head>
      RUS FIDELITY AND INSURANCE REQUIREMENTS FOR ELECTRIC AND
      TELECOMMUNICATIONS BORROWERS
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='901' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/901.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 901
            </subref>
          </aref>
           et seq.; 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='1921' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1921.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 1921
            </subref>
          </aref>
           et seq.; 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='6941' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/6941.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 6941
            </subref>
          </aref>
           et seq.
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            64 FR 2
          </aref>
          , Jan. 4, 1999, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='14710'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1788:A:1788.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1788.1
      </num>
      <head>
        General and definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1788' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              1788.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General and definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The standard forms of documents covering loans made or guaranteed
            by the Rural Utilities Service contain provisions regarding
            insurance and fidelity coverage to be maintained by each borrower.
            This part implements those provisions by setting forth the
            requirements to be met by all borrowers.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             As used in this part:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Borrower
          </E>
           means any entity with any outstanding loan made or guaranteed by RUS.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Irregularity
          </E>
           has the meaning found in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1773' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              1773.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Loan documents
          </E>
           means the loan agreement, notes, and mortgage evidencing or used in
          conjunction with an RUS loan.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Mortgage
          </E>
           means the mortgage, deed of trust, security agreement, or other
          security document securing an RUS loan.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Mortgaged property
          </E>
           means any property subject to the lien of a mortgage.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            RUS
          </E>
           means the Rural Utilities Service and includes the Rural Telephone
          Bank.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            RUS loan
          </E>
           means a loan made or guaranteed by RUS.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             RUS may revise these requirements on a case by case basis for
            borrowers with unusual circumstances.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14711'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1788:A:1788.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1788.2
      </num>
      <head>
        General insurance requirements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1788' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              1788.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General insurance requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Borrowers will take out, as the respective risks are incurred, and
            maintain the classes and amounts of insurance in conformance with
            generally accepted utility industry standards for such classes and
            amounts of coverage for utilities of the size and character of the
            borrower and consistent with Prudent Utility Practice. Prudent
            Utility Practice shall mean any of the practices, methods, and acts
            which, in the exercise of reasonable judgment, in light of the
            facts, including but not limited to, the practices, methods, and
            acts engaged in or approved by a significant portion of the electric
            utility industry in the case of an electric borrower or of the
            telecommunications industry in the case of a telecommunications
            borrowers prior thereto, known at the time the decision was made,
            would have been expected to accomplish the desired result consistent
            with cost-effectiveness, reliability, safety, and expedition. It is
            recognized that Prudent Utility Practice is not intended to be
            limited to optimum practice, method, or act to the exclusion of all
            others, but rather is a spectrum of possible practices, methods, or
            act which could have been expected to accomplish the desired result
            at the lowest reasonable cost consistent with cost-effectiveness,
            reliability, safety, and expedition.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The foregoing insurance coverage shall be obtained by means of bond
            and policy forms approved by regulatory 
            <PRTPAGE P='392' />
            authorities having jurisdiction, and, with respect to insurance upon
            any part of the mortgaged property securing an RUS loan, shall
            provide that the insurance shall be payable to the mortgagees as
            their interests may appear by means of the standard mortgagee clause
            without contribution. Each policy or other contract for such
            insurance shall contain an agreement by the insurer that,
            notwithstanding any right of cancellation reserved to such insurer,
            such policy or contract shall continue in force for at least 30 days
            after written notice to each mortgagee of suspension, cancellation,
            or termination.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the event of damage to or the destruction or loss of any portion
            of the mortgaged property which is used or useful in the
            borrower&apos;s business and which shall be covered by insurance,
            unless each mortgagee shall otherwise agree, the borrower shall
            replace or restore such damaged, destroyed, or lost portion so that
            such mortgaged property shall be in substantially the same condition
            as it was in prior to such damage, destruction, or loss and shall
            apply the proceeds of the insurance for that purpose. The borrower
            shall replace the lost portion of such mortgaged property or shall
            commence such restoration promptly after such damage, destruction,
            or loss shall have occurred and shall complete such replacement or
            restoration as expeditiously as practicable, and shall pay or cause
            to be paid out of the proceeds of such insurance form all costs and
            expenses in connection therewith.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Sums recovered under any policy or fidelity bond by the borrower
            for a loss of funds advanced under a note secured by a mortgage or
            recovered by any mortgagee or holder of any note secured by the
            mortgage for any loss under such policy or bond shall, unless
            applied as provided in the preceding paragraph, be used as directed
            by the borrower&apos;s mortgage.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Borrowers shall furnish evidence annually that the required
            insurance and fidelity coverage has been in force for the entire
            year, and that the borrower has taken all steps currently necessary
            and will continue to take all steps necessary to ensure that the
            coverage will remain in force until all loans made or guaranteed by
            RUS are paid in full. Such evidence shall be in a form satisfactory
            to RUS. Generally a certification included as part of the RUS
            Financial and Statistical Report filed by the borrower annually (RUS
            Form 7 or Form 12 for electric borrowers, RUS Form 479 for
            telecommunications borrowers, or the successors to these forms) is
            sufficient evidence of this coverage.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14712'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1788:A:1788.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1788.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Flood insurance.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1788' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              1788.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Flood insurance.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Borrowers shall purchase and maintain flood insurance for buildings
            in flood hazard areas to the extent available and required under the
            National Flood Insurance Act of 1968, as amended (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='42' sect='4001' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/42/4001.html'>
                42 U.S.C. 4001
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , et seq.) The insurance should cover, in addition to the building,
            any machinery, equipment, fixtures, and furnishings contained in the
            building.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The National Flood Insurance Program (see 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              44 CFR part 
              <subref title='44' part='59' tq='N'>
                59
              </subref>
            </aref>
             et seq.) provides for a standard flood insurance policy; however,
            other existing insurance policies which provide flood coverage may
            be used where flood insurance is available in lieu of the standard
            flood insurance policy. Such policies must be endorsed to provide:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             That the insurer give 30 days written notice of cancellation or
            nonrenewal to the insured with respect to the flood insurance
            coverage. To be effective, such notice must be mailed to both the
            insured and RUS and other mortgagees if any and must include
            information as to the availability of flood insurance coverage under
            the National Flood Insurance Program, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             That the flood insurance coverage is at least as broad as the
            coverage offered by the Standard Flood Insurance Policy.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14713'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1788:A:1788.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1788.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Disclosure of irregularities and illegal acts.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1788' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              1788.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Disclosure of irregularities and illegal acts.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Borrowers must immediately report, in writing, all irregularities
            and all indications or instances of illegal acts in its operations,
            whether material or not, to RUS and the Office of the Inspector
            General (OIG). See 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR 
              <subref title='7' part='1773' sect='9' psec='#c_3' tq='N'>
                1773.9(c)(3)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             for OIG addresses. The reporting requirements for borrowers are the
            same as those for CPA&apos;s set forth in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1773' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
                1773.9
              </subref>
            </aref>
            <PRTPAGE P='393' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Borrowers are required to make full disclosure to the bonding
            company of the dishonest or fraudulent acts.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14714'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1788:A:1788.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1788.5
      </num>
      <head>
        RUS endorsement required.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1788' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              1788.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          RUS endorsement required.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          In the case of a cooperative or mutual organization, RUS requires that
          the following: 
        </P>
        <EXTRACT>
          <P>
            Endorsement Waiving Immunity From Tort Liability” be included as a
            part of each public liability, owned, non-owned, hired automobile,
            and aircraft liability, employers&apos; liability policy, and boiler
            policy:
          </P>
          <P>
            The Insurer agrees with the Rural Utilities Service that such
            insurance as is afforded by the policy applies subject to the
            following provisions:
          </P>
          <P>
            1. The Insurer agrees that it will not use, either in the adjustment
            of claims or in the defense of suits against the Insured, the
            immunity of the Insured from tort liability, unless requested by the
            Insured to interpose such defense.
          </P>
          <P>
            2. The Insured agrees that the waiver of the defense of immunity
            shall not subject the Insurer to liability of any portion of a
            claim, verdict or judgment in excess of the limits of liability
            stated in the policy.
          </P>
          <P>
            3. The Insurer agrees that if the Insured is relieved of liability
            because of its immunity, either by interposition of such defense at
            the request of the Insured or by voluntary action of a court, the
            insurance applicable to the injuries on which such suit is based, to
            the extent to which it would otherwise have been available to the
            Insured, shall apply to officers and employees of the Insured in
            their capacity as such; provided that all defenses other than
            immunity from tort liability which would be available to the Insurer
            but for said immunity in suits against the Insured or against the
            Insurer under the policy shall be available to the Insurer with
            respect to such officers and employees in suits against such
            officers and employees or against the Insurer under the policy.
          </P>
        </EXTRACT>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14715'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1788:A:1788.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1788.6
      </num>
      <head>
        RUS right to place insurance.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1788' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              1788.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          RUS right to place insurance.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          If a borrower fails to purchase or maintain the required insurance and
          fidelity coverage, the mortgagees may place required insurance and
          fidelity coverage on behalf and in the name of the borrower. The
          borrower shall pay the cost of this coverage, as provided in the loan
          documents.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14716'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1788:A:1788.7-1788.10
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1788.7-1788.10
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1788' sect='7-1788' psec='' tq='N'>
              1788.7-1788
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .10
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14717'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1788:B:1788.11
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1788.11
      </num>
      <head>
        Minimum insurance requirements for contractors, engineers, and
        architects.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1788' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
              1788.11
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Minimum insurance requirements for contractors, engineers, and
          architects.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each electric borrower shall include the provisions in this
            paragraph in its agreements with contractors, engineers, and
            architects, said agreements that are wholly or partially financed by
            RUS loans or guarantees. The borrower should replace “Contractor”
            with “Engineer” or “Architect” as appropriate. 
          </text>
        </P>
        <EXTRACT>
          <P>
            1. The Contractor shall take out and maintain throughout the period
            of this Agreement insurance of the following minimum types and
            amounts:
          </P>
          <P>
            a. Worker&apos;s compensation and employer&apos;s liability
            insurance, as required by law, covering all their employees who
            perform any of the obligations of the contractor, engineer, and
            architect under the contract. If any employer or employee is not
            subject to workers&apos; compensation laws of the governing State,
            then insurance shall be obtained voluntarily to extend to the
            employer and employee coverage to the same extent as though the
            employer or employee were subject to the workers&apos; compensation
            laws.
          </P>
          <P>
            b. Public liability insurance covering all operations under the
            contract shall have limits for bodily injury or death of not less
            than $1 million each occurrence, limits for property damage of not
            less than $1 million each occurrence, and $1 million aggregate for
            accidents during the policy period. A single limit of $1 million of
            bodily injury and property damage is acceptable. This required
            insurance may be in a policy or policies of insurance, primary and
            excess including the umbrella or catastrophe form.
          </P>
          <P>
            c. Automobile liability insurance on all motor vehicles used in
            connection with the contract, whether owned, non-owned, or hired,
            shall have limits for bodily injury or death of not less than $1
            million per person and $1 million each occurrence, and property
            damage limits of $1 million for each occurrence. This required
            insurance may be in a policy or policies of insurance, primary and
            excess including the umbrella or catastrophe form.
          </P>
          <P>
            2. The Owner shall have the right at any time to require public
            liability insurance and property damage liability insurance greater
            than those required in paragraphs (a)(1)(b) and (a)(1)(c) of this
            section. In any 
            <PRTPAGE P='394' />
            such event, the additional premium or premiums payable solely as the
            result of such additional insurance shall be added to the Contract
            price.
          </P>
          <P>
            3. The Owner shall be named as Additional Insured on all policies of
            insurance required in (a)(1)(b) and (a)(1)(c) of this section.
          </P>
          <P>
            4. The policies of insurance shall be in such form and issued by
            such insurer as shall be satisfactory to the Owner. The Contractor
            shall furnish the Owner a certificate evidencing compliance with the
            foregoing requirements that shall provide not less than 30 days
            prior written notice to the Owner of any cancellation or material
            change in the insurance.
          </P>
        </EXTRACT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Electric borrowers shall also ensure that all architects and
            engineers working under contract with the borrower have insurance
            coverage for Errors and Omissions (Professional Liability Insurance)
            in an amount at least as large as the amount of the architectural or
            engineering services contract but not less than $500,000.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The borrower may increase the limits of insurance if desired.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The minimum requirement of $1 million of public liability insurance
            does not apply to contractors performing maintenance work,
            janitorial-type services, meter reading services, rights-of-way
            mowing, and jobs of a similar nature. However, borrowers shall
            ensure that the contractor performing the work has public liability
            coverage at a level determined to be appropriate by the borrower.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If requested by RUS, the borrower shall provide RUS with a
            certificate from the contractor, engineer, or architect evidencing
            compliance with the requirements of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14718'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1788:B:1788.12
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1788.12
      </num>
      <head>
        Contractors&apos; bonds.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1788' sect='12' psec='' tq='N'>
              1788.12
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Contractors&apos; bonds.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Electric borrowers shall require contractors to obtain
          contractors&apos; bonds when required by 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='1726' tq='N'>
              1726
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , Electric System Construction Policies and Procedures, of this
          chapter. Surety companies providing contractors&apos; bonds shall be
          listed as acceptable sureties in the U.S. Department of Treasury
          Circular No. 570. The circular is maintained through periodic
          publication in the 
          <E T='04'>
            Federal Register
          </E>
           and is available on the Internet under
          ftp://ftp.fedworld.gov/pub/tel/sureties.txt, and on the Department of
          the Treasury&apos;s computer bulletin board at 202-874-6817.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14719'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1788:C:1788.46
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1788.46
      </num>
      <head>
        General.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1788' sect='46' psec='' tq='N'>
              1788.46
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          This subpart sets forth RUS policies for minimum insurance
          requirements for contractors, engineers, and architects performing
          work under contracts which are wholly or partially financed by RUS
          loans or guarantees with telecommunications borrowers.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14720'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1788:C:1788.47
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1788.47
      </num>
      <head>
        Policy requirements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1788' sect='47' psec='' tq='N'>
              1788.47
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Policy requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Contractors, engineers, and architects performing work for
            borrowers under construction, engineering, and architectural service
            contracts shall obtain insurance coverage, as required in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1788' sect='48' psec='' tq='N'>
                1788.48
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , and maintain it in effect until work under the contracts is
            completed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Contractors entering into construction contracts with borrowers
            shall furnish a contractors&apos; bond, except as provided for in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1788' sect='49' psec='' tq='N'>
                1788.49
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , covering all of the contractors&apos; undertaking under the
            contract.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Borrowers shall make sure that their contractors, engineers, and
            architects comply with the insurance and bond requirements of their
            contracts.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14721'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1788:C:1788.48
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1788.48
      </num>
      <head>
        Contract insurance requirements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1788' sect='48' psec='' tq='N'>
              1788.48
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Contract insurance requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Contracts entered into between borrowers and contractors, engineers,
          and architects shall provide that they take out and maintain
          throughout the contract period insurance of the following types and
          minimum amounts:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Workers&apos; compensation and employers&apos; liability insurance,
            as required by law, covering all their employees who perform any of
            the obligations of the contractor, engineer, and architect under the
            contract. If any employer or employee is not subject to the
            workers&apos; compensation laws of the governing state, then
            insurance shall be obtained voluntarily to extend to the employer 
            <PRTPAGE P='395' />
            and employee coverage to the same extent as though the employer or
            employee were subject to the workers&apos; compensation laws.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Public liability insurance covering all operations under the
            contract shall have limits for bodily injury or death of not less
            than $1 million each occurrence, limits for property damage of not
            less than $1 million each occurrence, and $1 million aggregate for
            accidents during the policy period. A single limit of $1 million of
            bodily injury and property damage is acceptable. This required
            insurance may be in a policy or policies of insurance, primary and
            excess including the umbrella or catastrophe form.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Automobile liability insurance on all motor vehicles used in
            connection with the contract, whether owned, non-owned, or hired,
            shall have limits for bodily injury or death of not less than $1
            million per person and $1 million per occurrence, and property
            damage limits of $1 million for each occurrence. This required
            insurance may be in a policy or policies of insurance, primary and
            excess including the umbrella or catastrophe form.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When a borrower contracts for the installation of major equipment
            by other than the supplier or for the moving of major equipment from
            one location to another, the contractor shall furnish the borrower
            with an installation floater policy. The policy shall cover all
            risks of damage to the equipment until completion of the
            installation contract.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14722'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1788:C:1788.49
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1788.49
      </num>
      <head>
        Contractors&apos; bond requirements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1788' sect='49' psec='' tq='N'>
              1788.49
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Contractors&apos; bond requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Construction contracts in amounts in excess of $250,000 for facilities
          shall require contractors to secure a contractors&apos; bond, on a
          form approved by RUS, attached to the contract in a penal sum of not
          less than the contract price, which is the sum of all labor and
          materials including owner-furnished materials installed in the
          project. RUS Form 168b is for use when the contract exceeds $250,000.
          RUS Form 168c is for use when the contractor&apos;s surety has
          accepted a Small Business Administration guarantee and the contract is
          for $1,000,000 or less. For minor construction contracts under which
          work will be done in sections and no section will exceed a total cost
          of $250,000, the borrower may waive the requirement for a
          contractors&apos; bond.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14723'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1788:C:1788.50
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1788.50
      </num>
      <head>
        Acceptable sureties.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1788' sect='50' psec='' tq='N'>
              1788.50
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Acceptable sureties.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Surety companies providing contractors&apos; bonds shall be listed as
          acceptable sureties in the U.S. Department of Treasury Circular No.
          570. The circular is maintained through periodic publication in the 
          <E T='04'>
            Federal Register
          </E>
           and is available on the Internet under
          ftp://ftp.fedworld.gov/pub/tel/sureties.txt, and on the Department of
          the Treasury&apos;s computer bulletin board at 202-874-6817.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14724'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1788:C:1788.51-1788.53
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1788.51-1788.53
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1788' sect='51-1788' psec='' tq='N'>
              1788.51-1788
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .53
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14725'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1788:C:1788.54
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1788.54
      </num>
      <head>
        Compliance with contracts.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1788' sect='54' psec='' tq='N'>
              1788.54
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Compliance with contracts.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          It is the responsibility of the borrower to determine, before the
          commencement of work, that the engineer, architect, and the contractor
          have insurance that complies with their contract requirements.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14726'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1788:C:1788.55
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1788.55
      </num>
      <head>
        Providing RUS evidence.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1788' sect='55' psec='' tq='N'>
              1788.55
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Providing RUS evidence.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          When RUS shall specifically so direct, the borrower shall also require
          the engineer, the architect, and the contractor, to forward to RUS
          evidence of compliance with their contract representative of the
          insurance company and include a provision that no change in or
          cancellation of any policy listed in the certificate will be made
          without the prior written notice to the borrower and to RUS.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>