<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol6'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:G:662
    </extid>
    <num>
      662
    </num>
    <head>
      REGIONAL EQUITY
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <PRTPAGE P='613' />
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='16' sect='3841' note='' psec='#d' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/3841.html#d'>
              16 U.S.C. 3841(d)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            74 FR 63540
          </aref>
          , Dec. 4, 2009, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='6485'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:G:662:-:662.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        662.1
      </num>
      <head>
        General.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='662' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              662.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          This part sets forth the procedures that NRCS will use to implement
          the Regional Equity provision of the Food Security Act of 1985, 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='16' sect='3841' note='' psec='#d' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/3841.html#d'>
              16 U.S.C. 3841(d)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6486'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:G:662:-:662.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        662.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='662' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              662.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The following definitions are applicable to this part:
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Chief
          </E>
           means the Chief of NRCS or the person delegated authority to act on
          behalf of the Chief.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Contribution programs
          </E>
           means Regional Equity programs that contribute funding to Regional
          Equity States, as determined by the Chief each fiscal year, consistent
          with the limitations established in 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='16' sect='3841' note='' psec='#d' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/3841.html#d'>
              16 U.S.C. 3841(d)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Drawing account
          </E>
           means the aggregated amount of contribution program funds required to
          bring all States to the Regional Equity threshold.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Funding opportunity
          </E>
           means the amount of funding needed to bring a State to the
          $15,000,000 Regional Equity threshold for the aggregate of Regional
          Equity programs.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Initial allocation
          </E>
           means the amount of conservation program allocation funding provided
          to all States through a merit-based, natural resource focused process.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Obligated
          </E>
           means a specific binding agreement, in writing, for the purpose
          authorized by law and executed while the funding is available.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Regional Equity programs
          </E>
           mean conservation programs under Subtitle D (excluding the
          Conservation Reserve Program, Wetlands Reserve Program, and the
          Conservation Security Program) of the Food Security Act of 1985. These
          programs include: Conservation Stewardship Program, Farm and Ranch
          Lands Protection Program, Grassland Reserve Program, Environmental
          Quality Incentives Program, Conservation Innovation Grants,
          Agricultural Water Enhancement Program, Conservation of Private
          Grazing Land, Wildlife Habitat Incentive Program, Grassroots Source
          Water Protection Program, Great Lakes Basin Program, Chesapeake Bay
          Watershed Initiative, and the Voluntary Public Access and Habitat
          Incentive Program. Regional Equity programs will be aggregated to
          determine whether a State meets the $15,000,000 Regional Equity
          threshold. However, not all Regional Equity programs will be
          considered contribution programs.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Regional Equity provision
          </E>
           means the statutory requirement to give priority funding before April
          1 for approved applications for specific programs within States that
          have not received a $15,000,000 aggregate level of funding.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Regional Equity States
          </E>
           means any State not meeting the Regional Equity threshold of
          $15,000,000 through the initial allocation for Regional Equity
          programs.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Regional Equity threshold
          </E>
           means the $15,000,000 minimum aggregate amount of Regional Equity
          program funds.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Respective demand
          </E>
           means the mix of contribution program funds that each State
          Conservationist in a Regional Equity State requests to fill that
          State&apos;s funding opportunity.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State
          </E>
           means all 50 States, the District of Columbia, Commonwealth of Puerto
          Rico, Guam, Virgin Islands, American Samoa, Commonwealth of the
          Northern Mariana Islands, and the Freely Associated States.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State Conservationist
          </E>
           means the NRCS employee authorized to implement Regional Equity
          programs and direct and supervise NRCS activities in a State, the
          Caribbean Area, or the Pacific Islands Area.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6487'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:G:662:-:662.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        662.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Applicability.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='662' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              662.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Applicability.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The regulation in this part sets forth the policies and procedures for
          the Regional Equity provision as administered by the NRCS. This
          regulation applies to the Regional Equity programs defined in this
          part. The Chief will implement the Regional Equity provision by
          identifying programs that contribute to the establishment of
          program-specific drawing accounts for priority funding in Regional
          Equity States.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6488'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:G:662:-:662.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        662.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Regional Equity implementation procedure.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='662' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              662.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Regional Equity implementation procedure.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The following procedures will implement the Regional Equity provision:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Determine initial allocations.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS will determine initial conservation 
            <PRTPAGE P='614' />
            program funding levels for each State through a merit-based, natural
            resource focused allocation process as determined by the Chief.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Determine the funding opportunity.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The combined initial allocation funding level for Regional Equity
            programs, by State, will be compared to the Regional Equity
            threshold to determine each Regional Equity State&apos;s funding
            opportunity.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Establish contribution program fund levels.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subject to availability of funds, contribution program fund levels
            are determined by:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Identifying which programs contribute funds, as determined by the
            Chief, consistent with the limitations established in 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='16' sect='3841' note='' psec='#d' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/3841.html#d'>
                16 U.S.C. 3841(d)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each State&apos;s respective demand.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State Conservationists in Regional Equity States, in consultation
            with State Technical Committees, will evaluate and determine their
            respective program demands based on the following criteria:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_i_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Program applications and how they address national program
            priorities;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_i_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Historic trends in program interest; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_i_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State priority natural resource concerns.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State Conservationist&apos;s identified respective demand will
            assist the Chief in determining the composition of contribution
            program funds within the established drawing account.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Establish the drawing account.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS will establish a drawing account for each contribution
            program, as determined in paragraphs (c)(1) and (c)(2) of this
            section, and will give priority before April 1 of each fiscal year
            for such funds to be used to fund applications in Regional Equity
            States sufficient to bring each of the Regional Equity States to the
            Regional Equity threshold of $15,000,000.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Access the drawing account.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State Conservationists in Regional Equity States may request access
            to that State&apos;s assigned portion of the drawing account once
            that State has obligated at least 90 percent of its initial
            allocation for that same program. The Chief may waive the 90 percent
            threshold requirement for a specific program in response to specific
            program needs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Re-allocation of funds.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The program-specific drawing accounts for Regional Equity States
            will be available until April 1 of each fiscal year, after which
            date the remaining funds may be re-allocated at the discretion of
            the Chief.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>