<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol8'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:IX:-:999
    </extid>
    <num>
      999
    </num>
    <head>
      SPECIALTY CROPS; IMPORT REGULATIONS
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='601-674' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/601-674.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 601-674
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='1445c-3' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1445c-3.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 1445c-3
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , and 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='7271' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/7271.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 7271
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </AUTH>
    </text>
    <section orderid='10021'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:IX:-:999:-:999.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        999.1
      </num>
      <head>
        Regulation governing the importation of dates.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          28 FR 3469
        </aref>
        , Apr. 10, 1963, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          31 FR 960
        </aref>
        , Jan. 25, 1966; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          33 FR 15986
        </aref>
        , Oct. 31, 1968; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          36 FR 6736
        </aref>
        , Apr. 8, 1971; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 69190
        </aref>
        , Dec. 30, 1993; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          74 FR 2808
        </aref>
        , Jan. 16, 2009]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='999' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              999.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Regulation governing the importation of dates.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Definitions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Dates in retail packages
            </E>
             means whole or pitted dates, other than dates prepared or
            preserved, wrapped or packaged for sale at retail.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Dates for packaging
            </E>
             means whole or pitted dates in bulk containers which are to be
            repacked, in whole or part, in the United States as dates in retail
            packages.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Bulk container
            </E>
             means any container of dates which, together with the dates
            therein, weighs more than ten pounds.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Dates for processing
            </E>
             means any dates for use in a bakery, confectionery, or other
            product and includes dates coated with a substance materially
            altering their color.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Dates prepared or preserved
            </E>
             means dates processed into a confection or other product, dates
            coated with a substance materially altering their color, or dates
            prepared for incorporation into a product by chopping, slicing, or
            other processing which materially alters their form.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Person
            </E>
             means any individual, partnership, corporation, association, or
            other business unit.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Fruit and Vegetable Division
            </E>
             means the Fruit and Vegetable Division of the Consumer and
            Marketing Service, United States Department of Agriculture,
            Washington, DC 20250.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              USDA inspector
            </E>
             means an inspector of the Processed Products Standardization and
            Inspection Branch, Fruit and Vegetable Division or any other duly
            authorized employee of the USDA.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Inspection certificate
            </E>
             means a written statement or memorandum report issued by a USDA
            inspector setting forth in addition to appropriate descriptive
            information the quality and condition of the product inspected, and
            in the case of imported dates, a statement of meeting or failing, as
            applicable, the U.S. import requirements under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 8e of
            </aref>
             the AMA Act of 1937.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Importation
            </E>
             means release from custody of United States Bureau of Customs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Grade requirements.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as provided in paragraph (d) of this section, the
            importation into the United States of any lot of dates for packaging
            or dates in retail packages is prohibited unless the dates are
            wholesome and unadulterated and meet the following grade
            requirements which are determined to be comparable to those imposed
            upon domestic dates handled pursuant to Order No. 987, as amended (
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='987' tq='N'>
                987 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            : The whole or pitted dates in the lot are of one variety, and are
            of such quality and condition that upon inspection on the basis of a
            representative sample thereof, with hydration (of the sample) in
            accordance with good commercial practice or without any hydration,
            the dates possess a reasonably good color, are reasonably uniform in
            size, are reasonably free from defects, possess a reasonably good
            character, and score not less than 80 points when scored in
            accordance with the scoring system applicable to U.S. Grade B dates,
            as prescribed in the U.S. Standards for Grades of Dates (
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='52' sect='1001' psec='' tq='N'>
                52.1001
              </subref>
            </aref>
             through 52.1011 of this chapter): 
            <E T='03'>
              Provided,
            </E>
             That not more than 25 percent, by weight, of the dates may possess
            semidry or dry calyx ends except that not more than 5 percent, by
            weight, of the dates may possess dry calyx ends: 
            <E T='03'>
              And provided further,
            </E>
             That in determining the grade for pitted dates, the pitted dates
            shall not be scored as damaged because of the longitudinal slit
            caused by removing the pit or the mashing resulting therefrom unless
            the flesh is seriously torn or mangled.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Compliance with the grade requirements shall be determined on the
            basis of an inspection and certification by a USDA inspector.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Inspection and certification requirements—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Inspection.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Inspection shall be performed by USDA inspectors in accordance with
            the Regulations Governing the Inspection and Certification of
            Processed Fruits and Vegetables and Related Products (
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='52' tq='N'>
                52 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ). The cost of each such inspection and related certification shall
            be borne by the applicant. Applications for inspection shall be made
            at least 10 days in 
            <PRTPAGE P='687' />
            advance and be accompanied by, or there shall be submitted promptly
            thereafter, either an onboard bill of lading designating the lots to
            be inspected by USDA inspectors and those to be entered as dates for
            processing, or a list of such lots and their identifying marks.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Certification.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each lot of dates inspected in accordance with paragraph (c)(1) of
            this section shall be covered by an inspection certificate. Each
            such certificate shall set forth, among other things, the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The date and place of inspection.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The name of the applicant.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Customs entry number pertaining to the lot or shipment covered
            by the certificate;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The variety, quantity, and identifying marks of the lot inspected.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The statement, if applicable: “Meets U.S. import requirements under
            
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 8e of
            </aref>
             the AMA Act of 1937”.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the lot fails to meet the import requirements, a statement to
            that effect and the reasons therefor. governing imports of walnuts.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Exemptions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notwithstanding any other provisions of this section, any lot of
            dates for importation which in the aggregate does not exceed 70
            pounds and any dates that are so denatured as to render them unfit
            for human consumption may be imported exempt from the provisions of
            this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Exemptions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The grade, size, quality and maturity requirements of this section
            shall not apply to dates which are donated to needy persons,
            prisoners or Native Americans on reservations, but such dates shall
            be subject to the safeguard provisions contained in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='999' sect='500' psec='' tq='N'>
                999.500
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Importation.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No person may import dates into the United States unless he or she
            first files with the Collector of Customs at the port at which the
            Customs entry is filed, as a condition of each such importation,
            either an inspection certificate or an executed Form
            FV-6—‘Importer&apos;s Exempt Commodity Form.’
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Dates for packaging and dates in retail packages.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No person may import any lot of dates for packaging or dates in
            retail packages unless the dates are covered by an inspection
            certificate containing the statement as to meeting the requirements
            set forth in paragraph (c)(2)(v) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Dates for processing and dates prepared or preserved—importation.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any person may import dates for processing and dates prepared or
            preserved exempt from the grade, inspection, and certification
            requirements of this section if the importer first files as a
            condition of such importation an executed Form FV-6—‘Importer&apos;s
            Exempt Commodity Form.’ The importer shall promptly transmit a copy
            of the executed Form FV-6 to the Fruit and Vegetable Division.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Dates for processing—Sale by importer.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No importer or other person may import, sell, or use any dates for
            processing other than for use as set forth in paragraph (a)(4) of
            this section or as otherwise permitted by this section. Each
            importer of dates for processing shall obtain from each purchaser,
            no later than the time of delivery to such purchaser, and file with
            the Fruit and Vegetable Division not later than the fifth day of the
            month following the month in which the dates were delivered, an
            executed Form FV-6.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Dates for processing—sale by other than importer.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each wholesaler or other reseller of dates for processing should,
            for his protection, obtain from each purchaser and hold in his files
            a Form FV-6 certification covering each sale or all sales of a
            calendar year.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Filing and retention of certificates.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The executed Form FV-6—‘Importer&apos;s Exempt Commodity Form’
            required to be filed pursuant to this section shall be executed in
            not less than three copies, of which one shall be filed with the
            Fruit and Vegetable Division not later than the fifth day of the
            month immediately following the month of delivery of the dates
            covered thereby, one shall be retained by the importer and one shall
            be retained by the person accepting delivery.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Reclassification.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any dates submitted for importation as dates for packaging or dates
            in retail packages 
            <PRTPAGE P='688' />
            that fail to meet the import requirements of this section may, upon
            execution of Form FV-6—‘Importer&apos;s Exempt Commodity Form’ be
            resubmitted for importation as dates for processing subject to the
            limitations of paragraph (j) of this section. Subsequent to
            importation, (1) any dates for processing other than dates that were
            resubmitted for importation in accordance with the preceding
            sentence and (2) any dates for packaging which through unintentional
            error were submitted for importation as dates for processing, either
            category having been covered by an executed Form FV-6, may if still
            held by the importer and if certified by a USDA inspector as meeting
            the requirements of this section for dates for packaging, be so
            reclassified and used. The reclassification to dates for packaging
            shall not be applicable to any dates that were falsely classified,
            other than through unintentional error, as dates for processing and
            submitted as such for importation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Reconditioning.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Nothing contained in this section shall preclude the reconditioning
            of failing lots of dates, prior to importation, so that such dates
            may be made eligible to meet the grade requirements prescribed in
            paragraph (b) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Books and records.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each person subject to this section shall maintain true and
            complete records of his transactions with respect to imported dates.
            Such records and copies of executed forms shall be retained for not
            less than two years subsequent to the calendar year of acquisition.
            The Secretary, through his duly authorized representatives, shall
            have access to any such person&apos;s premises during regular
            business hours and shall be permitted at any such times to inspect
            such records and any dates held by such person.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Other restrictions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The provisions of this section do not supersede any restrictions or
            prohibitions on the importation of dates under the Plant Quarantine
            Act of 1912, the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act, or any other
            applicable laws or regulations or the need to comply with applicable
            food and sanitary regulations of city, county, State, or Federal
            agencies.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Compliance.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any person who violates any provision of this section shall be
            subject to a forfeiture in the amount prescribed in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 8a(5
            </aref>
            ) of the Agricultural Marketing Agreement Act of 1937, as amended (
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              sections 1-19, 48
            </aref>
             Stat. 31, as amended; 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='601-674' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/601-674.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 601-674
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ), or, upon conviction, a penalty in the amount prescribed in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 8c(14
            </aref>
            ) of said act, or to both such forfeiture and penalty. False
            representations to an agency of the United States on any matter
            within its jurisdiction, knowing it to be false, is a violation of 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='18' sect='1001' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/18/1001.html'>
                18 U.S.C. 1001
              </subref>
            </aref>
             which provides for a fine or imprisonment or both.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            28 FR 3469
          </aref>
          , Apr. 10, 1963, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            31 FR 960
          </aref>
          , Jan. 25, 1966; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            33 FR 15986
          </aref>
          , Oct. 31, 1968; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            36 FR 6736
          </aref>
          , Apr. 8, 1971; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 69190
          </aref>
          , Dec. 30, 1993; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            74 FR 2808
          </aref>
          , Jan. 16, 2009]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='10022'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:IX:-:999:-:999.100
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        999.100
      </num>
      <head>
        Regulation governing imports of walnuts.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          29 FR 230
        </aref>
        , Jan. 9, 1964, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          40 FR 29263
        </aref>
        , July 11, 1975; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          41 FR 2075
        </aref>
        , Jan. 14, 1976; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          42 FR 35146
        </aref>
        , July 8, 1977; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 69190
        </aref>
        , Dec. 30, 1993; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          74 FR 2809
        </aref>
        , Jan. 16, 2009]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='999' sect='100' psec='' tq='N'>
              999.100
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Regulation governing imports of walnuts.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Definitions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Walnuts
            </E>
             means all walnuts commonly known as English or Persian walnuts
            (Juglans regia).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Inshell walnuts
            </E>
             means walnuts, the kernels or edible portions of which are
            contained in the shell.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Shelled walnuts
            </E>
             means the kernels of walnuts after the shells are removed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Person
            </E>
             means any individual, partnership, corporation, association, or
            other business unit.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              USDA Inspector
            </E>
             means any Federal or Federal-State inspector of the Fresh Products
            Standardization and Inspection Branch of the Fruit and Vegetable
            Division, Consumer and Marketing Service, United States Department
            of Agriculture.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Importation of walnuts
            </E>
             means the release of walnuts from the custody of the United States
            Customs Service.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Grade and size regulations.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No person may import walnuts (Juglans regia) into the United States
            unless such walnuts have been inspected and certified by a USDA
            inspector as meeting the following requirements:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Inshell walnuts.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All inshell walnuts shall be of a quality equal to or better than
            the requirements of U.S. No. 2 and “baby” size as prescribed in the
            United States Standards for Walnuts (Juglans regia) in the Shell (
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='51' sect='2945' psec='' tq='N'>
                51.2945
              </subref>
            </aref>
             through 51.2966 of this title); or
            <PRTPAGE P='689' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Shelled walnuts.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All shelled walnuts shall be of a quality equal to or better than
            the requirements for U.S. Commercial Grade as prescribed in the
            United States Standards for Shelled Walnuts (Juglans regia) (
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='51' sect='2275' psec='' tq='N'>
                51.2275
              </subref>
            </aref>
             through 51.2294 of this title excluding 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='51' sect='2278' psec='#b' tq='N'>
                51.2278(b)
              </subref>
              , 
              <subref title='7' part='51' sect='2284' psec='' tq='N'>
                51.2284
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='51' sect='2285' psec='' tq='N'>
                51.2285
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) effective January 25, 1959, except that the minimum size shall be
            pieces not more than five percent of which will pass through a round
            opening 
            <FR>
              6/64
            </FR>
             inch in diameter and no other size requirements shall apply.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Inspection and certification.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All inspections and certifications required by paragraph (b) of
            this section shall be made by USDA inspectors in accordance with the
            regulations governing the inspection and certification of fresh
            fruits, vegetables, and other products (
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              Part 
              <subref title='7' part='51' tq='N'>
                51 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ). The cost of inspection and certification shall be borne by the
            applicant.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each inspection certificate shall set forth among other things the
            following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The date and place of inspection;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The name of the applicant;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The name of the importer;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Customs entry number pertaining to the lot or shipment covered
            by the certificate;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The quantity and identifying marks of the container; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The statement, if applicable, “Meets U.S. import requirements under
            
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 8e of
            </aref>
             the Agricultural Marketing Agreement Act of 1937”.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whenever walnuts are offered for inspection, the applicant shall
            furnish any labor and pay any costs incurred in moving and opening
            containers as may be necessary for proper sampling and inspection.
            The applicant shall also furnish the USDA inspector the entry number
            and such other identifying information for each lot as he may
            request.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Inspection must be completed prior to the importation of walnuts.
            To avoid delay the applicant should make advance arrangements with
            the USDA inspection office.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Reconditioning prior to importation.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Nothing contained in this section shall be deemed to preclude
            reconditioning walnuts prior to importation, in order that such
            walnuts may be made eligible to meet the grade and size regulations
            prescribed in paragraph (b) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Minimum quantity.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, the
            importation of any lot of walnuts which does not exceed, in net
            weight, 60 pounds of shelled walnuts or 115 pounds of inshell
            walnuts shall be exempt from the requirements of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Exemptions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The grade, size, quality and maturity requirements of this section
            shall not apply to walnuts which are: green walnuts (so immature
            that they cannot be used for drying and sale as dried walnuts);
            walnuts used in non-competitive outlets such as use by charitable
            institutions, relief agencies, governmental agencies for school
            lunch programs, and diversion to animal feed or oil manufacture, but
            such walnuts shall be subject to the safeguard provisions contained
            in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='999' sect='500' psec='' tq='N'>
                999.500
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Other import requirements.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The provisions of this section do not supersede any restrictions or
            prohibitions on walnuts under the Federal Plant Quarantine Act of
            1912, or any other applicable laws or regulations of city, county,
            State, or Federal Agencies including the Federal Food, Drug and
            Cosmetic Act.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Compliance.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any person violating any of the provisions of this regulation is
            subject to a forfeiture in the amount prescribed in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 608a(5
            </aref>
            ) of the Agricultural Marketing Agreement Act of 1937, as amended (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='601-674' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/601-674.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 601-674
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ), or, upon conviction, a penalty in the amount prescribed in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 608c(14
            </aref>
            ) of said act, or to both such forfeiture and penalty. False
            representations in any matter within the jurisdiction of any agency
            of the United States, knowing it to be false, is a violation of 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='18' sect='1001' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/18/1001.html'>
                18 U.S.C. 1001
              </subref>
            </aref>
             which provides for a fine or imprisonment or both.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            29 FR 230
          </aref>
          , Jan. 9, 1964, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            40 FR 29263
          </aref>
          , July 11, 1975; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            41 FR 2075
          </aref>
          , Jan. 14, 1976; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            42 FR 35146
          </aref>
          , July 8, 1977; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 69190
          </aref>
          , Dec. 30, 1993; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            74 FR 2809
          </aref>
          , Jan. 16, 2009]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='10023'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:IX:-:999:-:999.200
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        999.200
      </num>
      <head>
        Regulation governing the importation of prunes.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          36 FR 18782
        </aref>
        , Sept. 22, 1971, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          47 FR 47230
        </aref>
        , Oct. 25, 1982; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          57 FR 56245
        </aref>
        , Nov. 27, 1992; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          59 FR 38113
        </aref>
        , July 27, 1994; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          60 FR 57910
        </aref>
        , Nov. 24, 1995; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          74 FR 2809
        </aref>
        , Jan. 16, 2009]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='999' sect='200' psec='' tq='N'>
              999.200
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Regulation governing the importation of prunes.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Definitions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Prunes
            </E>
             means and includes all sun-dried or artificially dehydrated plums,
            of any type of variety, produced from plums, except: Sulfur-
            <PRTPAGE P='690' />
            bleached prunes which are produced from yellow varieties of plums
            and are commonly known as silver plums; (ii) plums which have not
            been dried or dehydrated to a point where they are capable of being
            stored prior to packing, without material deterioration or spoilage
            unless refrigeration or other artificial means of preservation are
            used, and so long as they are treated by a process which is in
            conformity with, or generally similar to, the processes for
            treatment of plums of that type which have been developed or
            recommended by the Food Technology Division, College of Agriculture,
            University of California, for the specialty pack known as “high
            moisture content prunes”, but this exception shall not apply if and
            when such plums are dried to the point where they are capable of
            being stored without material deterioration or spoilage,
            refrigeration or other artificial means of preservation; and (iii)
            brine dried prunes that have been impregnated with brine or salt
            during the dehydration process to the extent that they have lost
            their form and character as prunes, and cannot be reconstituted to
            permit economic use of the individual fruits as prunes, and are
            imported under International Harmonized Tariff Schedule No.
            0813.20.1000.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Pitted prunes
            </E>
             means prunes with the pit removed that are characterized by a
            uniform depression and minimal skin break where the pit has been
            removed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Macerated prunes
            </E>
             means dried prunes with the pit removed that are characterized by a
            flattened appearance with slightly more skin break where the pit has
            been removed than with pitted prunes.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Standard prunes
            </E>
             means any lot of prunes meeting the grade and size requirements
            prescribed in paragraph (b)(1) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Standard pitted prunes
            </E>
             means any lot of pitted prunes meeting the grade requirements
            prescribed in paragraphs (b)(2) and (b)(3) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Standard pitted macerated prunes
            </E>
             means any lot of pitted macerated prunes meeting the grade
            requirements in paragraphs (b)(2) and (b)(4) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Manufacturing grade substandard prunes
            </E>
             means any lot of prunes which meets the grade requirements
            prescribed in paragraph (b)(5) of this section but fails to meet the
            requirements for standard prunes, standard pitted prunes and
            standard pitted macerated prunes.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Size
            </E>
             means the number of prunes contained in a pound.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Person
            </E>
             means any individual, partnership, corporation, association, or
            other business unit.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Fruit and Vegetable Division
            </E>
             means the Fruit and Vegetable Division of the Agricultural
            Marketing Service, U.S. Department of Agriculture, Washington, DC
            20250.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_11'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (11)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              USDA inspector
            </E>
             means an inspector of the Processed Products Standardization and
            Inspection Branch, Fruit and Vegetable Division, or any other duly
            authorized employee of the USDA.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_12'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (12)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Importation
            </E>
             means release from custody of the U.S. Bureau of Customs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_13'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (13)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Undersized prunes
            </E>
             means those prunes that pass freely through a round opening 23/32
            of an inch in diameter.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Grade and size requirements.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as provided in paragraph (b)(5) or paragraph (d) of this
            section, no person may import any lot of prunes into the United
            States unless the prunes are inspected and an inspection certificate
            issued with respect thereto, and the lot meets the applicable grade
            requirements specified in exhibit A of this section and the average
            count (i.e., number) of the prunes in such lot is 100 or less per
            pound. In determining whether any lot conforms to the size
            requirement, the following tolerance shall apply: In a sample of 100
            ounces, the count per pound of 10 ounces of smallest prunes may not
            vary from the count per pound of 10 ounces of the largest prunes by
            more than 45 points.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No person may import any lot of pitted prunes or pitted macerated
            prunes for human consumption as pitted or pitted macerated prunes
            unless the lot meets the applicable minimum grade requirements set
            forth in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='999' sect='200' psec='' tq='N'>
                999.200
              </subref>
            </aref>
             (exhibit A), except that skin or flesh damage shall not be scored
            as a defect in determining whether the prunes meet the grade
            requirements. Pitted and pitted macerated prunes shall not 
            <PRTPAGE P='691' />
            be subject to size and undersized requirements.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No person may import any lot of pitted prunes for human consumption
            as pitted prunes unless the lot does not exceed an average of 0.5
            percent by count of prunes with whole pits and/or pit fragments 2 mm
            or longer and four of ten subsamples examined have no more than 0.5
            percent by count of prunes with whole pits and/or pit fragments 2 mm
            or longer.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No person may import any lot of pitted macerated prunes for human
            consumption as pitted macerated prunes unless the lot does not
            exceed an average of 2 percent by count of prunes with whole pits
            and/or pit fragments 2 mm or longer; and four of ten subsamples
            examined have no more than 2 percent by count with whole pits and/or
            pit fragments 2 mm or longer.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any person may import any lot of prunes, except any lot containing
            undersized prunes, pitted prunes or pitted macerated prunes, into
            the United States for use in human consumption outlets as prune
            products in which the prunes lose their form and character as prunes
            by conversion prior to consumption if the prunes are inspected and
            an inspection certificate issued with respect thereto, and each lot
            meets the grade requirements set forth in paragraphs (1), (2), and
            (3) of exhibit A of this section, and the importer first files as a
            condition of such importation an executed Form FV-6—‘Importer&apos;s
            Exempt Commodity Form.’.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Inspection and certification requirements—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Inspection.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Inspection shall be performed by a USDA inspector in accordance
            with the regulations governing inspection and certification of
            processed fruits and vegetables, processed products thereof, and
            certain other processed food products (
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='52' tq='N'>
                52 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ). The cost of each such inspection and related certification shall
            be borne by the applicant.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Certification.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each lot of prunes inspected in accordance with paragraph (c)(1) of
            this section shall be covered by an inspection certificate. Each
            such certificate shall set forth, among other things, the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The date and place of inspection.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The name of the applicant.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Customs entry number pertaining to the lot or shipment covered
            by the certificate;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The quantity and identifying marks of the lot inspected.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The statement, as applicable: “Meets U.S. import requirements for
            standard prunes, standard pitted and standard pitted macerated
            prunes under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 8e of
            </aref>
             the AMA Act of 1937”; “Meets U.S. import requirements for
            manufacturing grade substandard prunes under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 8e of
            </aref>
             the AMA Act of 1937”; or “Fails to meet U.S. import requirements
            for prunes under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 8e of
            </aref>
             the AMA Act of 1937”.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the lot fails to meet the import requirements, a statement of
            the reason therefor.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Exemptions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notwithstanding any other provisions of this section, the
            importation of any lot of prunes which in the aggregate does not
            exceed 150 pounds, net weight, and any prunes that are so denatured
            as to render them unfit for human consumption shall be exempt from
            the requirements of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Additional requirements—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Prior to importation of any prunes, the person importing such
            prunes shall file an inspection certificate with the Collector of
            Customs at the port at which the customs entry is filed. In
            addition, if such prunes are manufacturing grade substandard prunes,
            such person shall also file with the Collector of Customs an
            executed Form FV-6—‘Importer&apos;s Exempt Commodity Form.’ Promptly
            after such filing, such person shall transmit a copy of this form to
            the Fruit and Vegetable Division. No person may import, sell, or use
            any manufacturing grade substandard prunes other than for use as set
            forth in paragraph (b)(5) of this section. Each person importing
            manufacturing grade substandard prunes shall obtain from each
            purchaser, no later than the time of delivery to such purchaser, and
            file with the Fruit and Vegetable Division not later than the 5th
            day of the month following the month in which the prunes were
            delivered, an executed Form FV-6—‘Importer&apos;s Exempt Commodity
            Form.’ One copy of this executed form shall be retained by 
            <PRTPAGE P='692' />
            the importer and one copy shall be retained by the purchaser.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Manufacturing Grade Substandard Prune—sale by other than importer.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each wholesaler or other reseller of manufacturing grade
            substandard prunes should, for his or her protection, obtain from
            each purchaser and hold in his or her files an executed Form
            FV-6—‘Importer&apos;s Exempt Commodity Form’ covering each sale
            during the calendar year.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Reconditioning.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Nothing contained in this section shall preclude the reconditioning
            of failing lots of prunes, prior to importation, so that such prunes
            may be made eligible to meet the requirements prescribed pursuant to
            paragraphs (b)(1) through (5), as applicable, of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Books and records.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each person subject to this section shall maintain true and
            complete records of his transactions with respect to imported
            prunes. Such records and copies of executed forms shall be retained
            for not less than 2 years subsequent to the calendar year of
            acquisition. The Secretary, through his duly authorized
            representatives, shall have access to any such person&apos;s
            premises during regular business hours and shall be permitted at any
            such times to inspect such records and any prunes held by such
            person.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Other restrictions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The provisions of this section do not supersede any restrictions or
            prohibitions on the importation of prunes under the Plant Quarantine
            Act of 1912, the Federal Food, Drug and Cosmetic Act, or any other
            applicable laws or regulations or the need to comply with applicable
            food and sanitary regulations of city, county, State, or Federal
            agencies.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Compliance.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any person who violates any provision of this section shall be
            subject to a forfeiture in the amount prescribed in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 8a(5
            </aref>
            ) of the Agricultural Marketing Agreement Act of 1937, as amended (
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              sections 1-19, 48
            </aref>
             Stat. 31, as amended; 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='601-674' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/601-674.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 601-674
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ), or, upon conviction, a penalty in the amount prescribed in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 8c(14
            </aref>
            ) of said act, or to both such forfeiture and penalty. False
            representations to an agency of the United States on any matter
            within its jurisdiction, knowing it to be false, is a violation of 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='18' sect='1001' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/18/1001.html'>
                18 U.S.C. 1001
              </subref>
            </aref>
             which provides for a fine or imprisonment or both.
          </text>
        </P>
        <HD SOURCE='HD1'>
          Exhibit A
        </HD>
        <HD SOURCE='HD1'>
          grade requirements
        </HD>
        <P>
          A. 
          <E T='03'>
            Defects.
          </E>
           Defects are: (1) Off-color; (2) inferior meat condition; (3) end
          cracks; (4) fermentation; (5) skin or flesh damage; (6) scab; (7)
          burned; (8) mold; (9) imbedded dirt; (10) insect infestation; (11)
          decay.
        </P>
        <P>
          B. 
          <E T='03'>
            Explanation of terms.
          </E>
           (1) 
          <E T='03'>
            Off-color
          </E>
           means a dull color or skin differing noticeably in appearance from
          that which is characteristic of mature, properly handled fruit of a
          given variety or type.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Inferior meat condition
            </E>
             means flesh which is fibrous, woody, or otherwise inferior due to
            immaturity to the extent that the characteristic texture of the meat
            is substantially affected.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              End cracks
            </E>
             means callous growth cracks, at the blossom end of prunes,
            aggregating more than three-eighths of one inch (
            <FR>
              3/8
            </FR>
            ″) but not more than one-half of one inch (
            <FR>
              1/2
            </FR>
            ″) in length.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Fermentation
            </E>
             means damage to the flesh by fermentation to the extent that the
            characteristic appearance or flavor is substantially affected.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Skin or flesh damage
            </E>
             means growth cracks, splits, breaks in skin or flesh of the
            following descriptions:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Callous growth cracks, except end cracks as defined in this
            section, aggregating more than three-eighths of one inch (
            <FR>
              3/8
            </FR>
            ″) in length;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Splits or skin breaks exposing flesh and materially affecting the
            normal appearance of the prunes;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any cracks, splits, or breaks open to the pit;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Healed or unhealed surface or flesh blemishes caused by insect
            injury and which materially affect appearance, edibility or keeping
            quality.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Scab
            </E>
             means tough or thick scab exceeding in the aggregate the area of a
            circle three-eighths of one inch (
            <FR>
              3/8
            </FR>
            ″) in diameter or by unsightly scab of another character exceeding
            in the aggregate the area of a circle three-fourths of one inch (
            <FR>
              3/4
            </FR>
            ″) in diameter.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Burned
            </E>
             means injury by sunburn or excessive heat in dehydration to the 
            <PRTPAGE P='693' />
            extent that the characteristic appearance, flavor or edibility of
            the fruit is noticeably affected.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Mold
            </E>
             means a characteristic fungus growth and is self-explanatory.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Imbedded dirt
            </E>
             means the presence of dirt or other extraneous material so imbedded
            in, or adhering to, the prune that it cannot readily be removed in
            washing the fruit.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Insect infestation
            </E>
             means the presence of insects, insect fragments or insect remains.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          C. 
          <E T='03'>
            Maximum tolerances.
          </E>
           Tolerance allowances shall be on a weight basis and shall not exceed
          the following:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             There shall be no tolerance allowance for live insect infestation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The tolerance allowances for decay shall not exceed one percent
            (1%).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The combined tolerance allowance for mold, brown rot, imbedded
            dirt, insect infestation, and decay shall not exceed five percent
            (5%), and, within such tolerance, brown rot shall not exceed three
            percent (3%).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The combined tolerance allowance for fermentation, skin or flesh
            damage, scab, burned, mold, imbedded dirt, insect infestation, and
            decay shall not exceed eight percent (8%).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The combined tolerance allowance for end cracks, fermentation, skin
            or flesh damage, scab, burned, mold, imbedded dirt, insect
            infestation, and decay shall not exceed ten percent (10%), except
            that the first eight percent (8%) of end cracks shall be given
            one-half value and any additional percentage of end cracks shall be
            given full value.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The combined tolerance allowance for off-color, inferior meat
            condition, end cracks, fermentation, skin or flesh damage, scab,
            burned, mold, imbedded dirt, insect infestation, and decay shall not
            exceed fifteen percent (15%), except that the first eight percent
            (8%) of end cracks shall be given one-half value and any additional
            percentage of end cracks shall be given full value.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            36 FR 18782
          </aref>
          , Sept. 22, 1971, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            47 FR 47230
          </aref>
          , Oct. 25, 1982; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            57 FR 56245
          </aref>
          , Nov. 27, 1992; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            59 FR 38113
          </aref>
          , July 27, 1994; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            60 FR 57910
          </aref>
          , Nov. 24, 1995; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            74 FR 2809
          </aref>
          , Jan. 16, 2009]
        </CITA>
        <EFFDNOT>
          <HD SOURCE='HED'>
            Effective Date Note:
          </HD>
          <P>
            At 
            <aref type='FREGIST'>
              74 FR 2809
            </aref>
            , Jan. 16, 2009, 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='999' sect='200' psec='' tq='N'>
                999.200
              </subref>
            </aref>
             was suspended indefinitely.
          </P>
        </EFFDNOT>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='10024'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:IX:-:999:-:999.300
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        999.300
      </num>
      <head>
        Regulation governing importation of raisins.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          37 FR 5282
        </aref>
        , Mar. 14, 1972, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          37 FR 13635
        </aref>
        , July 12, 1972; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          37 FR 23820
        </aref>
        , Nov. 9, 1972; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          41 FR 52646
        </aref>
        , Dec. 1, 1976; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          43 FR 47972
        </aref>
        , Oct. 18, 1978; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          43 FR 57863
        </aref>
        , Dec. 11, 1978; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          45 FR 65513
        </aref>
        , Oct. 3, 1980; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          47 FR 51731
        </aref>
        , Nov. 17, 1982; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          50 FR 45808
        </aref>
        , Nov. 4, 1985; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          53 FR 34715
        </aref>
        , Sept. 8, 1988; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          67 FR 57505
        </aref>
        , Sept. 11, 2002; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          74 FR 2809
        </aref>
        , Jan. 16, 2009]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='999' sect='300' psec='' tq='N'>
              999.300
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Regulation governing importation of raisins.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Definitions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For purposes of this section:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Raisins
            </E>
             means grapes from which a part of the natural moisture has been
            removed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Varietal type
            </E>
             means the applicable one of the following: Thompson Seedless
            raisins, Muscat raisins, Layer Muscat raisins, Currant raisins,
            Monukka raisins, Other Seedless raisins, Golden Seedless raisins,
            and Other Seedless-Sulfured raisins.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Thompson Seedless Raisins
            </E>
             includes those raisins commonly referred to in international trade
            as Sultana raisins and means raisins made from Thompson Seedless
            (Sultana) grapes and from grapes with characteristics similar to
            Thompson Seedless (Sultanina) grapes.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Person
            </E>
             means any individual, partnership, corporation, association, or
            other business unit.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Fruit and Vegetable Quality Division
            </E>
             means the Fruit and Vegetable Quality Division of the Food Safety
            and Quality Service, U.S. Department of Agriculture, Washington, DC
            20250.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              USDA inspector
            </E>
             means an inspector of the Processed Products Branch, Fruit and
            Vegetable Quality Division, or any other duly authorized employee of
            the U.S. Department of Agriculture.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Importation of raisins
            </E>
             means the release of raisins from custody of the U.S. Customs
            Service.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Fruit and Vegetable Division
            </E>
             means the Fruit and Vegetable Division of the Agricultural
            Marketing Service, U.S. Department of Agriculture, Washington, DC
            20250.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Grade and size requirements.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The importation of raisins into the United States is prohibited
            unless the raisins are inspected and certified as provided in this
            section. Except as provided in paragraph (e)(2) of this section, no
            person may import raisins into the United States unless such raisins
            have been inspected and certified by a USDA inspector as to whether
            or not the raisins are of a varietal type, and if a varietal type,
            as at least meeting the following applicable grade and size
            requirements, which requirements are the same as those imposed upon
            domestic raisins handled pursuant to Order No. 989, as amended (
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='989' tq='N'>
                989 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ):
            <PRTPAGE P='694' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             With respect to Thompson Seedless and Other Seedless-Sulfured
            raisins—the requirements of U.S. Grade C as defined in the effective
            United States Standards of Grades of Processed Raisins (
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='52' sect='1841' psec='' tq='N'>
                52.1841
              </subref>
            </aref>
             through 52.1858 of this title): 
            <E T='03'>
              Provided,
            </E>
             That, at least 70 percent, by weight, of the raisins shall be
            well-matured or reasonably well-matured. With respect to
            select-sized and mixed-sized lots, the raisins shall at least meet
            the U.S. Grade B tolerances for pieces of stem and undeveloped and
            substandard raisins, and small (midget) sized raisins shall meet the
            U.S. Grade C tolerances for those factors;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             With respect to Muscat raisins—the requirements of U.S. Grade C as
            defined in said standards;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             With respect to Layer Muscat raisins—the requirements of U.S. Grade
            B as defined for “Layer or Cluster Raisins with Seeds” in said
            standards, except for the provisions therein relating to moisture
            content;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             With respect to Currant raisins—the requirements of U.S. Grade B as
            defined in said standards;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             With respect to Monukka and Other Seedless raisins—the requirements
            for Thompson Seedless Raisins prescribed in paragraph (b)(1) of this
            section, except that the tolerance for moisture shall be 19 percent
            rather than 18 percent;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             With respect to Golden Seedless raisins—the requirements prescribed
            in paragraph (b)(1) of this section for Thompson Seedless raisins
            and the color requirements for “colored” as defined in said
            standards.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Inspection and certification requirements.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All inspections and certifications required by paragraph (b) of
            this section shall be made by USDA inspectors in accordance with the
            regulations governing inspection and certification of processed
            fruits and vegetables, processed products thereof, and certain other
            processed food products (
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='52' tq='N'>
                52 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ). The cost of each such inspection and certification shall be borne
            by the applicant.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each lot of raisins inspected in accordance with paragraph (c)(1)
            of this section shall be covered by an inspection certificate. Each
            such certificate shall set forth, among other things, the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The date and place of inspection;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The name of the applicant;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The name of the importer;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Customs entry number pertaining to the lot or shipment covered
            by the certificate;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The quantity and identifying marks of the lot inspected;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The statement, as applicable, “Meets U.S. import requirements under
            
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 8e of
            </aref>
             the AMA Act of 1937” or “Fails to meet U.S. import requirements
            under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 8e of
            </aref>
             the AMA Act of 1937”; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_vii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the lot fails to meet the import requirements, a statement of
            the reasons therefor.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whenever raisins are offered for inspection, the applicant shall
            furnish any labor and pay any costs incurred in moving and opening
            containers as may be necessary for proper sampling and inspection.
            The applicant shall also furnish the USDA inspector the entry number
            and such other identifying information for each lot as he may
            request. “To avoid delay in scheduling the inspection the applicant
            should make advance arrangements with the USDA inspection office.”
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Reconditioning.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Nothing contained in this section shall preclude the reconditioning
            of failing lots of raisins prior to importation of raisins in order
            that such raisins may be made eligible to meet the applicable grade
            and size requirements in paragraph (b) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Exemptions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, any lot of
            raisins which in the aggregate does not exceed 100 pounds, net
            weight, may be imported without regard to the restrictions of this
            section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any person may import any lot of raisins which does not meet the
            applicable grade and size requirements of paragraph (b) of this
            section for use in the production of alcohol, syrup for industrial
            use, or which does not meet such requirements with respect to
            mechanical damage or sugaring for use in the production of raisin
            paste. Prior to such importation, such person shall file with the
            Customs Service Regional Commissioner or District Director, as
            applicable, at the port at which the 
            <PRTPAGE P='695' />
            customs entry is filed an executedForm FV-6—Importer&apos;s Exempt
            Commodity Form. Promptly after such filing, such person shall
            transmit a copy of this form to the Fruit and Vegetable Division. No
            person may import, sell, or use any raisins which do not meet the
            applicable grade and size requirements of paragraph (b) of this
            section other than for use as set forth in this paragraph. Each
            person importing raisins, which do not meet the applicable grade and
            size requirements of paragraph (b) of this section, for use in the
            production of alcohol, syrup for industrial use, or raisin paste
            shall obtain from each purchaser, not later than the time of
            delivery to such purchaser, and file with the Fruit and Vegetable
            Division not later than the fifth day of the month following the
            month in which the raisins were delivered, an executed Form FV-6.
            One copy of this executed form shall be retained by the importer and
            one copy shall be retained by the purchaser. Each reseller of
            raisins imported pursuant to this subparagraph should, for his
            protection, obtain from each purchaser and hold in his files an
            executed Form FV-6, covering such sales of such raisins during the
            calendar year. One copy of this executed form shall be retained by
            the reseller and one copy shall be retained by the purchaser.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Books and records.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each person subject to this section shall maintain true and
            complete records of his transactions with respect to imported
            raisins. Such records shall be retained for not less than 2 years
            subsequent to the calendar year of importation. The Secretary,
            through his duly authorized representatives, shall have access to
            any such person&apos;s premises during regular business hours and
            shall be permitted at any such time to inspect such records and any
            imported raisins held by such person.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Other restriction.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The provisions of this section do not supersede any restrictions or
            prohibitions on the importation of raisins under the Federal Plant
            Quarantine Act of 1912, the Federal Food, Drug and Cosmetic Act, or
            any other applicable laws or regulations, or the need to comply with
            applicable food and sanitary regulations of city, county, State, or
            Federal agencies.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Compliance.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any person violating any of the provisions of this regulation is
            subject to a forfeiture in the amount prescribed in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 8a(5
            </aref>
            ) of the Agricultural Marketing Agreement Act of 1937, as amended (
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              sections 1-19, 48
            </aref>
             Stat. 31, as amended; 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='601-674' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/601-674.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 601-674
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ), or, upon conviction, a penalty in the amount prescribed in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 8c(14
            </aref>
            ) of said act, or to both such forfeiture and penalty. False
            representation to an agency of the United States in any matter
            within its jurisdiction, knowing it to be false, is a violation of 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='18' sect='1001' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/18/1001.html'>
                18 U.S.C. 1001
              </subref>
            </aref>
             which provides for a fine or imprisonment or both.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            37 FR 5282
          </aref>
          , Mar. 14, 1972, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            37 FR 13635
          </aref>
          , July 12, 1972; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            37 FR 23820
          </aref>
          , Nov. 9, 1972; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            41 FR 52646
          </aref>
          , Dec. 1, 1976; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            43 FR 47972
          </aref>
          , Oct. 18, 1978; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            43 FR 57863
          </aref>
          , Dec. 11, 1978; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            45 FR 65513
          </aref>
          , Oct. 3, 1980; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            47 FR 51731
          </aref>
          , Nov. 17, 1982; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            50 FR 45808
          </aref>
          , Nov. 4, 1985; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            53 FR 34715
          </aref>
          , Sept. 8, 1988; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            67 FR 57505
          </aref>
          , Sept. 11, 2002; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            74 FR 2809
          </aref>
          , Jan. 16, 2009]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='10025'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:IX:-:999:-:999.400
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        999.400
      </num>
      <head>
        Regulation governing the importation of filberts.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          42 FR 64899
        </aref>
        , Dec. 29, 1977, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          45 FR 63482
        </aref>
        , Sept. 25, 1980; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          47 FR 12612
        </aref>
        , Mar. 24, 1982; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          48 FR 34015
        </aref>
        , July 27, 1983; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          74 FR 2809
        </aref>
        , Jan. 16, 2009]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='999' sect='400' psec='' tq='N'>
              999.400
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Regulation governing the importation of filberts.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Definitions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Filberts
            </E>
             means filberts or hazelnuts.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Inshell filberts
            </E>
             means filberts, the kernels or edible portions of which are
            contained in the shell.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Shelled filberts
            </E>
             means the kernels of filberts after the shells are removed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Person
            </E>
             means any individual, partnership, corporation, association, or
            other business unit.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              USDA inspector
            </E>
             means a Federal or Federal-State inspector, Food Safety and Quality
            Service, United States Department of Agriculture, or any other duly
            authorized employee of the USDA.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Importation
            </E>
             means release from custody of the United States Bureau of Customs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Grade and size requirements.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as provided in paragraph (d) of this section, no person
            shall import into the United States any lot of filberts unless the
            filberts meet the following requirements, which are identical to
            those for filberts grown in Oregon and Washington and handled
            pursuant to Order No. 982, as amended (
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='982' tq='N'>
                982
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ):
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Inshell filberts.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All inshell filberts shall be of a quality equal to or better than
            the requirements of U.S. No. 1 grade and medium size as defined in 
            <PRTPAGE P='696' />
            the U.S. Standards for Filberts in the Shell (
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='51' tq='N'>
                51
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ), except that the tolerance for insect injury shall be two percent.
            With this modification, the U.S. No. 1 grade, medium size is
            identical to the Oregon No. 1 grade, medium size (as defined in the
            Oregon Grade Standards Filberts in Shell) and prescribed for inshell
            filberts under Order No. 982, as amended.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Shelled filberts.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All shelled filberts shall be of a quality equal to or better than
            the requirements prescribed in exhibit A of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Inspection and certification requirements—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Compliance with the grade and size requirements of paragraph (b) of
            this section shall be determined on the basis of an inspection and
            certification by a USDA inspector.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Inspection.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Inspection shall be performed by USDA inspectors in accordance with
            the Regulations Governing the Inspection and Certification of Fresh
            Fruits and Vegetables and Related Products (
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='51' tq='N'>
                51
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ). The cost of each such inspection and related certification shall
            be borne by the applicant. Whenever filberts are offered for
            inspection, the applicant shall furnish any labor and pay any costs
            incurred in moving and opening containers as may be necessary for
            proper sampling and inspection. The applicant shall also furnish the
            USDA inspector the entry number and such other identifying
            information for each lot as he may request. Inspection must be
            completed prior to the importation of filberts. The applicant should
            make advance arrangements with the USDA inspection office to avoid
            delay in scheduling the inspection.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Certification.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each lot of filberts inspected in accordance with paragraph (c)(1)
            of this section shall be covered by an inspection certificate. Each
            such certificate shall set forth, among other things, the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The date and place of inspection.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The name of the applicant.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The name of the importer.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_3_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Customs entry number pertaining to the lot or shipment covered
            by the certificate;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_3_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The quantity, and identifying marks of the lot inspected.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_3_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The statement, if applicable: “Meets U.S. import requirements under
            
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 8e of
            </aref>
             the AMA Act of 1937”.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_3_vii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the lot fails to meet the import requirements, a statement to
            that effect and the reasons therefor.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Exemptions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notwithstanding any other provisions of this section, the
            importation of any lot of filberts which does not exceed 115 pounds
            in net weight shall be exempt from the requirements of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Reconditioning prior to importation.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Nothing contained in this section shall be deemed to preclude
            reconditioning filberts prior to importation, in order that such
            filberts may be made eligible to meet the applicable grade and size
            regulations prescribed in paragraph (b) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Other restrictions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The provisions of this section do not supersede the Federal Plant
            Quarantine Act of 1912, the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act, or
            any other applicable laws or regulations or the need to comply with
            applicable food and sanitary regulations of city, county, State or
            Federal agencies.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Compliance.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any person who violates any provision of this section shall be
            subject to a forfeiture in the amount prescribed in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 8a(5
            </aref>
            ) of the Agricultural Marketing Agreement Act of 1937, as amended (
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              sections 1-19, 48
            </aref>
             Stat. 31, as amended; 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='601-674' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/601-674.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 601-674
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ), or, upon conviction, a penalty in the amount prescribed in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 8c(14
            </aref>
            ) of said act, or to both such forfeiture and penalty. False
            representations to any agency of the United States on any matter
            within its jurisdiction, knowing it to be false, is a violation of 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='18' sect='1001' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/18/1001.html'>
                18 U.S.C. 1001
              </subref>
            </aref>
             which provides for a fine or imprisonment or both.
          </text>
        </P>
        <HD SOURCE='HD1'>
          Exhibit A
        </HD>
        <HD SOURCE='HD1'>
          grade requirements for shelled filberts
        </HD>
        <P>
          Filbert kernels or portions of filbert kernels shall meet the
          following requirements:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Well dried and clean;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Free from foreign material, mold, rancidity, decay or insect
            injury; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Free from serious damage caused by serious shriveling, or other
            means.
            <PRTPAGE P='697' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <HD SOURCE='HD1'>
          tolerances
        </HD>
        <P>
          In order to allow for variations incident to proper grading and
          handling the following tolerances, by weight, are permitted as
          specified:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For Foreign Material: 0.02 of one percent, for foreign material.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For Defects: Five percent for kernels or portions of kernels which
            are below the requirements of this grade, including not more than
            the following: Two percent for mold, rancidity, decay or insect
            injury: 
            <E T='03'>
              Provided,
            </E>
             That not more than one percent shall be for mold, rancidity, or
            insect injury.
          </text>
        </P>
        <HD SOURCE='HD1'>
          definitions
        </HD>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Well dried
            </E>
             means that the kernels are firm and crisp, not containing more than
            6 percent moisture.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Clean
            </E>
             means practically free from plainly visible adhering dirt or other
            foreign material.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Foreign material
            </E>
             means any substance other than the filbert kernels, or portions of
            kernels. (Loose skins, pellicles or corky tissue which have become
            separated from the kernels shall not be considered as foreign
            material, provided that this material does not exceed .02 of one
            percent by weight.)
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Serious damage
            </E>
             means any specific defect described in this section, or any equally
            objectionable variation of any one of these defects, or any other
            defects, or any combination of defects, which seriously detracts
            from the appearance or the edible or marketing quality of the
            individual portion of the kernel or of the lot as a whole. The
            following defects shall be considered as serious damage.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_4_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Serious shriveling
            </E>
             means when the kernel is seriously shrunken, wrinkled and tough.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_4_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Mold
            </E>
             means that there is a visible growth of mold either on the outside
            or inside of the kernel.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_4_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Rancidity
            </E>
             means that the kernel is noticeably rancid to the taste. An oily
            appearance of the flesh does not necessarily indicate a rancid
            condition.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_4_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Decay
            </E>
             means that any portion of the kernel is decomposed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_4_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Insect injury
            </E>
             means that the insect, frass or web is present, or the kernel or
            portion of kernel show definite evidence of insect feeding.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            42 FR 64899
          </aref>
          , Dec. 29, 1977, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            45 FR 63482
          </aref>
          , Sept. 25, 1980; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            47 FR 12612
          </aref>
          , Mar. 24, 1982; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            48 FR 34015
          </aref>
          , July 27, 1983; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            74 FR 2809
          </aref>
          , Jan. 16, 2009]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='10026'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:IX:-:999:-:999.500
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        999.500
      </num>
      <head>
        Safeguard procedures for walnuts, certain dates, and pistachios exempt
        from grade, size, quality, and maturity requirements.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          61 FR 13060
        </aref>
        , Mar. 26, 1996, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          77 FR 51690
        </aref>
        , Aug. 27, 2012]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='999' sect='500' psec='' tq='N'>
              999.500
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Safeguard procedures for walnuts, certain dates, and pistachios exempt
          from grade, size, quality, and maturity requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each person who imports or receives any of the commodities listed
            in paragraphs (a)(1) through (a)(3) of this section shall file an
            “Importer&apos;s Exempt Commodity Form” (FV-6) with the Marketing
            Order and Agreement Division, Fruit and Vegetable Programs, AMS,
            USDA, and shall provide a printed copy of the completed Form FV-6 to
            the U.S. Customs and Border Protection Regional Director or District
            Director, as applicable, at the port at which the customs entry is
            filed. A printed copy shall accompany the lot to the exempt outlet
            specified on the form. Any lot of any commodity offered for
            inspection or aflatoxin testing and, all or a portion thereof,
            subsequently imported as exempt under this provision shall also be
            reported on an “Importer&apos;s Exempt Commodity Form.” Such form,
            accompanied by a copy of the applicable inspection certificate,
            shall be provided to the Marketing Order and Agreement Division. The
            applicable commodities are:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Dates which are donated to needy persons, prisoners or Native
            Americans on reservations;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Walnuts which are: Green walnuts (so immature that they cannot be
            used for drying and sale as dried walnuts); walnuts used in
            non-competitive outlets such as use by charitable institutions,
            relief agencies, governmental agencies for school lunch programs,
            and diversion to animal feed or oil manufacture; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Substandard pistachios which are for non-human consumption
            purposes.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each person who receives an exempt commodity for the purposes
            specified in paragraph (a) of this section shall also receive a copy
            of the same numbered Importer&apos;s Exempt Commodity Form filed by
            the importer or customs broker and shall certify, by completing and
            signing Section II of 
            <PRTPAGE P='698' />
            the form and mailing the form to the Marketing Order Administration
            Branch within two days of receipt of the exempt lot, that such lot
            has been received and will be utilized in the exempt outlet.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             It is the responsibility of the importer to notify the Marketing
            Order Administration Branch of any lot of exempt commodity rejected
            by a receiver, shipped to an alternative exempt receiver, exported,
            or otherwise disposed of. In such cases, a second “Importer&apos;s
            Exempt Commodity Form” must be filed by the importer providing
            sufficient information to determine ultimate disposition of the
            exempt lot and such disposition shall be so certified by the final
            receiver.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All FV-6 forms and other correspondence regarding entry of 8e
            commodities must be submitted online, mailed or faxed to the
            Marketing Order and Agreement Division, Fruit and Vegetable
            Programs, AMS, USDA, 1400 Independence Avenue SW., STOP 0237,
            Washington, DC 20250-0237; Telephone (202) 720-4607; or FAX (202)
            720-5698. FV-6 forms submitted by FAX must be followed by a mailed,
            original copy of the FV-6.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            61 FR 13060
          </aref>
          , Mar. 26, 1996, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            77 FR 51690
          </aref>
          , Aug. 27, 2012]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='10027'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:IX:-:999:-:999.600
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        999.600
      </num>
      <head>
        Regulation governing the importation of pistachios.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          77 FR 51691
        </aref>
        , Aug. 27, 2012]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='999' sect='600' psec='' tq='N'>
              999.600
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Regulation governing the importation of pistachios.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Definitions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             As used in this part:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Aflatoxin
            </E>
             is one of a group of mycotoxins produced by the molds 
            <E T='03'>
              Aspergillus flavus
            </E>
             and 
            <E T='03'>
              Aspergillus parasiticus.
            </E>
             Aflatoxins are naturally occurring compounds produced by molds,
            which can be spread in improperly processed and stored nuts, dried
            fruits, and grains.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Aflatoxin inspection certificate
            </E>
             means a certificate issued by a USDA or USDA-accredited laboratory.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Certified lots of pistachios
            </E>
             are those for which aflatoxin inspection certificates have been
            issued.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Customs
            </E>
             means the U.S. Customs and Border Protection.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Importation of pistachios
            </E>
             means the release of pistachios from the custody of U.S. Customs
            and Border Protection.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Importer
            </E>
             means a person who engages in the importation of pistachios into
            the United States.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Inshell pistachios
            </E>
             means pistachios that have shells that have not been removed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Inspection Service
            </E>
             means the Federal Inspection Service, Fruit and Vegetable Programs,
            Agricultural Marketing Service, USDA, or the Federal-State
            Inspection Programs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Inspector
            </E>
             means any inspector authorized by USDA to draw and prepare
            pistachio samples.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Lot
            </E>
             means any quantity of pistachios that is submitted for testing
            purposes under this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_11'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (11)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Person
            </E>
             means an individual, partnership, limited-liability corporation,
            corporation, trust, association, or any other business unit.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_12'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (12)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Pistachio
            </E>
             means the nut of the pistachio tree, 
            <E T='03'>
              Pistachia vera,
            </E>
             whether inshell or shelled.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_13'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (13)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Secretary
            </E>
             means the Secretary of Agriculture of the United States or any
            officer or employee of the United States Department of Agriculture
            who is, or who may hereafter be, authorized to act in his/her stead.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_14'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (14)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Shelled pistachios
            </E>
             means pistachio kernels, or portions of kernels, after the
            pistachio shells have been removed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_15'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (15)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Substandard pistachios
            </E>
             means pistachios, inshell or shelled, that do not comply with the
            aflatoxin regulations of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_16'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (16)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              USDA
            </E>
             means the United States Department of Agriculture, including any
            officer, employee, service, program, or branch of the Department of
            Agriculture, or any other person acting as the Secretary&apos;s
            agent or representative in connection with any provisions of this
            section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_17'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (17)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              USDA laboratory
            </E>
             means laboratories of the Science and Technology Programs,
            Agricultural Marketing Service, USDA, that perform chemical analyses
            of pistachios for aflatoxin content.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_18'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (18)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              USDA-accredited laboratory
            </E>
             means a laboratory that has been approved or accredited by the U.S.
            Department of Agriculture to perform chemical analyses of pistachios
            for aflatoxin content.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Importation Requirements.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The importation of any lot of pistachios for human consumption is
            prohibited unless it meets the requirements contained in this
            section, which are determined to be the same as or comparable 
            <PRTPAGE P='699' />
            to those imposed upon domestic pistachios handled pursuant to Order
            No. 983, as amended (
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='983' tq='N'>
                983 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Maximum aflatoxin tolerance.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No importer shall ship for domestic human consumption lots of
            pistachios that exceed an aflatoxin level of 15 ppb. Compliance with
            the aflatoxin requirements of this section shall be determined upon
            the basis of sampling by a USDA-authorized inspector and testing by
            a USDA or USDA-accredited laboratory. All shipments must be covered
            by an aflatoxin inspection certificate issued by the laboratory.
            Testing and certification must be completed prior to the importation
            of pistachios.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Sampling.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Prior to, or upon, arrival of a pistachio lot at a port of entry,
            the importer shall provide a copy of the Customs entry documentation
            for the pistachio lot or lots to the Inspection Service office that
            will draw and prepare samples of the pistachio shipment. More than
            one lot may be listed on one entry document. The documentation shall
            include: The Customs entry number; the container number(s) or other
            identification of the lot(s); the weight of the pistachios in each
            lot being imported, the location where the lot will be made
            available for sampling; and a contact name or telephone number at
            the testing location. The Inspection Service shall sign, stamp, and
            return the entry document to the importer. The importer shall
            provide a copy of the relevant entry documentation and such other
            identifying information as may be requested for each pistachio lot
            to the inspector at the time samples are drawn and prepared.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All sampling for aflatoxin testing shall be performed by
            USDA-authorized inspectors in accordance with USDA rules and
            regulations governing the inspection and certification of fresh
            fruits, vegetables, and other products (
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='51' tq='N'>
                51
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ). The cost of each such sampling and related certification shall be
            borne by the applicant. Whenever pistachios are offered for sampling
            and testing, the applicant shall furnish any labor and pay any costs
            incurred for storing, moving, and opening containers as may be
            necessary for proper sampling and testing. The applicant should make
            advance arrangements with the Inspection Service to avoid delay in
            scheduling sampling. Importers may make arrangements for required
            sampling by contacting the Inspection Service office closest to
            where the pistachios will be made available for sampling. For
            questions regarding inspection services, a list of Federal or
            Federal-State Inspection Program offices, or for further assistance,
            importers may contact: Fresh Products Branch, Fruit and Vegetable
            Programs, AMS, USDA, 1400 Independence Avenue SW., Room 1536-S,
            Washington, DC, 20250; Telephone: (202) 720-5870; Fax: (202)
            720-0393.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Lot samples shall be drawn from each lot of pistachios designated
            for aflatoxin testing, and individual test samples shall be prepared
            by, or under the supervision of, an inspector. Each sample shall be
            drawn and prepared in accordance with the sample size requirements
            outlined in Tables 1 and 2 below. The gross weight of the inshell
            lot and test samples for aflatoxin testing and the minimum number of
            incremental samples required are shown in Table 1. The gross weight
            of the kernel lot and test samples for aflatoxin testing and the
            minimum number of incremental samples required is shown in Table 2.
            If more than one test sample is necessary, the test samples shall be
            designated by the inspector as Test Sample #1 and Test Sample #2.
            Each sample shall be placed in a suitable container, with the lot
            number clearly identified, and the importer shall submit it, along
            with a copy of the customs entry documentation, to a USDA or
            USDA-accredited laboratory. The importer shall assume all costs for
            shipping samples to the laboratory.
          </text>
        </P>
        <table class='gpotable' CDEF='s50,14,14,14' COLS='4' OPTS='L2'>
          <caption>
            <div>
              <strong>
                Table 1—Inshell Pistachio Lot Sampling Increments for Aflatoxin
                Certification
              </strong>
            </div>
          </caption>
          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th>
                Lot weight
                <LI>
                  (lbs.)
                </LI>
              </th>
              <th>
                Minimum number of incremental samples for the lot sample
              </th>
              <th>
                Total weight of lot sample
                <LI>
                  (kilograms)
                </LI>
              </th>
              <th>
                Weight of test sample
                <LI>
                  (kilograms)
                </LI>
              </th>
            </tr>
          </thead>
          <tfoot />
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                220 or less
              </td>
              <td>
                10
              </td>
              <td>
                2.0
              </td>
              <td>
                2.0
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                221-440
              </td>
              <td>
                15
              </td>
              <td>
                3.0
              </td>
              <td>
                3.0
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                441-1,100
              </td>
              <td>
                20
              </td>
              <td>
                4.0
              </td>
              <td>
                4.0
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                1,101-2,200
              </td>
              <td>
                30
              </td>
              <td>
                6.0
              </td>
              <td>
                6.0
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                2,201-4,400
              </td>
              <td>
                40
              </td>
              <td>
                8.0
              </td>
              <td>
                8.0
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                4,401-11,000
              </td>
              <td>
                60
              </td>
              <td>
                12.0
              </td>
              <td>
                6.0
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                11,001-22,000
              </td>
              <td>
                80
              </td>
              <td>
                16.0
              </td>
              <td>
                8.0
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                22,001-150,000
              </td>
              <td>
                100
              </td>
              <td>
                20.0
              </td>
              <td>
                10.0
              </td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>
        <table class='gpotable' CDEF='s50,14,14,14' COLS='4' OPTS='L2'>
          <caption>
            <div>
              <strong>
                Table 2—Shelled Pistachio Kernel Lot Sampling Increments for
                Aflatoxin Certification
              </strong>
            </div>
          </caption>
          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th>
                Lot weight
                <LI>
                  (lbs.)
                </LI>
              </th>
              <th>
                Minimum number of incremental samples for the lot sample
              </th>
              <th>
                Total weight of lot sample
                <LI>
                  (kilograms)
                </LI>
              </th>
              <th>
                Weight of test sample
                <LI>
                  (kilograms)
                </LI>
              </th>
            </tr>
          </thead>
          <tfoot />
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                220 or less
              </td>
              <td>
                10
              </td>
              <td>
                1.0
              </td>
              <td>
                1.0
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                221-440
              </td>
              <td>
                15
              </td>
              <td>
                1.5
              </td>
              <td>
                1.5
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                441-1,100
              </td>
              <td>
                20
              </td>
              <td>
                2.0
              </td>
              <td>
                2.0
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                1,101-2,200
              </td>
              <td>
                30
              </td>
              <td>
                3.0
              </td>
              <td>
                3.0
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                2,201-4,400
              </td>
              <td>
                40
              </td>
              <td>
                4.0
              </td>
              <td>
                4.0
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                4,401-11,000
              </td>
              <td>
                60
              </td>
              <td>
                6.0
              </td>
              <td>
                3.0
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                11,001-22,000
              </td>
              <td>
                80
              </td>
              <td>
                8.0
              </td>
              <td>
                4.0
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                22,001-150,000
              </td>
              <td>
                100
              </td>
              <td>
                10.0
              </td>
              <td>
                5.0
              </td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Aflatoxin testing.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Importers may make arrangements for required chemical analysis for
            aflatoxin content at the nearest USDA or USDA-accredited laboratory.
            For further information concerning chemical analysis and a list of
            laboratories authorized to conduct such analysis contact: Science
            and Technology Programs, AMS, USDA, 1400 Independence Avenue SW.,
            STOP 0270, Washington, DC 20250-0270; Telephone: (202) 720-5231;
            Fax: (202) 720-6496.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Aflatoxin test samples shall be received and logged by a USDA or
            USDA-accredited laboratory, and each test sample shall be prepared
            and analyzed using High Pressure Liquid Chromatography (HPLC) or the
            AOAC-approved immunoaffinity column with direct fluorometry method.
            The aflatoxin level shall be calculated on a kernel weight basis.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Lots that require a single test sample will be certified as
            “negative” on the aflatoxin inspection certificate if the sample has
            an aflatoxin level at or below 15 ppb. If the aflatoxin level is
            above 15 ppb, the lot fails and the laboratory shall fill out an 
            <E T='03'>
              Imported Pistachios—Failed Lot Notification
            </E>
             report (Form FV-249) as described in paragraph (h)(1) of this
            section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Lots that require two test samples will be certified as “negative”
            on the aflatoxin inspection certificate if Test Sample #1 has an
            aflatoxin level at or below 10 ppb. If the aflatoxin level of Test
            Sample #1 is above 20 ppb, the lot fails and the laboratory shall
            fill out an 
            <E T='03'>
              Imported Pistachios—Failed Lot Notification
            </E>
             report (Form FV-249). If the aflatoxin level of Test Sample #1 is
            above 10 ppb and at or below 20 ppb, the laboratory may, at the
            importer&apos;s discretion, analyze Test Sample #2 and average the
            test results of Test Samples #1 and #2. Alternately, the importer
            may elect to withdraw the lot from testing, rework the lot, and
            resubmit it for testing after reworking. If the importer directs the
            laboratory to proceed with the analysis of Test Sample #2, a lot
            will be certified as negative to aflatoxin and the laboratory shall
            issue an aflatoxin inspection certificate if the averaged result of
            Test Samples #1 and #2 is at or below 15 ppb. If the average
            aflatoxin level of Test Samples #1 and #2 is above 15 ppb, the lot
            fails and the laboratory shall fill out an 
            <E T='03'>
              Imported Pistachios—Failed Lot Notification
            </E>
             report (Form FV-249).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If an importer does not elect to use Test Sample #2 for
            certification 
            <PRTPAGE P='701' />
            purposes, the importer may request that the laboratory return the
            sample to the importer.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Certification.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each lot of pistachios sampled and tested in accordance with
            paragraphs (d) and (e) of this section shall be covered by an
            aflatoxin inspection certificate completed by the laboratory. The
            certification expires for the lot or remainder of the lot after 12
            months. Each such certificate shall set forth the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The date and place of sampling and testing.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The name of the applicant.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Customs entry number pertaining to the lot or shipment covered
            by the certificate.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The quantity and identifying marks of the lot tested.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The aflatoxin level of the lot, stated on a kernel weight basis.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The statement, if applicable: “Meets U.S. import requirements under
            
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 8e of
            </aref>
             the AMA Act of 1937.”
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the lot fails to meet the import requirements, a statement to
            that effect and the reasons therefore.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Failed lots/rework procedure.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any lot or portion thereof that fails to meet the import
            requirements prior to or after reconditioning may be exported, sold
            for non-human consumption, or disposed of under the supervision of
            Customs and, if necessary for verification purposes, the Federal or
            Federal-State Inspection Programs, with the costs of certifying the
            disposal of such lot paid by the importer.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Inshell rework procedure for aflatoxin.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If inshell rework is selected as a remedy to meet the aflatoxin
            requirements of this part, then 100 percent of the product within
            that lot shall be removed from the bulk and/or retail packaging
            containers and reworked to remove the portion of the lot that caused
            the failure. Reworking shall consist of mechanical, electronic, or
            manual procedures normally used in the handling of pistachios. After
            the rework procedure has been completed, the total weight of the
            accepted product and the total weight of the rejected product shall
            be reported by the importer to Customs and USDA on an 
            <E T='03'>
              Imported Pistachios—Rework and Failed Lot Disposition
            </E>
             report (Form FV-251) as described in paragraph (h)(2) of this
            section. The reworked lot shall be sampled and tested for aflatoxin
            as specified in paragraphs (d) and (e) of this section, except that
            the lot sample size and the test sample size shall be doubled. If,
            after the lot has been reworked and tested, it fails the aflatoxin
            test for a second time, the lot may be shelled and the kernels
            reworked, sampled, and tested in the manner specified for an
            original lot of kernels, or the failed lot may be exported, used for
            non-human consumption, or otherwise disposed of.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Kernel rework procedure for aflatoxin.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If pistachio kernel rework is selected as a remedy to meet the
            aflatoxin requirements of this part, then 100 percent of the product
            within that lot shall be removed from the bulk and/or retail
            packaging containers and reworked to remove the portion of the lot
            that caused the failure. Reworking shall consist of mechanical,
            electronic, or manual procedures normally used in the handling of
            pistachios. After the rework procedure has been completed the total
            weight of the accepted product and the total weight of the rejected
            product shall be reported to Customs and USDA on an 
            <E T='03'>
              Imported Pistachios—Rework and Failed Lot Disposition
            </E>
             report (Form FV-251). The reworked lot shall be sampled and tested
            for aflatoxin as specified in paragraphs (d) and (e) of this
            section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Failed lot reporting.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a lot fails to meet the aflatoxin requirements of this part, the
            testing laboratory shall complete an 
            <E T='03'>
              Imported Pistachios—Failed Lot Notification
            </E>
             report (Form FV-249) as described in paragraph (h)(1) of this
            section, and shall submit it to Customs, the importer, and USDA
            within 10 working days of the test failure. This form must be
            completed and submitted each time a lot fails aflatoxin testing.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Reports and Recordkeeping.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Form FV-249 Imported Pistachios—Failed Lot Notification.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each USDA or USDA-accredited laboratory shall notify the importer;
            Customs; and the Marketing Order and Agreement Division, Fruit and
            Vegetable Programs, AMS, USDA; of all lots that fail to meet the
            maximum aflatoxin requirements by completing this form and
            submitting it within 10 days of failed aflatoxin testing.
            <PRTPAGE P='702' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Form FV-251 Imported Pistachios—Rework and Failed Lot Disposition.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each importer who reworks a failing lot of pistachios shall
            complete this report and shall forward it to Customs and the
            Marketing Order and Agreement Division, Fruit and Vegetable
            Programs, AMS, USDA, no later than 10 days after the rework is
            completed. If rework is not selected as a remedy, the importer shall
            complete and submit this form within 10 days of alternate
            disposition of the lot.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Exemptions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any importer may import pistachios free of the requirements of this
            section if such importer imports a quantity not exceeding a total of
            5,000 dried pounds between September 1 and August 31 of each year.
            Substandard pistachios imported for use in non-human consumption
            outlets shall be subject to the safeguard provisions contained in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='999' sect='500' psec='' tq='N'>
                999.500
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Reconditioning prior to importation.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Nothing contained in this section shall be deemed to preclude
            reconditioning pistachios prior to importation, in order that such
            pistachios may be made eligible to meet the applicable aflatoxin
            regulations prescribed in paragraphs (c) through (f) of this
            section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Comingling.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Certified lots of pistachios may be comingled with other certified
            lots, but the comingling of certified lots and uncertified lots
            shall cause the loss of certification for the comingled lots.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='l'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (l)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Retesting.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whenever USDA has reason to believe that imported pistachios may
            have been damaged or deteriorated while in storage, USDA may reject
            the then effective inspection certificate and may require the owner
            of the pistachios to have them retested to establish whether or not
            such pistachios may be shipped for human consumption.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='m'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (m)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Compliance.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any person who violates any provision of this section shall be
            subject to a forfeiture in the amount prescribed in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 8a(5
            </aref>
            ) of the Agricultural Marketing Agreement Act of 1937, as amended (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='601-674' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/601-674.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 601-674
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ), or, upon conviction, a penalty in the amount prescribed in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 8c(14
            </aref>
            ) of the said Act, or to both such forfeiture and penalty. False
            representation to any agency of the United States on any matter
            within its jurisdiction, knowing it to be false, is a violation of 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='18' sect='1001' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/18/1001.html'>
                18 U.S.C. 1001
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , which provides for a fine or imprisonments or both.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='n'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (n)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Other import requirements.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The provisions of this section do not supersede any restrictions or
            prohibitions on pistachios under the Federal Plant Quarantine Act of
            1912, or any other applicable laws or regulations of city, county,
            State, or Federal Agencies including the Federal Food, Drug and
            Cosmetic Act.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            77 FR 51691
          </aref>
          , Aug. 27, 2012]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>