<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol2'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:A:36
    </extid>
    <num>
      36
    </num>
    <head>
      PROCEDURES BY WHICH THE AGRICULTURAL MARKETING SERVICE DEVELOPS, REVISES,
      SUSPENDS, OR TERMINATES VOLUNTARY OFFICIAL GRADE STANDARDS
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='1621-162' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1621-162.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 1621-162
            </subref>
          </aref>
          7.
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            62 FR 43439
          </aref>
          , Aug. 13, 1997, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='1926'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:A:36:-:36.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        36.1
      </num>
      <head>
        General information.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='36' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              36.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General information.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The Agricultural Marketing Service (AMS or agency) of the U.S.
          Department of Agriculture (USDA) facilitates the fair and efficient
          marketing of agricultural products by promulgating voluntary official
          grade standards for dairy, fresh and processed fruits and vegetables,
          livestock, meats and meat products, eggs, poultry and rabbit products,
          tobacco, wool, mohair, and other agricultural products. AMS standards
          provide a uniform language for describing the quality of various
          agricultural commodities in the marketplace. These standards may cover
          (but are not limited to) terms, classes, sizes (including quantities
          of packaged consumer agricultural commodities), dimensions,
          capacities, quality levels, performance criteria, inspection
          requirements, marking requirements, testing equipment, test
          procedures, and installation procedures.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Grade standards are officially designated as U.S. Grade Standards
            and the AMS assigns each grade standard an appropriate
            identification number. AMS develops, revises, suspends, or
            terminates official grade standards under procedures that allows for
            input by interested parties.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             These procedures set forth the process by which AMS will develop,
            revise, suspend, or terminate the U.S. standards.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Communications about AMS standards in general should be addressed
            to the Administrator, Attention: Functional Committee for Standards.
            Communications about specific standards (such as a request to
            develop or revise a standard) should be addressed to the Director of
            the appropriate Division (Dairy, Fruit and Vegetable, Livestock and
            Seed, Poultry, or Tobacco). All communications should include in the
            address: Agricultural Marketing Service, U.S. Department of
            Agriculture, P.O. Box 96456, Washington, DC 20090-6456.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='1927'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:A:36:-:36.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        36.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Initiating action on grade standards.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='36' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              36.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Initiating action on grade standards.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The Agency will develop, revise, suspend, or terminate grade standards
          if it determines that such action is in the public interest. Any
          standardization action should reflect the broad interest of
          individuals or an industry involved in manufacturing, producing,
          packaging, distributing, testing, consuming, or using the product; or
          the interest of a Federal, State, or local agency. Proposed actions
          should always be based on sound technical and marketing information
          and should include careful consideration of the factors that determine
          a commodity&apos;s quality and condition and that will allow trained
          personnel to determine objectively conformance or non-conformance.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             AMS encourages interested parties to participate in the review,
            development, and revision of grade standards. Interested parties
            include growers, producers, processors, shippers, distributors,
            consumers, individuals or groups, trade associations, companies, 
            <PRTPAGE P='181' />
            and State or Federal agencies. Such groups and individuals may at
            any time recommend that AMS develop, revise suspend, or terminate a
            grade standard. Requests for Agency action should be in writing,
            preferably accompanied by a draft of the suggested change.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Agency, in cooperation with interested parties, as applicable,
            will:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Determine the need for new or revised standards;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Collect technical, marketing, or other appropriate data;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Conduct research regarding new or revised standards, as
            appropriate; and,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Draft the proposed standards;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             [Reserved]
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the Agency determines that new standards are needed, existing
            standards need to be revised, or the suspension or termination of
            existing standards is justified, it will undertake the action, with
            input from all interested parties.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='1928'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:A:36:-:36.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        36.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Public notification of grade standards action.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='36' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              36.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Public notification of grade standards action.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          After developing a standardization proposal, the Agency will publish a
          notice in the 
          <E T='04'>
            Federal Register
          </E>
           describing new or changes to existing standards or to suspend or
          terminate existing standards. AMS will simultaneously issue a news
          release about these actions. AMS will also distribute copies of the
          full text of the proposals to anyone requesting a copy or to anyone
          the Agency believes may be interested, including other Federal, State,
          or local government agencies, and on the Internet. For other than
          minor editorial or technical changes, the notice will provide at least
          60 days for interested parties to submit comments to the Agency.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All comments received within the comment period will be part of the
            public record maintained by the Agency, will be available to the
            public for review, and will be considered by the Agency before final
            action is taken on the proposal.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Based on the comments received, the Agency&apos;s knowledge of
            standards, grading, marketing, and other technical factors, and any
            other relevant information AMS will decide whether the proposed
            actions should be implemented.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If AMS concludes that the actions as proposed or with minor
            modifications should be adopted, AMS will publish a description of
            the changes or actions in a 
            <E T='04'>
              Federal Register
            </E>
             notice. The Agency, through the appropriate AMS Divisions, will
            make the grade standards and related information available in
            printed form and electronic media.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the Agency determines that proposed changes are not warranted,
            or otherwise are not in the public interest, the Agency will either
            publish in the 
            <E T='04'>
              Federal Register
            </E>
             a notice withdrawing the proposal, or will revise the proposal and
            again seek public input.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             [Reserved]
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>