<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol11'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1738
    </extid>
    <num>
      1738
    </num>
    <head>
      RURAL BROADBAND ACCESS LOANS AND LOAN GUARANTEES
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref target='_blank' title='Pub. L. 107-171' alt='Pub. L. 107-171' href='http://www.gpo.gov/fdsys/pkg/PLAW-107publ171/html/PLAW-107publ171.htm'>
            Pub. L. 107-171
          </aref>
          , 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='901' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/901.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 901
            </subref>
          </aref>
          <E T='03'>
            et seq.
          </E>
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 13785
          </aref>
          , Mar. 14, 2011, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='13986'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1738:A:1738.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1738.1
      </num>
      <head>
        Overview.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              1738.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Overview.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Rural Broadband Access Loan and Loan Guarantee Program
            furnishes loans and loan guarantees to provide funds for the costs
            of construction, improvement, or acquisition of facilities and
            equipment needed to provide service at the broadband lending speed
            in eligible rural areas. This part sets forth the general policies,
            eligibility requirements, types and terms of loans and loan
            guarantees, and program requirements under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 107-171' alt='Public Law 107-171' href='http://www.gpo.gov/fdsys/pkg/PLAW-107publ171/html/PLAW-107publ171.htm'>
              Public Law 107-171
            </aref>
             and 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='901' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/901.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 901
              </subref>
            </aref>
            <E T='03'>
              et seq.
            </E>
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Additional information and application materials regarding the
            Rural Broadband Access Loan and Loan Guarantee Program can be found
            on the Rural Development Web site.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13987'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1738:A:1738.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1738.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              1738.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The following definitions apply to 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1738' tq='N'>
                1738
              </subref>
            </aref>
            :
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Acquisition
          </E>
           means the purchase of assets by acquiring facilities, equipment,
          operations, licenses, or majority stock interest of one or more
          organizations. Stock acquisitions must be arms-length transactions.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Administrator
          </E>
           means the Administrator of the Rural Utilities Service (RUS), or the
          Administrator&apos;s designee.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Advance
          </E>
           means the transfer of loan funds from the Agency to the borrower.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Affiliate
          </E>
           or 
          <E T='03'>
            affiliated company
          </E>
           of any specified person or entity means any other person or entity
          directly or indirectly controlling of, controlled by, under direct or
          indirect common control with, or related to, such specified entity, or
          which exists for the sole purpose of providing any service to one
          company or exclusively to companies which otherwise meet the
          definition of affiliate. This definition includes Variable Interest
          Entities as described in Financial Accounting Standards Board
          Interpretation (FIN) No. 46(R), 
          <E T='03'>
            Consolidation of Variable Interest Entities.
          </E>
           For the purpose of this definition, “control” means the possession
          directly or indirectly, of the power to direct or cause the direction
          of the management and policies of a company, whether such power is
          exercised through one or more intermediary companies, or alone, or in
          conjunction with or pursuant to an agreement with, one or more other
          companies, and whether such power is established through a majority or
          minority ownership voting of securities, common directors, officers,
          or stockholders, voting trust, or holding trusts (other than money
          exchanged) for property or services.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Agency
          </E>
           means the Rural Utilities Service, which administers the United
          States Department of Agriculture&apos;s (USDA&apos;s) Rural
          Development Utilities Programs, including the Rural Broadband Access
          Loan and Loan Guarantee Program.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Applicant
          </E>
           means an entity requesting approval of a loan or loan guarantee under
          this part.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Arm&apos;s-length transaction
          </E>
           means a transaction between two related or affiliated parties that is
          conducted as if they were unrelated, so that there is no question of
          conflict of interest, or a transaction between two otherwise unrelated
          or unaffiliated parties.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Borrower
          </E>
           means any organization that has an outstanding broadband or
          telecommunications loan made or guaranteed by the Agency.
          <PRTPAGE P='346' />
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Broadband borrower
          </E>
           means any organization that has an outstanding broadband loan made or
          guaranteed by the Agency.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Broadband grant
          </E>
           means a Community Connect or Broadband Initiatives Program grant
          approved by the Agency.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Broadband lending speed
          </E>
           means the minimum bandwidth requirement, as published by the Agency
          in its latest notice in the 
          <E T='04'>
            Federal Register
          </E>
           that an applicant must propose to deliver to every customer in the
          proposed funded service area in order for the Agency to approve a
          broadband loan and may be different for fixed and mobile broadband
          service. Broadband lending speed may be different from the minimum
          rate of data transmission required to determine the availability of
          broadband service when qualifying a service area. If a new broadband
          lending speed is published in the 
          <E T='04'>
            Federal Register
          </E>
           while an application is pending, the pending application may be
          returned unless the proposed broadband system can provide service at
          the new broadband lending speed. Returned applications will lose their
          place in the processing queue.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Broadband loan
          </E>
           means any loan approved under Title VI of the Rural Electrification
          Act of 1936 (RE Act).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Broadband service
          </E>
           means any technology identified by the Administrator as having the
          capacity to provide transmission facilities that enable the subscriber
          to the service to originate and receive high-quality voice, data,
          graphics, and video. The Agency will publish the minimum rate of data
          transmission that will qualify as broadband service in a notice in the
          
          <E T='04'>
            Federal Register
          </E>
           and this rate may be different for fixed and mobile broadband
          service. The minimum rate of data transmission that defines broadband
          service may be different than the broadband lending speed. If a new
          minimum rate of data transmission is published in the 
          <E T='04'>
            Federal Register
          </E>
           while an application is pending, broadband service for the purpose of
          reviewing the application will be defined by the minimum rate of data
          transmission that was required at the time the application was
          received by the Agency.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Build-out
          </E>
           means the construction, improvement, or acquisition of facilities and
          equipment.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Competitive analysis
          </E>
           means a study that identifies service providers and products in the
          service area that will compete with the applicant&apos;s proposed
          project.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Composite economic life
          </E>
           means the weighted (by dollar amount of each class of facility in the
          loan) average economic life as determined by the Agency of all classes
          of facilities financed by the loan.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Cost share
          </E>
           means equity, as defined by generally accepted accounting principles
          (GAAP).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Customer premises equipment
          </E>
           (CPE), in the context of network services, means any network-related
          equipment (
          <E T='03'>
            e.g.
          </E>
           routers, switches, modems, etc.) used by a customer to connect to a
          service provider&apos;s network.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Derivative
          </E>
           means any right, interest, instrument or security issued or traded on
          the credit of the guaranteed loan or any guaranteed loan portion,
          including but not limited to any participation share of, or undivided
          ownership or other equity interest in, the guaranteed loan or any
          guaranteed loan portion; any note, bond or other debt instrument or
          obligation which is collateralized or otherwise secured by a pledge
          of, or security interest in, the guaranteed loan or any guaranteed
          loan portion; or any such interest in such an interest or any such
          instrument secured by such an instrument.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Economic life
          </E>
           means the estimated useful service life of an asset financed by the
          loan, as determined by the Agency.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Equity
          </E>
           means total assets minus total liabilities, as determined by GAAP and
          as classified according to the Agency&apos;s system of accounts and as
          used in this Part for purposes of 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 306F of
          </aref>
           the RE Act includes the requirements of credit support and cost share
          in Title VI of the RE Act.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Feasibility study
          </E>
           means the evaluation of the pro forma financial analysis prepared by
          the Agency, based on the financial projections supplied by the
          applicant and as found acceptable by the Agency, to determine the
          financial feasibility of a loan request. Financial feasibility will be
          based on the entire 
          <PRTPAGE P='347' />
          operation of the applicant and not limited to the funded project.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Financial feasibility
          </E>
           means the applicant&apos;s ability to generate sufficient revenues to
          cover its expenses, sufficient cash flow to service its debts and
          obligations as they come due, and meet the minimum Times Interest
          Earned Ratio (TIER) requirement of 1.25 (see 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='211' psec='#b_2_ii' tq='N'>
              1738.211(b)(2)(ii)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ) by the end of the forecast period, as evaluated by the Agency.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Fiscal year
          </E>
           refers to the applicant or borrower&apos;s fiscal year, unless
          otherwise indicated.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Forecast period
          </E>
           means the time period used in the feasibility study to determine if
          an application is financially feasible. Financial feasibility of a
          loan application is based on five-year projections.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Funded service area
          </E>
           means the geographic area within which an applicant proposes to offer
          service at the broadband lending speed using loan funds. (See also
          “service area.”)
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            GAAP
          </E>
           means generally accepted accounting principles.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Guaranteed-amount debt derivative
          </E>
           means any note, bond, or other debt instrument or obligation which is
          collateralized or otherwise secured by a pledge of, or security
          interest in, the guaranteed loan note or any guaranteed loan portion
          note or any derivative, as the case may be, which has an exclusive or
          preferred claim to the guaranteed loan amount or the respective
          guaranteed loan portion amount or the respective guaranteed-amount
          equivalent, as the case may be.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Guaranteed-amount equity derivative
          </E>
           means any participation share of, or undivided ownership or other
          equity interest in, the guaranteed loan or any guaranteed loan portion
          or any derivative, as the case may be, which has an exclusive or
          preferred claim to the guaranteed loan amount or the respective
          guaranteed loan portion amount or the respective guaranteed-amount
          equivalent, as the case may be.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Guaranteed-amount equivalent
          </E>
           means, with respect to any derivative which is equal in principal
          amount to the guaranteed loan or any guaranteed loan portion, that
          amount of payment on account of such derivative which is equal to the
          guaranteed loan amount or the respective guaranteed loan portion
          amount, as the case may be; or with respect to any derivative which in
          the aggregate are equal in principal amount to the guaranteed loan or
          any guaranteed loan portion, that amount of payment on account of such
          derivatives which is equal to the guaranteed loan amount or the
          respective guaranteed loan portion amount, as the case may be.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Guaranteed loan amount
          </E>
           means the amount of the loan which is guaranteed by the Agency.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Guaranteed loan note
          </E>
           means, collectively, the note or notes executed and delivered by the
          borrower to evidence the guaranteed loan.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Guaranteed loan portion
          </E>
           means any portion of the guaranteed loan.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Guaranteed loan portion amount
          </E>
           means that amount of payment on account of any guaranteed loan
          portion which is guaranteed under the terms of the guarantee.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Guaranteed loan portion note
          </E>
           means any note executed and delivered by the borrower to evidence a
          guaranteed loan portion.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Grantee
          </E>
           means any organization that has an outstanding broadband grant made
          by the Agency.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Incumbent service provider
          </E>
           (i) Means a service provider that:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='a_1_i_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Offers terrestrial broadband service in the proposed funded service
            area;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='a_1_i_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Has not less than five percent of the households in an
            applicant&apos;s proposed funded service area subscribing to their
            broadband service at the time of application submission; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='a_1_i_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provides this information to the Agency through a timely response
            to the public notice described in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='204' psec='' tq='N'>
                1738.204
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Resellers are not considered incumbent service providers. If an
            applicant proposes an acquisition, the applicant will be considered
            a service provider for that area.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Indefeasible right to use agreement
          </E>
           (IRU) means the effective long-term lease of the capacity, or a
          portion thereof, of a cable, specified in terms of a certain number of
          channels of a given bandwidth.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Interim financing
          </E>
           means funds used for eligible loan purposes after the applicant is
          notified by the Agency that the application is complete. Such funds 
          <PRTPAGE P='348' />
          may be eligible for reimbursement from loan funds if a loan is made.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Loan
          </E>
           means any loan made or guaranteed under this part by the Agency,
          unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Loan contract
          </E>
           means the loan agreement between the Agency and the borrower,
          including all amendments thereto.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Loan documents
          </E>
           means the loan agreement, note(s), and security instrument between
          the borrower and the Agency and any associated documents pertaining to
          the broadband loan.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Loan guarantee
          </E>
           means a loan made by another lender, some portion of which is
          guaranteed by the Agency.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Loan guarantee documents
          </E>
           means the guarantee agreement between RUS and the lender, the loan
          and security agreement(s) between the guaranteed lender and the
          borrower, the loan note guarantee made by RUS, the guaranteed loan
          note, and other security documents.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Loan funds
          </E>
           means funds provided pursuant to a broadband loan made or guaranteed
          under this part by the Agency.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Market survey
          </E>
           means the collection of information on the supply, demand, usage, and
          rates for proposed services to be offered by an applicant within each
          service area. It supports the applicant&apos;s financial projections.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Pre-loan expense
          </E>
           means any expense associated with the preparation of a loan
          application. Pre-loan expenses may be reimbursed with loan funds, as
          approved by RUS.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            RE Act
          </E>
           means the Rural Electrification Act of 1936, as amended (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='901' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/901.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 901
            </subref>
          </aref>
          <E T='03'>
            et seq.
          </E>
          ).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Reject
          </E>
           means that the Agency returns the application to the applicant and
          discontinues processing of the loan application because the
          application failed to meet the requirements set forth herein. If an
          application is rejected, the loan application loses its place in the
          application processing queue.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Reseller
          </E>
           means, in the context of network services, a company that purchases
          network services from network service providers in bulk and resells
          them to commercial businesses and residential households. Resellers
          are not considered incumbent service providers.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Rural area
          </E>
           means any area, as confirmed by the latest decennial census of the
          Bureau of the Census, which is not located within:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A city, town, or incorporated area that has a population of greater
            than 20,000 inhabitants; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An urbanized area contiguous and adjacent to a city or town that
            has a population of greater than 50,000 inhabitants. For purposes of
            the definition of rural area, an urbanized area means a densely
            populated territory as defined in the latest decennial census of the
            U.S. Census Bureau.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Security documents
          </E>
           means any mortgage, deed of trust, security agreement, financing
          statement, or other document which grants to the Agency or perfects a
          security interest, including any amendments and supplements thereto.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Service area
          </E>
           means the geographic area within which a service provider offers
          telecommunications service.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Service level objectives (SLOs)
          </E>
           means the characteristics of the service to be delivered to the
          customer, for example the speed with which new service will be
          established, service availability, and response time for reports of
          system failure at a residence.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Service provider
          </E>
           means an entity providing telecommunications service.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Service territory
          </E>
           means “service area.”
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Start-up
          </E>
           means a new business venture without operations or service delivery
          available.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            System of accounts
          </E>
           means the Agency&apos;s system of accounts for maintaining financial
          records as described in RUS Bulletin 1770B-1.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Telecommunications
          </E>
           means electronic transmission and reception of voice, data, video,
          and graphical information using wireline and wireless transmission
          media.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Telecommunications loan
          </E>
           means any telecommunication loan made or guaranteed under Title II,
          III, or IV of the RE Act.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            TIER
          </E>
           means times interest earned ratio. TIER is the ratio of an
          applicant&apos;s net income (after taxes) plus (adding back) interest
          expense, all divided by interest expense (existing and that required
          in the proposed loan), and with all financial terms defined by GAAP.
          <PRTPAGE P='349' />
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Underserved household or Underserved area
          </E>
           means a household or an area that is not offered broadband service,
          or that is offered broadband service by only one incumbent service
          provider.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Unguaranteed amount equivalent
          </E>
           means all amounts of payment on account of any derivative other than
          the respective guaranteed-amount equivalent.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Unguaranteed loan amount
          </E>
           means all amounts of payment on account of the guaranteed loan other
          than the guaranteed amount.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Unguaranteed loan portion amount
          </E>
           means all amounts of payment on account of any guaranteed loan
          portion other than the respective guaranteed loan portion amount.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Accounting terms not otherwise defined in this part shall have the
            definition ascribed to them under GAAP and shall be recorded using
            the Agency&apos;s system of accounts.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13988'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1738:A:1738.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1738.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Substantially underserved trust areas.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              1738.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Substantially underserved trust areas.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the Administrator determines that a community in “trust land”
            (as defined in 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 3765 of
            </aref>
             title 38, United States Code) has a high need for the benefits of
            the Broadband Loan Program, he/she may designate the community as a
            “substantially underserved trust area” (as defined in 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 306F of
            </aref>
             the RE Act).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In order to improve the availability of the Broadband Loan Program
            in communities in substantially underserved trust areas, the
            Administrator retains the discretion to
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Make available to qualified utilities or applicants, financing with
            an interest rate as low as 2 percent, and with extended repayment
            terms;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Waive nonduplication restrictions, matching fund and equity
            requirements, or credit support requirements; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Give the highest funding priority to designated projects in
            substantially underserved trust areas.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Administrator will only make loans and loan guarantees that RUS
            finds are financially feasible and that provide eligible program
            benefits to substantially underserved trust areas.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Applicants should notify the National Office before preparing their
            applications that they are planning to seek waivers or adjustments
            based on this section (see 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='201' psec='' tq='N'>
                1738.201
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13989'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1738:A:1738.4-1738.50
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1738.4-1738.50
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='4-1738' psec='' tq='N'>
              1738.4-1738
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .50
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13990'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1738:B:1738.51
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1738.51
      </num>
      <head>
        Eligible loan purposes.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='51' psec='' tq='N'>
              1738.51
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Eligible loan purposes.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Loan funds may be used to pay for the following expenses:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To fund the construction, improvement, or acquisition of all
            facilities required to provide service at the broadband lending
            speed to rural areas, including facilities required for providing
            other services over the same facilities.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To fund the cost of leasing facilities required to provide service
            at the broadband lending speed if such lease qualifies as a capital
            lease under GAAP. Notwithstanding, loan funds can only be used to
            fund the cost of the capital lease for no more than the first three
            years of the loan amortization period.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To fund an acquisition, provided that:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The acquisition is necessary for furnishing or improving service at
            the broadband lending speed;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The acquired service area, if any, meets the eligibility
            requirements set forth in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='102' psec='' tq='N'>
                1738.102
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The acquisition cost does not exceed 50 percent of the broadband
            loan amount; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For the acquisition of another entity, the purchase provides the
            applicant with a controlling majority interest in the entity
            acquired.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To refinance an outstanding telecommunications loan made under the
            RE Act if refinancing the loan supports the construction,
            improvement, or acquisition of facilities and equipment for the
            provision of service at the broadband lending speed in rural areas
            provided that:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No more than 40 percent of the broadband loan amount is used to
            refinance the outstanding telecommunications loan;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The applicant is current with its payments on the telecommunication
            loan(s) to be refinanced; and
            <PRTPAGE P='350' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The amortization period for that portion of the broadband loan that
            will be needed for refinancing will not exceed the remaining
            amortization period for the telecommunications loan(s) to be
            refinanced. If multiple notes are being refinanced, an average
            remaining amortization period will be calculated based on the
            weighted dollar average of the notes being refinanced.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To fund pre-loan expenses in an amount not to exceed five percent
            of the broadband loan excluding amounts requested to refinance
            outstanding telecommunication loans. Pre-loan expenses may be
            reimbursed only if they are incurred prior to the date on which
            notification of a complete application is issued (see 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='205' psec='' tq='N'>
                1738.205
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13991'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1738:B:1738.52
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1738.52
      </num>
      <head>
        Ineligible loan purposes.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='52' psec='' tq='N'>
              1738.52
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Ineligible loan purposes.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Loan funds must not be used for any of the following purposes:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To fund operating expenses of the applicant;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To fund costs incurred prior to the date on which notification of a
            complete application is issued (see 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='205' psec='' tq='N'>
                1738.205
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ), with the exception of eligible pre-loan expenses (see
            1738.51(e)).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To fund the acquisition of the stock of an affiliate.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To fund the purchase or acquisition of any facilities or equipment
            of an affiliate, unless approved by the Agency in writing. The
            Agency may approve such a purchase or acquisition if the applicant
            demonstrates that the purchase or acquisition will involve an
            arms-length transaction and that the cost is advantageous for the
            applicant.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To fund the purchase of CPE and the installation of associated
            inside wiring unless the CPE will be owned by the applicant
            throughout its economic life or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The applicant pledges additional collateral that is not currently
            owned by the applicant, acceptable to the Agency. Such collateral
            must have a value at least equal to the purchase price of the CPE
            and cannot be purchased with loan funds; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The applicant establishes a revolving fund for the initial purchase
            of CPE to be sold, and as CPE is sold to the customer, at least the
            applicant&apos;s cost of such equipment is returned to the revolving
            fund and used to purchase additional CPE units.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To fund the purchase or lease of any vehicle unless it is used
            primarily in construction or system improvements.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To fund the cost of systems or facilities that have not been
            designed and constructed in accordance with the loan contract and
            other applicable requirements.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To fund broadband facilities leased under the terms of an operating
            lease.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To fund merger or consolidation of entities.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13992'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1738:B:1738.53-1738.100
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1738.53-1738.100
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='53-1738' psec='' tq='N'>
              1738.53-1738
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .100
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13993'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1738:C:1738.101
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1738.101
      </num>
      <head>
        Eligible applicants.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='101' psec='' tq='N'>
              1738.101
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Eligible applicants.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be eligible for a broadband loan, an applicant may be either a
            nonprofit or for-profit organization, and must take one of the
            following forms:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Corporation;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Limited liability company (LLC);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Cooperative or mutual organization;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Indian tribe or tribal organization as defined in 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='25' sect='450b' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/25/450b.html'>
                25 U.S.C. 450b
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State or local government, including any agency, subdivision, or
            instrumentality thereof.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be eligible for a broadband loan, the applicant must:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Submit a loan application which meets the requirements set forth
            herein as well as any additional requirements published in the 
            <E T='04'>
              Federal Register
            </E>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Agree to complete the build-out of the broadband system described
            in the loan application within three years from the day the
            applicant is notified that loan funds are available. The loan
            application must demonstrate that all proposed construction be
            completed within this three year period with the exception of CPE.
            CPE can be funded throughout the forecast period;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Demonstrate an ability to furnish, improve, or extend broadband
            facilities to provide service at the broadband lending speed in
            rural areas;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Demonstrate an equity position equal to at least 10 percent of the 
            <PRTPAGE P='351' />
            amount of the loan requested in the application (see 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='207' psec='' tq='N'>
                1738.207
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ); and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provide additional security if it is necessary to ensure financial
            feasibility (see 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='208' psec='' tq='N'>
                1738.208
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) as determined by the Administrator.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13994'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1738:C:1738.102
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1738.102
      </num>
      <head>
        Eligible service area.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='102' psec='' tq='N'>
              1738.102
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Eligible service area.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A service area may be eligible for a broadband loan if all of the
            following are true:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The service area is completely contained within a rural area;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             At least 25 percent of the households in the service area are
            underserved households;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No part of the service area has three or more incumbent service
            providers;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No part of the funded service area overlaps with the service area
            of current RUS borrowers and grantees;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No part of the funded service area is included in a pending
            application before RUS seeking funding to provide broadband service.
            If two or more applications are submitted for the same service area,
            a lending decision must be made on the application that was
            submitted to the Agency first before a lending decision can be made
            on the other application(s).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Multiple service areas may be included in a single broadband loan
            application. Non-contiguous areas are considered separate service
            areas and must be treated separately for the purpose of determining
            service area eligibility. If non-contiguous areas within an
            application are determined to be ineligible, the Agency may pursuant
            to this regulation consider the remaining areas in the application.
            If an applicant fails to respond to agency requests for additional
            information or modifications to remove ineligible areas, the
            application may be returned and the application will lose its place
            in the processing queue.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13995'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1738:C:1738.103
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1738.103
      </num>
      <head>
        Eligible service area exceptions for broadband facility upgrades.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='103' psec='' tq='N'>
              1738.103
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Eligible service area exceptions for broadband facility upgrades.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Broadband borrowers that apply to upgrade existing broadband
            facilities in its existing service area are exempt from the
            requirement concerning the number of underserved households in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='102' psec='#b_2' tq='N'>
                1738.102(b)(2)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Incumbent service providers, including borrowers and grantees,
            which apply to upgrade existing broadband facilities in existing
            service territories are exempt from the requirement concerning the
            number of incumbent service providers in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='102' psec='#b_3' tq='N'>
                1738.102(b)(3)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             unless they are eligible for funding under Titles II and III of the
            RE Act. Eligibility requirements for entities that would be eligible
            under Titles II and III can be found in 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1735' tq='N'>
                1735
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An applicant which is a borrower, grantee or incumbent service
            provider may submit one application to upgrade existing broadband
            facilities in existing service areas, which qualify for the
            exemptions specified in paragraphs (a) and (b) of this section, and
            to expand services at the broadband lending speed into new service
            areas, provided the upgrade area and the expansion area are proposed
            as two separate service areas even if the upgrade and expansion
            areas are contiguous.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The applicant will be asked to remove areas determined to be
            ineligible from their funding request. The application will then be
            evaluated on the basis of what remains. The applicant may be
            requested to provide additional information to the agency relating
            to the ineligible areas. If the applicant fails to respond, the
            application will be returned and the application will lose its place
            in the processing queue.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13996'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1738:C:1738.104
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1738.104
      </num>
      <head>
        Preliminary assessment of service area eligibility.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='104' psec='' tq='N'>
              1738.104
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Preliminary assessment of service area eligibility.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Agency will make information available to prospective
            applicants to allow a preliminary assessment of a proposed service
            area&apos;s eligibility. At a minimum, the prospective applicant
            will be able to determine:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whether the proposed service area is located in a rural area;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whether the proposed service area overlaps with any part of a
            borrower&apos;s or grantee&apos;s service area; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whether the proposed service area overlaps with any part of a
            proposed service area in a pending application for a loan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A preliminary assessment of service area eligibility does not
            account for all eligibility factors, and the situation within a
            proposed service area may 
            <PRTPAGE P='352' />
            change between the preliminary assessment and application
            submission. A preliminary assessment indicating that a proposed
            service area may be eligible does not guarantee that the area will
            remain eligible at the time of application.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13997'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1738:C:1738.105-1738.150
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1738.105-1738.150
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='105-1738' psec='' tq='N'>
              1738.105-1738
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .150
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13998'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1738:D:1738.151
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1738.151
      </num>
      <head>
        General.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='151' psec='' tq='N'>
              1738.151
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Direct loans shall be in the form of a cost-of-money loan, a
            4-percent loan, or a combination of the two.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The amount of funds available for each type of loan, as well as
            maximum and minimum loan amounts, will be published in the 
            <E T='04'>
              Federal Register
            </E>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An applicant that provides telecommunications or broadband service
            to at least 20 percent of the households in the United States is
            limited to a loan amount that is no more than 15 percent of the
            funds available to the Broadband Loan Program for the Federal fiscal
            year.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13999'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1738:D:1738.152
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1738.152
      </num>
      <head>
        Interest rates.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='152' psec='' tq='N'>
              1738.152
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Interest rates.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Direct cost-of-money loans shall bear interest at a rate equal to
            the cost of borrowing to the Department of Treasury for obligations
            of comparable maturity. The applicable interest rate will be set at
            the time of each advance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             [Reserved]
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14000'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1738:D:1738.153
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1738.153
      </num>
      <head>
        Loan terms and conditions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='153' psec='' tq='N'>
              1738.153
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Loan terms and conditions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Terms and conditions of loans are set forth in a mortgage, note, and
          loan contract. Samples of the mortgage, note, and loan contract can be
          found on the Agency&apos;s Web site.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Unless requested to be shorter by the applicant, broadband loans
            must be repaid with interest within a period that, rounded to the
            nearest whole year, is equal to the expected composite economic life
            of the assets to be financed, as determined by the Agency based upon
            acceptable depreciation rates.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Loan advances are made at the request of the borrower. Principal
            payments for each advance are amortized over the remaining term of
            the loan and are due monthly. Principal payments will be deferred
            until one year after the date of the first advance of loan funds.
            Interest begins accruing when the advance is made and interest
            payments are due monthly, with no deferral period.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Borrowers are required to carry fidelity bond coverage. Generally
            this amount will be 15 percent of the loan amount, not to exceed $5
            million. The Agency may reduce the percentage required if it
            determines that the amount is not commensurate with the risk
            involved.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14001'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1738:D:1738.154
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1738.154
      </num>
      <head>
        Loan security.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='154' psec='' tq='N'>
              1738.154
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Loan security.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The broadband loan must be secured by the assets purchased with the
            loan funds, as well as all other assets of the applicant and any
            other signer of the loan documents except as provided in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='155' psec='' tq='N'>
                1738.155
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Agency must be given an exclusive first lien, in form and
            substance satisfactory to the Agency, on all of the applicant&apos;s
            property and revenues and such additional security as the Agency may
            require. The Agency may share its first lien position with another
            lender on a 
            <E T='03'>
              pari passu,
            </E>
             prorated basis if security arrangements are acceptable to the
            Agency.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Unless otherwise designated by the Agency, all property purchased
            with loan funds must be owned by the applicant.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the case of loans that include financing of facilities that do
            not constitute self-contained operating systems, the applicant shall
            furnish assurance, satisfactory to the Agency, that continuous and
            efficient service at the broadband lending speed will be rendered.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Agency will require financial, investment, operational,
            reporting, and managerial controls in the loan documents.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14002'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1738:D:1738.155
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1738.155
      </num>
      <head>
        Special terms and conditions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='155' psec='' tq='N'>
              1738.155
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Special terms and conditions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Agency may, when it is in the best interest of the Agency and
            its mission, the affected community, and the applicant, aid in
            achieving financial feasibility in an underserved area by taking the
            following steps:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Extend the loan term up to 35 years, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Modify its security requirements.
            <PRTPAGE P='353' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Agency may reduce the security requirements discussed in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='154' psec='#a' tq='N'>
                1738.154(a)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             to ensure that the security is commensurate with the risk involved.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14003'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1738:D:1738.156
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1738.156
      </num>
      <head>
        Other Federal requirements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='156' psec='' tq='N'>
              1738.156
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Other Federal requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To receive a broadband loan, the applicant must certify or agree in
            writing to comply with a variety of Federal regulations including,
            but not limited to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The nondiscrimination and equal employment opportunity requirements
            of Title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964, as amended (
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='15' tq='N'>
                15
              </subref>
            </aref>
            );
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              Section 504 of
            </aref>
             the Rehabilitation Act of 1973, as amended (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='29' sect='794' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/29/794.html'>
                29 U.S.C. 794
              </subref>
            </aref>
            <E T='03'>
              et seq.
            </E>
            ; 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='15b' tq='N'>
                15b
              </subref>
            </aref>
            );
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Age Discrimination Act of 1975, as amended (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='42' sect='6101' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/42/6101.html'>
                42 U.S.C. 6101
              </subref>
            </aref>
            <E T='03'>
              et seq.
            </E>
            ; 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              45 CFR part 
              <subref title='45' part='90' tq='N'>
                90
              </subref>
            </aref>
            );
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Executive Order 11375, amending Executive Order (E.O.) 11246,
            Relating to Equal Employment Opportunity (3 CFR, 1966-1970). See 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR parts 
              <subref title='7' part='15' tq='N'>
                15
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='15b' tq='N'>
                15b
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='45' tq='N'>
                45
              </subref>
            </aref>
             CFR 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='90' tq='N'>
                90
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , RUS Bulletin 1790-1 (“Nondiscrimination Among Beneficiaries of RUS
            Programs”), and RUS Bulletin 20-15:320-15 (“Equal Employment
            Opportunity in Construction Financed with RUS Loans”);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Architectural Barriers Act of 1968, as amended (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='42' sect='4151' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/42/4151.html'>
                42 U.S.C. 4151
              </subref>
            </aref>
            <E T='03'>
              et seq.
            </E>
            );
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Uniform Federal Accessibility Standards (UFAS) (Appendix A to 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              41 CFR subpart 
              <subref title='41' part='101-19' subpart='6' tq='N'>
                101-19.6
              </subref>
            </aref>
            );
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The requirements of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969
            (NEPA), as amended;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Council on Environmental Quality Regulations for Implementing
            the Procedural Provisions of NEPA and certain related Federal
            environmental laws, statutes, regulations, and Executive Orders
            found in 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1794' tq='N'>
                1794
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Uniform Relocation Assistance and Real Property Acquisition
            Policies Act of 1970, as amended, 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='42' sect='4601' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/42/4601.html'>
                42 U.S.C. 4601
              </subref>
            </aref>
            <E T='03'>
              et seq.
            </E>
            , and with implementing Federal regulations in 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              49 CFR part 
              <subref title='49' part='24' tq='N'>
                24
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='49' part='7' tq='N'>
                7
              </subref>
            </aref>
             CFR 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='21' tq='N'>
                21
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The regulations implementing E.O. 12549, Debarment and Suspension, 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR 
              <subref title='7' part='3017' sect='510' psec='' tq='N'>
                3017.510
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , Participants&apos; Responsibilities;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_11'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (11)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The requirements regarding Lobbying for Contracts, Grants, Loans,
            and Cooperative Agreements in 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='31' sect='1352' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/31/1352.html'>
                31 U.S.C. 1352
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_12'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (12)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Certification regarding Flood Hazard Area Precautions;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_13'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (13)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Certification regarding Debarment, Suspension, and Other
            Responsibility Matters—Primary Covered Transactions; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_14'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (14)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Certification that the borrower is not delinquent on any Federal
            debt and has been informed of the collection options the Federal
            Government may use to collect delinquent debt.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Applicants must agree in writing to comply with all Federal, State
            and local laws, rules, regulations, ordinances, codes, and orders
            applicable to the project.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14004'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1738:D:1738.157-1739.200
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1738.157-1739.200
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='157-1739' psec='' tq='N'>
              1738.157-1739
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .200
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14005'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1738:E:1738.201
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1738.201
      </num>
      <head>
        Application submission.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='201' psec='' tq='N'>
              1738.201
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Application submission.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Loan applications must be submitted directly to the Agency&apos;s
            National Office or to the General Field Representative (GFR) that is
            assigned to the area where the applicant&apos;s headquarters are
            located. A list of GFRs and the areas they are assigned can be found
            on the Agency&apos;s Web site. All applications must contain two
            hard copies and an electronic copy of the entire application. An
            application is considered received upon receipt of the hard and
            electronic copies by the National Office. The date and time of that
            receipt will establish the application&apos;s placement in the
            processing queue.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Agency may publish additional application submission
            requirements in the 
            <E T='04'>
              Federal Register.
            </E>
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14006'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1738:E:1738.202
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1738.202
      </num>
      <head>
        Elements of a complete application.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='202' psec='' tq='N'>
              1738.202
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Elements of a complete application.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          An applicant must submit to the Agency a complete application in a
          format as required by the Agency in the Rural Broadband Access Loan
          and Loan Guarantee Program Application Guide (the Application Guide).
          To be considered complete, the application must contain at least the
          following items, each of which must be completed in a manner
          acceptable to the Agency:
          <PRTPAGE P='354' />
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A completed RUS Form 532, including any additional items required
            by the form;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Information required for the public notice to determine service
            area eligibility (see 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='204' psec='' tq='N'>
                1738.204
              </subref>
            </aref>
            );
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Documentation demonstrating how the applicant will meet the equity
            requirement (see 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='207' psec='' tq='N'>
                1738.207
              </subref>
            </aref>
            );
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A market survey, unless not required by 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='209' psec='#b' tq='N'>
                1738.209(b)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A competitive analysis (see 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='210' psec='' tq='N'>
                1738.210
              </subref>
            </aref>
            );
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Required financial information (see 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='211' psec='' tq='N'>
                1738.211
              </subref>
            </aref>
            );
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A network design (see 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='212' psec='' tq='N'>
                1738.212
              </subref>
            </aref>
            );
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A legal opinion that addresses the applicant&apos;s ability to
            enter into a loan as requested in the loan application, to pledge
            security as required by the Agency, to describe all pending
            litigation matters, and such other requirements as are detailed in
            the Application Guide;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All required licenses and regulatory approvals for the proposed
            operation or the status of obtaining these items; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Additional items that may be required by the Administrator through
            a notice in the 
            <E T='04'>
              Federal Register.
            </E>
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14007'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1738:E:1738.203
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1738.203
      </num>
      <head>
        Priority for processing loan applications.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='203' psec='' tq='N'>
              1738.203
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Priority for processing loan applications.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as provided in 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              Section 306F of
            </aref>
             the RE Act (SUTA) and 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 
              <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
                1738.3
              </subref>
            </aref>
             herein, in making or guaranteeing loans, the Agency shall give
            priority to applications in the following order:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Applications in which no broadband service is available in any
            funded service area;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Applications in which at least 75 percent of households in the
            funded service area have no incumbent service provider. For
            applications with multiple funded service areas, the 75 percent
            calculation is based on all funded service areas combined;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Applications in which at least 50 percent of households in the
            funded service area have no incumbent service provider. For
            applications with multiple funded service areas, the 50 percent
            calculation is based on all funded service areas combined;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Applications in which at least 25 percent of households in the
            funded service area have no incumbent service provider. For
            applications with multiple funded service areas, the 25 percent
            calculation is based on all funded service areas combined; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All other applications.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Once applications have been prioritized according to the criteria
            listed in paragraph (a) of this section, the applications will be
            processed on a first-in, first-out basis within each priority
            category.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Agency shall establish the National and State reserve levels in
            accordance with Title VI of the RE Act. In instances when funds in a
            particular area are insufficient to cover a loan request, priority
            will be given to processing applications for which funding is
            available.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14008'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1738:E:1738.204
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1738.204
      </num>
      <head>
        Public notice.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='204' psec='' tq='N'>
              1738.204
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Public notice.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Agency will publish a public notice of each application. The
            application must provide a summary of the information required for
            such public notice including all of the following information:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The identity of the applicant;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A map of each service area showing the rural area boundaries and
            the underserved areas using the Agency&apos;s Mapping Tool;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The estimated number of underserved households in each service
            area;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The estimated number of households without terrestrial-based
            broadband service in each service area; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A description of all the types of services that the applicant
            proposes to offer in each service area.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Agency will publish the public notice on an Agency webpage
            after the application has been received in the Agency&apos;s
            National Office. The notice will remain on the webpage for a period
            of 30 calendar days. The notice will ask existing service providers
            to submit to the Agency, within this 30-day period, the following
            information:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The number of residential and business customers within the
            applicant&apos;s service area that are currently offered broadband
            service by the existing service provider;
            <PRTPAGE P='355' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The number of residential and business customers within the
            applicant&apos;s service area currently purchasing the existing
            service provider&apos;s broadband service, the rates of data
            transmission being offered, and the cost of each level of broadband
            service charged by the existing service provider;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The number of residential and business customers within the
            applicant&apos;s service area receiving the existing service
            provider&apos;s non-broadband services and the associated rates for
            these other services; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A map showing where the existing service provider&apos;s services
            coincide with the applicant&apos;s service area using the
            Agency&apos;s Mapping Tool.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whether the existing service provider is an existing RUS borrower
            or grantee.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Agency will use the information submitted to determine if the
            existing service provider will be classified as an incumbent service
            provider. If an existing service provider does not submit a response
            within the timeframe specified in the public notice, it will not be
            considered an incumbent service provider. However, all existing
            service providers will be considered in the Agency&apos;s
            feasibility study and lending decision.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Agency will determine whether the service areas included in the
            application are eligible for funding based on the information
            provided during the public notice period, whether all portions of
            the service area qualify as rural areas, and the number of incumbent
            service providers servicing any portion of the service area. If the
            applicant&apos;s funded service area is ineligible, the Agency will
            contact the applicant and require that those ineligible areas be
            removed from the funded service area. If the ineligible service
            areas are not removed from the funding request, the Agency will
            reject the application and remove it from the processing queue. The
            applicant will be notified, in writing, and the application will be
            returned with an explanation of the reasons for the rejection.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The information submitted by an existing service provider will be
            treated as proprietary and confidential to the extent permitted
            under applicable law.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14009'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1738:E:1738.205
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1738.205
      </num>
      <head>
        Notification of completeness.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='205' psec='' tq='N'>
              1738.205
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Notification of completeness.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          If all funded service areas are eligible, the Agency will review the
          application for completeness. The completeness review will include an
          assessment of whether all required documents and information have been
          submitted and whether the information provided is of adequate quality
          to allow further analysis.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the application contains all required documents and information
            and is of adequate quality, the Agency will notify the applicant, in
            writing, that the application is complete. The notification of
            completeness will mark the date as of which costs incurred for the
            eligible purposes listed in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='51' psec='#a' tq='N'>
                1738.51(a)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             through (d) can be reimbursed with loan funds if the loan is
            ultimately made and proper procedures have been followed. A
            notification of completeness is not a commitment that the loan will
            be approved.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the application is of adequate quality but does not contain all
            required documents and information, the Agency will notify the
            applicant, in writing, that the application is incomplete. The
            notification of incompleteness will include a list of items that the
            applicant must address and will specify a date by which the
            applicant&apos;s additional information must be received.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the applicant fails to respond by the specified date, the
            application will be rejected.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the applicant responds by the specified date but does not
            satisfactorily address the issues identified, the Agency will assess
            the applicant&apos;s progress toward submission of a complete
            application. If the applicant has made progress acceptable to the
            Agency, a second notification of incompleteness will be provided. If
            the applicant&apos;s progress is not acceptable to the Agency, the
            application will be rejected.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the application is considered to be of inadequate quality, the
            Agency will notify the applicant, in writing, that the application
            has been rejected. 
            <PRTPAGE P='356' />
            The rejection letter will include an explanation of the reasons for
            the rejection and the application will be removed from the queue.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14010'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1738:E:1738.206
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1738.206
      </num>
      <head>
        Evaluation for feasibility.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='206' psec='' tq='N'>
              1738.206
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Evaluation for feasibility.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          After an applicant is notified that the application is complete, the
          Agency will evaluate the application&apos;s financial and technical
          feasibility. The Agency will only make a broadband loan if the
          applicant&apos;s financial operations, taking into account the impact
          of the facilities financed with the proceeds of the loan and the
          associated debt, are financially and technically feasible, as
          determined by the Agency.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Agency will determine financial feasibility by evaluating the
            applicant&apos;s equity, market survey (if required), competitive
            analysis, financial information, and other relevant information in
            the application.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Agency will determine technical feasibility by evaluating the
            applicant&apos;s network design and other relevant information in
            the application.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14011'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1738:E:1738.207
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1738.207
      </num>
      <head>
        Equity requirement.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='207' psec='' tq='N'>
              1738.207
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Equity requirement.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be eligible for a loan, an applicant must demonstrate a minimum
            equity position equal to 10 percent of the requested loan amount at
            the time of application which must remain available at loan closing.
            In addition to this minimum equity requirement, please refer to
            section 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='208' psec='' tq='N'>
                1738.208
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , Additional Cash Requirements which could cause the equity
            requirement to be higher than 10 percent.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the applicant does not have the required equity at the time the
            application is submitted, the applicant may satisfy the equity
            requirement at the time of application with an investor&apos;s
            unconditional legal commitment to cover the shortfall by providing
            additional equity. The additional equity must be transferred to the
            applicant prior to loan closing. If this option is elected, the
            applicant must provide evidence in the application that clearly
            identifies the investor&apos;s commitment to the applicant; the
            amount, terms, and conditions of the investment; and the
            investor&apos;s bank or financial statements that demonstrate its
            ability to fulfill its commitment. The terms and conditions of the
            investment must be acceptable to the Agency, which generally
            prohibits redemption of the investment until such time as stated
            requirements and financial thresholds are achieved by the applicant.
            The Agency will reject applications that do not provide evidence
            acceptable to the Agency regarding the investor&apos;s commitment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For State and local government applicants, the equity requirement
            can be satisfied with a general obligation bond, as long as the
            additional equity will be available to the applicant at closing. If
            the equity requirement is satisfied with a general obligation bond,
            the broadband loan cannot be subordinate to the bond. The applicant
            must submit an opinion from its legal counsel that the applicant has
            the authority to issue a general obligation bond in an amount
            sufficient to meet the minimum equity requirement. Revenue bonds
            supported by the operations to be funded cannot be used to satisfy
            the equity requirement.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14012'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1738:E:1738.208
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1738.208
      </num>
      <head>
        Additional cash requirements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='208' psec='' tq='N'>
              1738.208
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Additional cash requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the Agency&apos;s financial analysis indicates that the
            applicant&apos;s entire operation (existing operations and new
            operations combined) will show a negative cash balance at the end of
            any year during the five-year forecast period, the Agency will
            require the applicant to obtain additional cash infusions necessary
            to maintain an appropriate cash balance throughout the five-year
            forecast period. This cash infusion would be in conjunction with the
            required 10 percent minimum equity position.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Agency will require the applicant and its investors to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Infuse additional cash to cover projected deficits for the first
            two years of operations at loan closing; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Enter into legal arrangements that commit them to making additional
            cash infusions to ensure that the operation will sustain a positive
            cash position on a quarterly basis throughout the five-year forecast
            period.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For purposes of identifying the additional cash requirement for a
            start-up operation or an operation that has not demonstrated
            positive cash flow for the two years prior to the submission 
            <PRTPAGE P='357' />
            date of the application, 50 percent of projected revenues for each
            year of the five-year forecast period will be considered to
            determine if an operation can sustain a positive cash position. In
            addition to the initial financial projections required to
            demonstrate financial feasibility, such applicants must complete
            adjusted financial projections using the reduced revenue projections
            in order to identify the amount of additional cash that will be
            required. Projections must be fully supported with assumptions
            acceptable to the Agency. The applicant may present evidence in its
            loan application that projected revenues or a portion of projected
            revenues are based on binding commitments and request that more than
            50 percent of the projected revenues be considered for the purpose
            of identifying the additional cash requirement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For purposes of satisfying the additional cash requirements for an
            existing operation that has demonstrated a positive cash flow for
            the two fiscal years prior to the submission date of the
            application, 100 percent of the projected revenues for each year of
            the five-year forecast period will be used to determine if an
            operation can sustain a positive cash position, as long as these
            projections are fully supported with assumptions acceptable to the
            Agency.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If debt is incurred to satisfy the additional cash requirement,
            this debt must take a subordinate lien position to the Agency debt
            and must be at terms acceptable to the Agency.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An applicant may satisfy the additional cash requirement with an
            unconditional, irrevocable letter of credit (LOC) satisfactory to
            the Agency. The LOC must be issued from a financial institution
            acceptable to the Agency and must remain in effect throughout the
            forecast period. The applicant and the Agency must both be payees
            under the LOC. The LOC must have payment conditions acceptable to
            the Agency, and it must be in place prior to loan closing. The
            applicant cannot secure the LOC with its assets and cannot pay for
            any LOC charges or fees with its funds.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the Agency offers a loan to the applicant, the applicant must
            ensure that the additional cash infusion required in the first two
            years is deposited into its bank account within 120 days from the
            date the applicant signs the loan offer letter (see 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='251' psec='' tq='N'>
                1738.251
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) and must enter into any other legal arrangements necessary to
            cover further projected operating deficits (or in the case of the
            LOC, to provide an acceptable LOC to the Agency) prior to closing.
            If these requirements are not completed within this timeframe, the
            loan offer will be terminated, unless the applicant requests and the
            Agency approves an extension based on extenuating circumstances that
            the Agency was not aware of at the time the offer was made.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Administrator may modify the requirements of this section for
            loans in service areas that are underserved when it is in the best
            interests of the Agency.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14013'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1738:E:1738.209
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1738.209
      </num>
      <head>
        Market survey.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='209' psec='' tq='N'>
              1738.209
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Market survey.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as provided in paragraph (b) of this section, the applicant
            must complete a separate market survey for each service area where
            the applicant proposes to provide service at the broadband lending
            speed. Each market survey must demonstrate the need for the service
            at the broadband lending speed, support the projected penetration
            rates and price points for the services to be offered, and support
            the feasibility analysis. The market survey must also address all
            other services that will be provided in connection with the
            broadband loan. Additional information on the requirements of the
            market survey can be found in the Application Guide.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The applicant is not required to complete a market survey for any
            service offering for which the applicant is projecting less than a
            20 percent penetration rate in each service area by the end of the
            five-year forecast period. For example, if the applicant is
            projecting a penetration rate of 30 percent for data services and 15
            percent for video services, a market survey must be completed for
            the data services. The proposed prices for those services with a
            projected penetration rate less than 20 percent must be affordable,
            as determined by the Agency.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For a market survey to be acceptable to the Agency, it must have
            been completed within six months of the application submission date.
            The Agency 
            <PRTPAGE P='358' />
            may reject any application in which the financial projections are
            not supported by the market survey. If the demographics of the
            proposed service area have significantly changed since the survey
            was completed, the Agency may require an updated market survey.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Administrator may modify the requirements of this section for
            loans in service areas that are underserved when it is in the best
            interests of the Agency.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14014'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1738:E:1738.210
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1738.210
      </num>
      <head>
        Competitive analysis.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='210' psec='' tq='N'>
              1738.210
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Competitive analysis.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The applicant must submit a competitive market analysis for each
          service area regardless of projected penetration rates. Each analysis
          must identify all existing service providers and all resellers in each
          service area regardless of the provider&apos;s market share, for each
          type of service the applicant proposes to provide. This analysis must
          include each competitor&apos;s rate packages for all services offered,
          the area that is being covered, and to the extent possible, the
          quality of service being provided.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14015'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1738:E:1738.211
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1738.211
      </num>
      <head>
        Financial information.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='211' psec='' tq='N'>
              1738.211
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Financial information.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The applicant must submit financial information acceptable to the
            Agency that demonstrates that the applicant has the financial
            capacity to fulfill the loan requirements and to successfully
            complete the proposed project.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the applicant is an existing company, it must provide complete
            copies of audited financial statements (opinion letter, balance
            sheet, income statement, statement of changes in financial position,
            and notes to the financial statement) for the three fiscal years
            preceding the application submission. If audited statements are not
            available, the applicant must submit unaudited financial statements
            and tax returns for those fiscal years. Applications from start-up
            entities must, at a minimum, provide an opening balance sheet dated
            within 30 days of the application submission date.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the applicant is a subsidiary operation, it must also provide
            complete copies of audited financial statements for the parent
            operation for the fiscal year preceding the application submission.
            If audited statements are not available, unaudited financial
            statements and tax returns for the previous year must be submitted.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the applicant relies on services provided by an affiliated
            operation, it must also provide complete copies of audited financial
            statements for any affiliate for the fiscal year preceding the
            application submission. If audited statements are not available,
            unaudited statements and tax returns for the previous year must be
            submitted.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Applicants must provide a list of all its outstanding obligations.
            Copies of existing notes and loan and security agreements must be
            included in the application.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Applicants must provide a detailed description of working capital
            requirements and the source of these funds.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Applicants must submit the following documents that demonstrate the
            proposed project&apos;s financial viability and ability to repay the
            requested loan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Customer projections for the five-year forecast period that
            substantiate the projected revenues for each service that is to be
            provided. The projections must be provided on at least an annual
            basis and must be developed separately for each service area. These
            projections must be clearly supported by the information contained
            in the market survey, unless no market survey is required (see 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='209' psec='#b' tq='N'>
                1738.209(b)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Annual financial projections in the form of balance sheets, income
            statements, and cash flow statements for the five-year forecast
            period. Prior to the submission of an application, an applicant may
            request that alternative information related to financial viability
            be considered when the applicant can for good cause demonstrate why
            a full five-year forecast cannot be provided. If this request is
            approved by the Agency, then the applicant can submit the
            application using the alternative information that was approved.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             These projections must use a system of accounts acceptable to the
            Agency and be supported by a detailed narrative that fully explains
            the methodology and assumptions used to develop the projections.
            <PRTPAGE P='359' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The financial projections submitted by the applicant must
            demonstrate that their entire operation will be able to meet a
            minimum TIER requirement equal to 1.25 by the end of the five-year
            forecast period. Demonstrating that the operation can achieve a
            projected TIER of 1.25 does not ensure that the Agency will approve
            the loan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the financial analysis suggests that the operation will not be
            able to achieve the required TIER ratio, the Agency will not approve
            the loan without additional capital, additional cash, additional
            security, and/or a change in the loan terms.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Based on the financial evaluation, the loan documents will specify
            TIER requirements that must be met throughout the amortization
            period.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14016'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1738:E:1738.212
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1738.212
      </num>
      <head>
        Network design.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='212' psec='' tq='N'>
              1738.212
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Network design.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Applications must include a network design that demonstrates the
            project&apos;s technical feasibility. The network design must fully
            support the delivery of service at the broadband lending speed,
            together with any other services to be provided. In measuring speed,
            the Agency will take into account industry and regulatory standards.
            The design must demonstrate that the project will be complete within
            three years from the day the Agency notifies the applicant that loan
            funds are available and must include the following items:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A detailed description of the proposed technology that will be used
            to provide service at the broadband lending speed. This description
            must clearly demonstrate that all households in the funded service
            area will be offered service at the broadband lending speed;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A detailed description of the existing network. This description
            should provide a synopsis of the current network infrastructure;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A detailed description of the proposed network. This description
            should provide a synopsis of the proposed network infrastructure;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A description of measurable service metrics and target service
            level objectives (SLOs) that will be provided to the customer, and
            the methods that will be used to measure performance and respond to
            unmet SLOs;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A description of the approach and methodology for monitoring
            ongoing service delivery and service quality for the services being
            deployed;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Estimated project costs detailing all facilities that are required
            to complete the project. These estimated costs must be broken down
            to indicate costs associated with each proposed service area and
            must specify how Agency and non-Agency funds will be used to
            complete the project;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A construction build-out schedule of the proposed facilities by
            service area on a quarterly basis. The build-out schedule must
            include:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_7_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A description of the work force that will be required to complete
            the proposed construction;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_7_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A timeline demonstrating project completion within three years from
            the date the Agency notifies the applicant that loan funds are
            available;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_7_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Detailed information showing that all households within the funded
            service area will be offered service at the broadband lending speed
            when the system is complete; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_7_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Detailed information showing that construction of the proposed
            facilities will start within six months from the date the Agency
            notifies the borrower that loan funds are available.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A depreciation schedule for all facilities financed with loan and
            non-loan funds;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An environmental report prepared in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1794' tq='N'>
                1794
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any other system requirements required by the Administrator through
            a notice published in the 
            <E T='04'>
              Federal Register
            </E>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The network design must be prepared by a registered Professional
            Engineer with telecommunications experience or by qualified
            personnel on the applicant&apos;s staff. If the network design is
            prepared by the applicant&apos;s staff, the application must clearly
            demonstrate the staff&apos;s qualifications, experience, and ability
            to complete the network design. To be considered qualified, staff
            must have at least three years of experience in designing the type
            of broadband system proposed in the application.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Administrator may modify the requirements of this section for
            loans in underserved service areas.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14017'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1738:E:1738.213
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1738.213
      </num>
      <head>
        Loan determination.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='360' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='213' psec='' tq='N'>
              1738.213
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Loan determination.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the application meets all statutory and regulatory requirements
            and the feasibility study demonstrates that the TIER requirement can
            be satisfied, the application will be submitted to the Agency&apos;s
            credit committees for consideration. Submission of the application
            to the Agency&apos;s credit committees does not guarantee that a
            loan will be approved. In making a loan determination, the
            Administrator shall consider the recommendations of the credit
            committees.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The applicant will be notified of the Agency&apos;s decision in
            writing. If the Agency approves the loan, a loan offer will be
            extended. If the Agency does not approve the loan, a rejection
            letter will be sent to the applicant, and the application will be
            returned with an explanation of the reasons for the rejection.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14018'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1738:E:1738.214-1738.250
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1738.214-1738.250
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='214-1738' psec='' tq='N'>
              1738.214-1738
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .250
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14019'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1738:F:1738.251
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1738.251
      </num>
      <head>
        Loan offer and loan closing.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='251' psec='' tq='N'>
              1738.251
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Loan offer and loan closing.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The Agency will notify the applicant of the loan offer, in writing,
          and the applicant will typically have 10 working days to accept the
          offer. If the applicant accepts the loan offer, a loan contract will
          be executed and sent to the applicant. The applicant must execute the
          loan contract and satisfy all conditions precedent to loan closing
          within the timeframe specified by the Agency which is typically 120
          days from the date of the loan contract. If the conditions are not met
          within this timeframe, the loan offer will be terminated, unless the
          applicant requests and the Agency approves an extension. The Agency
          may approve such a request if the applicant has diligently sought to
          meet the conditions required for loan closing and has been unable to
          do so for reasons outside its control.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14020'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1738:F:1738.252
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1738.252
      </num>
      <head>
        Construction.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='252' psec='' tq='N'>
              1738.252
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Construction.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Construction paid for with broadband loan funds must comply with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1788' tq='N'>
                1788, 7
              </subref>
            </aref>
             CFR 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1794' tq='N'>
                1794
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , RUS Bulletin 1738-2 and any other guidance from the Agency.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon notification by the Agency that an applicant has submitted all
            the required documentation and the application is considered
            complete for analysis (see 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='205' psec='' tq='N'>
                1738.205
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ), the applicant, at its own risk, may enter into an interim
            financing agreement with a third-party lender or use its own funds
            to start construction that is included in the loan application. For
            this construction to be eligible for reimbursement with loan funds,
            all construction procedures contained herein must be followed. The
            Agency&apos;s determination that an application is complete is not a
            commitment that a loan will be approved.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The borrower must begin construction within six months from the
            date the Agency notifies the applicant that loan funds are
            available. This is the final step in closing the loan with the
            applicant. If the borrower fails to begin construction, the Agency
            may cancel the loan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The build-out must be complete within three years from the day the
            Agency notifies the applicant that loan funds are available.
            Build-out is considered complete when the network design has been
            fully implemented, the service operations and management systems
            infrastructure is operational, and the borrower is ready to support
            the activation and commissioning of individual customers to the new
            system.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14021'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1738:F:1738.253
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1738.253
      </num>
      <head>
        Servicing.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='253' psec='' tq='N'>
              1738.253
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Servicing.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Borrowers must make payments on the broadband loan as required in
            the note.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Borrowers must comply with all terms, conditions, affirmative
            covenants, and negative covenants contained in the loan documents.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the event of default of any required payment or other term or
            condition:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A late charge shall be charged on any payment not made in
            accordance with the terms of the note.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Agency may exercise the default remedies provided in the loan
            documents but is not required to do so.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the Agency chooses to not exercise its default remedies, it does
            not waive its right to do so in the future.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14022'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1738:F:1738.254
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1738.254
      </num>
      <head>
        Accounting, reporting, and monitoring requirements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='361' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='254' psec='' tq='N'>
              1738.254
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Accounting, reporting, and monitoring requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Borrowers must adopt a system of accounts for maintaining financial
            records acceptable to the Agency, as described in 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR 1770
            </aref>
            , subpart B.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Borrowers must submit annual audited financial statements along
            with a report on compliance and on internal control over financial
            reporting, and management letter in accordance with the requirements
            of 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1773' tq='N'>
                1773
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . The Certified Public Accountant (CPA) conducting the annual audit
            is selected by the borrower and must be approved by RUS as set forth
            in 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR 
              <subref title='7' part='1773' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
                1773.4
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Borrowers must comply with all reasonable Agency requests to
            support ongoing monitoring efforts. The Borrower shall afford RUS,
            through its representatives, reasonable opportunity, at all times
            during business hours and upon prior notice, to have access to and
            the right to inspect the Broadband System, and any other property
            encumbered by the Mortgage, and any or all books, records, accounts,
            invoices, contracts, leases, payrolls, timesheets, cancelled checks,
            statements, and other documents, electronic or paper of every kind
            belonging to or in the possession of the Borrower or in anyway
            pertaining to its property or business, including its subsidiaries,
            if any, and to make copies or extracts therefore.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Borrowers records shall be retained and preserved in accordance
            with the provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1770' tq='N'>
                1770
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , subpart A.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14023'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1738:F:1738.255-1738.300
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1738.255-1738.300
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='255-1738' psec='' tq='N'>
              1738.255-1738
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .300
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14024'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1738:G:1738.301
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1738.301
      </num>
      <head>
        General.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='301' psec='' tq='N'>
              1738.301
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Applicants wishing to obtain a loan guarantee for private financing
            are subject to the same requirements as direct loan borrowers with
            respect to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Loan purposes as described in subpart B;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Eligible borrowers and eligible areas as described in subpart C;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The loan terms described in subpart D, with the exception of the
            interest rates described in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='152' psec='' tq='N'>
                1738.152
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The application review and underwriting requirements in subpart E.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Agency will publish a notice annually in the 
            <E T='04'>
              Federal Register
            </E>
             indicating any additional requirements, as well as the amount of
            funds available, if any, for loan guarantees.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14025'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1738:G:1738.302
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1738.302
      </num>
      <head>
        Eligible guaranteed lenders.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='302' psec='' tq='N'>
              1738.302
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Eligible guaranteed lenders.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          To be eligible for a loan guarantee, a guaranteed lender must be:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A financial institution in good standing that has been a concurrent
            lender with RUS; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A legally organized lending institution, such as commercial bank,
            trust company, mortgage banking firm, insurance company, or any
            other institutional investor authorized by law to loan money, which
            must be subject to credit examination and supervision by a Federal
            or State agency, unless the Agency determines that alternative
            examination and supervisory mechanisms are adequate.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14026'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1738:G:1738.303
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1738.303
      </num>
      <head>
        Requirements for the loan guarantee.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='303' psec='' tq='N'>
              1738.303
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Requirements for the loan guarantee.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          At the time of application, applicants must provide in form and
          substance acceptable to the Agency:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Evidence of the guaranteed lender&apos;s eligibility under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='302' psec='' tq='N'>
                1738.302
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Evidence that the guaranteed lender has the demonstrated capacity
            to adequately service the guaranteed loan;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Evidence that the guaranteed lender is in good standing with its
            licensing authority and meets the loan making, loan servicing, and
            other requirements of the jurisdiction in which the lender makes
            loans;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Evidence satisfactory to the Agency of its qualification under this
            part, along with the name of the authority that supervises it;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A commitment letter from the guaranteed lender that will be
            providing the funding, and the terms of such funding, all of which
            may be conditioned on final approval of the broadband loan guarantee
            by the Agency; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A description of any and all charges and fees for the loan, along
            with documentation that they are comparable to those normally
            charged other applicants for the same type of 
            <PRTPAGE P='362' />
            loan in the ordinary course of business. Such charges and fees will
            not be included within the Agency&apos;s loan guarantee.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14027'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1738:G:1738.304
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1738.304
      </num>
      <head>
        Terms for guarantee.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='304' psec='' tq='N'>
              1738.304
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Terms for guarantee.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Loan guarantees will only be given on the conditions that:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The loan guarantee is no more than 80 percent of the principal
            amount, which shall exclude any and all charges and fees;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The guarantee is limited to the outstanding loan repayment
            obligation of the borrower and does not extend to guaranteeing that
            the guaranteed lender will remit to a holder, loan payments made by
            the borrower;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The interest rate must be fixed and must be the same or lesser for
            the guaranteed loan amount or the respective guaranteed loan portion
            amount or the respective guaranteed amount equivalent, as the case
            may be, and unguaranteed loan amount or the respective unguaranteed
            loan portion amount or the respective unguaranteed-amount
            equivalent, as the case may be;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The entire loan will be secured by the same security with equal
            lien priority for the guaranteed loan amount or the respective
            guaranteed loan portion amount or the respective guaranteed-amount
            equivalent, as the case may be, and unguaranteed loan amount or the
            respective unguaranteed loan portion amount or the respective
            unguaranteed-amount equivalent, as the case may be;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The unguaranteed loan amount or the respective unguaranteed loan
            portion amount or the respective unguaranteed-amount equivalent, as
            the case may be, will neither be paid first nor given any preference
            or priority over the guaranteed loan amount or the respective
            guaranteed loan portion amount or the respective guaranteed-amount
            equivalent, as the case may be;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Prior written approval is obtained from the Agency for any
            assignment by the guaranteed lender. Any assignment shall entitle
            the holder to all of the guaranteed lender&apos;s rights but shall
            maintain the guaranteed lender responsible for servicing the entire
            loan;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The borrower, its principal officers, members of the
            borrower&apos;s board of directors and members of the immediate
            families of said officials shall not be a holder of the guaranteed
            lender&apos;s loan;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Agency will not guarantee any loan under this subpart that
            provides for a balloon payment of principal or interest at the final
            maturity date of the loan or for the payment of interest on
            interest;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All loan guarantee documents between the Agency and the guaranteed
            lender are prepared by the Agency; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The guaranteed loan agreement between the borrower and the lender
            shall be subject to Agency approval.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14028'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1738:G:1738.305
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1738.305
      </num>
      <head>
        Obligations of guaranteed lender.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='305' psec='' tq='N'>
              1738.305
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Obligations of guaranteed lender.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Once a loan guarantee has been approved, the guaranteed lender will be
          responsible for:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Servicing the loan;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Determining that all prerequisites to each advance of loan funds by
            the lender under the terms of the contract of guarantee, all
            financing documents, and all related security documents have been
            fulfilled;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Obtaining approval from the Agency to advance funds prior to each
            advance;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Billing and collecting loan payments from the borrower;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notifying the Administrator promptly of any default in the payment
            of principal and interest on the loan and submit a report no later
            than 30 days thereafter, setting forth the reasons for the default,
            how long it expects the borrower will be in default, and what
            corrective actions the borrower states that it is taking to achieve
            a current debt service position; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notifying the Administrator of any known violations or defaults by
            the borrower under the lending agreement, contract of guarantee, or
            related security instruments or conditions of which the lender is
            aware which might lead to nonpayment, violation, or other default.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14029'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1738:G:1738.306
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1738.306
      </num>
      <head>
        Agency rights and remedies.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='306' psec='' tq='N'>
              1738.306
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Agency rights and remedies.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The guarantee must provide that upon notice to the lender, the
            Agency 
            <PRTPAGE P='363' />
            may assume loan servicing responsibilities for the loan or the
            guaranteed loan amount or the respective guaranteed loan portion
            amount or the respective guaranteed-amount equivalent, as the case
            may be, or require the lender to assign such responsibilities to a
            different entity, if the lender fails to perform its loan servicing
            responsibilities under the loan guarantee agreement, or if the
            lender becomes insolvent, makes an admission in writing of its
            inability to pay its debts generally as they become due, or becomes
            the subject of proceedings commenced under the Bankruptcy Reform Act
            of 1978 (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='11' sect='101' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/11/101.html'>
                11 U.S.C. 101
              </subref>
            </aref>
            <E T='03'>
              et seq.
            </E>
            ) or any similar applicable Federal or State law, or is no longer in
            good standing with its licensing authority, or ceases to meet the
            eligibility requirements of this subpart. Such negligent servicing
            is defined as the failure to perform those services which a
            reasonable prudent lender would perform in servicing its own
            portfolio of loans that are not guaranteed and includes not only a
            failure to act but also not acting in a timely manner.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The guarantee shall cease to be effective with respect to any
            guaranteed loan amount or any guaranteed loan portion amount or any
            guaranteed-amount equivalent to the extent that:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The guaranteed loan amount or the respective guaranteed loan
            portion amount or the respective guaranteed amount equivalent, as
            the case may be, is separated at any time from the unguaranteed loan
            amount or the respective unguaranteed loan portion amount or the
            respective unguaranteed-amount equivalent, as the case may be, in
            any way, directly or through the issuance of any guaranteed-amount
            equity derivative or any guaranteed-amount debt derivative; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any holder of the guaranteed loan note or any guaranteed loan
            portion note or any derivative, as the case may be, having a claim
            to payments on the guaranteed loan receives more than its pro-rata
            percentage of any payment due to such holder from payments made
            under the guarantee at any time during the term of the guaranteed
            loan.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14030'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1738:G:1738.307
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1738.307
      </num>
      <head>
        Additional policies.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='307' psec='' tq='N'>
              1738.307
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Additional policies.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The Agency shall provide additional loan guarantee policies,
          consistent with OMB Circular A-129, in order to achieve its mission of
          promoting broadband in rural areas, which shall be published annually
          in the 
          <E T='04'>
            Federal Register
          </E>
          .
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14031'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1738:G:1738.308
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1738.308
      </num>
      <head>
        Full faith and credit of the United States.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='308' psec='' tq='N'>
              1738.308
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Full faith and credit of the United States.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Loan guarantees made under this part are supported by the full faith
          and credit of the United States and are incontestable except for fraud
          or misrepresentation of which the holder had actual knowledge at the
          time it became a holder.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14032'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1738:G:1738.309-1738.349
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1738.309-1738.349
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='309-1738' psec='' tq='N'>
              1738.309-1738
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .349
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14033'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1738:G:1738.350
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1738.350
      </num>
      <head>
        OMB control number.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1738' sect='350' psec='' tq='N'>
              1738.350
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          OMB control number.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The information collection requirements in this part are approved by
          the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) and assigned OMB control
          number 0572-0130.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>