<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol6'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:F:658
    </extid>
    <num>
      658
    </num>
    <head>
      FARMLAND PROTECTION POLICY ACT
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='4201-420' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/4201-420.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 4201-420
            </subref>
          </aref>
          9.
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            49 FR 27724
          </aref>
          , July 5, 1984, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='6472'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:F:658:-:658.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        658.1
      </num>
      <head>
        Purpose.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='658' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              658.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Purpose.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          This part sets out the criteria developed by the Secretary of
          Agriculture, in cooperation with other Federal agencies, pursuant to 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 1541(a) of
          </aref>
           the Farmland Protection Policy Act (FPPA or the Act) 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='4202' note='' psec='#a' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/4202.html#a'>
              7 U.S.C. 4202(a)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          . As required by 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 1541(b) of
          </aref>
           the Act, 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='4202' note='' psec='#b' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/4202.html#b'>
              7 U.S.C. 4202(b)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , Federal agencies are (a) to use the criteria to identify and take
          into account the adverse effects of their programs on the preservation
          of farmland, (b) to consider alternative 
          <PRTPAGE P='604' />
          actions, as appropriate, that could lessen adverse effects, and (c) to
          ensure that their programs, to the extent practicable, are compatible
          with State and units of local government and private programs and
          policies to protect farmland. Guidelines to assist agencies in using
          the criteria are included in this part. The Department of Agriculture
          (hereinafter USDA) may make available to States, units of local
          government, individuals, organizations, and other units of the Federal
          Government, information useful in restoring, maintaining, and
          improving the quantity and quality of farmland.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6473'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:F:658:-:658.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        658.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          49 FR 27724
        </aref>
        , July 5, 1984, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          59 FR 31117
        </aref>
        , June 17, 1994]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='658' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              658.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Farmland
            </E>
             means prime or unique farmlands as defined in 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 1540(c)(1) of
            </aref>
             the Act or farmland that is determined by the appropriate state or
            unit of local government agency or agencies with concurrence of the
            Secretary to be farmland of statewide of local importance.
            “Farmland” does not include land already in or committed to urban
            development or water storage. Farmland “already in” urban
            development or water storage includes all such land with a density
            of 30 structures per 40-acre area. Farmland already in urban
            development also includes lands identified as “urbanized area” (UA)
            on the Census Bureau Map, or as urban area mapped with a “tint
            overprint” on the USGS topographical maps, or as “urban-built-up” on
            the USDA Important Farmland Maps. Areas shown as white on the USDA
            Important Farmland Maps are not “farmland” and, therefore, are not
            subject to the Act. Farmland “committed to urban development or
            water storage” includes all such land that receives a combined score
            of 160 points or less from the land evaluation and site assessment
            criteria.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Federal agency
            </E>
             means a department, agency, independent commission, or other unit
            of the Federal Government.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Federal program
            </E>
             means those activities or responsibilities of a Federal agency that
            involve undertaking, financing, or assisting construction or
            improvement projects or acquiring, managing, or disposing of Federal
            lands and facilities.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The term “Federal program” does not include:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Federal permitting, licensing, or rate approval programs for
            activities on private or non-Federal lands; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Construction or improvement projects that were beyond the planning
            stage and were in either the active design or construction state on
            August 4, 1984.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For the purposes of this section, a project is considered to be
            “beyond the planning stage and in either the active design or
            construction state on August 4, 1984” if, on or before that date,
            actual construction of the project had commenced or:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Acquisition of land or easements for the project had occurred or
            all required Federal agency planning documents and steps were
            completed and accepted, endorsed, or approved by the appropriate
            agency;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A final environmental impact statement was filed with the
            Environmental Protection Agency or an environmental assessment was
            completed and a finding of no significant impact was executed by the
            appropriate agency official; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The engineering or architectural design had begun or such services
            had been secured by contract. The phrase “undertaking, financing, or
            assisting construction or improvement projects” includes providing
            loan guarantees or loan insurance for such projects and includes the
            acquisition, management and disposal of land or facilities that a
            Federal agency obtains as the result of foreclosure or other actions
            taken under a loan or other financial assistance provided by the
            agency directly and specifically for that property. For the purposes
            of this section, the phrase “acquiring, managing, or disposing of
            Federal lands and facilities” refers to lands and facilities that
            are acquired, managed, or used by a Federal agency specifically in
            support of a Federal activity or program, such as national parks,
            national forests, or military bases, and does not refer to lands and
            facilities that are acquired by a Federal agency as the incidental
            result of actions by the agency that give the agency temporary
            custody or ownership of the lands or facilities, such as 
            <PRTPAGE P='605' />
            acquisition pursuant to a lien for delinquent taxes, the exercise of
            conservatorship or receivership authority, or the exercise of civil
            or criminal law enforcement forfeiture or seizure authority.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              State or local government policies or programs to protect farmland
            </E>
             include: Zoning to protect farmland; agricultural land protection
            provisions of a comprehensive land use plan which has been adopted
            or reviewed in its entirety by the unit of local government in whose
            jurisdiction it is operative within 10 years preceding proposed
            implementation of the particular Federal program; completed purchase
            or acquisition of development rights; completed purchase or
            acquisition of conservation easements; prescribed procedures for
            assessing agricultural viability of sites proposed for conversion;
            completed agricultural districting and capital investments to
            protect farmland.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Private programs to protect farmland
            </E>
             means programs for the protection of farmland which are pursuant to
            and consistent with State and local government policies or programs
            to protect farmland of the affected State and unit of local
            government, but which are operated by a nonprofit corporation,
            foundation, association, conservancy, district, or other
            not-for-profit organization existing under State or Federal laws.
            Private programs to protect farmland may include: (1) Acquiring and
            holding development rights in farmland and (2) facilitating the
            transfer of development rights of farmland.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Site
            </E>
             means the location(s) that would be converted by the proposed
            action(s).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Unit of local government
            </E>
             means the government of a county, municipality, town, township,
            village, or other unit of general government below the State level,
            or a combination of units of local government acting through an
            areawide agency under a State law or an agreement for the
            formulation of regional development policies and plans.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            49 FR 27724
          </aref>
          , July 5, 1984, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            59 FR 31117
          </aref>
          , June 17, 1994]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6474'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:F:658:-:658.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        658.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Applicability and exemptions.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          49 FR 27724
        </aref>
        , July 5, 1984, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          59 FR 31117
        </aref>
        , June 17, 1994]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='658' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              658.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Applicability and exemptions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              Section 1540(b) of
            </aref>
             the Act, 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='4201' note='' psec='#b' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/4201.html#b'>
                7 U.S.C. 4201(b)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , states that the purpose of the Act is to minimize the extent to
            which Federal programs contribute to the unnecessary and
            irreversible conversion of farmland to nonagricultural uses.
            Conversion of farmland to nonagricultural uses does not include the
            construction of on-farm structures necessary for farm operations.
            Federal agencies can obtain assistance from USDA in determining
            whether a proposed location or site meets the Act&apos;s definition
            of farmland. The USDA Natural Resources Conservation Service (NRCS)
            field office serving the area will provide the assistance. Many
            State or local government planning offices can also provide this
            assistance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Acquisition or use of farmland by a Federal agency for national
            defense purposes is exempted by 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 1547(b) of
            </aref>
             the Act, 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='4208' note='' psec='#b' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/4208.html#b'>
                7 U.S.C. 4208(b)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Act and these regulations do not authorize the Federal
            Government in any way to regulate the use of private or non-Federal
            land, or in any way affect the property rights of owners of such
            land. In cases where either a private party or a non-Federal unit of
            government applies for Federal assistance to convert farmland to a
            nonagricultural use, the Federal agency should use the criteria set
            forth in this part to identify and take into account any adverse
            effects on farmland of the assistance requested and develop
            alternative actions that would avoid or mitigate such adverse
            effects. If, after consideration of the adverse effects and
            suggested alternatives, the landowners want to proceed with
            conversion, the Federal agency, on the basis of the analysis set
            forth in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='658' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
                658.4
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and any agency policies or procedures for implementing the Act, may
            provide or deny the requested assistance. Only assistance and
            actions that would convert farmland to nonagricultural uses are
            subject to this Act. Assistance and actions related to the purchase,
            maintenance, renovation, or replacement of existing structures and
            sites converted prior to the time of an application for assistance
            from a Federal agency, including assistance and actions related to
            the construction of minor new ancillary structures (such as garages
            or sheds), are not subject to the Act.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              Section 1548 of
            </aref>
             the Act, as amended, 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='4209' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/4209.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 4209
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , states that the Act 
            <PRTPAGE P='606' />
            shall not be deemed to provide a basis for any action, either legal
            or equitable, by any person or class of persons challenging a
            Federal project, program, or other activity that may affect
            farmland. Neither the Act nor this rule, therefore, shall afford any
            basis for such an action. However, as further provided in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 1548
            </aref>
            , the governor of an affected state, where a state policy or program
            exists to protect farmland, may bring an action in the Federal
            district court of the district where a Federal program is proposed
            to enforce the requirements of 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 1541 of
            </aref>
             the Act, 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='4202' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/4202.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 4202
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , and regulations issued pursuant to that section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            49 FR 27724
          </aref>
          , July 5, 1984, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            59 FR 31117
          </aref>
          , June 17, 1994]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6475'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:F:658:-:658.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        658.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Guidelines for use of criteria.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          49 FR 27724
        </aref>
        , July 5, 1984, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          59 FR 31118
        </aref>
        , June 17, 1994]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='658' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              658.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Guidelines for use of criteria.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          As stated above and as provided in the Act, each Federal agency shall
          use the criteria provided in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='658' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              658.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
           to identify and take into account the adverse effects of Federal
          programs on the protection of farmland. The agencies are to consider
          alternative actions, as appropriate, that could lessen such adverse
          effects, and assure that such Federal programs, to the extent
          practicable, are compatible with State, unit of local government and
          private programs and policies to protect farmland. The following are
          guidelines to assist the agencies in these tasks:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An agency may determine whether or not a site is farmland as
            defined in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='658' sect='2' psec='#a' tq='N'>
                658.2(a)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             or the agency may request that NRCS make such a determination. If
            an agency elects not to make its own determination, it should make a
            request to NRCS on Form AD-1006, the Farmland Conversion Impact
            Rating Form, available at NRCS offices, for determination of whether
            the site is farmland subject to the Act. If neither the entire site
            nor any part of it are subject to the Act, then the Act will not
            apply and NRCS will so notify the agency. If the site is determined
            by NRCS to be subject to the Act, then NRCS will measure the
            relative value of the site as farmland on a scale of 0 to 100
            according to the information sources listed in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='658' sect='5' psec='#a' tq='N'>
                658.5(a)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . NRCS will respond to these requests within 10 working days of
            their receipt except that in cases where a site visit or land
            evaluation system design is needed, NRCS will respond in 30 working
            days. In the event that NRCS fails to complete its response within
            the required period, if further delay would interfere with
            construction activities, the agency should proceed as though the
            site were not farmland.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Form AD 1006, returned to the agency by NRCS will also include
            the following incidental information: The total amount of farmable
            land (the land in the unit of local government&apos;s jurisdiction
            that is capable of producing the commonly grown crop); the
            percentage of the jurisdiction that is farmland covered by the Act;
            the percentage of farmland in the jurisdiction that the project
            would convert; and the percentage of farmland in the local
            government&apos;s jurisdiction with the same or higher relative
            value than the land that the project would convert. These statistics
            will not be part of the criteria scoring process, but are intended
            simply to furnish additional background information to Federal
            agencies to aid them in considering the effects of their projects on
            farmland.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             After the agency receives from NRCS the score of a site&apos;s
            relative value as described in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='658' sect='4' psec='#a' tq='N'>
                658.4(a)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and then applies the site assessment criteria which are set forth
            in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='658' sect='5' psec='#b' tq='N'>
                658.5 (b) and (c)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , the agency will assign to the site a combined score of up to 260
            points, composed of up to 100 points for relative value and up to
            160 points for the site assessment. With this score the agency will
            be able to identify the effect of its programs on farmland, and make
            a determination as to the suitability of the site for protection as
            farmland. Once this score is computed, USDA recommends:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Sites with the highest combined scores be regarded as most suitable
            for protection under these criteria and sites with the lowest
            scores, as least suitable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Sites receiving a total score of less than 160 need not be given
            further consideration for protection and no additional sites need to
            be evaluated.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Sites receiving scores totaling 160 or more be given increasingly
            higher levels of consideration for protection.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When making decisions on proposed actions for sites receiving
            scores 
            <PRTPAGE P='607' />
            totaling 160 or more, agency personnel consider:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_4_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Use of land that is not farmland or use of existing structures;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_4_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Alternative sites, locations and designs that would serve the
            proposed purpose but convert either fewer acres of farmland or other
            farmland that has a lower relative value;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_4_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Special siting requirements of the proposed project and the extent
            to which an alternative site fails to satisfy the special siting
            requirements as well as the originally selected site.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Federal agencies may elect to assign the site assessment criteria
            relative weightings other than those shown in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='658' sect='5' psec='#b' tq='N'>
                658.5 (b) and (c)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . If an agency elects to do so, USDA recommends that the agency
            adopt its alternative weighting system (1) through rulemaking in
            consultation with USDA, and (2) as a system to be used uniformly
            throughout the agency. USDA recommends that the weightings stated in
            
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='658' sect='5' psec='#b' tq='N'>
                658.5 (b) and (c)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             be used until an agency issues a final rule to change the
            weightings.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             It is advisable that evaluations and analyses of prospective
            farmland conversion impacts be made early in the planning process
            before a site or design is selected, and that, where possible,
            agencies make the FPPA evaluations part of the National
            Environmental Policy Act (NEPA) process. Under the agency&apos;s own
            NEPA regulations, some categories of projects may be excluded from
            NEPA which may still be covered under the FPPA. 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              Section 1540(c)(4) of
            </aref>
             the Act exempts projects that were beyond the planning stage and
            were in either the active design or construction state on the
            effective date of the Act. 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              Section 1547(b)
            </aref>
             exempts acquisition or use of farmland for national defense
            purposes. There are no other exemptions of projects by category in
            the Act.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Numerous States and units of local government are developing and
            adopting Land Evaluation and Site Assessment (LESA) systems to
            evaluate the productivity of agricultural land and its suitability
            for conversion to nonagricultural use. Therefore, States and units
            of local government may have already performed an evaluation using
            criteria similar to those contained in this rule applicable to
            Federal agencies. USDA recommends that where sites are to be
            evaluated within a jurisdiction having a State or local LESA system
            that has been approved by the governing body of such jurisdiction
            and has been placed on the NRCS State conservationist&apos;s list as
            one which meets the purpose of the FPPA in balance with other public
            policy objectives, Federal agencies use that system to make the
            evaluation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To meet reporting requirements of 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 1546 of
            </aref>
             the Act, 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='4207' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/4207.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 4207
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , and for data collection purposes, after the agency has made a
            final decision on a project in which one or more of the alternative
            sites contain farmland subject to the FPPA, the agency is requested
            to return a copy of the Form AD-1006, which indicates the final
            decision of the agency, to the NRCS field office.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Once a Federal agency has performed an analysis under the FPPA for
            the conversion of a site, that agency&apos;s, or a second Federal
            agency&apos;s determination with regard to additional assistance or
            actions on the same site do not require additional redundant FPPA
            analysis.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            49 FR 27724
          </aref>
          , July 5, 1984, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            59 FR 31118
          </aref>
          , June 17, 1994]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6476'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:F:658:-:658.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        658.5
      </num>
      <head>
        Criteria.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='658' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              658.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Criteria.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          This section states the criteria required by 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 1541(a) of
          </aref>
           the Act, 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='4202' note='' psec='#a' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/4202.html#a'>
              7 U.S.C. 4202(a)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          . The criteria were developed by the Secretary of Agriculture in
          cooperation with other Federal agencies. They are in two parts, (1)
          the land evaluation criterion, relative value, for which NRCS will
          provide the rating or score, and (2) the site assessment criteria, for
          which each Federal agency must develop its own ratings or scores. The
          criteria are as follows:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Land Evaluation Criterion—Relative Value.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The land evaluation criterion is based on information from several
            sources including national cooperative soil surveys or other
            acceptable soil surveys, NRCS field office technical guides, soil
            potential ratings or soil productivity ratings, land capability
            classifications, and important farmland determinations. Based on
            this information, groups of soils within a local government&apos;s
            jurisdiction will be 
            <PRTPAGE P='608' />
            evaluated and assigned a score between 0 to 100, representing the
            relative value, for agricultural production, of the farmland to be
            converted by the project compared to other farmland in the same
            local government jurisdiction, This score will be the Relative Value
            Rating on Form AD 1006.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Site Assessment Criteria.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Federal agencies are to use the following criteria to assess the
            suitability of each proposed site or design alternative for
            protection as farmland along with the score from the land evaluation
            criterion described in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='658' sect='5' psec='#a' tq='N'>
                658.5(a)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . Each criterion will be given a score on a scale of 0 to the
            maximum points shown. Conditions suggesting top, intermediate and
            bottom scores are indicated for each criterion. The agency would
            make scoring decisions in the context of each proposed site or
            alternative action by examining the site, the surrounding area, and
            the programs and policies of the State or local unit of government
            in which the site is located. Where one given location has more than
            one design alternative, each design should be considered as an
            alternative site. The site assessment criteria are:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             How much land is in nonurban use within a radius of 1.0 mile from
            where the project is intended? 
          </text>
        </P>
        <EXTRACT>
          <FP SOURCE='FP-1'>
            More than 90 percent—15 points
          </FP>
          <FP SOURCE='FP-1'>
            90 to 20 percent—14 to 1 point(s)
          </FP>
          <FP SOURCE='FP-1'>
            Less than 20 percent—0 points
          </FP>
        </EXTRACT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             How much of the perimeter of the site borders on land in nonurban
            use? 
          </text>
        </P>
        <EXTRACT>
          <FP SOURCE='FP-1'>
            More than 90 percent—10 points
          </FP>
          <FP SOURCE='FP-1'>
            90 to 20 percent—9 to 1 point(s)
          </FP>
          <FP SOURCE='FP-1'>
            Less than 20 percent—0 points
          </FP>
        </EXTRACT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             How much of the site has been farmed (managed for a scheduled
            harvest or timber activity) more than 5 of the last 10 years?
          </text>
        </P>
        <EXTRACT>
          <FP SOURCE='FP-1'>
            More than 90 percent—20 points
          </FP>
          <FP SOURCE='FP-1'>
            90 to 20 percent—19 to 1 points(s)
          </FP>
          <FP SOURCE='FP-1'>
            Less than 20 percent—0 points
          </FP>
        </EXTRACT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is the site subject to State or unit of local government policies
            or programs to protect farmland or covered by private programs to
            protect farmland? 
          </text>
        </P>
        <EXTRACT>
          <FP SOURCE='FP-1'>
            Site is protected—20 points
          </FP>
          <FP SOURCE='FP-1'>
            Site is not protected—0 points
          </FP>
        </EXTRACT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             How close is the site to an urban built-up area? 
          </text>
        </P>
        <EXTRACT>
          <FP SOURCE='FP-1'>
            The site is 2 miles or more from an urban built-up area—15 points
          </FP>
          <FP SOURCE='FP-1'>
            The site is more than 1 mile but less than 2 miles from an urban
            built-up area—10 points
          </FP>
          <FP SOURCE='FP-1'>
            The site is less than 1 mile from, but is not adjacent to an urban
            built-up area—5 points
          </FP>
          <FP SOURCE='FP-1'>
            The site is adjacent to an urban built-up area—0 points
          </FP>
        </EXTRACT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             How close is the site to water lines, sewer lines and/or other
            local facilities and services whose capacities and design would
            promote nonagricultural use? 
          </text>
        </P>
        <EXTRACT>
          <FP SOURCE='FP-1'>
            None of the services exist nearer than 3 miles from the site—15
            points
          </FP>
          <FP SOURCE='FP-1'>
            Some of the services exist more than 1 but less than 3 miles from
            the site—10 points
          </FP>
          <FP SOURCE='FP-1'>
            All of the services exist within 
            <FR>
              1/2
            </FR>
             mile of the site—0 points
          </FP>
        </EXTRACT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is the farm unit(s) containing the site (before the project) as
            large as the average-size farming unit in the county? (Average farm
            sizes in each county are available from the NRCS field offices in
            each State. Data are from the latest available Census of
            Agriculture, Acreage of Farm Units in Operation with $1,000 or more
            in sales.) 
          </text>
        </P>
        <EXTRACT>
          <FP SOURCE='FP-1'>
            As large or larger—10 points
          </FP>
          <FP SOURCE='FP-1'>
            Below average—deduct 1 point for each 5 percent below the average,
            down to 0 points if 50 percent or more below average—9 to 0 points
          </FP>
        </EXTRACT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If this site is chosen for the project, how much of the remaining
            land on the farm will become non-farmable because of interference
            with land patterns? 
          </text>
        </P>
        <EXTRACT>
          <FP SOURCE='FP-1'>
            Acreage equal to more than 25 percent of acres directly converted by
            the project—10 points
          </FP>
          <FP SOURCE='FP-1'>
            Acreage equal to between 25 and 5 percent of the acres directly
            converted by the project—9 to 1 point(s)
          </FP>
          <FP SOURCE='FP-1'>
            Acreage equal to less than 5 percent of the acres directly converted
            by the project—0 points
          </FP>
        </EXTRACT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Does the site have available adequate supply of farm support
            services and markets, i.e., farm suppliers, equipment dealers,
            processing and storage facilities and farmer&apos;s markets? 
          </text>
        </P>
        <EXTRACT>
          <FP SOURCE='FP-1'>
            All required services are available—5 points
            <PRTPAGE P='609' />
          </FP>
          <FP SOURCE='FP-1'>
            Some required services are available—4 to 1 point(s)
          </FP>
          <FP SOURCE='FP-1'>
            No required services are available—0 points
          </FP>
        </EXTRACT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Does the site have substantial and well-maintained on-farm
            investments such as barns, other storage buildings, fruit trees and
            vines, field terraces, drainage, irrigation, waterways, or other
            soil and water conservation measures? 
          </text>
        </P>
        <EXTRACT>
          <FP SOURCE='FP-1'>
            High amount of on-farm investment—20 points
          </FP>
          <FP SOURCE='FP-1'>
            Moderate amount of on-farm investment—19 to 1 point(s)
          </FP>
          <FP SOURCE='FP-1'>
            No on-farm investment—0 points
          </FP>
        </EXTRACT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_11'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (11)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Would the project at this site, by converting farmland to
            nonagricultural use, reduce the demand for farm support services so
            as to jeopardize the continued existence of these support services
            and thus, the viability of the farms remaining in the area? 
          </text>
        </P>
        <EXTRACT>
          <FP SOURCE='FP-1'>
            Substantial reduction in demand for support services if the site is
            converted—10 points
          </FP>
          <FP SOURCE='FP-1'>
            Some reduction in demand for support services if the site is
            converted—9 to 1 point(s)
          </FP>
          <FP SOURCE='FP-1'>
            No significant reduction in demand for support services if the site
            is converted—0 points
          </FP>
        </EXTRACT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_12'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (12)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is the kind and intensity of the proposed use of the site
            sufficiently incompatible with agriculture that it is likely to
            contribute to the eventual conversion of surrounding farmland to
            nonagricultural use? 
          </text>
        </P>
        <EXTRACT>
          <FP SOURCE='FP-1'>
            Proposed project is incompatible with existing agricultural use of
            surrounding farmland—10 points
          </FP>
          <FP SOURCE='FP-1'>
            Proposed project is tolerable to existing agricultural use of
            surrounding farmland—9 to 1 point(s)
          </FP>
          <FP SOURCE='FP-1'>
            Proposed project is fully compatible with existing agricultural use
            of surrounding farmland—0 points
          </FP>
        </EXTRACT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Corridor-type Site Assessment Criteria.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The following criteria are to be used for projects that have a
            linear or corridor-type site configuration connecting two distant
            points, and crossing several different tracts of land. These include
            utility lines, highways, railroads, stream improvements, and flood
            control systems. Federal agencies are to assess the suitability of
            each corridor-type site or design alternative for protection as
            farmland along with the land evaluation information described in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='658' sect='4' psec='#a' tq='N'>
                658.4(a)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . All criteria for corridor-type sites will be scored as shown in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='658' sect='5' psec='#b' tq='N'>
                658.5(b)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             for other sites, except as noted below:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Criteria 5 and 6 will not be considered.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Criterion 8 will be scored on a scale of 0 to 25 points, and
            criterion 11 will be scored on a scale of 0 to 25 points.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6477'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:F:658:-:658.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        658.6
      </num>
      <head>
        Technical assistance.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='658' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              658.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Technical assistance.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              Section 1543 of
            </aref>
             the Act, 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='4204' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/4204.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 4204
              </subref>
            </aref>
             states, “The Secretary is encouraged to provide technical
            assistance to any State or unit of local government, or any
            nonprofit organization, as determined by the Secretary, that desires
            to develop programs or policies to limit the conversion of
            productive farmland to nonagricultural uses.” In 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              § 2.62, of
            </aref>
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='2' tq='N'>
                2
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , subtitle A, NRCS is delegated leadership responsibility within
            USDA for the activities treated in this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In providing assistance to States, local units of government, and
            nonprofit organizations, USDA will make available maps and other
            soils information from the national cooperative soil survey through
            NRCS field offices.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Additional assistance, within available resources, may be obtained
            from local offices of other USDA agencies. The Agricultural
            Stabilization and Conservation Service and the Forest Service can
            provide aerial photographs, crop history data, and related
            information. A reasonable fee may be charged. In many States, the
            Cooperative Extension Service can provide help in understanding and
            identifying farmland protection issues and problems, resolving
            conflicts, developing alternatives, deciding on appropriate actions,
            and implementing those decisions.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Officials of State agencies, local units of government, nonprofit
            organizations, or regional, area, State-level, or field offices of
            Federal agencies may obtain assistance by contacting the office of
            the NRCS State conservationist. A list of Natural Resources
            Conservation Service State office locations appears in appendix A, 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='661' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
                661.6
              </subref>
               of this title
            </aref>
            . If further assistance is needed, requests 
            <PRTPAGE P='610' />
            should be made to the Assistant Secretary for Natural Resources and
            Environment, Office of the Secretary, Department of Agriculture,
            Washington, DC 20250.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6478'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:F:658:-:658.7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        658.7
      </num>
      <head>
        USDA assistance with Federal agencies&apos; reviews of policies and
        procedures.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          49 FR 27724
        </aref>
        , July 5, 1984, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          59 FR 31118
        </aref>
        , June 17, 1994]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='658' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              658.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          USDA assistance with Federal agencies&apos; reviews of policies and
          procedures.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              Section 1542(a) of
            </aref>
             the Act, 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='4203' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/4203.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 4203
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , states, “Each department, agency, independent commission or other
            unit of the Federal Government, with the assistance of the
            Department of Agriculture, shall review current provisions of law,
            administrative rules and regulations, and policies and procedures
            applicable to it to determine whether any provision thereof will
            prevent such unit of the Federal Government from taking appropriate
            action to comply fully with the provisions of this subtitle.”
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              Section 1542(b) of
            </aref>
             the Act, 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='4203' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/4203.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 4203
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , requires, as appropriate, each department, agency, independent
            commission, or other unit of the Federal Government, with the
            assistance of the Department of Agriculture, to develop proposals
            for action to bring its programs, authorities, and administrative
            activities into conformity with the purpose and policy of the Act.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             USDA will provide certain assistance to other Federal agencies for
            the purposes specified in 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 1542 of
            </aref>
             the Act, 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='4203' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/4203.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 4203
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . If a Federal agency identifies or suggests changes in laws,
            administrative rules and regulations, policies, or procedures that
            may affect the agency&apos;s compliance with the Act, USDA can
            advise the agency of the probable effects of the changes on the
            protection of farmland. To request this assistance, officials of
            Federal agencies should correspond with the Chief, Natural Resources
            Conservation Service, P.O. Box 2890, Washington, DC 20013.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To meet the reporting requirements of 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 1546 of
            </aref>
             the Act, 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='4207' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/4207.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 4207
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , and for data collection purposes, each Federal agency is requested
            to report to the Chief of the Natural Resources Conservation Service
            by November 15th of each year on progress made during the prior
            fiscal year to implement 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              sections 1542 (a) and (b) of
            </aref>
             the Act, 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='4203' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/4203.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 4203
              </subref>
            </aref>
             (a) and (b). Until an agency fully implements those sections, the
            agency should continue to make the annual report, but may omit the
            report upon full implementation. However, an agency is requested to
            file an annual report for any future year in which the agency has
            substantially changed its process for compliance with the Act.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            49 FR 27724
          </aref>
          , July 5, 1984, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            59 FR 31118
          </aref>
          , June 17, 1994]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>