<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol1'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15d
    </extid>
    <num>
      15d
    </num>
    <head>
      NONDISCRIMINATION IN PROGRAMS OR ACTIVITIES CONDUCTED BY THE UNITED STATES
      DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='5' sect='301' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/5/301.html'>
              5 U.S.C. 301
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            64 FR 66709
          </aref>
          , Nov. 30, 1999, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='680'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15d:-:15d.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15d.1
      </num>
      <head>
        Purpose.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15d' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              15d.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Purpose.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The purpose of this part is to set forth the nondiscrimination policy
          of the United States Department of Agriculture in programs or
          activities conducted by the Department, including such programs and
          activities in which the Department or any agency thereof makes
          available any benefit directly to persons under such programs and
          activities.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='681'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15d:-:15d.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15d.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Discrimination prohibited.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15d' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              15d.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Discrimination prohibited.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No agency, officer, or employee of the United States Department of
            Agriculture shall, on the ground of race, color, religion, sex, age,
            national origin, marital status, familial status, 
            <PRTPAGE P='465' />
            sexual orientation, or disability, or because all of part of an
            individual&apos;s income is derived from any public assistance
            program, exclude from participation in, deny the benefits of, or
            subject to discrimination any person in the United States under any
            program or activity conducted by the United States Department of
            Agriculture.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No person shall be subjected to reprisal for opposing any practice
            prohibited by this part or for filing a complaint or participating
            in any other manner in a proceeding under this part.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='682'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15d:-:15d.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15d.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Compliance.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15d' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              15d.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Compliance.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The Director of the Office of Civil Rights shall evaluate each
          agency&apos;s efforts to comply with this part and shall make
          recommendations for improving such efforts.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='683'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15d:-:15d.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15d.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Complaints.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15d' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              15d.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Complaints.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any person who believes that he or she (or any specific class of
            individuals) has been, or is being, subjected to practices
            prohibited by this part may file on his or her own, or through an
            authorized representative, a written complaint alleging such
            discrimination. No particular form of complaint is required. The
            written complaint must be filed within 180 calendar days from the
            date the person knew or reasonably should have known of the alleged
            discrimination, unless the time is extended for good cause by the
            Director of the Office of Civil Rights or his or her designee. Any
            person who complains of discrimination under this part in any
            fashion shall be advised of his or her right to file a complaint as
            herein provided.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All complaints under this part should be filed with the Director of
            the Office of Civil Rights, United States Department of Agriculture,
            Washington, D.C. 20250, who will investigate the complaints. The
            Director of the Office of Civil Rights will make final
            determinations as to the merits of complaints under this part and as
            to the corrective actions required to resolve program complainants.
            The complaint will be notified of the final determination on his or
            her complaint.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any complaint filed under this part alleging discrimination on the
            basis of disability will be processed under 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='15e' tq='N'>
                15e
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>