<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol7'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:786
    </extid>
    <num>
      786
    </num>
    <head>
      DAIRY DISASTER ASSISTANCE PAYMENT PROGRAM (DDAP-III)
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            Sec. 9007
          </aref>
          , 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Pub. L. 110-28' alt='Pub. L. 110-28' href='http://www.gpo.gov/fdsys/pkg/PLAW-110publ28/html/PLAW-110publ28.htm'>
            Pub. L. 110-28
          </aref>
          , 
          <aref target='_blank' title='121 Stat. 112' alt='121 Stat. 112' href='http://www.gpo.gov/fdsys/pkg/STATUTE-121/html/STATUTE-121-Pg112.htm'>
            121 Stat. 112
          </aref>
          ; and 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            Sec. 743
          </aref>
          , 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Pub. L. 110-161' alt='Pub. L. 110-161' href='http://www.gpo.gov/fdsys/pkg/PLAW-110publ161/html/PLAW-110publ161.htm'>
            Pub. L. 110-161
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            73 FR 11522
          </aref>
          , Mar. 4, 2008, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='7268'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:786:-:786.100
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        786.100
      </num>
      <head>
        Applicability.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='786' sect='100' psec='' tq='N'>
              786.100
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Applicability.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subject to the availability of funds, this part specifies the terms
            and conditions applicable to the Dairy Disaster Assistance Payment
            Program (DDAP-III) authorized by 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 9007 of
            </aref>
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 110-28' alt='Public Law 110-28' href='http://www.gpo.gov/fdsys/pkg/PLAW-110publ28/html/PLAW-110publ28.htm'>
              Public Law 110-28
            </aref>
             (extended by 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Pub. L. 110-161' alt='Pub. L. 110-161' href='http://www.gpo.gov/fdsys/pkg/PLAW-110publ161/html/PLAW-110publ161.htm'>
              Pub. L. 110-161
            </aref>
            ). Benefits are available to eligible United States producers who
            have suffered dairy production losses in eligible counties as a
            result of a natural disaster declared during the period between
            January 1, 2005, and December 31, 2007, (that is, after January 1,
            2005, and before December 31, 2007).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be eligible for this program, a producer must have been a milk
            producer anytime during the period of January 2, 2005, through
            December 30, 2007, in a county declared a natural disaster by the
            Secretary of Agriculture, declared a major disaster or emergency
            designated by the President of the United States. For a county for
            which there was a timely Presidential declaration, but the
            declaration did not cover the loss, the county may still be eligible
            if the county is one for which an appropriate determination of a
            Farm Service Agency (FSA) Administrator&apos;s Physical Loss Notice
            applies. Counties contiguous to a county that is directly eligible
            by way of a natural disaster declaration are also eligible. Only
            losses occurring in eligible counties are eligible for payment in
            this program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subject to the availability of funds, FSA will provide benefits to
            eligible dairy producers. Additional terms and conditions may be
            specified in the payment application that must be completed and
            submitted by producers to receive a disaster assistance payment for
            dairy production losses.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be eligible for payments, producers must meet the provisions of,
            and their losses must meet the conditions of, this part and any
            other conditions imposed by FSA.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='7269'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:786:-:786.101
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        786.101
      </num>
      <head>
        Administration.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='786' sect='101' psec='' tq='N'>
              786.101
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Administration.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             DDAP-III will be administered under the general supervision of the
            Administrator, FSA, or a designee, and be carried out in the field
            by FSA State and county committees (State and county committees) and
            FSA employees.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State and county committees, and representatives and employees
            thereof, do not have the authority to modify or waive any of the
            provisions of the regulations of this part.
            <PRTPAGE P='375' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State committee will take any action required by the
            regulations of this part that has not been taken by the county
            committee. The State committee will also:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Correct, or require the county committee to correct, any action
            taken by such county committee that is not in accordance with the
            regulations of this part; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Require a county committee to withhold taking any action that is
            not in accordance with the regulations of this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No provision of delegation in this part to a State or county
            committee will preclude the Administrator, FSA, or a designee, from
            determining any question arising under the program or from reversing
            or modifying any determination made by the State or county
            committee.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Deputy Administrator, Farm Programs, FSA, may authorize State
            and county committees to waive or modify deadlines in cases where
            lateness or failure to meet such requirements do not adversely
            affect the operation of the DDAP-III and does not violate statutory
            limitations of the program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Data furnished by the applicants is used to determine eligibility
            for program benefits. Although participation in DDAP-III is
            voluntary, program benefits will not be provided unless the producer
            furnishes all requested data.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='7270'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:786:-:786.102
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        786.102
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='786' sect='102' psec='' tq='N'>
              786.102
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The definitions in 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR part 
            <subref title='7' part='718' tq='N'>
              718
            </subref>
          </aref>
           apply to this part except to the extent they are inconsistent with
          the provisions of this part. In addition, for the purpose of this
          part, the following definitions apply.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Administrator
          </E>
           means the FSA Administrator, or a designee.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Application
          </E>
           means DDAP-III application.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Application period
          </E>
           means the time period established by the Deputy Administrator for
          producers to apply for program benefits.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Base annual production
          </E>
           means the pounds of production determined by multiplying the average
          annual production per cow calculated from base period information
          times the average number of cows in the dairy herd during each
          applicable disaster year.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            County committee
          </E>
           means the FSA county committee.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            County office
          </E>
           means the FSA office responsible for administering FSA programs for
          farms located in a specific area in a State.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Dairy operation
          </E>
           means any person or group of persons who, as a single unit, as
          determined by FSA, produces and markets milk commercially from cows
          and whose production facilities are located in the United States.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Department or USDA
          </E>
           means the United States Department of Agriculture.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Deputy Administrator
          </E>
           means the Deputy Administrator for Farm Programs (DAFP), FSA, or a
          designee.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Disaster claim period
          </E>
           means the calendar year(s) applicable to the disaster declaration
          during the eligible period in which the production losses occurred.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Disaster county
          </E>
           means a county included in the geographic area covered by a natural
          disaster declaration, and any county contiguous to a county that
          qualifies by a natural disaster declaration.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Farm Service Agency or FSA
          </E>
           means the Farm Service Agency of the Department.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Hundredweight or cwt.
          </E>
           means 100 pounds.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Milk handler or cooperative
          </E>
           means the marketing agency to, or through, which the producer
          commercially markets whole milk.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Milk marketings
          </E>
           means a marketing of milk for which there is a verifiable sale or
          delivery record of milk marketed for commercial use.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Natural disaster declaration
          </E>
           means a natural disaster declaration issued by the Secretary of
          Agriculture after January 1, 2005, but before December 31, 2007, under
          
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 321(a) of
          </aref>
           the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='1961' note='' psec='#a' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1961.html#a'>
              7 U.S.C. 1961(a)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ), a major disaster or emergency designation by the President of the
          United States in that period under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster
          Relief and Emergency Assistance Act, or a determination of a Farm
          Service Agency Administrator&apos;s Physical Loss Notice for a county
          covered 
          <PRTPAGE P='376' />
          in an otherwise eligible Presidential declaration.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Payment pounds
          </E>
           means the pounds of milk production from a dairy operation for which
          the dairy producer is eligible to be paid under this part.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Producer
          </E>
           means any individual, group of individuals, partnership, corporation,
          estate, trust association, cooperative, or other business enterprise
          or other legal entity who is, or whose members are, a citizen of, or a
          legal resident alien in, the United States, and who directly or
          indirectly, as determined by the Secretary, have a share entitlement
          or ownership interest in a commercial dairy&apos;s milk production and
          who share in the risk of producing milk, and make contributions
          (including land, labor, management, equipment, or capital) to the
          dairy farming operation of the individual or entity.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Reliable production evidence
          </E>
           means records provided by the producer subject to a determination of
          acceptability by the county committee that are used to substantiate
          the amount of production reported when verifiable records are not
          available; the records may include copies of receipts, ledgers of
          income, income statements of deposit slips, register tapes, and
          records to verify production costs, contemporaneous measurements, and
          contemporaneous diaries.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Verifiable production records
          </E>
           means evidence that is used to substantiate the amount of production
          marketed, including any dumped production, and that can be verified by
          FSA through an independent source.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='7271'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:786:-:786.103
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        786.103
      </num>
      <head>
        Time and method of application.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='786' sect='103' psec='' tq='N'>
              786.103
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Time and method of application.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Dairy producers may obtain an application, in person, by mail, by
            telephone, or by facsimile from any FSA county office. In addition,
            applicants may download a copy of the application at 
            <E T='03'>
              http://www.sc.egov.usda.gov.
            </E>
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A request for benefits under this part must be submitted on a
            completed DDAP-III application. Applications and any other
            supporting documentation must be submitted to the FSA county office
            serving the county where the dairy operation is located, but, in any
            case, must be received by the FSA county office by the close of
            business on the date established by the Deputy Administrator.
            Applications not received by the close of business on such date will
            be disapproved as not having been timely filed and the dairy
            producer will not be eligible for benefits under this program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All persons who share in the milk production of the dairy operation
            and risk of the dairy operation&apos;s total production must certify
            to the information on the application before the application will be
            considered complete.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each dairy producer requesting benefits under this part must
            certify to the accuracy and truthfulness of the information provided
            in their application and any supporting documentation. Any
            information entered on the application will be considered
            information from the applicant regardless of who entered the
            information on the application. All information provided is subject
            to verification by FSA. Refusal to allow FSA or any other agency of
            the Department of Agriculture to verify any information provided may
            result in a denial of eligibility. Furnishing the information is
            voluntary; however, without it program benefits will not be
            approved. Providing a false certification to the Government may be
            punishable by imprisonment, fines, and other penalties or sanctions.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='7272'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:786:-:786.104
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        786.104
      </num>
      <head>
        Eligibility.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='786' sect='104' psec='' tq='N'>
              786.104
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Eligibility.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Producers in the United States will be eligible to receive dairy
            disaster benefits under this part only if they have suffered dairy
            production losses, previously uncompensated by disaster payments
            including any previous dairy disaster payment program, during the
            claim period applicable to a natural disaster declaration in a
            disaster county. To be eligible to receive payments under this part,
            producers in a dairy operation must:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Have produced and commercially marketed milk in the United States
            and commercially marketed the milk produced anytime during the
            period of January 2, 2005 through December 30, 2007;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be a producer on a dairy farm operation physically located in an
            eligible county where dairy production losses were incurred as a
            result of a 
            <PRTPAGE P='377' />
            disaster for which an applicable natural disaster declaration was
            issued between January 1, 2005 and December 31, 2007, and limit
            their claims to losses that occurred in those counties, specific to
            conditions resulting from the declared disaster as described in the
            natural disaster declaration;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provide adequate proof, to the satisfaction of the FSA county
            committee, of the average number of cows in the dairy herd and
            annual milk production commercially marketed by all persons in the
            eligible dairy operation during the years of the base period (2003
            and 2004 calendar years) and applicable disaster year that
            corresponds with the issuance date of the applicable natural
            disaster declaration, or other period as determined by FSA, to
            determine the total pounds of eligible losses that will be used for
            payment; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Apply for payments during the application period established by the
            Deputy Administrator.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payments may be made for losses suffered by an otherwise eligible
            producer who is now deceased or is a dissolved entity if a
            representative who currently has authority to enter into a contract
            for the producer or the producer&apos;s estate signs the application
            for payment. Proof of authority to sign for the deceased
            producer&apos;s estate or a dissolved entity must be provided. If a
            producer is now a dissolved general partnership or joint venture,
            all members of the general partnership or joint venture at the time
            of dissolution or their duly-authorized representatives must sign
            the application for payment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Producers associated with a dairy operation must submit a timely
            application and satisfy the terms and conditions of this part,
            instructions issued by FSA, and instructions contained in the
            application to be eligible for benefits under this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             As a condition to receive benefits under this part, a producer must
            have been in compliance with the Highly Erodible Land Conservation
            and Wetland Conservation provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='12' tq='N'>
                12
              </subref>
            </aref>
             for the calendar year applicable to the natural disaster
            declaration and loss claim period, and must not otherwise be barred
            from receiving benefits under 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='12' tq='N'>
                12
              </subref>
            </aref>
             or any other law or regulation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payments are limited to losses in eligible counties, in eligible
            disaster years.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All payments under this part are subject to the availability of
            funds.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Eligible losses are determined from the applicable base annual
            production, as defined in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='786' sect='102' psec='' tq='N'>
                786.102
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , that corresponds to the natural disaster declaration and must have
            occurred during that same period as follows:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For disaster declarations for disasters during a calendar year
            (2005, 2006, or 2007), the disaster claim period is the full
            calendar year and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For disaster declarations issued during one calendar year that ends
            in another calendar year, the producer will be eligible for both
            disaster years.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Deductions in eligibility will be made for any disaster payments
            previously received for the loss including any made under a previous
            dairy disaster assistance payment program for 2005.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='7273'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:786:-:786.105
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        786.105
      </num>
      <head>
        Proof of production.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='786' sect='105' psec='' tq='N'>
              786.105
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Proof of production.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Evidence of production is required to establish the commercial
            marketing and production history of the dairy operation so that
            dairy production losses can be computed in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='786' sect='106' psec='' tq='N'>
                786.106
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A dairy producer must, based on the instructions issued by the
            Deputy Administrator, provide adequate proof of the dairy
            operation&apos;s commercial production, including any dairy herd
            inventory records available for the operation, for the years of the
            base period (2003 and 2004 calendar years) and disaster claim period
            that corresponds with the issuance date of the applicable natural
            disaster declaration.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A producer must certify and provide such proof as requested that
            losses for which compensation is claimed were related to the
            disaster declaration issued and occurred in an eligible county
            during the eligible claim period.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A producer must certify to the average number of cows in the dairy
            herd during the base period and applicable disaster claim period
            when there is insufficient documentation available for verification.
            <PRTPAGE P='378' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Additional supporting documentation may be requested by FSA as
            necessary to verify production losses to the satisfaction of FSA.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Adequate proof of production history of the dairy operation under
            paragraph (b) of this section must be based on milk marketing
            statements obtained from the dairy operation&apos;s milk handler or
            marketing cooperative. Supporting documents may include, but are not
            limited to: Tank records, milk handler records, daily milk
            marketings, copies of any payments received from other sources for
            production losses, or any other documents available to confirm or
            adjust the production history losses incurred by the dairy
            operation. All information provided is subject to verification, spot
            check, and audit by FSA.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             As specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='786' sect='106' psec='' tq='N'>
                786.106
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , loss calculations will be based on comparing the expected base
            annual production consistent with this part and the actual
            production during the applicable disaster claim year. Such
            calculations are subject to adjustments as may be appropriate such
            as a correction for losses not due to the disaster. If adequate
            proof of normally marketed production and any other production for
            relevant periods is not presented to the satisfaction of FSA, the
            request for benefits will be rejected. Special adjustments for new
            producers may be made as determined necessary by the Administrator.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='7274'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:786:-:786.106
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        786.106
      </num>
      <head>
        Determination of losses incurred.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='786' sect='106' psec='' tq='N'>
              786.106
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Determination of losses incurred.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Eligible payable losses are calculated on a dairy operation by
            dairy operation basis and are limited to those occurring during the
            applicable disaster claim period, as provided by 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='786' sect='104' psec='#g' tq='N'>
                786.104(g)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , that corresponds with the applicable natural disaster declaration.
            Specifically, dairy production losses incurred by producers under
            this part are determined on the established history of the dairy
            operation&apos;s average number of cows in the dairy herd and actual
            commercial production marketed during the base period and applicable
            disaster claim period that corresponds with the applicable natural
            disaster declaration, as provided by the dairy operation consistent
            with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='786' sect='105' psec='' tq='N'>
                786.105
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . Except as otherwise provided in this part, the base annual
            production, as defined in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='786' sect='102' psec='' tq='N'>
                786.102
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and established in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='786' sect='104' psec='#g' tq='N'>
                786.104(g)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             is determined for each applicable disaster year based on the
            average annual production per cow determined according to the
            following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The average of annual marketed production during the base period
            calendar years of 2003 and 2004, divided by;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The average number of cows in the dairy operation&apos;s herd
            during the base period calendar years of 2003 and 2004.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If relevant information to calculate the average annual production
            per cow for one or both of the base period calendar years of 2003
            and 2004, is not available, an alternative method of determining the
            average annual production per cow may be established by the FSA
            Administrator. For example, for new dairies not in operation during
            2003 and 2004, information from three similar farms may be obtained
            by FSA to estimate base annual production.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The average annual production per cow, as determined according to
            paragraphs (a)(1) and (a)(2) of this section, is multiplied by the
            average number of cows in the dairy operation&apos;s herd during the
            applicable disaster year (excluding cow losses resulting from the
            disaster occurrence), to determine base annual production for the
            dairy operation for each applicable disaster claim period year.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The eligible dairy production losses for a dairy operation for each
            of the authorized disaster claim period years will be:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The relevant period&apos;s base annual production for the dairy
            operation calculated under paragraph (c) of this section less,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For each such disaster claim period for each dairy operation the
            actual commercially-marketed production relevant to that period.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Spoiled or dumped milk, disposed of for reasons unrelated to the
            disaster occurrence, must be counted as production for the relevant
            disaster claim period. Actual production losses may be adjusted to
            the extent the reduction in production is not certified by the
            producer to be the result of the disaster identified in the natural
            disaster declaration or is determined by FSA not 
            <PRTPAGE P='379' />
            to be related to the natural disaster identified in the natural
            disaster declaration. FSA county committees will determine
            production losses that are not caused by the disaster associated
            with the natural disaster declaration. The calculated production
            loss determined in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='786' sect='106' psec='#d' tq='N'>
                786.106(d)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             will be adjusted to account for pounds of production losses
            determined by the FSA county committee to not have been associated
            with the declared natural disaster for an eligible disaster county.
            The FSA county committee may convert cow numbers to actual pounds of
            production used in the adjustment, by multiplying the average annual
            production per cow determined from base period information, by the
            applicable number of cows determined to be ineligible to generate
            claims for benefits. Other appropriate adjustments will be made on
            such basis as the Deputy Administrator finds to be consistent with
            the objectives of the program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Actual production, as adjusted, that exceeds the base annual
            production will mean that the dairy operation incurred no eligible
            production losses for the corresponding claim period as a result of
            the natural disaster.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Eligible production losses as otherwise determined under paragraphs
            (a) through (f) of this section for each authorized year of the
            program are added together to determine total eligible losses
            incurred by the dairy operation under DDAP-III subject to all other
            eligibility requirements as may be included in this part or
            elsewhere, including the deduction for previous payments including
            those made under a previous DDAP program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payment on eligible dairy operation losses will be calculated using
            whole pounds of milk. No double counting is permitted, and only one
            payment will be made for each pound of milk calculated as an
            eligible loss after the distribution of the dairy operation&apos;s
            eligible production loss among the producers of the dairy operation
            according to 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='786' sect='107' psec='#b' tq='N'>
                786.107(b)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . Payments under this part will not be affected by any payments for
            dumped or spoiled milk that the dairy operation may have received
            from its milk handler, marketing cooperative, or any other private
            party; however, produced milk that was dumped or spoiled for reasons
            unrelated to the disaster occurrence will still count as production.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='7275'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:786:-:786.107
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        786.107
      </num>
      <head>
        Rate of payment and limitations on funding.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='786' sect='107' psec='' tq='N'>
              786.107
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Rate of payment and limitations on funding.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subject to the availability of funds, the payment rate for eligible
            production losses determined according to 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='786' sect='106' psec='' tq='N'>
                786.106
              </subref>
            </aref>
             is, depending on the State, the annual average Mailbox milk price
            for the Marketing Order, applicable to the State where the eligible
            disaster county is located, as reported by the Agricultural
            Marketing Service during the relevant period. States not regulated
            under a Marketing Order will be assigned a payment rate based on
            contiguous or nearby State&apos;s Mailbox milk price. Maximum per
            pound payment rates for eligible losses for dairy operations located
            in specific states during the relevant period are as follows:
          </text>
        </P>
        <table class='gpotable' CDEF='s50,12,12,12,12' COLS='4' OPTS='L2'>
          <caption />
          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th>
                State
              </th>
              <th>
                Mailbox price 2005
              </th>
              <th>
                Mailbox price 2006
              </th>
              <th>
                Mailbox price 2007 *
              </th>
            </tr>
          </thead>
          <tfoot>
            <tr>
              <td class='tnote' colspan='4'>
                <E T='02'>
                  Note:
                </E>
                 Calculations are rounded to 7 decimal places.
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td class='tnote' colspan='4'>
                * Payment rates for 2007 are currently unavailable, but will be
                based on the annual average Mailbox milk price for the Marketing
                Order, applicable to the State where the eligible disaster
                county is located, as reported by the Agricultural Marketing
                Service, consistent with payment rates provided for 2005 and
                2006.
              </td>
            </tr>
          </tfoot>
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Alabama
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1596
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1443
              </td>
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Alaska
              </td>
              <td>
                0.2040
              </td>
              <td>
                0.2010
              </td>
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Arizona
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1388
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1128
              </td>
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Arkansas
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1596
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1443
              </td>
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                California
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1388
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1128
              </td>
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Colorado
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1403
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1214
              </td>
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Connecticut
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1539
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1344
              </td>
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Delaware
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1539
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1344
              </td>
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Florida
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1758
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1603
              </td>
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Georgia
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1596
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1443
              </td>
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Hawaii
              </td>
              <td>
                0.2700
              </td>
              <td>
                0.2600
              </td>
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Idaho
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1402
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1215
              </td>
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Illinois
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1514
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1283
              </td>
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Indiana
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1503
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1294
              </td>
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Iowa
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1507
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1285
              </td>
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Kansas
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1403
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1214
              </td>
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Kentucky
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1527
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1349
              </td>
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Louisiana
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1596
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1443
              </td>
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Maine
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1539
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1344
              </td>
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Maryland
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1539
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1344
              </td>
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Massachusetts
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1539
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1344
              </td>
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Michigan
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1478
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1264
              </td>
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Minnesota
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1512
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1277
              </td>
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Mississippi
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1596
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1443
              </td>
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Missouri (Northern)
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1403
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1214
              </td>
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Missouri (Southern)
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1467
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1254
              </td>
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Montana
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1512
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1277
              </td>
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Nebraska
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1403
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1214
              </td>
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Nevada
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1388
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1128
              </td>
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                New Hampshire
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1539
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1344
              </td>
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                New Jersey
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1539
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1344
              </td>
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                New Mexico
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1323
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1108
              </td>
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                New York
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1539
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1303
              </td>
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                North Carolina
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1527
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1349
              </td>
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                North Dakota
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1512
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1277
              </td>
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Ohio
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1506
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1302
              </td>
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Oklahoma
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1596
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1443
              </td>
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Oregon
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1402
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1215
              </td>
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Pennsylvania (Eastern)
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1539
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1340
              </td>
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Pennsylvania (Western)
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1539
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1302
              </td>
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Puerto Rico
              </td>
              <td>
                0.2550
              </td>
              <td>
                0.2570
              </td>
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Rhode Island
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1539
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1344
              </td>
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                South Carolina
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1527
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1349
              </td>
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                South Dakota
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1512
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1277
              </td>
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Tennessee
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1527
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1349
              </td>
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Texas
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1405
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1194
              </td>
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Vermont
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1539
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1344
              </td>
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Virginia
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1527
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1349
              </td>
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Washington
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1402
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1215
              </td>
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                West Virginia
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1506
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1302
              </td>
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Wisconsin
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1535
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1305
              </td>
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Wyoming
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1403
              </td>
              <td>
                0.1214
              </td>
              <td />
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subject to the availability of funds, each eligible dairy
            operation&apos;s payment is calculated by multiplying the applicable
            payment rate under paragraph (a) of this section by the
            operation&apos;s total eligible losses as adjusted pursuant to this
            part. Where there are multiple producers in the dairy operation,
            individual producers&apos; payments are disbursed according to each
            producer&apos;s share of the dairy operation&apos;s production as
            specified in the application.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the total value of losses claimed nationwide under paragraph (b)
            of this section exceeds the $16 million available for the DDAP-III,
            less any reserve that may be created under paragraph (e) of this
            section, total eligible losses of individual dairy operations that,
            as calculated as an overall percentage for each full disaster claim
            period applicable to the disaster declaration, are greater than 20
            percent of the total base annual production will be paid at the
            maximum rate under paragraph (a) of this section to the extent
            available funding allows. A loss of over 20 percent in only one or
            two months during the applicable disaster claim period does not of
            itself qualify for the maximum per-pound payment. Rather, the
            priority level must be reached as an average over the whole disaster
            claim period for the relevant calendar year. Total eligible losses
            for a producer, as calculated under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              § 786.106, of
            </aref>
             less than or equal to 20 percent during the eligible claim period
            will then be paid at a rate, not to exceed the rate allowed in
            paragraph (a) of this section, determined by dividing the eligible
            losses of less than 20 percent by the funds remaining after making
            payments for all eligible losses above the 20-percent threshold.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In no event will the payment exceed the value determined by
            multiplying the producer&apos;s total eligible loss times the
            average price received for commercial milk production in the 
            <PRTPAGE P='381' />
            producer&apos;s area as defined in paragraph (a) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No participant will receive disaster benefits under this part that
            in combination with the value of production not lost would result in
            an amount that exceeds 95 percent of the value of the expected
            production for the relevant period as estimated by the Secretary.
            Unless otherwise program funds would not be fully expended, the sum
            of the value of the production not lost, if any; and the disaster
            payment received under this part, cannot exceed 95 percent of what
            the production&apos;s value would have been if there had been no
            loss. In no case, however, may the value of production and the
            payment exceed the value the milk would have without the loss.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A reserve may be created to handle pending or disputed claims, but
            claims will not be payable once the available funding is expended.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='7276'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:786:-:786.108
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        786.108
      </num>
      <head>
        Availability of funds.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='786' sect='108' psec='' tq='N'>
              786.108
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Availability of funds.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The total available program funds are $16 million as provided by 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 9007 of
          </aref>
           Title IX of 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 110-28' alt='Public Law 110-28' href='http://www.gpo.gov/fdsys/pkg/PLAW-110publ28/html/PLAW-110publ28.htm'>
            Public Law 110-28
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='7277'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:786:-:786.109
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        786.109
      </num>
      <head>
        Appeals.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='786' sect='109' psec='' tq='N'>
              786.109
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Appeals.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Provisions of the appeal regulations set forth at 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR parts 
            <subref title='7' part='11' tq='N'>
              11
            </subref>
             and 
            <subref title='7' part='780' tq='N'>
              780
            </subref>
          </aref>
           apply to this part. Appeals of determinations of ineligibility or
          payment amounts are subject to the limitations in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='786' sect='107' psec='' tq='N'>
              786.107
            </subref>
             and 
            <subref title='7' part='786' sect='108' psec='' tq='N'>
              786.108
            </subref>
          </aref>
           and other limitations that may apply.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='7278'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:786:-:786.110
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        786.110
      </num>
      <head>
        Misrepresentation, scheme, or device.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='786' sect='110' psec='' tq='N'>
              786.110
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Misrepresentation, scheme, or device.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In addition to other penalties, sanctions, or remedies that may
            apply, a dairy producer is ineligible to receive assistance under
            this program if the producer is determined by FSA to have:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Adopted any scheme or device that tends to defeat the purpose of
            this program,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Made any fraudulent representation,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Misrepresented any fact affecting a program determination, or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Violated 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR 
              <subref title='7' part='795' sect='17' psec='' tq='N'>
                795.17
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and thus be ineligible for the year(s) of violation and the
            subsequent year.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any funds disbursed pursuant to this part to any person or dairy
            operation engaged in a misrepresentation, scheme, or device, must be
            refunded with interest together with such other sums as may become
            due. Interest will run from the date of the disbursement to the
            producer or other recipient of the payment from FSA. Any person or
            dairy operation engaged in acts prohibited by this section and any
            person or dairy operation receiving payment under this part is
            jointly and severally liable with other persons or dairy operations
            involved in such claim for benefits for any refund due under this
            section and for related charges. The remedies provided in this part
            are in addition to other civil, criminal, or administrative remedies
            that may apply.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='7279'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:786:-:786.111
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        786.111
      </num>
      <head>
        Death, incompetence, or disappearance.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='786' sect='111' psec='' tq='N'>
              786.111
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Death, incompetence, or disappearance.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          In the case of death, incompetency, disappearance, or dissolution of
          an individual or entity that is eligible to receive benefits in
          accordance with this part, such alternate person or persons specified
          in 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR part 
            <subref title='7' part='707' tq='N'>
              707
            </subref>
          </aref>
           may receive such benefits, as determined appropriate by FSA.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='7280'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:786:-:786.112
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        786.112
      </num>
      <head>
        Maintaining records.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='786' sect='112' psec='' tq='N'>
              786.112
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Maintaining records.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Persons applying for benefits under this program must maintain records
          and accounts to document all eligibility requirements specified herein
          and must keep such records and accounts for 3 years after the date of
          payment to their dairy operations under this program. Destruction of
          the records after such date is at the risk of the party required, by
          this part, to keep the records.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='7281'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:786:-:786.113
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        786.113
      </num>
      <head>
        Refunds; joint and several liability.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='786' sect='113' psec='' tq='N'>
              786.113
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Refunds; joint and several liability.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Excess payments, payments provided as the result of erroneous
            information provided by any person, or payments resulting from a
            failure to meet any requirement or condition for payment under the
            application or this part, must be refunded to FSA.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A refund required under this section is due with interest
            determined in accordance with paragraph (d) of this section and late
            payment charges as provided in 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='792' tq='N'>
                792
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . Notwithstanding any other regulation, interest 
            <PRTPAGE P='382' />
            will be due from the date of the disbursement to the producer or
            other recipient of the funds.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Persons signing a dairy operation&apos;s application as having an
            interest in the operation will be jointly and severally liable for
            any refund and related charges found to be due under this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the event FSA determines a participant owes a refund under this
            part, FSA will charge program interest from the date of disbursement
            of the erroneous payment. Such interest will accrue at the rate that
            the United States Department of the Treasury charges FSA for funds
            plus additional charges as deemed appropriate by the Administrator
            or provided for by regulation or statute.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The debt collection provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='792' tq='N'>
                792 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
             applies to this part except as is otherwise provided in this part.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='7282'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:786:-:786.114
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        786.114
      </num>
      <head>
        Miscellaneous provisions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='786' sect='114' psec='' tq='N'>
              786.114
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Miscellaneous provisions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payments or any portion thereof due under this part must be made
            without regard to questions of title under State law and without
            regard to any claim or lien against the livestock, or proceeds
            thereof, in favor of the owner or any other creditor except agencies
            and instrumentalities of the U.S. Government.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any producer entitled to any payment under this part may assign any
            payments in accordance with the provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1404' tq='N'>
                1404
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='7283'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:786:-:786.115
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        786.115
      </num>
      <head>
        Termination of program.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='786' sect='115' psec='' tq='N'>
              786.115
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Termination of program.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          This program will be terminated after payment has been made to those
          applicants certified as eligible pursuant to the application period
          established in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='786' sect='104' psec='' tq='N'>
              786.104
            </subref>
          </aref>
          . All eligibility determinations will be final except as otherwise
          determined by the Deputy Administrator. Any claim for payment may be
          denied once the allowed funds are expended, irrespective of any other
          provision of this part.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>