<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol14'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1956
    </extid>
    <num>
      1956
    </num>
    <head>
      DEBT SETTLEMENT
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='5' sect='301' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/5/301.html'>
              5 U.S.C. 301
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='1989' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1989.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 1989
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='31' sect='3711' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/31/3711.html'>
              31 U.S.C. 3711
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='42' sect='1480' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/42/1480.html'>
              42 U.S.C. 1480
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            51 FR 45434
          </aref>
          , Dec. 18, 1986, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='15567'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1956:B:1956.51
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1956.51
      </num>
      <head>
        Purpose.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          61 FR 59779
        </aref>
        , Nov. 22, 1996, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          69 FR 69106
        </aref>
        , Nov. 26, 2004]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='51' psec='' tq='N'>
              1956.51
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Purpose.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          This subpart delegates authority and prescribes policy and procedures
          for 
          <PRTPAGE P='159' />
          settlement of debts owed to the United States under the Farm Credit
          loan programs of the Farm Service Agency (FSA) and the Multi-Family
          Housing (MFH) program of the Rural Housing Service (RHS). It also
          applies to Nonprogram (NP) loans secured by MFH property of the RHS.
          Settlement of claims against recipients of grant funds for reasons
          such as the use of funds for improper purposes is also covered by this
          subpart. Settlement of claims against third party converters, and
          Economic Opportunity (EO) loans is authorized under the Federal Claims
          Collection Standards, 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            4 CFR parts 
            <subref title='4' part='101-105' tq='N'>
              101-105
            </subref>
          </aref>
          . This subpart does not apply to RHS direct Single Family Housing
          (SFH) loans, RHS NP loans secured by SFH property, or to the Rural
          Rental Housing, Rural Cooperative Housing, and Farm Labor Housing
          programs.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            61 FR 59779
          </aref>
          , Nov. 22, 1996, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            69 FR 69106
          </aref>
          , Nov. 26, 2004]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15568'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1956:B:1956.52-1956.53
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1956.52-1956.53
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='52-1956' psec='' tq='N'>
              1956.52-1956
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .53
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15569'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1956:B:1956.54
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1956.54
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          56 FR 10147
        </aref>
        , Mar. 11, 1991, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 21344
        </aref>
        , Apr. 21, 1993; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          62 FR 10157
        </aref>
        , Mar. 5, 1997; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          72 FR 64123
        </aref>
        , Nov. 15, 2007]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='54' psec='' tq='N'>
              1956.54
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Adjustment.
          </E>
           The reduction of a debt or claim conditioned upon completion of
          payment of the adjusted amount at a specific future time or times,
          with or without the payment of any consideration when the adjustment
          offer is approved. An adjustment is not a final settlement until all
          payments under the adjustment agreement(s) have been made.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Amount of debt.
          </E>
           The outstanding balance of the amount loaned including principal and
          interest plus any outstanding advances, including interest, and
          subsidy to be recaptured made by the Government on behalf of the
          borrower.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Cancellation.
          </E>
           The final discharge of a debt without any payment on it.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Chargeoff.
          </E>
           The writing off of a debt and termination of collection activity
          without release of personal liability.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Compromise.
          </E>
           The satisfaction of a debt or claim by the acceptance of a lump-sum
          payment of less than the total amount owed on the debt or claim.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Debt forgiveness.
          </E>
           For the purposes of servicing Farm Loan Programs loans, debt
          forgiveness is defined as a reduction or termination of a direct FLP
          loan in a manner that results in a loss to the Government. Included,
          but not limited to, are losses from a writedown or writeoff under 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR part 
            <subref title='7' part='766' tq='N'>
              766
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , debt settlement, after discharge under the provisions of the
          bankruptcy code, and associated with release of liability. Debt
          cancellation through conservation easements or contracts is not
          considered debt forgiveness for loan servicing purposes.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Debtor.
          </E>
           The borrower of funds under any of the FmHA or its successor agency
          under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
           programs. This includes co-signors, guarantors and persons or
          entities that initially obtained or assumed a loan. Debtor also
          includes grant recipients.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Farm Loan Programs (FLP) loans.
          </E>
           Farm Ownership (FO), Operating (OL), Soil and Water (SW), Economic
          Emergency (EE), Emergency (EM), Recreation (RL), Special Livestock
          (SL), Softwood Timber (ST) loans, and/or Rural Housing Loans for farm
          services buildings (RHF).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Housing programs.
          </E>
           All programs and claims arising under programs administered by FmHA
          or its successor agency under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
           under title V of the Housing Act of 1949.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Servicing office.
          </E>
           The FmHA or its successor agency under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
           office that is responsible for the account.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Settlement.
          </E>
           The compromise, adjustment, cancellation, or chargeoff of a debt owed
          to FmHA or its successor agency under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
          . The term “Settlement” is used for convenience in referring to
          compromise, adjustment, cancellation, or chargeoff actions,
          individually or collectively.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            United States Attorney.
          </E>
           An attorney for the United States Department of Justice.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            56 FR 10147
          </aref>
          , Mar. 11, 1991, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 21344
          </aref>
          , Apr. 21, 1993; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            62 FR 10157
          </aref>
          , Mar. 5, 1997; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            72 FR 64123
          </aref>
          , Nov. 15, 2007]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15570'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1956:B:1956.55-1956.56
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1956.55-1956.56
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='55-1956' psec='' tq='N'>
              1956.55-1956
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .56
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15571'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1956:B:1956.57
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1956.57
      </num>
      <head>
        General provisions.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          56 FR 10147
        </aref>
        , Mar. 11, 1991, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 21344
        </aref>
        , Apr. 21, 1993; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          62 FR 10157
        </aref>
        , Mar. 5, 1997; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          68 FR 7700
        </aref>
        , Feb. 18, 2003]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='57' psec='' tq='N'>
              1956.57
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General provisions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Application of policies.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All debtors are entitled to impartial treatment and uniform
            consideration under this subpart. Accordingly. FmHA or its successor
            agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
            <PRTPAGE P='160' />
            personnel charged with any responsibility in connection with debt
            settlement will adhere strictly to the authorizations, requirements,
            and limitations in this subpart, and will not substitute individual
            feelings or sympathies in connection with any settlement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Information needed for debt settlement.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A debtor requesting debt settlement must submit complete and
            accurate information from which a full determination of his/her
            financial condition can be made. This should include, where
            applicable, but is not limited to, obtaining verification of
            employment, providing expense verification, verifying farm program
            benefits (e.g., Farm Service Agency/Commodity Credit Corporation
            payments), and examining county records to determine what other
            assets the debtor has or recently disposed of. When a FLP debtor is
            continuing to farm, a farm operating plan must be obtained. Also,
            where a spouse is not a co-debtor the spouse&apos;s income will be
            considered in meeting family living expenses. If it appears that a
            debtor will not be able to pay in full and the indebtedness is
            eligible for settlement under this subpart, action should be taken,
            if possible, to avoid unnecessary litigation to enforce collection.
            If the debt is eligible for settlement, the debt settlement
            authorities of FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             should be explained and the privileges thereof extended to the
            debtor. The information obtained from the debtor should be
            documented on a debt settlement form.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Negotiating a settlement.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             County Supervisors may approve or reject compromises, adjustments,
            cancellations, or chargeoffs of SFH debts (to include recapture
            receivables), regardless of the amount. District Directors and
            County Supervisors cannot approve other debt settlement actions;
            therefore, other than SFH debt settlements, they will make no
            statements to a debtor concerning the action that may be taken upon
            a debtor&apos;s application. In negotiating a settlement, all of the
            factors which are pertinent to determining ability to pay will be
            discussed to assist the debtor in arriving at the proper type and
            terms of a settlement. The present and future repayment ability of a
            debtor, the factors mentioned in this subpart, and any other
            pertinent information will be the basis of determining whether the
            debt should be collected in full, compromised, adjusted, canceled,
            or charged off. It is impossible in cases eligible for debt
            settlement to forecast accurately the debtor&apos;s future repayment
            ability over a long period of time; consequently, the period of time
            during which payments on settlement offers are to be made should not
            exceed five years. Debtors have the right to make voluntary
            settlement offers in any amount should they elect to do so.
            Adjustment offers will not be approved in any case unless there is
            reasonable assurance that the debtor will be able to make the
            payments as they become due.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Disposition of property.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Security may be retained by the debtor only under the conditions
            specified in 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              § 1956.66 of
            </aref>
             this subpart.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Proceeds from the disposal of security prior to approval of a debt
              settlement offer.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A debtor is not required to have disposed of the security prior to
            application for debt settlement for a loan to be settled. However,
            if a debtor has disposed of security prior to applying for debt
            settlement, proceeds from the disposed security must first be
            applied on the debtor&apos;s account, irrespective of an application
            for debt settlement unless the conditions specified in 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              § 1956.66 of
            </aref>
             this subpart are met.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             [Reserved]
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Settlement when legal or investigative action has been taken,
              recommended, or is contemplated.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Debts cannot be settled:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the matter has been referred either to the Office of the
            Inspector General (OIG) under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              § 1962.49(a) of
            </aref>
             subpart A of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1962' tq='N'>
                1962 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
             or to Office of the General Counsel (OGC) because of suspected
            criminal violation, or criminal prosecution is pending because of an
            illegal act(s) committed by the debtor in connection with the debt
            or the security for that debt, the procedure outlined in paragraph
            (g)(3) of this section will be followed, unless, the OIG has
            declined to investigate the matter or, OGC has advised otherwise, or
            the case is in the hands of the United States Attorney.
            <PRTPAGE P='161' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a request for referral to the United States Attorney to
            institute a civil action to protect the interest of the Government
            has been made by FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as provided in paragraph (g)(3) of this section, if the case
            has been referred to the United States Attorney and is not closed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a debtor&apos;s account is involved in a fiscal irregularity
            investigation in which final action has not been taken or the
            account shows evidence that a shortage may exist and an
            investigation will be requested, the account will not be approved
            for settlement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When a claim has been referred to, or a judgment has been obtained
            by the United States Attorney, and the debtor requests settlement,
            the employee in charge of the account will explain to the debtor
            that the United States Attorney has exclusive jurisdiction over the
            claim or judgment, that FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             has no authority to agree to a settlement offer when the United
            States Attorney&apos;s file is not closed, and that if the debtor
            wishes to make a compromise or adjustment offer when the United
            States Attorney&apos;s file is not closed, if will be submitted with
            any related payment directly to the United States Attorney for a
            decision on the settlement offer.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Advice from OGC.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State Directors will obtain, when necessary, advice from the OGC in
            handling proposed debt settlement actions which involve legal
            problems.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Settlement of claims against estates.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Settlement of a claim against an estate under the provisions of
            this subpart will be based on the recovery that may reasonably be
            expected, taking into consideration such items as the security,
            costs of administration, allowances of minor children and surviving
            spouse, allowable funeral expenses, and dower and courtesy rights,
            and specific encumbrances on the property having priority over
            claims of the Government.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Joint debtors.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Settlement may not be approved for one joint debtor unless approved
            for all debtors. “Joint debtors” includes all parties (individuals,
            partnerships, joint operators, cooperatives, corporations, estates)
            who are legally liable for payment of the debt.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Separate and individual adjustment offers from joint debtors must
            be accepted and processed only as a joint offer. Joint debtors must
            be advised that all debtors will remain liable for the balance of
            the debt until all payments due under the joint offer have been
            made.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A separate Form FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             1956-1 will be completed by each debtor, unless the debtors are
            members of the same family and all necessary financial information
            on each debtor can be shown clearly on a single application.
            Separate applications will be sent to the State Office as a unit.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If one debtor applies for compromise, adjustment, or cancellation,
            or if the debt is to be charged off, and the other debtor(s) is
            deceased or has received a discharge of the debt in bankruptcy, or
            the whereabouts of the other debtor(s) is unknown, or it is
            impossible or impracticable to obtain the signature of the other
            debtor(s), Form FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             1956-1 or Form FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             1956-2 (for housing loans) “Cancellation or Charge-off of FmHA or
            its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             Indebtedness,” will be prepared by showing at the top of the form
            the name of the debtor requesting settlement, following by the name
            of the other debtor.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          For example, “John Doe, joint debtor with Bill Doe, deceased,” “John
          Doe, joint debtor with Sam Doe, discharged in bankruptcy,” “John Doe,
          joint debtor with Mary Doe, impossible or impracticable to obtain
          signature,” as appropriate. In addition to the information concerning
          settlement of the debt by the applicant, information which justifies
          settlement of the debt as to the debtor(s) not joining in the
          application will be shown on Form FmHA or its successor agency under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
           1956-1, or 1956-2 for housing loans.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Settlement where debtor owes more than one type of Agency loan.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             It is not the policy to settle any loan indebtedness of a debtor
            who is also indebted on 
            <PRTPAGE P='162' />
            another agency loan and who will continue as an active borrower. In
            such case, the facts will be fully documented in part VIII of Form
            RD 1956-1.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='l'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (l)
            </enum>
            <head>
              No previous debt forgiveness.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Debt settlement may not be approved for any direct Farm Loan
            Programs loan if the borrower has received debt forgiveness on any
            other direct loan as defined in 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              § 1956.54 of
            </aref>
             this subpart.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            56 FR 10147
          </aref>
          , Mar. 11, 1991, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 21344
          </aref>
          , Apr. 21, 1993; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            62 FR 10157
          </aref>
          , Mar. 5, 1997; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            68 FR 7700
          </aref>
          , Feb. 18, 2003]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15572'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1956:B:1956.58-1956.65
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1956.58-1956.65
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='58-1956' psec='' tq='N'>
              1956.58-1956
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .65
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15573'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1956:B:1956.66
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1956.66
      </num>
      <head>
        Compromise and adjustment of nonjudgment debts.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          56 FR 10147
        </aref>
        , Mar. 11, 1991, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 21345
        </aref>
        , Apr. 21, 1993; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          62 FR 10157
        </aref>
        , Mar. 5, 1997]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='66' psec='' tq='N'>
              1956.66
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Compromise and adjustment of nonjudgment debts.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Nonjudgment debts which the debtor is unable to pay may be compromised
          or adjusted in accordance with applicable provisions of this section,
          and the debtor may retain the security property, if any. Application
          will be made on Form RD 1956-1 by the debtor; or if the debtor is
          unable to act, by another party having legal authority to act for the
          debtor. Collection of a lump sum offer may be deferred until the
          debtor is advised that the offer is approved. Upon full payment of the
          approved compromise or adjustment amount, the Agency will release the
          debtor from liability by delivering the note(s) to the debtor stamped
          “Satisfied by compromise or adjustment.”
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              FLP debts.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The debt or any extension thereof on which compromise or adjustment
            is requested does not have to be due and payable under the terms of
            the note or other instrument, or because of acceleration by written
            notice prior to the date of application. Nonjudgment secured FLP
            debts may be compromised or adjusted in accordance with the
            following conditions:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Security may be retained by the debtor if the debtor offers an
            amount at least equal to the current fair market value (including
            any crop security) less any prior lien amounts. Any remaining
            unsecured debt may be debt settled.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Where the debtor is able to pay an amount in excess of the lump sum
            compromise offer, an adjustment offer must call for a lump sum
            payment as set out in paragraph (a)(1) of this section, plus any
            additional amounts the Agency determines the debtor is able to pay
            over a period of time not to exceed 5 years.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The acceptability of a compromise or adjustment offer will be
            arrived at by determining and evaluating:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Statement of indebtedness owed on any prior liens. Statements will
            be retained in the debtor&apos;s file.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Value of existing security as determined by a current appraisal
            made or obtained by the Agency. The appraisal will be retained in
            the debtor&apos;s file.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Debtor&apos;s total present income and probable sources, amount and
            stability of income over the next 5 years. Old age pensions, other
            public assistance, and veteran&apos;s disability pensions will not
            be considered as sources of funds for making compromise and
            adjustment offers.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Amount of debtor&apos;s other debts.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Amount of debtor&apos;s essential family living expenses, and farm
            or business operation expenses necessary to continue the operation,
            if applicable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Age and health when the debtor is largely depending on income from
            an occupation where manual labor is required.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_vii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Size of debtor&apos;s family, their ages and health.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_viii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (viii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Value of debtor&apos;s assets in relation to debts and liens of
            third parties. Reasonable equity in a modest nonsecurity homestead
            occupied by the debtor will not be considered as available for
            settlement. Nonsecurity property in excess of minimum family living
            needs which is not exempt from levy and execution should be
            considered in determining the debtor&apos;s ability to pay.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Housing debts (both Single-family and Multi-family).
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Nonjudgment secured debts may be compromised or adjusted as
            follows:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The debt is fully matured under the terms of the note or other
            instrument; or has been accelerated by written notice prior to the
            date of the settlement application.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A compromise offer must at least equal the value of the security as
            determined by FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             (less any prior liens) plus any additional amount FmHA or its
            successor agency 
            <PRTPAGE P='163' />
            under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             determines the debtor is able to pay based on a current financial
            statement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An adjustment offer must meet the requirements of paragraph (b)(2)
            of this section, except the debt (or the amount offered) is to be
            scheduled for payment over the shortest period FmHA or its successor
            agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             determines is feasible based on the debtor&apos;s financial
            resources, but not to exceed 5 years.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Unsecured debts.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Unsecured debts considered under this paragraph (c) are most
            frequently account balances remaining after the debtor has sold
            security property to another party/entity, the security has been
            liquidated through foreclosure, or FmHA or its successor agency
            under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             has accepted a deed in lieu of foreclosure and the borrower was not
            released from liability. An offer to compromise or adjust an
            unsecured debt must represent the maximum amount FmHA or its
            successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             determines the debtor can pay based on a current financial
            statement and other information available to FmHA or its successor
            agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
            . An adjustment offer is to be scheduled for payment over the
            shortest period FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             determines is feasible, but not to exceed 5 years.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            56 FR 10147
          </aref>
          , Mar. 11, 1991, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 21345
          </aref>
          , Apr. 21, 1993; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            62 FR 10157
          </aref>
          , Mar. 5, 1997]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15574'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1956:B:1956.67
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1956.67
      </num>
      <head>
        Debts which the debtor is able to pay in full but refuses to do so.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='67' psec='' tq='N'>
              1956.67
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Debts which the debtor is able to pay in full but refuses to do so.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Debts which the debtor may have the ability to pay in full but has
          refused to do so may be compromised or adjusted in the following
          situations on Form FmHA or its successor agency under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
           1956-1:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When the full amount cannot be collected because of the refusal of
            the debtor to pay the debt in full and the OGC advises that the
            Government is unable to enforce collection in full within a
            reasonable time by enforced collection proceedings, the debt may be
            compromised. In determining inability to collect, the following
            factors will be considered:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Availability of assets or income which may be realized by enforced
            collection proceedings, considering the applicable exemptions
            available to the debtor under State and Federal law.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Inheritance prospects within 5 years.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Likelihood of debtor obtaining nonexempt property or income within
            5 years, out of which there could be collected a substantially
            larger sum than the amount of the present offer.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Uncertainty as to price the security or other property will bring
            at forced sale.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The debt may be compromised or adjusted when the OGC has advised in
            writing that:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             There is a real doubt concerning the Government&apos;s ability to
            prove its case in court for the full amount of the debt, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The amount offered represents a reasonable settlement considering:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The probability of prevailing on the legal issues involved.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The probability of proving facts to establish full or partial
            recovery, with due regard to the availability of witnesses and other
            pertinent factors.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The probable amount of court costs and attorney&apos;s fees which
            may be assessed against the Government if it is unsuccessful in
            litigation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When the cost of collecting the debt does not justify enforced
            collection of the full amount, the amount accepted in compromise or
            adjustment may reflect an appropriate discount for administrative
            and litigation costs of collection. Such discount will not exceed
            $2,000 unless the OGC advises that in the particular case a larger
            discount is appropriate. The cost of collecting may be a substantial
            factor in settling small debts but normally will not carry great
            weight in settling large debts.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15575'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1956:B:1956.68
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1956.68
      </num>
      <head>
        Compromise or adjustment without debtor&apos;s signature.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='68' psec='' tq='N'>
              1956.68
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Compromise or adjustment without debtor&apos;s signature.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Debts of a living debtor may be compromised or adjusted if it is
          impossible or impracticable to obtain a signed application and all
          other requirements of this section applicable to compromise or
          adjustment with a signed application have been met. Form FmHA or its
          successor agency under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
           1956-1 will show:
          <PRTPAGE P='164' />
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The sources from which the information was obtained.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             That a current effort was made to obtain the debtor&apos;s
            signature and the date(s) of such effort.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The specific reasons why it was impossible or impracticable to
            obtain the signature of the debtor and, if the debtor refused to
            sign, the reason(s) given.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15576'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1956:B:1956.69
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1956.69
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='69' psec='' tq='N'>
              1956.69
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15577'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1956:B:1956.70
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1956.70
      </num>
      <head>
        Cancellation.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          56 FR 10147
        </aref>
        , Mar. 11, 1991, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          68 FR 7700
        </aref>
        , Feb. 18, 2003]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='70' psec='' tq='N'>
              1956.70
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Cancellation.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Nonjudgment debts may be canceled in the following instances:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              With application.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The debt or any extension thereof on Farmer Programs debts 
            <E T='03'>
              do not
            </E>
             have to be due and payable under the terms of the note or other
            instrument, or because of acceleration by written notice prior to
            the date of application. Debts due the FmHA or its successor agency
            under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             may be canceled upon application of the debtor, or if a debtor is
            unable to act, upon application of a guardian, executor, or
            administrator, subject to the following conditions:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             employee in charge of the account furnishes a report and favorable
            recommendation concerning the cancellation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             There is no known security for the debt and the debtor has no other
            assets from which the debt could be collected.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The debtor is unable to pay any part of the debt and has no
            reasonable prospect of being able to do so.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Without application.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Debts due the FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             may be canceled upon a report and the favorable recommendation of
            the employee in charge of the account in the following instances:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Deceased debtors.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The following conditions must exist:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             There is no known security; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An administrator or executor has not been appointed to settle the
            debtor&apos;s estate and the financial condition of the estate has
            been investigated and it has been established that there is no
            reasonable prospect of recovery; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An administrator or executor has been appointed to settle the
            estate of the debtor; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='b_1_iii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A final settlement has been made and confirmed by the probate court
            and the Government&apos;s claim was recognized properly and the
            Government has received all funds it was entitled to, or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='b_1_iii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A final settlement has not been made and confirmed by the probate
            court but there are no assets in the estate from which there is any
            reasonable prospect of recovery, or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='b_1_iii_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Regardless of whether a final settlement has been made, there were
            assets in the estate from which recovery might have been affected
            but such assets have been disposed of or lost in a manner which OGC
            advises will preclude any reasonable prospect of recovery by the
            Government.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Disappeared debtors.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The debt may be canceled without application where the debtor has
            no known assets or future debt-paying ability, has disappeared and
            cannot be found without undue expense, and there is no existing
            security for the debt. Reasonable efforts will be made to locate the
            debtor. These efforts will generally include contacts, either in
            person or in writing, with postmasters, motor vehicle licensing and
            title authorities, telephone directories, city directories, utility
            companies, State and local governmental agencies, other Federal
            agencies, employees, friends, and credit agency skip locate reports,
            known relatives, neighbors and County Committee members. Also, the
            debtor&apos;s loan file should be reviewed carefully for possible
            leads that may be of assistance in locating the debtor. The efforts
            made to locate the debtor, including the names and dates of
            contacts, and the information furnished by each person, will be
            fully documented in the appropriate space on Form FmHA or its
            successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             1956-1 or Form FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             1956-2 for housing loans.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Debtors discharged in bankruptcy.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If there is no security for the debt, debts discharged in
            bankruptcy shall be cancelled by use of the appropriate Agency form
            with the attachments noted below. No attempt will be made to obtain
            the debtor&apos;s signature. If the debtor has executed a new
            promise to pay prior to discharge and has otherwise accomplished a
            valid reaffirmation of 
            <PRTPAGE P='165' />
            the debt in accordance with advice from OGC, the debt is not
            discharged.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Chapter 7 Bankruptcy cases will be documented with a copy of the
            “Discharge of Debtor” order(s) by the court for all obligors.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For debts identified as being part of an unsecured claim under
            Chapter 11, the cancellation will be documented with a copy of the
            organization plan, copy of the order by the court confirming the
            plan, a copy of the order completing the plan (a similar order), and
            an opinion by OGC that the confirming order has discharged the
            obligor(s) of liability to that part of the debt.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For debts identified as being part of an unsecured claim under
            chapters 12 or 13, the cancellation will be documented with a copy
            of the reorganization plan and confirmation order, as above, a copy
            of the order completing the plan and closing the case, and an
            opinion by OGC that the completion order has discharged the
            obligor(s) of liability to that portion of the debt.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Signature of debtor cannot be obtained.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Debts of a living debtor may be canceled if it is impossible or
            impracticable to obtain a signed application and the requirements in
            paragraph (a) of this section concerning cancellation with
            application have been met or if the debt has been discharged in
            bankruptcy and there is no security. Form FmHA or its successor
            agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             1956-1 will state:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The sources of information obtained.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             That a current effort was made to obtain the debtor&apos;s
            application and the date of such effort.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The specific reasons why it was impossible or impracticable to
            obtain the signature of the debtor and, if the debtor refused to
            sign, the reason(s) given.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            56 FR 10147
          </aref>
          , Mar. 11, 1991, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            68 FR 7700
          </aref>
          , Feb. 18, 2003]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15578'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1956:B:1956.71
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1956.71
      </num>
      <head>
        Settling uncollectible recapture receivables.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 21345
        </aref>
        , Apr. 21, 1993]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='71' psec='' tq='N'>
              1956.71
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Settling uncollectible recapture receivables.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The settlement of uncollectible recapture receivables will be fully
          documented on a debt settlement form and retained in the case file.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 21345
          </aref>
          , Apr. 21, 1993]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15579'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1956:B:1956.72-1956.74
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1956.72-1956.74
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='72-1956' psec='' tq='N'>
              1956.72-1956
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .74
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15580'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1956:B:1956.75
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1956.75
      </num>
      <head>
        Chargeoff.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='75' psec='' tq='N'>
              1956.75
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Chargeoff.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Judgment debts.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subject to the provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='57' psec='#g_3' tq='N'>
                1956.57(g)(3)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , judgment debts may be charged off by use of Form FmHA or its
            successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             1956-1 or Form FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             1956-2 for housing upon a report and favorable recommendation of
            the employee in charge of the account provided:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The United States Attorney&apos;s file is closed, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The requirements of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='70' psec='#b_2' tq='N'>
                1956.70(b)(2)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             have been met, or two years have elapsed since any collections were
            made on the judgment and the debtor(s) has no equity in property on
            which the judgment is a lien or on which it can presently be made a
            lien.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Nonjudgment debts.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Debts which cannot be settled under other sections of this subpart
            may be charged off using Form FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             1956-1 or Form FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             1956-2 for housing loans without the debtor&apos;s signature
            subject to the following provisions:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When the principal balance is $2,000 or less and efforts to collect
            have been unsuccessful or it is apparent that further collection
            efforts would be ineffectual or uneconomical,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When the OGC advises in writing that the claim is legally without
            merit.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Even though FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             considers the claim to be valid, when efforts to induce voluntary
            payments are unsuccessful and the OGC advises in writing that
            evidence necessary to prove the claim in court cannot be produced,
            or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When the employee in charge of the account recommends the chargeoff
            and has made the following determinations on the basis of
            information in FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
            &apos;s official files or from other informed reliable sources:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             That the debtor is:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_4_i_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Unable to pay any part of the debt and has no apparent future debt
            repayment ability as specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='66' psec='#a' tq='N'>
                1956.66(a)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ; or
            <PRTPAGE P='166' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_4_i_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Able to pay part or all of the debt but is unwilling to do so, it
            is clear that the Government cannot enforce collection of a
            significant amount from assets or income, and an opinion is received
            from OGC to that effect; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_4_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             There is no security for the debt.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For debts identified as being part of an unsecured claim under a
            confirmed Chapter 11 plan, the chargeoff will be documented with a
            copy of the organization plan, a copy of the court order confirming
            the plan, an opinion by OGC that the order confirming the plan has
            discharged the debtor(s) of liability on the unsecured part of the
            debt.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15581'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1956:B:1956.76-1956.83
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1956.76-1956.83
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='76-1956' psec='' tq='N'>
              1956.76-1956
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .83
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15582'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1956:B:1956.84
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1956.84
      </num>
      <head>
        Approval or rejection.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 21345
        </aref>
        , Apr. 21, 1993, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          68 FR 7700
        </aref>
        , Feb. 18, 2003]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='84' psec='' tq='N'>
              1956.84
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Approval or rejection.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            -(d) [Reserved]
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Appeal rights.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A debtor whose debt settlement offer is rejected will be notified
            of appeal rights pursuant to 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='11' tq='N'>
                11
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 21345
          </aref>
          , Apr. 21, 1993, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            68 FR 7700
          </aref>
          , Feb. 18, 2003]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15583'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1956:B:1956.85
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1956.85
      </num>
      <head>
        Payments and receipts.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          56 FR 10147
        </aref>
        , Mar. 11, 1991, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 21345
        </aref>
        , Apr. 21, 1993; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          68 FR 61332
        </aref>
        , Oct. 28, 2003; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          69 FR 69106
        </aref>
        , Nov. 26, 2004]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='85' psec='' tq='N'>
              1956.85
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Payments and receipts.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Servicing office handling.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An application with which the debtor offers a lump-sum payment in
            compromise, or with which the debtor offers an initial payment on an
            adjustment offer, will be accompanied by the payments required at
            the time such application is filed in the servicing office.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             [Reserved]
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Checks or check transmittal letter containing restrictive notations
            such as “Settlement in full” or “Payment in full,” or in those
            exceptional instances when the debtor refuses to sign the Form FmHA
            or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             1956-1 in connection with a compromise offer, will be forwarded to
            the State Office where they will be retained until approval or
            rejection of the offer. The use of restrictive notations will be
            discouraged to the fullest extent possible.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Finance Office handling.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All payments evidenced by Form FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             451-2, “Schedule of Remittances,” bearing the legend “Compromise
            Offer—FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
            ” or “Adjustment Offer—FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
            ,” will be held in the Deposits Fund Account by the Finance Office
            until notification is received from the State Office of the approval
            or rejection of the offer. In cases of approved offers, remittances
            will be applied in accordance with established policies, beginning
            with the oldest loan included in the settlement, except that when
            the request for settlement includes loans made from different
            revolving funds the Finance Office will prorate the amount received,
            on the basis of the total principal balance due the respective
            revolving funds. Upon notification of a rejection of a debtor&apos;s
            offer and receipt of a request from the State Director for a refund,
            the Finance Office will refund to the debtor, in care of the
            employee in charge of the account, the amount held in the Deposits
            Fund Account representing a rejected compromise or adjustment offer.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When a debtor&apos;s adjustment offer is approved, the accounts
            involved will not be adjusted in the records of the Finance Office
            until all payments have been made. Form FmHA or its successor agency
            under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             1956-1 will be held in a suspense file pending payment of the full
            amount of the approved offer. The original Form FmHA or its
            successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             1956-1 in approved cases will be retained in the Finance Office.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            56 FR 10147
          </aref>
          , Mar. 11, 1991, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 21345
          </aref>
          , Apr. 21, 1993; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            68 FR 61332
          </aref>
          , Oct. 28, 2003; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            69 FR 69106
          </aref>
          , Nov. 26, 2004]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15584'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1956:B:1956.86-1956.95
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1956.86-1956.95
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='86-1956' psec='' tq='N'>
              1956.86-1956
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .95
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15585'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1956:B:1956.96
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1956.96
      </num>
      <head>
        Delinquent adjustment agreements.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          68 FR 7700
        </aref>
        , Feb. 18, 2003]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='96' psec='' tq='N'>
              1956.96
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Delinquent adjustment agreements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          A 90-day extension for making the payments may be given by the Agency
          when the circumstances of the case justify an extension. A decision
          not to extend the time for making payments is not appealable. If the
          debtor is delinquent under the terms of the adjustment agreement and
          is likely to be financially unable to meet the terms of the agreement,
          the Agency may cancel the existing agreement and process a different
          type of settlement more consistent with the debtor&apos;s repayment 
          <PRTPAGE P='167' />
          ability, provided the facts in the case justify such action. The
          cancellation of an adjustment agreement is appealable. If an agreement
          is cancelled, any payments received shall be retained as payments on
          the debt owed at the time of the adjustment agreement.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            68 FR 7700
          </aref>
          , Feb. 18, 2003]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15586'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1956:B:1956.97
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1956.97
      </num>
      <head>
        Disposition of promissory notes.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          56 FR 10147
        </aref>
        , Mar. 11, 1991. Redesignated and amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 21346
        </aref>
        , Apr. 21, 1993]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
              1956.97
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Disposition of promissory notes.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notes evidencing debts settled by completed adjustments, completed
            compromise with or without signature, or canceled with signature
            will be returned to the debtor or to the debtor&apos;s legal
            representative. The original and copies of notes will be stamped
            “Satisfied by Approved Compromise,” “Satisfied by Approved
            Cancellation,” or “Satisfied by Completed Adjustment Offer.” In such
            cases, the security instrument(s) will be released of record
            according to State law.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notes evidencing debts canceled without application will be placed
            in the debtor&apos;s case folder and disposed of pursant to FmHA or
            its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             Instruction 2033-A (available in any FmHA or its successor agency
            under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             office). However, if the debtor requests the notes, they may be
            stamped “Satisfied By Approved Cancellation” and returned.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notes evidencing charged off debts will be retained in the
            servicing office and will not be stamped or returned to the debtor.
            They will be destroyed six years after charged off pursuant to FmHA
            or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             Instruction 2033-A (available in any FmHA or its successor agency
            under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             office).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In case of a transfer of security with assumption for less than the
            debt, the promissory note will be attached to the assumption
            agreement covered by the note and kept in the transferee&apos;s
            file.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            56 FR 10147
          </aref>
          , Mar. 11, 1991. Redesignated and amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 21346
          </aref>
          , Apr. 21, 1993]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15587'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1956:B:1956.98
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1956.98
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='98' psec='' tq='N'>
              1956.98
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15588'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1956:B:1956.99
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1956.99
      </num>
      <head>
        Exception authority.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='99' psec='' tq='N'>
              1956.99
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Exception authority.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The Administrator may, in individual cases, make an exception to any
          requirement or provision of this subpart which is not inconsistent
          with the authorizing statute or other applicable law if the
          Administrator determines that application of the requirement or
          provision would adversely affect the Government&apos;s interest. The
          Administrator will exercise this authority only at the request of the
          State Director and on the recommendation of the appropriate program
          Assistant Administrator. Requests for exceptions must be made in
          writing by the State Director and supported with documentation to
          explain the adverse affect on the Government&apos;s interest, propose
          alternative courses of action, and show how the adverse affect will be
          eliminated or minimized if the exception is granted. Any settlement
          actions approved by the Administrator under this section will be
          documented on Form FmHA or its successor agency under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
           1956-1 and returned to the State Office for submission to the Finance
          Office.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15589'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1956:B:1956.100
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1956.100
      </num>
      <head>
        OMB control number.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='100' psec='' tq='N'>
              1956.100
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          OMB control number.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The collection of information requirements in this regulation have
          been approved by the Office of Management and Budget and assigned OMB
          control number 0575-0118. Public reporting burden for this collection
          of information is estimated to vary from 
          <E T='03'>
            15
          </E>
           to 
          <E T='03'>
            20
          </E>
           minutes per response, with an average of 
          <E T='03'>
            20
          </E>
           minutes per response including time for reviewing instructions,
          searching existing data sources, gathering and maintaining the data
          needed, and completing and reviewing the collection of information.
          Send comments regarding this estimate or any other aspect of this
          collection of information, including suggestions for reducing this
          burden, to Department of Agriculture, Clearance Officer, OIRM, Room
          404-W, Washington, DC 20250; and to the Office of Information and
          Regulatory Affairs, Office of Management and Budget, Washington, DC
          20503.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15590'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1956:C:1956.101
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1956.101
      </num>
      <head>
        Purpose.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          72 FR 55019
        </aref>
        , Sept. 28, 2007]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='168' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='101' psec='' tq='N'>
              1956.101
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Purpose.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          This subpart delegates authority and prescribes policies and
          procedures for debt settlement of Community Facility loans;
          Association Recreation loans; Rural Renewal loans; direct Business and
          Industry loans; and Shift-in-land-use loans. Settlement of Economic
          Opportunity Cooperative loans, Claims Against Third Party Converters,
          Non-program loans, Rural Business Enterprise/Television Demonstration
          Grants, Rural Development Loan Fund loans, Intermediary Relending
          Program loans, Nonprofit National Corporations Loans and Grants, and
          601 Energy Impact Assistance Grants, is not authorized under
          independent statutory authority, and settlement under these programs
          is handled pursuant to the Federal Claims Collection Joint Standards, 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            4 CFR parts 
            <subref title='4' part='101-105' tq='N'>
              101-105
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , as described in 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            § 1956.147 of
          </aref>
           this subpart. In addition, this subpart does not apply to Water and
          Waste Programs of the Rural Utilities Service, Watershed loans, and
          Resource Conservation and Development loans, which are serviced under 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='1782' tq='N'>
              1782 of this title
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            72 FR 55019
          </aref>
          , Sept. 28, 2007]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15591'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1956:C:1956.102
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1956.102
      </num>
      <head>
        Application of policies.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          53 FR 13100
        </aref>
        , Apr. 21, 1988, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          59 FR 46160
        </aref>
        , Sept. 7, 1994]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='102' psec='' tq='N'>
              1956.102
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Application of policies.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a debt is eligible for settlement, the debt settlement
            authorities of the Farmers Home Administration or its successor
            agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             (FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
            ) should be explained and the privileges thereof extended to the
            debtor. All debtors are entitled to impartial treatment and uniform
            consideration under this subpart. Accordingly, FmHA or its successor
            agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             personnel charged with any responsibility in connection with debt
            settlement will adhere strictly to the authorizations, requirements,
            and limitations in this subpart.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              For hospitals and health care facilities only.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Loan servicing and debt restructuring options according to 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              § 1956.143 of
            </aref>
             this subpart must be exhausted before the other settlement
            authorities of this subpart are applicable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            53 FR 13100
          </aref>
          , Apr. 21, 1988, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            59 FR 46160
          </aref>
          , Sept. 7, 1994]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15592'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1956:C:1956.103-1956.104
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1956.103-1956.104
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='103-1956' psec='' tq='N'>
              1956.103-1956
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .104
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15593'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1956:C:1956.105
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1956.105
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          53 FR 13100
        </aref>
        , Apr. 21, 1988, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          54 FR 47510
        </aref>
        , Nov. 15, 1989; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          66 FR 1569
        </aref>
        , Jan. 9, 2001]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='105' psec='' tq='N'>
              1956.105
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Settlement.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The compromise, adjustment, cancellation, or chargeoff of a debt
            owed to FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
            . The term “settlement” is used for convenience in referring to
            compromise, adjustment, cancellation, or chargeoff actions,
            individually or collectively.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Compromise.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The satisfaction of a debt, including a release of liability, by
            the acceptance of a lump-sum payment of less than the total amount
            owed on the debt.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Adjustment.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The satisfaction of a debt, including a release of liability, when
            acceptance is conditioned upon completion of payment of the adjusted
            amount at a specific future time or times, with or without the
            payment of any consideration when the adjustment offer is approved.
            An adjustment is not a final settlement until all payments under the
            adjustment agreement have been made.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Cancellation.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The final discharge of a debt with a release of liability.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Chargeoff.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To write off a debt and terminate all servicing activity 
            <E T='03'>
              without
            </E>
             a release of liability. This is not a final discharge of the debt,
            but rather a decision upon the part of the agency to remove the debt
            from agency receivables.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Debtor.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The borrower of loan funds under any of the FmHA or its successor
            agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             programs specified in 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              § 1956.101 of
            </aref>
             this subpart.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Security.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All that serves as collateral for the FmHA or its successor agency
            under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             loan(s), including, but not limited to, revenues, tax levies,
            municipal bonds, and real and chattel property.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Servicing official.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             official who is primarily responsible for servicing the account.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              United States Attorney.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An attorney for the United States Department of Justice.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Independent Qualified Fee Appraiser.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An individual who is a designated member of the American Institute
            of Real Estate Appraisers, Society 
            <PRTPAGE P='169' />
            of Real Estate Appraisers, or an equivalent organization, requiring
            appraisal education, testing, and experience.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            53 FR 13100
          </aref>
          , Apr. 21, 1988, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            54 FR 47510
          </aref>
          , Nov. 15, 1989; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            66 FR 1569
          </aref>
          , Jan. 9, 2001]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15594'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1956:C:1956.106-1956.108
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1956.106-1956.108
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='106-1956' psec='' tq='N'>
              1956.106-1956
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .108
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15595'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1956:C:1956.109
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1956.109
      </num>
      <head>
        General requirements for debt settlement.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='109' psec='' tq='N'>
              1956.109
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General requirements for debt settlement.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Debt due and payable.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The debt or any extension thereof on which settlement is requested
            must be due and payable under the terms of the note or other
            instrument, or because of acceleration by written notice prior to
            the date of application for settlement, unless the debt is to be
            cancelled without application under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='130' psec='#b' tq='N'>
                1956.130(b)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             or charged off under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              § 1956.136 of
            </aref>
             this subpart.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Disposition of security.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Ordinarily, all security will be disposed of prior to the date of
            application for settlement. There are exceptions:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             It may be necessary to abandon security through the debt settlement
            process. For example, a community may be rendered uninhabitable by a
            toxic or hazardous substance. In such cases, debt settlement may
            proceed provided the servicing official determines:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             That further collection efforts with respect to the security in
            question would be ineffective or uneconomical,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             That it is in the best interests of the Government to proceed with
            debt settlement,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             That the proposal otherwise meets the requirements appropriate to
            the type of settlement under consideration, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The approval of the Administrator is obtained.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A servicing action may have been carried out which resulted in a
            less than complete disposition of security. For example, the
            Government may have consented to a voluntary sale of a debtor&apos;s
            real and chattel property without reference to other security, which
            might include, but is not limited to: an additional lien on revenue,
            a third party pledge of security, or a pledge of personal liability.
            In such cases, debt settlement may proceed provided the requirements
            of 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              § 1956.109(b)(1) of
            </aref>
             this subpart are met.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Security can be retained under the compromise and adjustment offers
            as specified in 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              § 1956.124 of
            </aref>
             this subpart.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Settlement of a claim against an estate will be based on the
            recovery that may reasonably be expected, taking into consideration
            such items as the security, costs of administration, allowances of
            minor children and surviving spouse, allowable funeral expenses,
            dower and curtesy rights, and specific encumbrances on the property
            having priority over claims of the Government.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Proceeds from the sale of security.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Proceeds from the sale of security must be applied on the
            debtor&apos;s account, taking into consideration the disposition
            requirements of any grant agreement, prior to the date of
            application for settlement, except when security is retained as
            provided for in 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              § 1956.109(b) of
            </aref>
             this subpart. Debtors will not be allowed to sell security and use
            the proceeds as part or all of the debt settlement offer.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              County Committee review.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Proposed settlement actions will be reviewed by the County
            Committee except for the cancellation of debts discharged in
            bankruptcy under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              § 1956.130(b)(1) of
            </aref>
             this subpart or when a claim has been referred to a United States
            Attorney under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              § 1956.112(d) of
            </aref>
             this subpart. No settlement shall be approved if it is more
            favorable to the debtor than recommended by the County Committee.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Assistance from Office of General Counsel (OGC).
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When necessary, State Directors will obtain advice from OGC in
            handling proposed debt settlement actions.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Format.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Form FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             1956-1, “Application for Settlement of Indebtedness,” will be
            utilized for all settlement actions under this subpart.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15596'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1956:C:1956.110
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1956.110
      </num>
      <head>
        Joint debtors.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='110' psec='' tq='N'>
              1956.110
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Joint debtors.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Settlements may not be approved for one joint debtor unless approved
          for all debtors. Joint debtors includes all parties, individuals, and
          organizations, who are legally liable for payment of the debt.
          <PRTPAGE P='170' />
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Individual settlement offers from joint debtors can be accepted and
            processed only as a joint offer. A separate Form FmHA or its
            successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             1956-1 will be completed by each debtor unless the debtors are
            members of the same family and all necessary financial information
            on each debtor can be shown clearly on a single application.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If one of the joint debtors is deceased or has received a discharge
            of the debt in bankruptcy, or if the whereabouts of one of the
            debtors is unknown, or it is otherwise impossible or impractical to
            obtain the signature of the debtor, the application for settlement
            may be accepted without that debtor&apos;s signature if it contains
            adequate information on each of the debtors to justify settlement of
            the debt as to each of the debtors. The name of the debtor
            requesting settlement will be shown at the top of Form FmHA or its
            successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             1956-1 followed by name and status of the other debtor. For
            example, “John Doe, joint debtor with Jane Doe, deceased.”
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Joint debtors must be advised in writing that all debtors will
            remain liable for the balance of the debt until any payment(s) due
            under the joint offer have been made.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15597'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1956:C:1956.111
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1956.111
      </num>
      <head>
        Debtors in bankruptcy.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='111' psec='' tq='N'>
              1956.111
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Debtors in bankruptcy.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          FmHA or its successor agency under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
           personnel will process reorganization plans of debtors filing under
          Chapter 9, Chapter 11, or Chapter 13 as follows:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Plans submitted by debtors under Chapters 9, 11, and 13 must be
            sent by the servicing official to the State Director who will
            recommend either acceptance or rejection of the plans and refer them
            to the United States Attorney through OGC. When the plan calls for
            the adjustment of a debt to FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
            , the State Director will obtain the advice of the Administrator
            before providing OGC with a recommendation on acceptance or
            rejection of this plan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The United States Attorney will advise the State Director, through
            OGC, as to approval or rejection of the debtor&apos;s reorganization
            plan. The State Director will then notify the Finance Office by
            memorandum of the terms and conditions of the bankruptcy
            reorganization plan, including any adjustment of the debt.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15598'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1956:C:1956.112
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1956.112
      </num>
      <head>
        Debts ineligible for settlement.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='112' psec='' tq='N'>
              1956.112
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Debts ineligible for settlement.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Debts will not be settled:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If referral to the Office of Inspector General (OIG) and/or to the
            OGC is contemplated or pending because of suspected criminal
            violation, or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If civil action to protect the interests of the Government is
            contemplated or pending, or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If an investigation for suspected fiscal irregularity is
            contemplated or pending, or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When a claim has been referred to or a judgment has been obtained
            by the United States Attorney and the debtor requests settlement,
            the servicing official will explain to the debtor that the United
            States Attorney has exclusive jurisdiction over the claim or
            judgment, and therefore, FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             has no authority to agree to a settlement offer. If the debtor
            wishes to make a settlement offer, it must be submitted with any
            related payment directly to the United States Attorney for
            consideration.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15599'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1956:C:1956.113-1956.117
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1956.113-1956.117
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='113-1956' psec='' tq='N'>
              1956.113-1956
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .117
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15600'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1956:C:1956.118
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1956.118
      </num>
      <head>
        Approval authority.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='118' psec='' tq='N'>
              1956.118
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Approval authority.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          District Directors cannot approve debt settlement actions. Therefore,
          they will make no statements to a debtor concerning the action that
          may be taken upon a debtor&apos;s application. Subject to this
          subpart, the compromise, adjustment, cancellation, or chargeoff of
          debts will be approved or rejected:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             By the State Director when the outstanding balance of the
            indebtedness involved in the settlement is less then $50,000,
            including principal, interest, and other charges.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             By the Administrator or his designee when the outstanding balance
            of the indebtedness involved in the settlement is $50,000 or more,
            including principal, interest, and other charges.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15601'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1956:C:1956.119-1956.123
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1956.119-1956.123
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='171' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='119-1956' psec='' tq='N'>
              1956.119-1956
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .123
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15602'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1956:C:1956.124
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1956.124
      </num>
      <head>
        Compromise and adjustment.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='124' psec='' tq='N'>
              1956.124
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Compromise and adjustment.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Nonjudgment debts may be compromised or adjusted upon application of
          the debtor(s), or if the debtor is an individual and unable to act,
          upon application of the guardian, executor, or administrator of the
          debtor&apos;s estate.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General provisions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Debts, regardless of the amount, may be compromised or adjusted
            subject to the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The debt or any extension thereof on which compromise or adjustment
            is requested is due and payable under the terms of the note or other
            instrument, or because of acceleration by written notice, prior to
            the date of application for settlement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The period of time during which payments on adjustment offers are
            to be made cannot exceed five years without the approval of the
            Administrator.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Efforts will be made to avoid applications for settlement in which
            debtors offer a specified amount payable upon notice of approval of
            the proposed settlement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Debtor&apos;s ability to pay.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In evaluating the debtor&apos;s settlement application, it is
            essential that reliable information be obtained in sufficient detail
            to assure that the offer accurately reflects the debtor&apos;s
            ability to pay. The debtor&apos;s income, expenses, and nonsecurity
            assets are critical factors in determining the type of settlement
            and the amount which the debtor can reasonably be expected to offer.
            Critical information should include the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The debtor&apos;s total present income from all sources will be
            determined. In addition, careful consideration will be given to the
            probable sources, amount, and stability of income to be received
            over a reasonable period of years. For individuals, public welfare
            assistance and pensions, including old age pensions and pensions
            received by veterans for pensionable disabilities will not be
            considered as sources of funds with which to make compromise and
            adjustment offers.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The debtor&apos;s operation and maintenance expenses, and, in the
            case of individuals, probable living expenses.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The priority of payments on debts to third parties.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When the debtor is largely dependent on income from an occupation
            in which manual labor is required, age and health of the individual
            are vital factors in determining the ability to pay. The number in
            the debtor&apos;s family, their ages and condition of health, will
            also be weighed in determining the ability to pay. However, when the
            debtor&apos;s income is from investments, business enterprises, or
            management efforts, age and health of both individual and family are
            of less importance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The value of the debtor&apos;s assets in relation to debts and
            liens of third parties is important in determining the debtor&apos;s
            ability to pay. It is recognized that debtors must retain a
            reasonable equity in essential nonsecurity property in order to
            continue normal operations and, in the case of an individual, to
            meet family living expenses over a period of years. Under this
            policy a reasonable equity in a modest nonsecurity homestead
            occupied by the debtor, whether or not exempt from levy and
            execution will not be considered as available for offer in
            settlement. Nonsecurity property which is in excess of minimum
            business and/or family living needs and which is not exempt from
            levy and execution should be considered when determining the
            debtor&apos;s ability to pay.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Debtor unable to pay in full.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Debts may be compromised or adjusted and security property retained
            by the debtor, provided:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The debtor is unable to pay the indebtedness in full, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The debtor has offered an amount equal to the present fair market
            value of all security or facility financed, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The debtor has offered any additional amount which the debtor is
            able to pay, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The total amount offered represents a reasonable determination of
            the debtor&apos;s ability to pay.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Debtor able to pay in full but refuses to do so.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the debtor has the ability to pay in full but refuses to do so,
            debts may be compromised or adjusted and security property retained
            by the debtor under certain conditions:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The OGC advises that the Government is unable to enforce collection
            in 
            <PRTPAGE P='172' />
            full within a reasonable time by enforced collection proceedings,
            and the amount offered represents a reasonable settlement
            considering:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Availability of assets or income which may be realized by enforced
            collection proceedings, considering the applicable exemptions
            available to the debtor under State and Federal law, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Inheritance prospects within 5 years, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Likelihood of debtor obtaining nonexempt property or income within
            5 years out of which there could be collected a substantially larger
            sum than the amount of the present offer, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Uncertainty as to the price that the security or other property
            will bring at forced sale, 
            <E T='03'>
              or
            </E>
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The OGC advises that there is a real doubt concerning the
            Government&apos;s ability to prove its case in court for the full
            amount of the debt, and the amount offered represents a reasonable
            settlement considering:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The probability of prevailing on the legal issues involved, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The probability of proving facts to establish full or partial
            recovery, with due regard to the availability of witnesses and other
            pertinent factors, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The probable amount of court costs and attorney&apos;s fees which
            may be assessed against the Government if it is unsuccessful in
            litigation, 
            <E T='03'>
              or
            </E>
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When the cost of collecting the debt does not justify enforced
            collection of the full amount. In such cases, the amount accepted in
            compromise or adjustment may reflect an appropriate discount for
            administrative and litigious costs of collection. Such discount will
            not exceed $600 unless the OGC advises that in the particular case a
            larger discount is appropriate. The cost of collecting may be a
            substantial factor in settling small debts but normally will not
            carry great weight in settling large debts.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15603'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1956:C:1956.125-1956.129
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1956.125-1956.129
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='125-1956' psec='' tq='N'>
              1956.125-1956
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .129
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15604'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1956:C:1956.130
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1956.130
      </num>
      <head>
        Cancellation.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='130' psec='' tq='N'>
              1956.130
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Cancellation.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Nonjudgment debts, regardless of the amount, may be cancelled with or
          without application by the debtor.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              With application by debtor.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Debts may be cancelled upon application of the debtor(s), or if the
            debtor is an individual and unable to act, upon application of the
            guardian, executor, or administrator of the debtor&apos;s estate.
            The following conditions apply:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The servicing official furnishes a favorable recommendation
            concerning the cancellation, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             There is no known security for the debt and the debtor has no other
            assets from which the debt could be collected, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The debtor is unable to pay any part of the debt and has no
            reasonable prospect of being able to do so, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The debt or any extension thereof is due and payable under the
            terms of the note or other instrument, or because of acceleration by
            written notice prior to the date of application.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Without application by debtor.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Debts may be cancelled upon a favorable recommendation of the
            servicing official in the following instances:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Debtors discharged in bankruptcy.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If there is no security for the debt, debts discharged in
            bankruptcy shall be cancelled by the use of Form FmHA or its
            successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             1956-1 with a copy of the Bankruptcy Court&apos;s Discharge Order
            attached. No attempt will be made to obtain the debtor&apos;s
            signature and County Committee review is unnecessary. If the debtor
            has executed a new promise to pay prior to discharge and has
            otherwise accomplished a valid reaffirmation of the debt in
            accordance with advice from OGC, the debt is not discharged.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Impossible or impractical to obtain a debtor&apos;s signature.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Debts may be cancelled if it is impossible or impractical to obtain
            a signed application and the requirements of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='130' psec='#a' tq='N'>
                1956.130(a) (1), (2), and (3)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            <E T='03'>
              only
            </E>
             of this subpart are met. Form FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             1956-1 will document:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The sources of information obtained.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             That a current effort was made to obtain the debtor&apos;s
            application and the date of such effort.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The specific reasons why it was impossible or impracticable to
            obtain the signature of the debtor and, if the 
            <PRTPAGE P='173' />
            debtor refused to sign, the reason(s) given.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Deceased debtors (individuals only).
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The following conditions must exist:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             There is no known security,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An administrator or executor has not been appointed to settle the
            debtor&apos;s estate but the financial condition of the estate has
            been investigated and it has been established that there is no
            reasonable prospect of recovery, 
            <E T='03'>
              or
            </E>
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An administrator or executor has been appointed to settle the
            estate of the debtor, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='b_3_iii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A final settlement has been made and confirmed by the probate court
            and the Government&apos;s claim was recognized properly and the
            Government has received all funds it was entitled to, or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='b_3_iii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A final settlement has not been made and confirmed by the probate
            court, but there are no assets in the estate from which there is any
            reasonable prospect of recovery, or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='b_3_iii_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Regardless of whether a final settlement has been made, there were
            assets in the estate from which recovery might have been effected
            but such assets have been disposed of or lost in a manner which the
            OGC advises will preclude any reasonable prospect of recovery by the
            Government.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Disappeared debtor (individuals only).
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The following conditions must exist:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_4_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The debtor has disappeared and cannot be found without undue
            expense. Reasonable efforts either in person or in writing will be
            made to locate the debtor. These efforts, including the names and
            dates of contacts, and the information furnished by each person,
            will be fully documented on Form FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             1956-1,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_4_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             There is no known security for the debt and the debtor has no other
            assets from which the debt could be collected, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_4_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The debtor is unable to pay any part of the debt and has no
            reasonable prospect of being able to do so.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15605'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1956:C:1956.131-1956.135
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1956.131-1956.135
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='131-1956' psec='' tq='N'>
              1956.131-1956
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .135
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15606'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1956:C:1956.136
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1956.136
      </num>
      <head>
        Chargeoff.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='136' psec='' tq='N'>
              1956.136
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Chargeoff.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Judgment debts.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subject to the provisions of 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              § 1956.112(d) of
            </aref>
             this subpart, judgment debts, regardless of the amount, may be
            charged off without the debtor&apos;s signature upon a favorable
            recommendation of the servicing official provided:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The United States Attorney&apos;s file is closed, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The requirements of 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              § 1956.130(b)(1), (2), (3), or (4) of
            </aref>
             this subpart have been met, as appropriate, or two years have
            elapsed since any collections were made on the judgment and the
            debtor(s) has no equity in property on which the judgment is a lien
            or on which it can presently be made a lien.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Nonjudgment debts.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Debts which cannot be settled under other sections of this subpart
            may be charged off without the debtor&apos;s signature upon a
            favorable recommendation of the servicing official in the following
            instances:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When the OGC advises in writing that the claim is legally without
            merit, or that evidence necessary to prove the claim in court
            cannout be produced.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When there is no known security for the debt, the debtor has no
            other assets from which the debt could be collected, and the debtor:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is unable to pay any party of the debt and has no reasonable
            prospect of being able to do so, or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is able to pay part or all of the debt but refuses to do so, and an
            opinion is received from OGC to the effect that the Government
            cannot enforce collection of a significant amount from assets or
            income.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When the debtor is deceased (individuals only), disappeared
            (individuals only), or when it is impossible or impractical to
            obtain the debtor&apos;s signature, and the conditions of 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              § 1956.136(b)(2) of
            </aref>
             this subpart are met.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15607'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1956:C:1956.137
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1956.137
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='137' psec='' tq='N'>
              1956.137
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15608'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1956:C:1956.138
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1956.138
      </num>
      <head>
        Processing.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='138' psec='' tq='N'>
              1956.138
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Processing.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Approval.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When a debt settlement application is approved, the State Director
            will:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Send the original approved Form FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             1956-1 to the Finance Office.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notify debtors in writing of settlement approval, including the
            specific amount and terms of the offer that 
            <PRTPAGE P='174' />
            were accepted, for compromise and adjustment offers under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='124' psec='' tq='N'>
                1956.124
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and cancellations with application under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              § 1956.130(a) of
            </aref>
             this subpart.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Not be required to notify debtors of settlement approval when debts
            are cancelled without application under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='130' psec='#b' tq='N'>
                1956.130(b)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             or charged off under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              § 1956.136 of
            </aref>
             this subpart.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Requesting additional information.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When rejection appears to be necessary either because of lack of
            information or because the amount of a compromise or adjustment
            offer is inadequate, the State Director may request the servicing
            official to obtain the additional information or make an effort to
            obtain a more acceptable offer, as the circumstances justify. Notice
            of rejection of an offer will be withheld in such cases until
            sufficient time has elapsed to enable the debtor to present further
            information or a new offer.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Rejection.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When a debt settlement application is rejected, the State Director
            will:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Insert the reasons for rejection on the Form FmHA or its successor
            agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             1956-1.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Retain the original Form FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             1956-1 in the State Office and return case files and copies of Form
            FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             1956-1 to the servicing official.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Request the Finance Office to return any adjustment or compromise
            payment held by the Finance Office to the borrower, in care of the
            servicing official.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Return any adjustment or compromise payment held by the State
            Office to the borrower, in care of the servicing official.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notify the debtor in writing of the reasons for the rejection for
            compromise and adjustment offers under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='124' psec='' tq='N'>
                1956.124
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and cancellations with application under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              § 1956.130(a) of
            </aref>
             this subpart.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Appeal rights.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In accordance with Subpart B of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              Part 
              <subref title='7' part='1900' tq='N'>
                1900 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , the debtor will be given the right to appeal the rejection of any
            debt settlement offer made by the debtor under this subpart.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15609'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1956:C:1956.139
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1956.139
      </num>
      <head>
        Collections.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          53 FR 13100
        </aref>
        , Apr. 21, 1988, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          68 FR 61332
        </aref>
        , Oct. 28, 2003]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='139' psec='' tq='N'>
              1956.139
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Collections.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When the debtor offers a lump-sum payment in compromise or an
            initial payment on an adjustment offer, that payment will accompany
            the settlement application at the time the application is filed with
            the servicing official.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             [Reserved]
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Checks or check transmittal letters containing restrictive
            notations such as “Settlement in full” or “Payment in full,” will be
            forwarded to the State Office where they will be retained until
            approval or rejection of the offer. The use of restrictive notations
            will be discouraged to the fullest extent possible.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All payments evidenced by Form FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             451-2, “Schedule of Remittances,” bearing the legend “Compromise
            Offer—FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
            ” or “Adjustment Offer—FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
            ,” will be held in the Deposits Fund Account by the Finance Office
            until notification is received from the State Office of the approval
            or rejection of the offer.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon receipt of an approved Form FmHA or its successor agency under
            
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             1956-1, remittances will be applied in accordance with established
            policies, beginning with the oldest loan included in the settlement,
            except that when the request for settlement includes loans made from
            different revolving funds, the Finance Office will prorate the
            amount received on the basis of the total principal balance due the
            respective revolving funds.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon notification of a rejection of a debtor&apos;s offer and
            receipt of a request from the State Director for a refund, the
            Finance Office will refund to the debtor, in care of the servicing
            official, the amount held in the Deposits Fund Account.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When a debtor&apos;s adjustment offer is approved, the accounts
            involved will not be adjusted in the records of the Finance Office
            until all payments have been made. Form FmHA or its successor agency
            under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             1956-1 will be held in a suspense file 
            <PRTPAGE P='175' />
            pending payment of the full amount of the approved offer.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If an approved debt settlement agreement is later voided by the
            State Director in accordance with 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              § 1956.142(e) of
            </aref>
             this subpart, any payments which have been received shall be
            retained as payments on the debt owed at the time the compromise or
            adjustment offer was approved.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            53 FR 13100
          </aref>
          , Apr. 21, 1988, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            68 FR 61332
          </aref>
          , Oct. 28, 2003]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15610'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1956:C:1956.140-1956.141
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1956.140-1956.141
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='140-1956' psec='' tq='N'>
              1956.140-1956
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .141
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15611'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1956:C:1956.142
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1956.142
      </num>
      <head>
        Delinquent adjustment agreements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='142' psec='' tq='N'>
              1956.142
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Delinquent adjustment agreements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The servicing official is responsible for notifying debtors in
            advance of the due dates of payments on debt settlement agreements
            and for monitoring compliance with the terms of settlement
            agreements. If a payment is delinquent, the servicing official
            should contact the debtor promptly to determine the reason for the
            delinquency and the debtor&apos;s plan for completing the agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Delinquencies of 30 days or more will be reported to the State
            Director along with other pertinent information and the
            recommendation of the servicing official regarding further handling
            of the case.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State Director may extend, for ninety days, the time for making
            the payments when the circumstances of the case justify an
            extension. Extensions for a greater period of time may be made by
            the State Director upon the recommendation of the County Committee
            and the servicing official.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When the debtor is financially unable to meet the terms of the debt
            settlement agreement, the State Director may void the existing
            agreement and process a new settlement more consistent with the
            debtor&apos;s repayment ability, provided the facts in the case
            justify such action.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the State Director determines that the debtor cannot or will not
            meet the terms of the settlement agreement and if the facts do not
            justify approval of a new settlement agreement, the State Director
            will void the existing agreement and direct the servicing official
            to take other servicing actions appropriate to the circumstances of
            the case.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When an adjustment agreement is voided, the State Director will
            notify the debtor giving the reasons in writing, with a copy to the
            Finance Office and to the servicing official. Upon receipt, the
            Finance Office will return the original Form FmHA or its successor
            agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             1956-1 to the State Office.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15612'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1956:C:1956.143
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1956.143
      </num>
      <head>
        Debt restructuring—hospitals and health care facilities.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          59 FR 46160
        </aref>
        , Sept. 7, 1994, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          68 FR 61332
        </aref>
        , Oct. 28, 2003; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          69 FR 69106
        </aref>
        , Nov. 26, 2004]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='143' psec='' tq='N'>
              1956.143
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Debt restructuring—hospitals and health care facilities.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          This section pertains exclusively to delinquent Community Facility
          hospital and health care facility loans. Those facilities which are
          nonprogram (NP) loans as defined in 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            § 1951.203 (f) of
          </aref>
           subpart E of 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='1951' tq='N'>
              1951 of this chapter
            </subref>
          </aref>
           are excluded. The purpose of debt restructuring is to keep the
          hospital or health care facility in operation with manageable debt.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Definitions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             As used in this section, the following definitions apply:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Consolidation.
          </E>
           The combining of two or more debt instruments into one instrument,
          normally accompanied by reamortization.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Debt writedown.
          </E>
           A one-time reduction of the debt owed to FmHA or its successor agency
          under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
           including principal and interest. This reduction will be the minimum
          amount necessary to meet the level of the facility&apos;s ability to
          service the debt. The writedown will be applied first to interest and
          then principal.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Delinquency due to circumstances beyond the control of the debtor.
          </E>
           Includes situations such as: The debtor has less money than planned
          due to unexpected and uncontrollable events such as unexpected loss of
          service area population, unforeseeable costs incurred for compliance
          with State or Federal regulatory requirements, or the loss of key
          personnel.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Delinquent debtor.
          </E>
           For purposes of this section, delinquency is defined as being 180
          days behind schedule on the FmHA or its successor agency under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
           payments. That is, one full annual installment or the equivalent for
          monthly, quarterly, or semiannual installments.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Eligibility.
          </E>
           Applicants must be delinquent due to circumstances beyond 
          <PRTPAGE P='176' />
          their control and have acted in good faith by trying to fulfill the
          agreements with FmHA or its successor agency under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
           in connection with the delinquent loans.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Interest rate reduction.
          </E>
           Reduction of the interest rate on the restructured loan to as low as
          the poverty line interest rate in effect on community and business
          programs loans.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Loan deferral.
          </E>
           The temporary delay of principal and interest payments for up to 6
          months. The debtor must be able to demonstrate the ability to pay the
          debt, as restructured, at the end of this delay period.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Net recovery value.
          </E>
           A calculation of the net value of the collateral and other assets
          held by the debtor. This value would be determined by adding the fair
          market value of FmHA or its successor agency under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
          &apos;s interest in any real property pledged as collateral for the
          loan, plus the value of any other assets pledged or otherwise
          available for the repayment of the debt, minus the anticipated
          administrative and legal expenses that would be incurred in connection
          with the liquidation of the loan. This value of the assets should be
          calculated based upon the facility continuing to operate as a going
          concern. Therefore, the facility should be valued not merely as an
          empty building but as a facility continuing to offer health care
          services which may, or may not, be similar to those offered by the
          current operators.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Operations review.
          </E>
           A study of management and business operations of the facility by an
          independent expert. For example, a study of a hospital and nursing
          home would include such areas as: general and administrative, dietary,
          housekeeping, laundry, nursing, physical plant, social services,
          income potential, Federal, State, and insurance payments, and rate
          analysis. Also, recommendations and conclusions are to be included in
          the study which would indicate the creditworthiness of the facility
          and its ability to continue as a going concern. In analyzing a
          debtor&apos;s proposed restructuring plan, FmHA or its successor
          agency under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
           may contract for the completion of an operations review. These
          reviews will be developed by individuals and entities who have
          demonstrated an expertise in the analysis of health care facilities
          from an operational and administrative standpoint. FmHA or its
          successor agency under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
           will consider the following criteria for selection: past experience
          in health care facility analysis, a familiarity with the problems of
          rural health care facilities, a knowledge of the particular area
          currently served by the facility in question, and a willingness to
          work with both FmHA or its successor agency under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
           and the debtor in developing a final plan for restructuring.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Restructured loan.
          </E>
           A revision of the debt instruments including any combination of the
          following: writing down of accumulated interest charges and principal,
          deferral, consolidation, and adjustment of the interest rates and
          terms, usually followed by reamortization.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Debtor notification.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All servicing actions permitted under subpart E of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1951' tq='N'>
                1951 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
             are to be exhausted prior to consideration for debt restructuring
            under this section. To this end, the servicing official must ensure
            that the casefile clearly documents that all servicing actions under
            subpart E of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1951' tq='N'>
                1951 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
             have been exhausted and that the debtor is at least 1 full
            year&apos;s debt service behind schedule for a minimum of 180 days.
            The debtor then should be informed of the debt restructuring
            available under this section by using language similar to that
            provided in Guide 1 of this subpart (available in any FmHA or its
            successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             Office) as follows:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any introductory paragraph;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A paragraph concerning prior servicing attempts;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A discussion of eligibility, as defined in this section, including
            the provision that the debtor acted in good faith in connection with
            their FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             loan and that the delinquency was caused by circumstances beyond
            their control;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Two paragraphs that explain the goal of the debt restructuring
            program;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A paragraph stating that debt restructuring may include a
            combination of servicing actions listed in paragraph (a) of this
            section;
            <PRTPAGE P='177' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Information that details what the debtor must do to apply for
            restructuring. A response must be received within 45 days of receipt
            of this letter to request consideration for debt restructuring and
            the request must include projected balance sheets, budgets, and
            cash-flow statements which include and clearly identify funding of
            the FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             reserve account for the next 3 years;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A discussion of FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
            &apos;s analysis and calculation process; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A paragraph identifying the FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             official who may be contacted for assistance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              State Director&apos;s restructuring determination.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon receipt of the delinquent debtor&apos;s request for debt
            restructuring consideration, the State Director will:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Within 15 days of receipt of debtor&apos;s request, if an
            operations review is deemed necessary, send a memorandum to the
            Administrator asking for program authority to contract for the
            review in accordance with Exhibit D of FmHA or its successor agency
            under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             Instruction 2024-A (available in any FmHA or its successor agency
            under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             Office). The name of the debtor involved and the projected amount
            of funds anticipated to be spent for the contract should also be
            provided. It is anticipated that an operations review will be
            necessary in most cases and that the only exceptions would be for
            smaller health care facilities or facilities that have developed a
            proposed plan that is comprehensive and realistic. Upon receipt of
            the Administrator&apos;s program contracting approval authority, a
            contract is to be awarded to an organization qualified to perform an
            operations review as defined in paragraph (a) of this section. The
            operations review normally will be completed and delivered to FmHA
            or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             within 60 days of the award date.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Contract for an appraisal to be performed by an independent,
            qualified fee appraiser. Note: To the extent possible, the appraisal
            should be scheduled for completion no later than the completion date
            of the operations review.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Complete an analysis of the operations review, appraisal, and other
            documented information, and make an eligibility determination.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Eligibility determination. The State Director must conclude that
            the debtor is eligible for debt restructuring consideration. This
            conclusion will be clearly documented in the casefile based on a
            review of the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_3_i_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The debtor acted in good faith with regard to the delinquent loan.
            The casefile must reflect the debtor&apos;s cooperation in exploring
            servicing alternatives. The casefile should contain no evidence of
            fraud, waste, or conversion by the debtor, and no evidence that the
            debtor violated the loan agreement or FmHA or its successor agency
            under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             regulations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_3_i_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The delinquency was caused by circumstances beyond the control of
            the debtor. This determination will be based on the debtor&apos;s
            narrative on this issue, which is a required part of the application
            for debt restructuring, and a separate review of the debtor&apos;s
            casefile and operations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_3_i_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             As part of the application for debt restructuring, the debtor
            submitted a proposed operating plan that presents feasible
            alternatives for addressing the delinquency.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Debtor determined eligible.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the debtor is determined to be eligible for debt restructuring,
            a determination of a net recovery value and level of debt the
            facility will support will be made. It is anticipated that meetings
            with the debtor, the contractor who performed the operations review,
            and others, as appropriate, could be necessary to develop these
            values; although it should be emphasized throughout these meetings
            that any calculations and conclusions reached are preliminary in
            nature, pending final review by the Administrator. For debt
            restructuring calculations and computing a feasible cash-flow
            projection, the following order and combinations of loan servicing
            actions will be followed:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_3_ii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Loan deferral for up to 6 months.
            <PRTPAGE P='178' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_3_ii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Interest rate reduction to not less than the poverty line rate as
            determined by FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             Instruction 440.1, exhibit B (available in any FmHA or its
            successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             Office). Interest rate reduction will be considered only in
            conjunction with an extension of the term of the loan to the
            remaining useful life of the facility or 40 years, whichever is
            less.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_3_ii_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Debt writedown. Other creditors of the debtor, representing a
            substantial portion of the total debt, are expected to participate
            in the development of a restructuring plan which includes debt
            writedown. Debt writedown participation by other creditors should be
            on a pro rata basis with the FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             writedown. However, failure of these creditors to agree to
            participate in the plan shall not preclude the use of principal and
            interest writedown by FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             if it is determined that this option results in the least cost to
            the Federal Government.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Debtor determined ineligible.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the State Director concludes that the debtor is not eligible for
            debt restructuring consideration for any of the reasons listed in
            paragraph (c)(3)(i) of this section, then the debtor will be
            notified by a letter that includes the following information:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_3_iii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The basis for the determination;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_3_iii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The next step in servicing the loan: possible acceleration if the
            delinquency is not cured; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_3_iii_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The debtor may appeal this determination in accordance with subpart
            B of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1900' tq='N'>
                1900 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_3_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
            <head>
              State Director&apos;s recommendation.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon completion of the determination of net recovery value and
            restructured debt in accordance with paragraph (c)(3)(ii) of this
            section, and prior to formal presentation to the borrower, the State
            Director will forward a recommendation to the National Office with
            the following documentation:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_3_iv_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             That all other servicing efforts have been exhausted as required in
            paragraph (b) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_3_iv_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Financial statements including balance sheets, income and expense,
            cash-flows for the most recent actual year, and projections for the
            next 3 years. The amount of FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
            &apos;s restructured debt and reserve account requirements are to be
            clearly indicated on the projected statements. Also, operating
            statistics including number of beds, patient days of care,
            outpatient visits, occupancy percentage, etc., for the same periods
            of time must be included.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_3_iv_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Copies of the operations review, developed for the particular loan,
            and appraisal.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_3_iv_D'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (D)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Calculations of the net recovery value.(E) Debt restructuring
            calculations including a listing of the various servicing
            combinations used in these calculations as contained in paragraph
            (c)(3)(ii) of this section. For example:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          (
          <E T='03'>
            1
          </E>
          ) Interest rate reduced from the applicant&apos;s current rate on all
          loans to the poverty line rate as determined by FmHA or its successor
          agency under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
           instruction 440.1, exhibit B (available in any FmHA or its successor
          agency under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
           Office); and
        </P>
        <P>
          (
          <E T='03'>
            2
          </E>
          ) Extension of the terms from 25 to 30 years.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_3_iv_F'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (F)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Information concerning discussions with the debtor and their
            agreement or disagreement with the calculations and recommendations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_3_iv_G'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (G)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If debt restructuring is proposed:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          (
          <E T='03'>
            1
          </E>
          ) A draft of Form RD 3560-15, if applicable, and any other necessary
          comments or requirements that may be required by OGC and Bond Counsel
          in 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            § 1951.223 (c)(3) and (4) of
          </aref>
           subpart E of 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='1951' tq='N'>
              1951 of this chapter
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          (
          <E T='03'>
            2
          </E>
          ) A draft of Form FmHA or its successor agency under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
           1956-1, if applicable. Complete only parts I, II, VI, and VIII. Part
          VI, “Debtor&apos;s Offer and Certification,” will be in a separate
          attachment and contain the adjusted unpaid principal amount for which
          FmHA or its successor agency under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
           approval is requested. In Part VI of the form, type “see attached.”
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_3_iv_H'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (H)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the proposed restructured debt will not cash-flow or is less
            than the net recovery value, omit the items in paragraph
            (c)(3)(iv)(G) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              National Office processing of State Director&apos;s request.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             After reviewing 
            <PRTPAGE P='179' />
            the recommendation to either debt restructure or liquidate for the
            net recovery value, the Administrator, after concurring, modifying,
            or not concurring in the recommendation, will return the submission
            for further processing.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a debt writedown is used in the restructuring process, the
            amount will be included in the National Office transmittal
            memorandum. The draft Form FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             1956-1 will not need to be finalized and returned to the
            Administrator for signature. The State Director&apos;s signature on
            the final copy will be sufficient. However, a copy of the National
            Office memorandum is to be attached to the form when completed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Debtor notification of debt restructuring and net recovery value
              calculations.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State Director will provide a copy of the basis for the debt
            restructuring or net recovery determination to the debtor.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the value of the restructured loan is equal to, or greater than,
            the recovery value, the debtor will be made an offer to accept the
            restructured debt by using language similar to that provided in
            Guide 2 of this subpart (available in any FmHA or its successor
            agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             Office) and including the following paragraphs:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An introductory paragraph indicating that FmHA or its successor
            agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             has concluded its consideration of the debtor&apos;s request;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A paragraph indicating FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
            &apos;s approval of the debt restructuring request and that
            acceptance must be received by FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             within 45 days from receipt of this letter; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             That the debtor&apos;s acceptance will require the execution of a
            Shared Appreciation Agreement similar to Guide 4 of this subpart
            (available in any FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             Office) and possible new debt instruments accompanied by Bond
            Counsel opinions.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the debt analysis calculations indicate that a restructured debt
            would be less than the net recovery value of the security, a letter
            using language similar to that provided in Guide 3 of this subpart
            (available in any FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             Office), will be sent to the debtor that includes the following
            paragraphs:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An introductory paragraph indicating that FmHA or its successor
            agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             has concluded its consideration of the debtor&apos;s request;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Paragraphs indicating that:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='e_2_ii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The debtor may pay FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             the net recovery value of the loan. The debtor will be given 30
            days from receipt of this letter to inform FmHA or its successor
            agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             of its intent, 90 days to finalize the payoff, and will be notified
            that an election to pay off FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             would require the execution of a Net Recovery Buy Out Recapture
            Agreement, similar to that provided in Guide 5 of this subpart
            (available in any FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             Office); or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='e_2_ii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the debt is not paid off at the net recovery value, FmHA or its
            successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             will proceed to liquidate the loan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Debtor responses to debt restructuring and net recovery value
              calculations.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Responses from the debtor will be handled as follows:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Acceptance of FmHA or its successor agency under 
              <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
                Public Law 103-354
              </aref>
              &apos;s restructured debt offer.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When a debtor accepts the offer for debt restructuring, processing
            will be in accordance with 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              § 1951.223 (c) of
            </aref>
             subpart E of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1951' tq='N'>
                1951 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
             using the adjusted unpaid principal and outstanding accrued
            interest at the Administrator&apos;s approved interest rate and
            terms. The debtor will be required to execute a Shared Appreciation
            Agreement which will provide that, should the debtor sell or
            transfer title to the facility within the next 10 years, FmHA or its
            successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             is entitled to a portion of any gain realized. This agreement will
            include language similar to that found in Guide 4 of this subpart
            (available in any FmHA or its successor agency under Public Law 103-
            <PRTPAGE P='180' />
            354 Office). The original of Form FmHA or its successor agency under
            
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             1956-1, with appropriate attachments signed by the State Director,
            and a copy of the Shared Appreciation Agreement will be sent to the
            Finance Office. Note: All documents pertaining to this transaction
            will be sent to the Finance Office in one single complete package;
            and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Acceptance by debtor to pay off loan at the recovery value.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Processing of this transaction will be in accordance with 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              § 1956.124 of
            </aref>
             this subpart. However, the account does not need to be accelerated.
            The debtor will be required to execute a Net Recovery Buy Out
            Recapture Agreement, similar to that found in Guide 5 of this
            subpart (available in any FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             Office). The original of Form FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             1956-1, with appropriate attachments signed by the State Director,
            and a copy of the recorded Net Recovery Buy Out Recapture Agreement
            will be sent to the Finance Office. The executed Net Recovery Buy
            Out Recapture Agreement will be recorded in the county in which the
            facility is located. The Finance Office will credit the accounts of
            debtors who entered into Net Recovery Buy Out Recapture Agreements
            with the amount paid by the debtor (net recovery value). Note: All
            documents pertaining to this transaction will be sent to the Finance
            Office in one single complete package.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Collection and processing of recapture.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             becomes aware of the sale or transfer of title to the facility on
            which there is an effective Net Recovery Buy Out Recapture Agreement
            (Guide 5 of this subpart available in any FmHA or its successor
            agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             Office) or a Shared Appreciation Agreement (Guide 4 of this subpart
            available in any FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             Office) outstanding and a determination is made that a recapture is
            appropriate, FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             will notify the debtor of the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Date and amount of recapture due; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             action to be taken if debtor does not respond within the designated
            timeframe with the amount of recapture due.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             [Reserved]
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When the amount of the recapture has been paid and credited to the
            debtor&apos;s account, the debtor will be released from liability by
            using Form FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             1965-8, “Release from Personal Liability,” modified as appropriate.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
            <head>
              No recapture due.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             determines there is no recapture due, the Net Recovery Buy Out
            Recapture Agreement (Guide 5 of this subpart available in any FmHA
            or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             Office) or Shared Appreciation Agreement (Guide 4 of this subpart
            available in any FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             Office) will be appropriately annotated, the Recapture Agreement
            released from the record, and the Agreement returned to the debtor.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            59 FR 46160
          </aref>
          , Sept. 7, 1994, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            68 FR 61332
          </aref>
          , Oct. 28, 2003; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            69 FR 69106
          </aref>
          , Nov. 26, 2004]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15613'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1956:C:1956.144
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1956.144
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='144' psec='' tq='N'>
              1956.144
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15614'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1956:C:1956.145
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1956.145
      </num>
      <head>
        Disposition of essential FmHA or its successor agency under Public Law
        103-354 records.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          53 FR 13100
        </aref>
        , Apr. 21, 1988, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 21346
        </aref>
        , Apr. 21, 1993]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='145' psec='' tq='N'>
              1956.145
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Disposition of essential FmHA or its successor agency under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
           records.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          FmHA or its successor agency under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
           Instruction 2033-A (available in any FmHA or its successor agency
          under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
           office) identifies an “essential FmHA or its successor agency under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
           record” as the original of any document or record which provides
          evidence of indebtedness or obligation to FmHA or its successor agency
          under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
           and includes, but is not limited to: promissory notes, assumption
          agreements and valuable documents, such as bonds fully registered as
          to principal and interest.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Essential FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             records evidencing debts settled by compromise, completed
            adjustment or cancelled with application will be returned to the
            debtor or to the debtors&apos; 
            <PRTPAGE P='181' />
            legal representative. The appropriate legend, such as “Satisfied by
            Approved Compromise,” and the date of the final action will be
            stamped or typed on the original document. This same information
            plus the date the original document is returned to the debtor will
            be shown on a copy to be placed in the debtor&apos;s case folder.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Essential FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             records evidencing debts cancelled without application will be
            placed in the debtor&apos;s case folder and disposed of pursuant to
            FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             Instruction 2033-A (available in any FmHA or its successor agency
            under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             office). However, if the debtor requests the document(s), they must
            be stamped “Satisfied by Approved Cancellation” and returned.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Essential FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             records evidencing charged off debts will be retained in the
            servicing office and will not be stamped or returned to the debtor.
            They will be destroyed six years after chargeoff pursuant to FmHA or
            its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             Instruction 2033-A (available in any FmHA or its successor agency
            under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             office).
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            53 FR 13100
          </aref>
          , Apr. 21, 1988, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 21346
          </aref>
          , Apr. 21, 1993]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15615'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1956:C:1956.146
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1956.146
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='146' psec='' tq='N'>
              1956.146
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15616'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1956:C:1956.147
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1956.147
      </num>
      <head>
        Debt settlement under the Federal Claims Collection Act.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          55 FR 30197
        </aref>
        , July 25, 1990, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          59 FR 46162
        </aref>
        , Sept. 7, 1994]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='147' psec='' tq='N'>
              1956.147
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Debt settlement under the Federal Claims Collection Act.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The U.S. Department of Justice (DOJ) and the General Accounting Office
          are charged with the responsibility for implementing the Federal
          Claims Collection Act and have promulgated the Federal Claims
          Collection Act Joint Standards (FCCAJS) (
          <aref type='CFR'>
            4 CFR parts 
            <subref title='4' part='101-105' tq='N'>
              101-105
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ) to inform Government Agencies on how to settle debts and claims
          which the Agency does not have independent statutory authority to
          settle. With the exception of loans and claims with outstanding
          balances of $20,000 or less, exclusive of interest, penalties, and
          administrative costs, settlements must be submitted to and approved by
          the United States Attorney or the DOJ. Debt Settlement of Economic
          Opportunity Cooperative loans, Claims Against Third Party Converters,
          Nonprogram loans, Industrial Development Grants, Rural Development
          Loan Fund loans, Intermediary Relending Program loans, Nonprofit
          National Corporations Loans and Grants, Indian Tribal Land Acquisition
          Loans (to the extent settlement cannot be effected pursuant to 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='137' psec='' tq='N'>
              1956.137
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ), and 601 Energy Impact Assistance Grants are programs that must be
          settled under the FCCAJS.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Debt settlement of the subject loans and claims falls in the
            following categories:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Settlement of loans and claims may be approved by the Administrator
            when the outstanding balance of the indebtedness involved in the
            settlement in $20,000 or less, exclusive of interest, penalties, and
            administrative costs. These loans and claims will be submitted to
            the National Office on Form FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             1956-1, “Application for Settlement of Indebtedness,” for debt
            settlement. Subsequent to approval, Form FmHA or its successor
            agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             1956-1 will be distributed in accordance with the Forms Manual
            Insert (FMI).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Loans and claims with an outstanding balance of $200,000 or less
            inclusive of interest, penalties, and administrative costs, but with
            an outstanding balance greater than $20,000, exclusive of interest,
            penalties, and administrative costs, after approval by the State
            Director will be referred to your Regional Office of the General
            Counsel (OGC) for referral to the United States Attorney in whose
            judicial district the debtor can be found. The form to be used is
            the Claims Collection Litigation Report (CCLR). This form should be
            available through the U.S. Attorney. A memorandum from the State
            Director should be attached to the CCLR recommending acceptance of
            the debt settlement. If the State Director after reviewing the CCLR
            does not recommend acceptance, the State Director has the authority
            to reject the debt settlement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Loans and claims with an outstanding balance over $200,000,
            inclusive of interest, penalties, and administrative costs, will be
            referred to the 
            <PRTPAGE P='182' />
            Administrator and will include the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The case file(s).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A completed CCLR.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Copies of the notes, security agreements, and mortgages.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A current appraisal of any security owned by the debtor.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A narrative which will include:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='a_3_v_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Recommendation for the acceptance of the debt settlement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='a_3_v_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The type of loan involved, a short history of the loan, and why the
            debtor failed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='a_3_v_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Steps taken to collect the loan(s).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='a_3_v_D'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (D)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An analysis of the debtor&apos;s future repayment ability. This
            should discuss if the debtor has any other assets or has concealed
            or improperly transferred assets, if known. If the debtor is an
            individual, this should include consideration of the debtor&apos;s
            present and potential income and inheritance prospects.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='a_3_v_E'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (E)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Why acceptance of the debt settlement offer is in the best interest
            of the Government.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the Administrator concurs with the recommendation for the debt
            settlement, it will be referred by the FmHA or its successor agency
            under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             National Office to OGC for referral to the Commercial Litigation
            Branch, Civil Division, U.S. Department of Justice, Washington, DC
            20530.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When a debtor has a Community Programs or Business and Industry
            loans(s) and defined in this subpart, these loan(s) will be debt
            settled under the authority of the Consolidated Farm and Rural
            Development Act. In such cases, the subject loans and claims should
            be listed under part II(B) on Form FmHA or its successor agency
            under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             1956-1, as other debts owed FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
            . Normally, all the security for the subject loans and claims should
            be disposed of prior to the submission for debt settlement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             It is not necessary to obtain approval of the United States
            Attorney or the DOJ (as the case may be) in cases where FmHA or its
            successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             decides not to settle a loan or claim.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            55 FR 30197
          </aref>
          , July 25, 1990, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            59 FR 46162
          </aref>
          , Sept. 7, 1994]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15617'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1956:C:1956.148
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1956.148
      </num>
      <head>
        Exception authority.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='148' psec='' tq='N'>
              1956.148
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Exception authority.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The Administrator may make an exception to any requirement or
          provision of this subpart which is not inconsistent with the
          authorizing statute or other applicable law if the Administrator
          determines that application of the requirement or provision would
          adversely affect the Government&apos;s interest. Requests for
          exceptions must be made in writing by the State Director and supported
          with documentation to explain the adverse effect on the
          Government&apos;s interest, propose alternative courses of action, and
          show how the adverse effect will be eliminated or minimized if the
          exception is granted. Any settlement actions approved by the
          Administrator under this section will be documented on Form FmHA or
          its successor agency under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
           1956-1 and returned to the State Office for submission to the Finance
          Office.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15618'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1956:C:1956.149
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1956.149
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='149' psec='' tq='N'>
              1956.149
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15619'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1956:C:1956.150
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1956.150
      </num>
      <head>
        OMB control number.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          59 FR 46162
        </aref>
        , Sept. 7, 1994]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='150' psec='' tq='N'>
              1956.150
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          OMB control number.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The reporting requirements contained in this regulation have been
          approved by the Office of Management and Budget and assigned OMB
          control number 0575-0124. Public reporting burden for this collection
          of information is estimated to vary from 
          <FR>
            1/2
          </FR>
           hour to 30 hours per response with an average of 8.14 hours per
          response, including the time for reviewing instructions, searching
          existing data sources, gathering and maintaining the data needed, and
          completing and reviewing the collection of information. Send comments
          regarding this burden estimate or any other aspect of this collection
          of information, including suggestions for reducing this burden, to
          Department of Agriculture, Clearance Officer, OIRM, Ag Box 7630,
          Washington, D.C. 20250; and to the Office of Information and
          Regulatory Affairs, Office of Management and Budget, Washington, DC
          20503.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            59 FR 46162
          </aref>
          , Sept. 7, 1994]
          <PRTPAGE P='183' />
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>