<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol12'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779
    </extid>
    <num>
      1779
    </num>
    <head>
      WATER AND WASTE DISPOSAL PROGRAMS GUARANTEED LOANS
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='5' sect='301' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/5/301.html'>
              5 U.S.C. 301
            </subref>
            , 
            <subref title='5' sect='7' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/5/7.html'>
              7
            </subref>
          </aref>
           U.S.C. 1989, 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='16' sect='1005' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/1005.html'>
              16 U.S.C. 1005
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            66 FR 23138
          </aref>
          , May 8, 2001, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='14421'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1779.1
      </num>
      <head>
        General.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This part contains the regulations for Water and Waste Disposal
            (WW) loans guaranteed by the Agency and applies to lenders, holders,
            borrowers, and other parties involved in making, guaranteeing,
            holding, servicing, or liquidating such loans.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The purpose of the WW guaranteed loan program is to provide a loan
            guarantee for the construction or improvement of water and waste
            projects serving the financially needy communities in rural areas.
            This purpose is achieved through bolstering the existing private
            credit structure through the guarantee of quality loans which will
            provide lasting benefits.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14422'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1779.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The following general definitions are applicable to the terms used in
          this part:
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Agency.
          </E>
           The Rural Utilities Service which is within the Rural Development
          mission area of the United States Department of Agriculture or its
          successor agencies with authority delegated by the Secretary of
          Agriculture to administer the Water and Waste Disposal Programs.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Application.
          </E>
           An Agency prescribed form to request an Agency guarantee (available
          in any Agency office).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Arm&apos;s length transaction.
          </E>
           The sale, release, or disposition of assets in which the title to the
          property passes to a ready, willing, and able third party who is not
          affiliated with, or related to, and has no security, monetary, or
          stockholder interest in the borrower or transferor at the time of the
          transaction.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Assignment Guarantee Agreement.
          </E>
           The signed agreement among the Agency, the lender, and the holder
          setting forth the terms and conditions of an assignment of the
          guaranteed portion of a loan or any part thereof (available in any
          Agency office).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Borrower.
          </E>
           The entity that borrows money from the lender.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Collateral.
          </E>
           Property pledged to secure the guaranteed loan.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Conditional Commitment for Guarantee.
          </E>
           The Agency&apos;s written statement to the lender that the material
          submitted is approved subject to the completion of all conditions and
          requirements contained in the commitment (available in any Agency
          office).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Guaranteed loan.
          </E>
           A loan made and serviced by a lender for which the Agency and lender
          have entered into a Lender&apos;s Agreement and for which the 
          <PRTPAGE P='269' />
          Agency has issued a Loan Note Guarantee.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Holder.
          </E>
           The person or entity (other than the lender) who holds all or a part
          of the guaranteed portion of the loan with no servicing
          responsibilities. When the lender assigns part or all of the
          guaranteed portion of the loan to an assignee, the assignee becomes a
          holder when the Assignment Guarantee Agreement is signed by all
          parties.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Immediate family.
          </E>
           Individuals who are closely related by blood or by marriage, or
          within the same household, such as a spouse, parent, child, brother,
          sister, aunt, uncle, grandparent, grandchild, niece, or nephew.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            In-house expenses.
          </E>
           In-house expenses include, but are not limited to, employees&apos;
          salaries, retainers being paid to lawyers, travel, and overhead.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Insurance.
          </E>
           Fire, windstorm, lightning, hail, explosion, riot, civil commotion,
          aircraft, vehicles, smoke, builder&apos;s risk, liability, property
          damage, flood or mudslide, worker&apos;s compensation, fidelity bond,
          malpractice, or any similar insurance that is available and needed to
          protect the security or that is required by law.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Joint financing.
          </E>
           Two or more lenders (or any combination of lenders and other
          financial sources) making separate relatively contemporaneous loans or
          grants to supply the funds required by one borrower. For example, such
          joint financing may consist of the Agency&apos;s financial assistance
          with the Economic Development Administration, Department of Housing
          and Urban Development (HUD), or other Federal and State agencies, and
          private and quasi-public financial institutions.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Lender.
          </E>
           The person or organization making and responsible for servicing the
          loan. The lender is also referred to in this part as the applicant who
          is requesting a guarantee during the preapplication and application
          stage of processing.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Lender&apos;s Agreement.
          </E>
           The signed agreement between the Agency and the lender containing the
          lender&apos;s responsibilities when the Loan Note Guarantee is issued
          (available in any Agency office).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Loan Note Guarantee.
          </E>
           The signed commitment issued by the Agency containing the terms and
          conditions of the guarantee of an identified loan (available in any
          Agency office).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Market value.
          </E>
           The amount for which property would sell for its highest and best use
          at a voluntary sale in an arm&apos;s length transaction.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Note.
          </E>
           An evidence of debt. In those instances where the Agency guarantees a
          bond issue, “note” shall also be construed to include a bond or other
          evidence of indebtedness, as appropriate.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Participation.
          </E>
           Sale of an interest in a loan in which the lender retains the note,
          collateral securing the note, and all responsibility for loan
          servicing and liquidation.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Principals of borrowers.
          </E>
           The owners, officers, directors, entities, and supervisors directly
          involved in the operation and management of the borrower.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Protective advances.
          </E>
           Advances made by the lender for the purpose of preserving and
          protecting the collateral where the debtor has failed to, and will not
          or cannot, meet obligations to protect or preserve collateral.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Report of loss.
          </E>
           An Agency form used by lenders when reporting a loss under an Agency
          guarantee (available in any Agency office).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Rural and rural area.
          </E>
           Any area not in a city or town with a population in excess of 10,000
          inhabitants, according to the latest decennial census of the United
          States
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Service area.
          </E>
           The area reasonably expected to be served by the project being
          financed by the guaranteed loan.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State.
          </E>
           Any of the 50 States, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin
          Islands of the United States, Guam, American Samoa, Commonwealth of
          the Northern Mariana Islands, Republic of the Marshall Islands,
          Republic of Palau, and the Federated States of Micronesia.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State Bond Banks and State Bond Pools.
          </E>
           An entity authorized by the State to issue State debt instruments and
          utilize the funds received to finance the construction or improvement
          of drinking water or waste disposal facilities.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State Director.
          </E>
           The Rural Development State Director or the staff member who has been
          delegated authority to perform action on behalf of the State Director.
          <PRTPAGE P='270' />
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Substantive change.
          </E>
           Any change in the purpose of the loan or any change in the financial
          condition of the borrower or the collateral which would jeopardize the
          performance of the loan.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Transfer and assumption.
          </E>
           The conveyance by a debtor to an assuming party of the assets,
          collateral, and liabilities of the loan in return for the assuming
          party&apos;s binding promise to pay the outstanding debt.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Waste disposal.
          </E>
           Sanitary sewer (treatment and collection), solid waste, and storm
          drainage facilities.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            WW.
          </E>
           An acronym for Water and Waste Disposal.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14423'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1779.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Full faith and credit.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Full faith and credit.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The Loan Note Guarantee constitutes an obligation supported by the
          full faith and credit of the United States and is not contestable
          except for fraud or misrepresentation (including negligent
          misrepresentation) of which the lender or holder has actual knowledge,
          participates in, or condones. A note which provides for the payment of
          interest on interest shall not be guaranteed and any Loan Note
          Guarantee or Assignment Guarantee Agreement attached to, or relating
          to, a note which provides for payment of interest on interest is void.
          The Loan Note Guarantee will not be enforceable by the lender to the
          extent any loss is occasioned by violation of usury laws, negligent
          servicing, or failure to obtain the required security regardless of
          the time at which the Agency acquires knowledge of the foregoing. Any
          losses occasioned will not be enforceable by the lender to the extent
          that loan funds are used for purposes other than those specifically
          approved by the Agency in its Conditional Commitment for Guarantee.
          Negligent servicing is defined as the failure to perform those
          services which a reasonably prudent lender would perform in servicing
          its own portfolio of loans that are not guaranteed. The term includes
          not only the concept of a failure to act, but also not acting in a
          timely manner, acting in a manner contrary to the manner in which a
          reasonably prudent lender would act up to the time of loan maturity,
          or until a final loss is paid. The Loan Note Guarantee or Assignment
          Guarantee Agreement in the hands of a holder shall not cover interest
          accruing 90 days after the holder has demanded repurchase by the
          lender, nor shall the Loan Note Guarantee or Assignment Guarantee
          Agreement in the hands of a holder cover interest accruing 90 days
          after the lender or Agency has requested the holder to surrender the
          evidence of debt for repurchase.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14424'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1779.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Conditions of guarantee.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Conditions of guarantee.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          A loan guarantee under this part will be evidenced by a Loan Note
          Guarantee issued by the Agency. Each lender will also execute a
          Lender&apos;s Agreement.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The entire loan will be secured by the same security with equal
            lien priority for the guaranteed and non-guaranteed portions of the
            loan. The non-guaranteed portion of the loan will not be paid first
            nor given any preference or priority over the guaranteed portion.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The lender will be responsible for servicing the entire loan and
            will remain mortgagee or secured party of record notwithstanding the
            fact that another party may hold a portion of the loan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When a guaranteed portion of a loan is sold to a holder, the holder
            shall have all rights of the lender under the Loan Note Guarantee to
            the extent of the portion purchased. The lender will remain bound by
            all the obligations under the Loan Note Guarantee, Lender&apos;s
            Agreement, and Agency program regulations. If the Agency makes a
            payment to a holder, then the lender must reimburse the Agency.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A lender will receive all payments of principal and interest on the
            account of the entire loan and will promptly remit to each holder a
            pro rata share, less any lender servicing fee.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The lender may retain all of the unguaranteed portion of the loan
            or may sell part of the unguaranteed portion of the loan through
            participation. However, the lender is required to retain 5 percent
            of the loan amount from the unguaranteed portion in their portfolio.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14425'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.5-1779.7
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1779.5-1779.7
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='271' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='5-1779' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.5-1779
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .7
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14426'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.8
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1779.8
      </num>
      <head>
        Access to lender&apos;s records.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.8
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Access to lender&apos;s records.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Upon request by the Agency, the lender will permit representatives of
          the Agency (or other agencies of the U.S. Department of Agriculture
          authorized by that Department or the U.S. Government) to inspect and
          make copies of any of the records of the lender pertaining to the
          guaranteed loans. Such inspection and copying may be made during
          regular office hours of the lender or at any other time the lender and
          the Agency agree upon.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14427'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.9
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1779.9
      </num>
      <head>
        Environmental requirements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.9
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Environmental requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Facilities financed must undergo an environmental impact analysis in
          accordance with the National Environmental Policy Act and Agency
          requirements as contained in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='1794' tq='N'>
              1794 of this chapter
            </subref>
          </aref>
          . In accordance with Agency guidance documents (RUS Bulletin
          1794A-602; this document is available in any Agency State Office or
          online at 
          <E T='03'>
            http://www.usda.gov/rus/water/ees/index.htm
          </E>
          ), the environmental review requirements shall be performed by the
          applicant simultaneously and concurrently with the project&apos;s
          engineering planning and design. This should provide flexibility to
          consider reasonable alternatives to the project and development
          methods to mitigate any adverse environmental effects. Facility
          planning and design must not only be responsive to the owner&apos;s
          needs but must consider the environmental consequences of the proposed
          project. Facility design will incorporate and integrate, where
          practicable, mitigation measures that avoid or minimize adverse
          environmental impacts. The lender must assist the Agency in ensuring
          that the borrower complies with the Agency&apos;s environmental review
          process and implements any mitigation measure identified in the
          environmental review document or Conditional Commitment for Guarantee.
          This assistance includes ensuring that the borrower takes no action
          (for example, initiation of construction) or incur any obligations
          that will have an adverse environmental impact or limit the range of
          alternatives to be considered prior to completion of the environmental
          review process. If construction is started prior to completion of the
          environmental review and the Agency is deprived of its opportunity to
          fulfill its obligation to comply with applicable environmental
          requirements, the application for financial assistance may be denied.
          Satisfactory completion of the environmental review process must occur
          prior to the approval of the applicant&apos;s request or commitment of
          Agency resources.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14428'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.10-1779.11
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1779.10-1779.11
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='10-1779' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.10-1779
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .11
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14429'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.12
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1779.12
      </num>
      <head>
        Inspections.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='12' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.12
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Inspections.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The lender will notify the Agency of any scheduled field inspections
          during construction and after issuance of the Loan Note Guarantee. The
          Agency may attend such field inspections. Any inspections or review
          conducted by the Agency, including those with the lender, are for the
          benefit of the Agency only and not for the benefit of other parties in
          interest. Agency inspections do not relieve any parties in interest of
          their responsibilities to conduct necessary inspections.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14430'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.13
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1779.13
      </num>
      <head>
        Appeals.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='13' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.13
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Appeals.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Only the borrower, lender, or holder can appeal an Agency decision. In
          cases where the Agency has denied or reduced the amount of final loss
          payment to the lender, the adverse decision may be appealed only by
          the lender. A decision by a lender adverse to the interest of the
          borrower is not a decision by the Agency, whether or not concurred in
          by the Agency. Appeals will be handled in accordance with the
          regulations of the National Appeals Division, U.S. Department of
          Agriculture, published at 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR part 
            <subref title='7' part='11' tq='N'>
              11
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14431'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.14-1779.16
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1779.14-1779.16
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='14-1779' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.14-1779
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .16
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14432'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.17
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1779.17
      </num>
      <head>
        Exception authority.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='17' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.17
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Exception authority.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The Administrator may, in individual cases, make an exception to any
          requirement or provision of this part which is not inconsistent with
          the authorizing statute or other applicable law and is determined to
          be in the Government&apos;s interest.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14433'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.18-1779.19
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1779.18-1779.19
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='272' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='18-1779' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.18-1779
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .19
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14434'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.20
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1779.20
      </num>
      <head>
        Eligibility.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='20' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.20
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Eligibility.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Availability of credit from other sources.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Agency must determine that the borrower is unable to obtain the
            required credit without the loan guarantee from private, commercial,
            or cooperative sources at reasonable rates and terms for loans for
            similar purposes and periods of time. The Agency must also determine
            if an outstanding judgment obtained by the United States in a
            Federal Court (other than the U.S. Tax Court) has been entered
            against the borrower or if the borrower has an outstanding
            delinquent debt with any Federal agency. Such judgment or
            delinquency shall cause the potential borrower to be ineligible to
            receive a loan guarantee until the judgment is paid in full or
            otherwise satisfied or the delinquency is cured.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Legal authority and responsibility.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each borrower must have, or will obtain, the legal authority
            necessary to construct, operate, and maintain the proposed facility
            and services. They must also have legal authority for obtaining,
            giving security for, and repaying the proposed loan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The borrower shall be responsible for operating, maintaining, and
            managing the facility and services, and providing for the continued
            availability and use of the facility and services at reasonable
            rates and terms.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Applicant.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Eligible entities are:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A public body such as a municipality, county, district, authority,
            or other political subdivision of a State located in a rural area.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An organization operated on a not-for-profit basis, such as an
            association, cooperative, or private corporation. The organization
            must be an association controlled by a local public body or bodies,
            or have a broadly based ownership by or membership of people of the
            local community; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Indian tribes on Federal and State reservations and other federally
            recognized Indian tribes.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Facility location.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Facilities must be located in rural areas, except: For utility
            services such as drinking water, sanitary sewer, solid waste
            disposal or storm drainage facilities serving both rural and
            non-rural areas. In such cases, Agency funds may be used to finance
            only that portion serving rural areas, regardless of facility
            location.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Facilities for public use.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All facilities financed under the provisions of this part shall be
            for public purposes.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Facilities will be installed to serve any user within the service
            area who desires service and can be feasibly and legally served.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In no case will boundaries for the proposed service area be chosen
            in such a way that any user or area will be excluded because of
            race, color, religion, sex, marital status, age, disability, or
            national origin.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The lender will determine that, when feasible and legally possible,
            inequities within the proposed project&apos;s service area for the
            same type service proposed will be remedied by the owner on, or
            before, completion of the project. Inequities are defined as
            unjustified variations in availability, adequacy, or quality of
            service. User rate schedules for portions of existing systems or
            facilities that were developed under different financing, rates,
            terms, or conditions do not necessarily constitute inequities.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14435'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.21-1779.23
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1779.21-1779.23
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='21-1779' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.21-1779
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .23
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14436'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.24
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1779.24
      </num>
      <head>
        Eligible loan purposes.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='24' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.24
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Eligible loan purposes.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To construct, enlarge, extend, or otherwise improve rural drinking
            water, sanitary sewage, solid waste disposal, and storm wastewater
            disposal facilities.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To construct or relocate public buildings, roads, bridges, fences,
            or utilities, and to make other public improvements necessary for
            the successful operation or protection of facilities authorized in
            paragraph (a) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To relocate private buildings, roads, bridges, fences, or
            utilities, and other private improvements necessary for the
            successful operation or protection of facilities authorized in
            paragraph (a) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For payment of other utility connection charges as provided in
            service contracts between utility systems.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When a necessary part of the project relates to those facilities
            authorized in paragraphs (a), (b), (c) or (d) 
            <PRTPAGE P='273' />
            of this section the following may be considered:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Reasonable fees and costs such as: legal, engineering,
            administrative services, fiscal advisory, recording, environmental
            analyses and surveys, possible salvage or other mitigation measures,
            planning, establishing or acquiring rights;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Costs of acquiring interest in land: rights, such as water rights;
            leases; permits; rights-of-way; and other evidence of land or water
            control or protection necessary for development of the facility;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Purchasing or renting equipment necessary to install, operate,
            maintain, extend, or protect facilities;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Cost of additional applicant labor and other expenses necessary to
            install and extend service;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In unusual cases such as a low-income area, the cost for connecting
            the user to the main service line;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Interest incurred during construction in conjunction with multiple
            advances or interest on interim financing;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Initial operating expenses, including interest, for a period
            ordinarily not exceeding one year when the applicant is unable to
            pay such expenses;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The purchase of existing facilities when it is necessary either to
            improve service or prevent the loss of service; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Refinancing non-Agency debts incurred by, or on behalf of, an
            applicant when all of the following conditions exist:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_9_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The debts being refinanced are a secondary part of the total loan
            unless the debt being refinanced is an Agency direct loan;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_9_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The debts were incurred for the facility or service being financed
            or any part thereof; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_9_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Arrangements cannot be made with the creditors to extend or modify
            the terms of the debts so that a sound basis will exist for making a
            loan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Refinancing Agency debts.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14437'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.25
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1779.25
      </num>
      <head>
        Ineligible loan purposes.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='25' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.25
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Ineligible loan purposes.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Loan funds may not be used to finance:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Facilities which are not modest in size, design, and cost;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Loan or grant finder&apos;s fees;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The construction of any new combined storm and sanitary sewer
            facilities;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any portion of the cost of a facility which does not serve a rural
            area;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             That portion of project costs normally provided by a business or
            industrial user, such as wastewater pretreatment;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Rental for the use of equipment or machinery owned by the
            applicant;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For other purposes not directly related to operating and
            maintenance of the facility being installed or improved; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The payment of a judgment which would disqualify an applicant for a
            loan under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='20' psec='#a' tq='N'>
                1779.20(a)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14438'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.26
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1779.26
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='26' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.26
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14439'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.27
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1779.27
      </num>
      <head>
        Lenders.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='27' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.27
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Lenders.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Eligible lenders.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Eligible lenders may participate in the loan guarantee program.
            These lenders must be subject to credit examination and supervision
            by an appropriate agency of the United States or a State that
            supervises and regulates credit institutions. A lender must have the
            capability to adequately service loans for which a guarantee is
            requested. Eligible lenders are:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any Federal or State chartered bank or savings and loan
            association;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any mortgage company that is a part of a bank holding company;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Co-Bank, National Rural Utilities Cooperative Finance Corporation,
            Farm Credit Bank of the Federal Land Bank, or other Farm Credit
            System institution with direct lending authority authorized to make
            loans of the type guaranteed by this part;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An insurance company regulated by a State or National insurance
            regulatory agency;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State Bond Banks or State Bond Pools; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Other lenders that possess the legal powers necessary and
            incidental to making and servicing guaranteed loans involving
            community development-type projects. Lenders under this category
            must be approved by the National Office prior to the issuance of the
            loan guarantee.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Conflict of interest.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When the lender&apos;s officers, stockholders, directors, or
            partners (including their immediate 
            <PRTPAGE P='274' />
            families) or the borrower, its officers, stockholders, directors, or
            partners (including their immediate families) own, or have
            management responsibilities in each other, the lender must disclose
            such business or ownership relationships. The Agency will determine
            if such relationships are likely to result in a conflict of
            interest. This does not preclude lender officials from being on the
            borrower&apos;s board of directors.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14440'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.28
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1779.28
      </num>
      <head>
        Transfer of lenders or borrowers (prior to issuance of Loan Note
        Guarantee).
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='28' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.28
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Transfer of lenders or borrowers (prior to issuance of Loan Note
          Guarantee).
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Prior to issuance of the loan guarantee, the Agency may approve the
            transfer of an outstanding Conditional Commitment for Guarantee from
            the present lender to a new eligible lender: Provided, That:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The former lender states in writing why it does not wish to
            continue to be the lender for this project;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No substantive changes in ownership or control of the borrower has
            occurred;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No substantive changes in the borrower&apos;s written plan, scope
            of work, or changes in the purpose or intent of the project has
            occurred; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No substantive changes in the loan agreement or Conditional
            Commitment for Guarantee are required.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The substitute lender must execute a new application for loan and
            guarantee (available in any Agency office).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If approved, the Agency will issue a letter of amendment to the
            original Conditional Commitment for Guarantee reflecting the new
            lender who will acknowledge acceptance of the offer in writing.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Once the Conditional Commitment for Guarantee is issued, the Agency
            will not approve any substitution of borrowers, including changes in
            the form of the legal entity, except a change in the legal entity
            may be requested when the original borrower is replaced with
            substantially the same individuals or officers with the same
            interest as originally approved.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14441'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.29
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1779.29
      </num>
      <head>
        Fees and charges by lender.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='29' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.29
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Fees and charges by lender.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Routine charges and fees.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The lender may establish charges and fees for the loan if they do
            not exceed those charged other borrowers for similar types of
            transactions. “Similar types of transactions” mean those
            transactions involving the same type of loan for which a
            non-guaranteed loan borrower would be assessed charges and fees.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Late payment fees.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Late payment charges will not be covered by the Loan Note
            Guarantee. Such charges may not be added to the principal and
            interest due under any guaranteed note. Late payment charges may be
            made only if:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             They are routinely made by the lender in all types of loan
            transactions;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payment has not been received within the customary timeframe
            allowed by the lender; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The lender agrees with the borrower, in writing, that the rate or
            method of calculating the late payment charges will not be changed
            to increase charges while the Loan Note Guarantee is in effect.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Guarantee fees.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The guaranteed loan fee will be the applicable guarantee fee rate
            multiplied by the principal loan amount multiplied by the percent of
            guarantee. The one-time guarantee fee is paid when the Loan Note
            Guarantee is issued.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The fee will be paid to the Agency by the lender and is
            nonreturnable. The lender may pass the fee to the borrower.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The guarantee fee rates are available in any Agency office.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14442'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.30
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1779.30
      </num>
      <head>
        Loan guarantee limitations.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='30' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.30
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Loan guarantee limitations.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The guarantee will be 90 percent of eligible loss.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The lender will retain a minimum of 5 percent of the total loan
            amount. The retained amount must be from the unguaranteed portion of
            the loan and cannot be participated to another lender.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14443'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.31-1779.32
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1779.31-1779.32
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='31-1779' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.31-1779
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .32
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14444'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.33
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1779.33
      </num>
      <head>
        Interest rates.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='33' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.33
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Interest rates.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Rates will be negotiated between the lender and the borrower. They
            may be either fixed or variable rates. Interest rates will be those
            rates customarily charged borrowers in similar circumstances in the
            ordinary 
            <PRTPAGE P='275' />
            course of business and are subject to Agency review and approval.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Variable rate publication.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A variable interest rate must be tied to a base rate published
            periodically in a recognized national or regional financial
            publication specifically agreed to by the lender and borrower. Such
            an agreement must be documented in the borrower or lender loan
            agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Interest rate caps and incremental adjustment limitations will also
            be negotiated between the lender and the borrower. Notice of any
            interest rate change proposed by the lender should allow a
            sufficient time period for the borrower to obtain any required State
            or other regulatory approval and to implement any user rate
            adjustments necessary as a result of the interest rate change. The
            intervals between interest rate adjustments will be specified in the
            loan agreement (but not more often than quarterly).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The lender must incorporate within the variable rate note, the
            provision for adjustment of payments coincident with an interest
            rate adjustment. This will ensure the outstanding principal balance
            is properly amortized within the prescribed loan maturity and
            eliminate the possibility of a balloon payment at the end of the
            loan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Changes.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any change in the interest rate between the date of issuance of the
            Conditional Commitment for Guarantee and before the issuance of the
            Loan Note Guarantee must be approved by the Agency. Approval of such
            change will be shown as an amendment to the Conditional Commitment
            for Guarantee.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Different rates on guaranteed and unguaranteed portion of the
              loan.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             It is permissible to have one interest rate on the guaranteed
            portion of the loan and another interest rate on the unguaranteed
            portion of the loan, provided the lender and borrower agree, and:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The rate on the unguaranteed portion does not exceed that currently
            being charged on loans for similar purposes to borrowers under
            similar circumstances; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The rate on the guaranteed portion of the loan will not exceed the
            rate on the unguaranteed portion. This requirement does not apply
            when the unguaranteed rate is variable and the guaranteed portion is
            fixed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Multi-rates.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When multi-rates are used, the lender will provide the Agency with
            the overall effective interest rate for the entire loan. Multi-rate
            loans may be either fixed, variable, or a combination of fixed and
            variable.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14445'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.34
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1779.34
      </num>
      <head>
        Terms of loan repayment.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='34' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.34
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Terms of loan repayment.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Principal and interest on the loan will be due and payable as
            provided in the note except, any interest accrued as the result of
            the borrower&apos;s default on the guaranteed loan over and above
            that which would have accrued at the note rate on the guaranteed
            loan will not be guaranteed by the Agency. The lender will structure
            repayments as established in the loan agreement between the lender
            and borrower. Ordinarily, such installments will be scheduled for
            payment as agreed upon by the lender and borrower on terms that
            reasonably ensure repayment of the loan. However, the first
            installment to include a repayment of principal may be scheduled for
            payment after the project is operable and has begun to generate
            income. Such installment must be due and payable within 3 years from
            the date of the note and at least annually thereafter. Interest will
            be due at least annually from the date of the note. Monthly payments
            will be required except for borrowers with income limited to less
            frequent intervals.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Term length.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The maximum time allowable for final maturity for a guaranteed WW
            loan will be limited to the useful life of the facility, not to
            exceed 40 years.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Balloon payments.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The principal balance should be properly amortized within the
            prescribed loan maturity. Balloon payments at the end of the loan
            are prohibited.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14446'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.35-1779.36
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1779.35-1779.36
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='35-1779' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.35-1779
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .36
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14447'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.37
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1779.37
      </num>
      <head>
        Insurance and fidelity bonds.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='37' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.37
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Insurance and fidelity bonds.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The lender must provide evidence that the borrower has adequate
          insurance and fidelity bond coverage by loan closing or start of
          construction, whichever occurs first. Adequate coverage must be
          maintained for the life of the 
          <PRTPAGE P='276' />
          loan and is subject to Agency review and approval.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14448'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.38-1779.41
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1779.38-1779.41
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='38-1779' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.38-1779
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .41
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14449'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.42
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1779.42
      </num>
      <head>
        Design and construction requirements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='42' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.42
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Design and construction requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The lender will provide the Agency with a written certification at the
          end of construction that all funds were utilized for authorized
          purposes. The borrower and the lender will authorize designs and plans
          based upon the preliminary architectural and engineering reports or
          plans approved by the lender and concurred in by the Agency. The
          borrower will take into consideration any lender or Agency comments
          when the facility is being designed.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Architectural and engineering practices.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All project facilities must be designed utilizing accepted
            architectural and engineering practices and must conform to
            applicable Federal, State, and local codes and requirements. The
            lender must ensure that the planned project will be completed within
            the available funds and, once completed, will be suitable for the
            borrower&apos;s needs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Construction monitoring.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The lender will monitor the progress of construction and undertake
            the reviews and inspections necessary to ensure that construction
            proceeds in accordance with the approved plans, specifications, and
            contract documents and that funds are used for eligible project
            costs. The lender must expeditiously report any problems in project
            development to the Agency.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Equal employment opportunities.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For all construction contracts in excess of $10,000, the contractor
            must comply with Executive Order 11246 (
            <aref type='FREGIST'>
              30 FR 12319, 3
            </aref>
             CFR, 1964-1965 Comp., p. 339) entitled “Equal Employment
            Opportunity” as amended and as supplemented by applicable Department
            of Labor regulations (
            <aref type='CFR'>
              41 CFR part 
              <subref title='41' part='60-1' tq='N'>
                60-1
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ). The borrower and lender are responsible for ensuring that the
            contractor complies with these requirements.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Americans with Disabilities Act.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             WW loans which involve the construction of, or addition to,
            facilities that accommodate the public and commercial facilities as
            defined by the Americans with Disabilities Act (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='42' sect='12181' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/42/12181.html'>
                42 U.S.C. 12181
              </subref>
            </aref>
             et seq.) must comply with that Act. The lender and borrower are
            responsible for compliance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Administrative.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When the Agency reviews the preliminary architectural and
            engineering reports or plans, they must also consider all applicable
            Federal laws such as the seismic requirements of Executive Order
            12699 (
            <aref type='FREGIST'>
              55 FR 835, 3
            </aref>
             CFR, 1990 Comp., p. 269), the debarment requirements of 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3017' tq='N'>
                3017
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , and the Copeland Anti-Kickback Act (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='18' sect='874' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/18/874.html'>
                18 U.S.C. 874
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14450'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.43
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1779.43
      </num>
      <head>
        Other Federal, State, and local requirements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='43' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.43
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Other Federal, State, and local requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          In addition to the specific requirements of this part and beginning on
          the date of issuance of the Loan Note Guarantee, proposals for
          facilities financed in whole or in part with a loan guaranteed by the
          Agency will be coordinated with all appropriate Federal, State, and
          local agencies. Borrowers and lenders will be required to comply with
          any Federal, State, or local laws or regulatory commission rules which
          are in existence and which affect the project including, but not
          limited to:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Applicant&apos;s authority to design, construct, develop, operate,
            and maintain the proposed facilities;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Borrowing money, giving security, and raising revenues for
            repayment;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land use zoning;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Health, safety, and sanitation standards as well as design and
            installation standards; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Protection of the environment and consumer affairs.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14451'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.44-1779.46
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1779.44-1779.46
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='44-1779' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.44-1779
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .46
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14452'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.47
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1779.47
      </num>
      <head>
        Economic feasibility requirements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='47' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.47
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Economic feasibility requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          All projects financed under the provisions of this section must be
          based on taxes, assessments, revenues, fees, or other sources of
          revenues in an amount sufficient to provide for facility operation and
          maintenance, a reasonable reserve, and debt payment. The lender is
          responsible for determining the credit quality and economic
          feasibility of the proposed loan and must address all elements of the
          credit quality in a written financial feasibility analysis which
          includes adequacy of equity, 
          <PRTPAGE P='277' />
          cash flow, security, history, and management capabilities. Financial
          feasibility reports must take into consideration any interest rate
          adjustment which may be instituted under the terms of the note. The
          lender&apos;s financial credit analysis may also serve as the
          feasibility analysis when sufficient evidence is included to determine
          economic feasibility as well as financial viability. The
          borrower&apos;s consulting engineer may complete the financial
          feasibility analysis for WW systems. If the facility is used by
          businesses and the success or failure of the facility is dependent on
          individual businesses, then the economic viability of those businesses
          must be assessed.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Exceptions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Agency loan approval official may exempt the lender from the
            requirement for an independent financial feasibility report (when
            requested by the borrower and the lender) provided the approval
            official determines that the financial feasibility analysis prepared
            by the borrower fairly represents the financial feasibility of the
            facility and the financial feasibility analysis contains an accurate
            projection of the usage, revenues, and expenses of the facility.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Insufficient information.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When the lender or Agency has insufficient information to determine
            the borrower&apos;s repayment ability, an independent feasibility
            analysis is required.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14453'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.48
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1779.48
      </num>
      <head>
        Collateral.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='48' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.48
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Collateral.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Lender responsibility.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The lender is responsible for obtaining and maintaining proper and
            adequate collateral to protect the interest of the lender, the
            holder, and the Government.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Type of collateral.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Collateral must be of such a nature that repayment of the loan is
            reasonably ensured when considered with the integrity and ability of
            project management, soundness of the project, and the
            borrower&apos;s prospective earnings. The collateral may include,
            but is not limited to, the following: General obligation bonds,
            revenue bonds, pledge of taxes or assessments, assignment of
            facility revenue, land, easements, rights-of-way, water rights,
            buildings, machinery, equipment, accounts receivable, contracts,
            cash, or other accounts or assignments of leases or leasehold
            interest.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Separate collateral.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All collateral must secure the entire loan. The lender will not
            take separate security to secure only the unguaranteed portion of
            the loan. The lender will not require compensating balances or
            certificates of deposit as a means of eliminating the lender&apos;s
            exposure on the unguaranteed portion of the loan.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14454'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.49-1779.51
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1779.49-1779.51
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='49-1779' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.49-1779
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .51
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14455'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.52
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1779.52
      </num>
      <head>
        Processing.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='52' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.52
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Processing.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Preapplications.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The preapplication package may be submitted either alone or the
            necessary information may be submitted simultaneously with the
            application. The preapplication package will contain:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An Application for Federal Assistance on a form provided by the
            Agency (available in any Agency office);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State intergovernmental or other type review comments and
            recommendations for the borrower&apos;s project (clearinghouse
            comments, if applicable);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Supporting documentation necessary to make an eligibility
            determination such as financial statements, audits, copies of
            organizational documents, or existing debt instruments; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Documentation of lender eligibility in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='27' psec='' tq='N'>
                1779.27
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the Agency determines that the project may meet requirements and
            is likely to be funded, the lender must submit a complete
            application if it has not previously submitted one.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Applications.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Contents of application package:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Application for Loan and Guarantee on a form prescribed by the
            Agency (available in any Agency office);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Proposed loan agreement;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Environmental Report. (See RUS Bulletin 1794A-602; this document is
            available in any Agency State Office or online at 
            <E T='03'>
              http://www.usda.gov/rus/water/ees/index.htm
            </E>
            );
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Preliminary architectural or engineering report (PER);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Cost estimates;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Appraisal reports (as appropriate);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Credit reports (as appropriate);
            <PRTPAGE P='278' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Financial feasibility analysis and report (as appropriate) if not
            included in PER; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any additional information required.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14456'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.53
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1779.53
      </num>
      <head>
        Evaluation of application.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='53' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.53
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Evaluation of application.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          If the Agency determines that the borrower is eligible, the proposed
          loan is for an eligible purpose, there is reasonable assurance of
          repayment ability, sufficient collateral and equity exists, the
          proposed loan complies with all applicable statutes and regulations,
          the environmental impact analyses is complete, and adequate funds are
          available, the Agency will provide the lender and the borrower with
          the Conditional Commitment for Guarantee, listing all conditions for
          the guarantee. Applicable requirements will include the following:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Approved use of guaranteed loan funds (source and use of funds);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Rates and terms of the loan;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Scheduling of payments;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Number of customers;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Security and lien priority;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Appraisals;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Insurance and bonding;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Financial reporting;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Equal opportunity and nondiscrimination;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Mitigation measures for environmental issues (if necessary);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Americans with Disabilities Act;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='l'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (l)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             By-laws and articles of incorporation changes; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='m'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (m)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Other requirements necessary to protect the Government.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14457'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.54-1779.58
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1779.54-1779.58
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='54-1779' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.54-1779
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .58
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14458'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.59
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1779.59
      </num>
      <head>
        Review of requirements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='59' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.59
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Review of requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Lender and borrower.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The lender and borrower must complete and sign the Acceptance of
            Conditions and return a copy to the Agency as soon as possible.
            Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, if certain conditions cannot
            be met, the lender and borrower may propose alternate conditions for
            Agency consideration.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Cancellation.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the lender decides at any time after receiving a Conditional
            Commitment for Guarantee that it no longer wants a guarantee, the
            lender must immediately advise the Agency of the cancellation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Modifications.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The lender agrees that once the Conditional Commitment for
            Guarantee is issued and accepted by the lender and borrower, it will
            not be modified as to the scope of the project, overall facility
            concept, project purpose, use of proceeds, or other terms and
            conditions.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14459'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.60-1779.62
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1779.60-1779.62
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='60-1779' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.60-1779
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .62
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14460'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.63
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1779.63
      </num>
      <head>
        Conditions precedent to issuance of the Loan Note Guarantee.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='63' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.63
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Conditions precedent to issuance of the Loan Note Guarantee.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The Loan Note Guarantee will not be issued until:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The lender certifies that:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No changes have been made in the lender&apos;s loan conditions and
            requirements since the issuance of the Conditional Commitment for
            Guarantee except those approved in the interim by the Agency in
            writing.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All planned property acquisition has been completed and all
            development has been substantially completed in accordance with
            plans, specifications, and applicable building codes. No costs have
            exceeded the amounts approved by the lender and the Agency.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Required insurance is in effect.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The loan has been properly closed and the required security
            instruments have been obtained on any after-acquired property that
            cannot be covered initially under State statutory provisions.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The borrower has marketable title to the collateral then owned by
            the borrower, subject to the instrument securing the loan to be
            guaranteed and subject to any other exceptions approved, in writing,
            by the Agency.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When required, the entire amount of the loan for working capital
            has been disbursed except in cases where the Agency has approved
            disbursement over an extended time.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All other requirements of the Conditional Commitment for Guarantee
            have been met.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Lien priorities are consistent with requirements of the Conditional
            Commitment for Guarantee.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The loan proceeds have been disbursed for purposes and in amounts
            consistent with the Conditional Commitment for Guarantee and as
            specified on the application for the guaranteed loan. A copy of a
            detailed statement by 
            <PRTPAGE P='279' />
            the lender detailing the use of loan funds will be attached to
            support this certification.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             There has been no substantive adverse change in the borrower&apos;s
            financial condition nor any other adverse change in the borrower
            during the period of time from the Agency&apos;s issuance of the
            Conditional Commitment for Guarantee to issuance of the Loan Note
            Guarantee. The lender&apos;s certification must address all adverse
            changes of the borrower and the guarantors. For purposes of this
            paragraph (a)(10), the term borrower includes any parent, affiliate,
            or subsidiary of the borrower.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_11'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (11)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All Federal, State, and local design and construction requirements
            have been met.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_12'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (12)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The lender understands and will meet the requirements of the Debt
            Collection Act (31 U.S.C. Chapter 37).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_13'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (13)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The lender would not make the loan without an Agency guarantee.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The lender has executed and delivered the Lender&apos;s Agreement
            and closing report for the guaranteed loan along with the
            appropriate guarantee fee.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The lender has advised the Agency of plans to sell or assign any
            part of the loan as provided in the Lender&apos;s Agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Where applicable, the lender must certify that the borrower has
            obtained:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A legal opinion relative to the title to rights-of-way and
            easements. Lenders are responsible for ensuring that borrowers have
            obtained valid, continuous, and adequate rights-of-way and easements
            needed for the construction, operation, and maintenance of a
            facility.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A title opinion or title insurance showing ownership of the land
            and all mortgages or other lien defects, restrictions, or
            encumbrances, if any. It is the responsibility of the lender to
            ensure that the borrower has obtained and recorded such releases,
            consents, or subordinations to such property rights from holders of
            outstanding liens or other instruments as may be necessary for the
            construction, operation, and maintenance of the facility and to
            provide the required security. For example, when a site is for major
            structures and the lender and borrower are able to obtain only a
            right-of-way or easement on such a site rather than a fee simple
            title, such a title opinion must be requested.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the Loan Note Guarantee cannot be issued before the Conditional
            Commitment expires, the lender must submit a written request for an
            extension of the expiration date. The lender must document and
            certify to paragraph (a)(1) and (a)(11) of this section specifically
            identifying any modifications.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Coincident with, or immediately after, loan closing, the lender
            will contact the Agency and provide those documents and
            certifications required in this section. For loans to public bodies,
            lenders may require an opinion from recognized bond counsel
            regarding the adequacy of the preparation and issuance of the debt
            instruments. Only when the Agency is satisfied that all conditions
            for the guarantee have been met will the Loan Note Guarantee be
            executed.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14461'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.64
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1779.64
      </num>
      <head>
        Issuance of Lender&apos;s Agreement, Loan Note Guarantee, and Assignment
        Guarantee Agreement.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='64' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.64
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Issuance of Lender&apos;s Agreement, Loan Note Guarantee, and
          Assignment Guarantee Agreement.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Lender&apos;s Agreement.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the Agency finds that all requirements have been met, the lender
            and the Agency will execute the Lender&apos;s Agreement. The
            original will be retained by the Agency and a signed duplicate
            original will be retained by the lender. A separate Lender&apos;s
            Agreement must be executed for each loan to be guaranteed by the
            Agency.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Loan Note Guarantee.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon receipt of the executed Lender&apos;s Agreement and after all
            requirements have been met, the Agency will execute the Loan Note
            Guarantee. All originals of the Loan Note Guarantee will be provided
            to the lender and attached to the note.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the lender has selected the multi-note system, a Loan Note
            Guarantee will be prepared and attached to each note the borrower
            issues. All the notes will be listed on the Loan Note Guarantee. Not
            more than ten notes will be issued for the guaranteed portion
            (unless the Agency and borrower agree otherwise) and one note issued
            for the unguaranteed portion.
            <PRTPAGE P='280' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Assignment of Guarantee.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the event the lender assigns the guaranteed portion of the loan
            to a holder, the lender, holder, and Agency will execute an Agency
            prescribed Assignment Guarantee Agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Failure to meet conditions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the Agency determines that it cannot execute the Loan Note
            Guarantee because all requirements have not been met, the lender
            will have a reasonable period within which to satisfy the
            objections. If the lender satisfies the objections within the time
            allowed, the guarantee will be issued.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Loan closing report.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The lender will prepare and deliver a guaranteed loan closing
            report for each loan to be guaranteed and a guarantee fee to the
            Agency in return for the Loan Note Guarantee.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14462'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.65
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1779.65
      </num>
      <head>
        Lender&apos;s sale or assignment of the guaranteed portion of loan.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='65' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.65
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Lender&apos;s sale or assignment of the guaranteed portion of loan.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The lender may retain all of the guaranteed loan. The lender must not
          sell or participate any amount of the guaranteed or non-guaranteed
          portion of the loan to the borrower or to members of the
          borrower&apos;s immediate families, the borrower&apos;s officers,
          directors, stockholders, other owners, or a subsidiary or affiliate.
          Disposition of the guaranteed portion of a loan may not be made prior
          to full disbursement, completion of construction, and acquisition of
          real estate and equipment without the prior written approval of the
          Agency. If the lender desires to market all or part of the guaranteed
          portion of the loan at, or subsequent to, loan closing, the loan must
          not be in default.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Assignment.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any sale or assignment by the lender of the guaranteed portion of
            the loan must be accomplished in accordance with the conditions in
            the Lender&apos;s Agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Participation.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The lender may obtain participation in the loan under its normal
            operating procedures.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Minimum retention.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The lender is required to hold in its own portfolio or retain a
            minimum of 5 percent of the total loan amount. This amount must be
            of the non-guaranteed portion of the loan and cannot be participated
            to another. The lender may sell the remaining amount of the
            non-guaranteed portion of the loan only through participation.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14463'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.66-1779.68
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1779.66-1779.68
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='66-1779' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.66-1779
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .68
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14464'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.69
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1779.69
      </num>
      <head>
        Loan servicing.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='69' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.69
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Loan servicing.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Lender responsibilities.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The lender is responsible for servicing the entire loan in
            accordance with the lender&apos;s loan agreement. The unguaranteed
            portion of the loan will not be paid first nor given any preference
            or priority over the guaranteed portion of the loan. The lender is
            responsible for taking all servicing actions that a prudent lender
            would perform in servicing a portfolio of loans that are not
            guaranteed. This responsibility includes, but is not limited to, the
            collection of payments; obtaining compliance with the covenants and
            provisions in the note, loan agreement, security instrument, or any
            supplemental agreements; obtaining and analyzing financial
            statements; verifying the payment of taxes and insurance premiums;
            and maintaining liens on collateral. The lender must notify the
            Agency of any violation of the loan agreement with the borrower
            within 30 days of such violation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Financial reports.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The lender must obtain the financial statements required by the
            Loan Agreement. The lender must submit the borrower&apos;s annual
            financial statements to the Agency within 120 days of the end of the
            borrower&apos;s fiscal year. The lender must analyze the financial
            statements and provide the Agency with a written summary of the
            lender&apos;s analysis and conclusions, including trends, strengths,
            weaknesses, extraordinary transactions, and other indications of the
            financial condition of the borrower. Additionally, when applicable,
            the lender will require an audit in accordance with Office of
            Management and Budget (OMB) circulars (available in any Agency
            office).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Delinquent loans.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The lender will service delinquent loans in accordance with the
            Lender&apos;s Agreement and reasonable and prudent lending
            standards.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Loan balances.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The lender must report to the Agency the outstanding principal and
            interest balance on each guaranteed loan semiannually.
            <PRTPAGE P='281' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Collateral inspections.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The lender will inspect the collateral as often as necessary to
            properly service the loan.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14465'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.70-1779.72
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1779.70-1779.72
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='70-1779' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.70-1779
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .72
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14466'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.73
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1779.73
      </num>
      <head>
        Replacement of loss, theft, destruction, mutilation, or defacement of
        Loan Note Guarantee or Assignment Guarantee Agreement.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='73' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.73
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Replacement of loss, theft, destruction, mutilation, or defacement of
          Loan Note Guarantee or Assignment Guarantee Agreement.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Replacement.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Agency may issue a replacement Loan Note Guarantee or
            Assignment Guarantee Agreement which may have been lost, stolen,
            destroyed, mutilated, or defaced to the lender or holder upon
            receipt of a certificate of loss and an indemnity bond in accordance
            with this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Lender responsibilities.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When a Loan Note Guarantee or Assignment Guarantee Agreement is
            lost, stolen, destroyed, mutilated, or defaced while in the custody
            of the lender or holder, the lender will coordinate the activities
            of the party who seeks the replacement documents and will submit the
            required documents to the Agency for processing. The requirements
            for replacement are as follows:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A certificate of loss properly notarized which includes:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Legal name and present address of either the lender or the holder
            who is requesting the replacement forms;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Legal name and address of the lender of record;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Capacity of person certifying;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Full identification of the Loan Note Guarantee or Assignment
            Guarantee Agreement, including the name of the borrower, Agency case
            number, date of the Loan Note Guarantee, Assignment Guarantee
            Agreement, face amount of the evidence of debt purchased, date of
            evidence of debt, present balance of the loan, percentages of
            guarantee and, if Assignment Guarantee Agreement, the original named
            holder and the percentage of the guaranteed portion of the loan
            assigned to that holder. Any existing parts of the document to be
            replaced must be attached to the certificate;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A full statement of circumstances of the loss, theft, or
            destruction of the Loan Note Guarantee or Assignment Guarantee
            Agreement; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The holder shall present evidence demonstrating current ownership
            of the Loan Note Guarantee and Note or Assignment Guarantee
            Agreement. If the present holder is not the same as the original
            holder, a copy of the endorsement of each successive holder in the
            chain of transfer from the initial holder to present holder must be
            included. If copies of the endorsement cannot be obtained, best
            available records of transfer must be presented to the Agency (e.g.,
            order confirmation, canceled checks).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An indemnity bond acceptable to the Agency shall accompany the
            request for replacement except when the holder is the United States,
            a Federal Reserve Bank, a Federal Government corporation, a State or
            Territory, or the District of Columbia.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All indemnity bonds must be issued and payable to the United States
            of America. The bond shall be in an amount not less than the unpaid
            principal and interest. The bond shall hold the Government harmless
            against any claim or demand which might arise or against any damage,
            loss, costs, or expenses which might be sustained or incurred by
            reasons of the loss or replacement of the instruments.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14467'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.74
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1779.74
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='74' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.74
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14468'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.75
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1779.75
      </num>
      <head>
        Defaults by borrower.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='75' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.75
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Defaults by borrower.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Lender notification to Agency.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The lender must notify the Agency when a borrower is 30 days past
            due on a payment, has not met its responsibilities of providing the
            required financial statements, or is otherwise in default. The
            lender will continue to keep the Agency informed on a bimonthly
            basis until such time as the loan is no longer in default. If a
            monetary default exceeds 60 days, the lender will arrange a meeting
            with the borrower to resolve the default. The lender will provide a
            summary of the meeting and any decisions or actions agreed upon.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Servicing options.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In considering servicing options, the prospects for providing a
            permanent cure without adversely affecting the risks to the Agency
            and the lender must be the paramount objective. Temporary curative
            actions (such as payment deferments or collateral subordination)
            must strengthen the loan and be in the best financial interest of
            the lender and 
            <PRTPAGE P='282' />
            the Agency. Some of these actions may require concurrence of the
            holder.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Multi-note.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the loan was closed with the multi-note option, the lender may
            need to possess all notes to take some servicing actions. In those
            situations when the Agency is holder of some of the notes, the
            Agency may endorse the notes back to the lender, provided a proper
            receipt is received from the lender which defines the reason for the
            transfer. Under no circumstances will the Agency endorse the
            original Loan Note Guarantee to the lender.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14469'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.76-1779.77
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1779.76-1779.77
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='76-1779' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.76-1779
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .77
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14470'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.78
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1779.78
      </num>
      <head>
        Repurchase of loan.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='78' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.78
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Repurchase of loan.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Repurchase by lender.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The lender has the option to repurchase the loan from a holder
            within 30 days of written demand from the holder when the borrower
            is in default not less than 60 days on payment. The repurchase will
            be for an amount equal to the unpaid guaranteed portion of principal
            and accrued interest less the lender&apos;s servicing fee. The
            guarantee does not cover the note interest to the holder on the
            guaranteed loan accruing after 90 days from the date of the demand
            letter to the lender. The holder will concurrently send a copy of
            the demand to the Agency. The lender will accept an assignment
            without recourse from the holder upon repurchase. The lender is
            encouraged to repurchase the loan to facilitate the accounting of
            funds, resolve the problem, and permit the borrower to cure the
            default, where reasonable. The lender will notify the holder and the
            Agency of its decision within 30 days of receipt of demand from the
            holder.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Agency repurchase.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the lender does not repurchase as provided in paragraph (a) of
            this section, the Agency will purchase from the holder the unpaid
            principal balance of the guaranteed portion together with accrued
            interest to date of repurchase (less the lender&apos;s servicing
            fee) within 30 days after a specific written demand directed to the
            Agency. The copy of the demand on the lender is not sufficient. The
            guarantee will not cover the note interest to the holder on the
            guaranteed loan accruing after 90 days from the date of the original
            demand letter. The lender shall not charge the Agency any servicing
            fees nor are any such fees collectible from the Agency.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The holder&apos;s demand to the Agency must include a copy of the
            written demand made upon the lender. The holder or duly authorized
            agent must also include evidence of the right to require payment
            from the Agency. Such evidence will consist of either the original
            of the Loan Note Guarantee properly endorsed to the Agency or the
            original of the Assignment Guarantee Agreement properly assigned to
            the Agency without recourse including all rights, title, and
            interest in the loan. The Agency will be subrogated to all rights of
            the holder. The holder must include in the demand the amount due
            including unpaid principal, unpaid interest to date of demand, and
            interest subsequently accruing from the date of demand to the
            proposed payment date. Unless otherwise agreed to by the Agency,
            such proposed payment will not be later than 30 days from the date
            of demand.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The lender must promptly provide the Agency with the information
            necessary for the Agency&apos;s determination of the appropriate
            amount due the holder upon the Agency&apos;s notification to the
            lender of the holder&apos;s demand for payment. This information
            must be certified by an authorized officer of the lender. Any
            discrepancy between the amount claimed by the holder and the
            information submitted by the lender must be resolved before payment
            will be approved. The Agency will notify both parties and such
            conflict will suspend the running of the 30-day payment requirement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any purchase by the Agency does not change, alter, or modify any of
            the lender&apos;s obligations to the Agency arising from the loan or
            guarantee nor does it waive any of the Agency&apos;s rights against
            the lender. The Agency may set off against the lender all rights
            inuring to the Agency as the holder of the instrument against the
            Agency&apos;s obligation to the lender under the Loan Note
            Guarantee.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Repurchase for servicing.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When the lender determines that repurchase of the guaranteed
            portion of the loan is necessary to service the loan, the holder
            must sell the guaranteed portion to 
            <PRTPAGE P='283' />
            the lender for the unpaid principal and interest balance (less the
            lender&apos;s servicing fee). The guarantee does not cover interest
            accruing after 90 days from the date the lender&apos;s or
            Agency&apos;s letter requesting the holder to tender its guaranteed
            portion. The lender must not repurchase from the holder for
            arbitrage purposes to further its own financial gain. Any repurchase
            must be made only after the lender obtains the Agency written
            approval. If the lender does not repurchase the portion from the
            holder, the Agency may, at its option, purchase such guaranteed
            portion for servicing purposes.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14471'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.79
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1779.79
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='79' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.79
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14472'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.80
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1779.80
      </num>
      <head>
        Interest rate changes after loan closing.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='80' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.80
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Interest rate changes after loan closing.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subject to the restrictions below, the borrower, lender, and holder
            (if any) may collectively effect a permanent reduction in the
            interest rate on the guaranteed loan at any time during the life of
            the loan on written agreement by all of the applicable parties.
            After such a permanent reduction, the Loan Note Guarantee will only
            cover losses of interest at the reduced interest rate. The Agency
            must be notified by the lender, in writing, within 10 calendar days
            of the change. When the Agency is a holder, it will concur only when
            it is demonstrated that the change is more viable than liquidation
            and that the Government&apos;s financial interests are not adversely
            affected. Factors which will be considered in making such
            determination are the Government&apos;s cost of borrowing money and
            the project&apos;s enhancement of rural development. The monetary
            recovery must be greater than the liquidation recovery, and a
            financial feasibility analysis must show the project&apos;s
            continued viability.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Fixed rates cannot be changed to variable rates to reduce the
            interest rate to the borrower unless the variable rate has a ceiling
            which is less than the original fixed rate.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Variable rates can be changed to a lower fixed rate. In a final
            loss settlement when qualifying rate changes are made with the
            required written agreements and notification, the interest will be
            calculated for the periods the given rates were in effect. The
            lender must maintain records which adequately document the accrued
            interest claimed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The lender is responsible for the legal documentation of interest
            rate changes. However, the lender may not issue a new note.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Increases.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No increases in interest rates will be permitted under the loan
            guarantee except the normal fluctuations in approved variable
            interest rate loans.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14473'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.81
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1779.81
      </num>
      <head>
        Liquidation.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='81' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.81
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Liquidation.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Liquidation will occur when the lender concludes that liquidation of
          the guaranteed loan is necessary because of default or third party
          actions that the borrower cannot, or will not, cure or eliminate
          within a reasonable period of time and the Agency concurs with the
          lender; or the Agency, at any time, independently concludes that
          liquidation is necessary. The lender will proceed as expeditiously as
          possible, including giving any notices or taking any legal actions
          required by the security instruments.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a lender has made a loan guaranteed by the Agency under previous
            regulations, the lender has the option to liquidate the loan under
            the provisions of this part or under the provisions of previous
            regulations. The lender will notify the Agency in writing within 10
            days after its decision to liquidate, which regulatory provisions it
            chooses to use. The lender may not choose some provisions of one
            regulation and other provisions of the other regulation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Acquiring property titles.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a lender acquires title to property, the Agency may elect to
            permit the lender the option of calculating the final loss
            settlement using the net proceeds received at the time of the
            ultimate disposition of the property. The lender must submit to the
            Agency a written request to use this option within 15 days of
            acquiring title and the Agency must agree, in writing, prior to the
            lender submitting any request for estimated loss payment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Liquidation plan.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The lender will (within 30 days after a decision to liquidate)
            submit to the Agency, in writing, a proposed, detailed liquidation 
            <PRTPAGE P='284' />
            plan. Upon approval by the Agency of the liquidation plan, the
            lender will commence liquidation. The lender&apos;s liquidation plan
            must include, but is not limited to, the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Such proof as the Agency requires to establish the lender&apos;s
            ownership of the guaranteed loan notes and related security
            instruments, a copy of the payment ledger or other documentation
            which reflects the outstanding loan balance and accrued interest to
            date, and the method of computing the interest;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A complete list of collateral;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The recommended liquidation methods for making the maximum
            collection possible on the indebtedness and the justification for
            such methods, including the recommended action for acquiring and
            disposing of all collateral;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Necessary steps for preservation of the collateral;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Copies of the borrower&apos;s latest available financial
            statements;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An itemized list of estimated liquidation expenses expected to be
            incurred and justification for each expense;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A schedule to periodically report to the Agency on the progress of
            the liquidation;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Estimated protective advance amounts with justification;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Proposed protective bid amounts on collateral to be sold at auction
            and a discussion of how the amounts were determined;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a voluntary conveyance is considered, the proposed amount to be
            credited to the guaranteed debt;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_11'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (11)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Legal opinions, as needed; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_12'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (12)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the outstanding balance of principal and interest is less than
            $250,000, the lender will obtain an estimate of fair market and
            potential liquidation value of the collateral. If the outstanding
            balance of principal and interest is $250,000 or more, the lender
            will obtain an independent appraisal report on all collateral
            securing the loan which will reflect the fair market value and
            potential liquidation value. The independent appraiser&apos;s fee
            will be shared equally by the Agency and the lender.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Partial liquidation plan.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If actions are necessary to immediately preserve and protect the
            collateral, a partial liquidation plan may be submitted and, when
            approved, must be followed by a complete liquidation plan prepared
            by the lender.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Disposition of collateral.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Disposition of collateral acquired by the lender must be approved,
            in writing, by the Agency when:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The lender&apos;s cost to acquire the collateral of a borrower
            exceeds the potential recovery value of the security and the lender
            proposes abandoning the collateral in lieu of liquidation; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The acquired collateral is to be sold to the borrower,
            borrower&apos;s stockholders or officers, or the lender or
            lender&apos;s stockholders or officers.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Agency liquidation.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Agency will liquidate at its option only when it is a holder
            and there is reason to believe the lender is not likely to initiate
            liquidation efforts that will result in maximum recovery. When the
            Agency liquidates, proceeds derived from the sale of the collateral
            will be applied first to reasonable liquidation expenses and second
            to the guaranteed portion of the loan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Final loss payment.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Final loss payments will be made only after all collateral has been
            properly accounted for and liquidation expenses are determined to be
            reasonable and within approved limits. Any estimated loss payments
            made to the lender will be credited against the final loss on the
            guaranteed loan. The amount of an estimated loss payment must be
            credited as a deduction from the principal balance of the loan.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14474'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.82
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1779.82
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='82' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.82
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14475'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.83
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1779.83
      </num>
      <head>
        Protective advances.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='83' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.83
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Protective advances.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Protective advances can only be added to the loan account for purposes
          of requirements to preserve the value of the security. Protective
          advances constitute an indebtedness of the borrower to the lender and
          must be secured by collateral to the same extent as principal and
          interest. Protective advances include, but are not limited to,
          advances made for taxes, annual assessments, ground rent, hazard and
          flood insurance premiums affecting the 
          <PRTPAGE P='285' />
          collateral (including any other expenses necessary to protect the
          collateral). Attorney fees are not a protective advance.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Agency approval.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Agency must approve, in writing, all protective advances on
            loans within its loan approval authority which exceed a total
            cumulative advance amount of $5,000 to the same borrower. Protective
            advances must be reasonable when associated with the value of the
            collateral being preserved.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Preserving collateral.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When considering protective advances, sound judgment must be
            exercised in determining that the additional funds advanced will
            actually preserve collateral and recovery is actually enhanced by
            making the advance.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14476'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.84
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1779.84
      </num>
      <head>
        Additional loans or advances.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='84' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.84
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Additional loans or advances.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The lender will not make additional expenditures or new loans to the
          borrower without first obtaining the written approval of the Agency
          even though such expenditures or loans will not be guaranteed.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14477'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.85
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1779.85
      </num>
      <head>
        Bankruptcy.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='85' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.85
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Bankruptcy.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Calculating losses.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Report of Loss form (available in any Agency office) will be used
            for calculating estimated and final loss determinations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Lender responsibility.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The lender is responsible for protecting the guaranteed loan debt
            and all the collateral securing it in bankruptcy proceedings. These
            responsibilities include, but are not limited to, the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Filing a proof of claim, where necessary, and all necessary papers
            and pleadings;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Attending and, where necessary, participating in meetings of the
            creditors and all court proceedings;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Immediately seeking adequate protection of the collateral if it is
            subject to being used by the trustee in bankruptcy or the debtor in
            possession;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Where appropriate, seeking involuntary conversion of a pending
            chapter 11 case to a liquidation proceeding or seeking dismissal of
            the proceedings; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Keeping the Agency adequately and regularly informed, in writing,
            of all aspects of the proceedings.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Appraisals.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In a chapter 9 or chapter 11 reorganization, the lender must obtain
            an independent appraisal of the collateral if the Agency believes an
            independent appraisal is necessary. The Agency and the lender will
            share the appraisal fee equally.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Liquidation expenses.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Only expenses authorized by the court of chapter 9 plans or chapter
            11 reorganizations, or chapters 11 or 7 liquidation (unless the
            liquidation is by the lender), may be deducted from the collateral
            proceeds.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Repurchase from the holder.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Agency or the lender, with the approval of the Agency, may
            initiate the repurchase of the unpaid guaranteed portion of the loan
            from the holder. If the lender is the holder, an estimated loss
            payment may be filed at the initiation of a chapter 7 proceeding or
            after a chapter 9 or chapter 11 proceeding becomes a liquidation
            proceeding. Any loss payment on loans in bankruptcy must be approved
            by the Agency.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Chapter 11 bankruptcy.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a borrower has filed for protection under chapters 9 or 11 of
            the United States Code for a reorganization (but not chapter 13) and
            all or a portion of the debt has been discharged, the lender may
            request an estimated loss payment of the guaranteed portion of the
            accrued interest and principal discharged by the court. If the court
            approves revisions to the chapter 9 plan or chapter 11
            reorganization plan, subsequent estimated loss payments may be
            requested in accordance with the court approved changes. Once the
            reorganization plan has been satisfactorily completed, the lender is
            responsible for submitting the documentation necessary for the
            Agency to review and adjust the estimated loss claim to reflect any
            actual discharge of principal and interest and to reimburse the
            lender for any court ordered interest-rate reduction under the terms
            of the reorganization plan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Agency approval of estimated liquidation expenses.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Agency must approve, in advance and in writing, the
            lender&apos;s estimated liquidation expenses of collateral in a
            liquidation if the liquidation is performed by the lender. These
            expenses must be reasonable and 
            <PRTPAGE P='286' />
            customary and not include in-house expenses of the lender.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Reconciliation.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the event that the estimated loss payment exceeds the actual
            loss, the lender will reimburse the Agency the amount in excess of
            the actual loss plus interest at the note rate from the date of the
            estimated loss payment.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14478'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.86-1779.87
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1779.86-1779.87
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='86-1779' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.86-1779
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .87
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14479'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.88
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1779.88
      </num>
      <head>
        Transfers and assumptions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='88' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.88
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Transfers and assumptions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For all transfers and assumptions, the lender must concur in the
            plans for disposition of funds in the transferor&apos;s debt
            service, reserve, and operation and maintenance account. The Agency
            will approve, in writing, transfers and assumptions of loans to
            transferees who will continue the original purpose of the guaranteed
            loan subject to the following applicable provisions:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When the transaction is to a member of the borrower&apos;s
            organization, it will be at an amount which will not result in a
            loss to the lender.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Transfers to eligible borrowers will receive preference if recovery
            to the lender from the sale price is not less than it would be if
            the transfer was to an ineligible borrower.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The present borrower is unable or unwilling to accomplish the
            objectives of the guaranteed loan, and the transfer will be to the
            lender&apos;s and Agency&apos;s advantage.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The transferee will assume an amount at least equal to either the
            present market value or the debt, whichever is less.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Transfers to an eligible borrower.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The total indebtedness may be transferred to an eligible borrower
            on the same terms.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The total indebtedness may be transferred to another eligible
            borrower on different terms not to exceed those terms for which an
            initial guaranteed loan can be made.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Less than the total indebtedness may be transferred to another
            eligible borrower on the same or different terms and the pro rata
            share of any eligible loss paid to the lender.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A guaranteed loan for which the transferee is eligible may be made
            in connection with a transfer subject to the policies and procedures
            governing the type of loan being made.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the transferor is to receive a payment for the equity, the total
            debt must be assumed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Ineligible borrower.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Transfers to ineligible borrowers are considered only when needed
            as a method for servicing problem cases when an eligible transferee
            is not available. Transfers should not be considered as a means by
            which members can obtain equity or as a method of providing a source
            of easy credit for purchasers. Transfers must meet the following
            requirements:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All transfers to ineligible borrowers will include a one-time
            nonrefundable transfer fee to the Agency of no more than 1 percent.
            Transfer fees will be collected, and payments applied, in accordance
            with paragraph (d) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For all loans covered by this part, the Agency may approve a
            transfer of indebtedness to, and assumption of, a loan by a
            transferee who does not meet the eligibility requirements for the
            kind of loan being assumed when the ineligible borrower will:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Make a significant down payment, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Agree to pay the remaining balance within not more than 15 years.
            Installments will be at least equal to the amount amortized over a
            period not greater than the remaining life of the debt being
            transferred, and the balance will be due the fifteenth year.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Interest rates to ineligible transferees will be the rate specified
            in the note of the transferor or the rates customarily charged
            borrowers in similar circumstances in the ordinary course of
            business and are subject to Agency review and approval. The rates
            may be either fixed or variable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Transferees must have the ability to repay as determined by the
            lender the debt according to the Assumption Agreement and must have
            the legal authority to enter into the contract. The transferee will
            submit a current balance sheet to the lender. The lender will obtain
            and analyze the credit history of the transferee.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The transferor may receive equity payments only when the full
            amount of the debt is assumed. However, equity payments will not be
            made 
            <PRTPAGE P='287' />
            on more favorable terms than those on which the balance of the debt
            will be paid.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Transfer fees.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Transfer fees are a one-time nonrefundable cost to be collected by
            the lender at the time of application or proposal.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The transfer fees will be a standard fee plus the cost of the
            appraisal.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The lender will collect and submit the fee to the Agency.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Agency may waive the transfer fee if it determines that such
            waiver is in the best interest of the Agency.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Processing transfers and assumptions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In any transfer and assumption case, the transferor (including any
            guarantor) may be released from liability by the lender only with
            prior Agency written concurrence and only when the value of the
            collateral being transferred is at least equal to the amount of the
            loan, or part of the loan, being assumed. If the transfer is for
            less than the entire debt:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Agency must determine that the transferor and any guarantor
            have no reasonable debt-paying ability considering their assets and
            income at the time of transfer, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The lender must certify that the transferor has cooperated in good
            faith, used due diligence to maintain the collateral against loss,
            and has otherwise fulfilled all of the regulations of this part to
            the best of the borrower&apos;s ability.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The lender will make, in all cases, a complete credit analysis to
            determine viability of the project (subject to the Agency review and
            approval) including any requirement for deposit in an escrow account
            as security to meet the determined equity requirements for the
            project.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The lender will confirm that the transaction can be properly
            transferred and the conveyance instruments will be filed,
            registered, or recorded as appropriate and legally permissible.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The assumption will be made on the lender&apos;s form of Assumption
            Agreement and will contain the Agency case number of the transferor
            and transferee.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Loan terms cannot be changed by the Assumption Agreement unless
            previously approved in writing by the Agency with the concurrence of
            holder and the transferor (including guarantor if it has not been
            released from personal liability). Any new loan terms cannot exceed
            those authorized in this part. The lender&apos;s request will be
            supported by:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_5_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An explanation of the reasons for the proposed change in the loan
            terms, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_5_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Certification that the lien position securing the guaranteed loan
            will be maintained or improved, and proper hazard insurance will be
            continued in effect.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the case of a transfer and assumption, it is the lender&apos;s
            responsibility to see that all such transfers and assumptions will
            be noted on all originals of the Loan Note Guarantee. The lender
            will provide the Agency a copy of the Transfer and Assumption
            Agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a loss should occur upon a complete transfer of assets and
            assumption for less than the full amount of the debt and the
            transferor-debtor (including personal guarantor) is released from
            personal liability (as provided in paragraph (e)(1)(i) of this
            section), the lender (if holding the guaranteed portion) may file an
            estimated Report of Loss to recover their pro rata share of the
            actual loss at that time. Approved protective advances and accrued
            interest made during the arrangement of a transfer and assumption,
            if not assumed by the transferee, will be entered on the estimated
            Report of Loss.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14480'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.89
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1779.89
      </num>
      <head>
        Mergers.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='89' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.89
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Mergers.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Agency may approve mergers or consolidations (herein referred
            to as “mergers”) when the resulting organization will be eligible
            for an Agency guaranteed loan and assumes all the liabilities and
            acquires all the assets of the merged borrower. Mergers may be
            approved when:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The merger is in the best interest of the Government and the
            merging borrower;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The resulting borrower can meet all required conditions as
            contained in specific loan note agreements; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All property can be legally transferred to the resulting borrower.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Distinguishing mergers from transfers and assumptions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Mergers occur when one entity combines with another 
            <PRTPAGE P='288' />
            entity in such a way that the first entity ceases to exist as a
            separate entity while the other continues. In a consolidation, two
            or more entities combine to form a new, consolidated entity with the
            original entity ceasing to exist. Such transactions must be
            distinguished from transfers and assumptions in which a transferor
            will not necessarily go out of existence, and the transferee will
            not always take all the transferor&apos;s assets nor assume all the
            transferor&apos;s liabilities.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14481'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.90
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1779.90
      </num>
      <head>
        Disposition of acquired property.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='90' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.90
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Disposition of acquired property.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When the lender acquires title to the collateral and the final loss
            claim is not paid until final disposition, the lender must proceed
            as quickly as possible to develop a plan to fully protect the
            collateral, and the lender must dispose of the collateral without
            delay.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Re-title collateral.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any collateral accepted by the lender must not be titled in the
            Agency&apos;s name in whole or in part. The Agency&apos;s position
            is that of a guarantor relating to losses, not a lender.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Collateral preservation.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             After acquiring the collateral, the lender must protect the
            collateral from deterioration (weather, vandalism, etc.). Hazard
            insurance in an amount necessary to cover the fair market value of
            the collateral must be maintained.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Collateral sale.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The lender will prepare and submit to the Agency a plan on the best
            method of sale, keeping in mind any prospective purchasers. The
            Agency must approve the plan in writing. If an existing approved
            liquidation plan addresses the disposition of acquired property, no
            further review is required unless modification of the plan is
            needed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Anytime there is a case when the conversion of collateral to cash
            can reasonably be expected to result in a negative net recovery
            amount, abandonment of the collateral should be considered. The
            Agency must approve abandonment in writing.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14482'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.91-1779.93
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1779.91-1779.93
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='91-1779' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.91-1779
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .93
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14483'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.94
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1779.94
      </num>
      <head>
        Determination and payment of loss.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='94' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.94
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Determination and payment of loss.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          In all liquidation cases, final settlement will be made with the
          lender after the collateral is liquidated. The Agency will have the
          right to recover losses paid under the guarantee from any liable
          party.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the lender takes title to collateral, any loss will be based on
            the collateral value at the time the lender obtains title.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Loss calculations.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Report of Loss form (available in any Agency office) will be
            used for calculations of all estimated and final loss
            determinations. Estimated loss payments may only be approved after
            the lender has submitted a liquidation plan approved by the Agency.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Estimated loss payments.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When the lender is conducting the liquidation and owns any of the
            guaranteed portion of the loan, it may request an estimated loss
            payment by submitting an estimate of loss that will occur in
            connection with liquidation of the loan. An estimated loss payment
            may be approved after the Agency has approved the liquidation plan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The lender will prepare and submit a Report of Loss using the
            appraised value in lieu of amount received from sale of collateral.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The estimated loss payment shall be calculated as of the date of
            such payment. The total amount of the loss payment remitted by the
            Agency will be applied by the lender on the guaranteed portion of
            the loan debt. Such application does not release the borrower from
            liability. At the time of final loss settlement, the lender may
            notify the borrower that the loss payment has been so applied.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             After liquidation has been completed, a final Report of Loss will
            be submitted by the lender to the Agency.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Final report of loss.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            In all cases, a final Report of Loss must be submitted to the
            Agency. Before Agency approval of any final loss report, the lender
            must account for all funds obtained, disposition of the collateral,
            all costs incurred, and any other information necessary for the
            successful completion of liquidation. Upon receipt of the final 
            <PRTPAGE P='289' />
            accounting and Report of Loss, the Agency may conduct an audit and
            will determine the final loss. The lender will make its records
            available to, and otherwise assist, the Agency in making any audit
            it requires of the Report of Loss. The documentation accompanying
            the Report of Loss must support the loss claimed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The lender must document and show that all of the collateral has
            been accounted for and properly liquidated and that liquidation
            proceeds have been properly accounted for and applied correctly on
            the loan. The Agency must be satisfied that the lender has
            accomplished this in the manner contained herein and that the lender
            has maximized the collections in conducting the liquidation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The lender must show a breakdown on any protective advance amount
            as to the payee, purpose of the expenditure, date paid, evidence
            that the amount expended was proper, and that the amount was
            actually paid.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The lender must show a breakdown of liquidation expenses as to the
            payee, purpose of the expenditure, date paid, evidence that the
            amount expended was proper, and that the amount was actually paid.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Accrued interest should be supported by attachments showing how the
            amount was accrued by the lender. A copy of the promissory note and
            ledger will be attached. If the interest rate was a variable rate,
            the lender must include documentation of changes in the selected
            base rate and when the changes in the loan rate became effective.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Liquidation income.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any net rental or other income that has been received by the lender
            from the collateral will be applied on the guaranteed loan debt.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Liquidation costs.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Certain reasonable liquidation costs will be allowed during the
            liquidation process. The liquidation costs must be submitted as a
            part of the liquidation plan. Such costs will be deducted from gross
            proceeds received from the disposition of collateral unless the
            costs have been previously determined by the lender (with Agency
            concurrence) to be protective advances. If changed circumstances
            after submission of the liquidation plan require a revision of
            liquidation costs, the lender will obtain the Agency&apos;s written
            concurrence prior to proceeding with the proposed changes. No
            in-house expenses of the lender will be allowed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Protective advance losses.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In those instances where the lender made authorized protective
            advances, the lender may claim recovery for the guaranteed portion
            of any loss of monies advanced as well as interest resulting from
            such protective advances. These claims shall be included in the
            final Report of Loss.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Final loss approval.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             After the final Report of Loss has been tentatively approved:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the actual loss is greater than any estimated loss payment, such
            loss will be paid by the Agency;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the actual loss is less than any estimated loss payment, the
            lender will reimburse the Agency;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the Agency conducted the liquidation, it will provide an
            accounting to the lender and will pay the lender in accordance with
            the Loan Note Guarantee.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Loss limits.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The amount payable by the Agency to the lender cannot exceed the
            limits contained in the Loan Note Guarantee. If the Agency conducts
            the liquidation, loss occasioned by accruing interest will be
            covered by the guarantee only to the date the Agency accepts this
            responsibility. When the liquidation is conducted by the lender,
            loss occasioned by accruing interest will be covered to the extent
            of the guarantee to the date of final settlement provided the lender
            proceeds expeditiously with the liquidation plan approved by the
            Agency.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14484'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.95
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1779.95
      </num>
      <head>
        Future recovery.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='95' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.95
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Future recovery.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          After a loan has been liquidated and a final loss has been paid by the
          Agency, any future funds which may be recovered by the lender will be
          pro-rated between the Agency and the lender in accordance with the
          guaranteed percentage even if the Loan Note Guarantee has been
          terminated.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14485'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.96
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1779.96
      </num>
      <head>
        Termination of Loan Note Guarantee.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='96' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.96
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Termination of Loan Note Guarantee.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The Loan Note Guarantee under this part will terminate automatically:
          <PRTPAGE P='290' />
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon full payment of the guaranteed loan; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon full payment of any loss obligation or negotiated loss
            settlement except for future recovery provisions; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon written request from the lender to the Agency, provided that
            the lender holds all of the guaranteed portion and the original Loan
            Note Guarantee is returned to the Agency.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14486'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.97-1779.99
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1779.97-1779.99
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='97-1779' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.97-1779
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .99
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14487'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1779:-:1779.100
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1779.100
      </num>
      <head>
        OMB control number.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1779' sect='100' psec='' tq='N'>
              1779.100
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          OMB control number.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The reporting and recordkeeping requirements contained in this part
          have been approved by the Office of Management and Budget and have
          been assigned OMB control number 0572-0122.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>