<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol10'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1488
    </extid>
    <num>
      1488
    </num>
    <head>
      FINANCING OF SALES OF AGRICULTURAL COMMODITIES
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            Sec. 5(f), 62
          </aref>
           Stat. 1072 (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='15' sect='714c' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/15/714c.html'>
              15 U.S.C. 714c
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ) and 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            sec. 4(a), 80
          </aref>
           Stat. 1538, as amended by 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            sec. 101, 92
          </aref>
           Stat. 1685 (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='1707a' note='' psec='#a' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1707a.html#a'>
              7 U.S.C. 1707a(a)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ).
        </P>
      </AUTH>
    </text>
    <section orderid='13157'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1488:A:1488.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1488.1
      </num>
      <head>
        General statement.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1488' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              1488.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General statement.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as otherwise provided in this paragraph (a), the regulations
            and the supplements thereto contained in this subpart A supersede
            the regulations and supplements revised April 1975, and set forth
            the terms and conditions governing the CCC Export Credit Sales
            Program (GSM-5). The maximum financing period shall be three years.
            The regulations and supplements as revised in April 1971 and April
            1975, shall remain in effect for all transactions under financing
            approvals issued thereunder.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subject to the terms and conditions set forth in this subpart A,
            CCC will purchase for cash, after delivery, the exporter&apos;s
            account receivable arising from the export sale.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The provisions of Pub. L. 83-664 are not applicable to shipments
            under this program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The regulations contained in this subpart A may be supplemented by
            such additional terms and conditions, applicable to specified
            agricultural commodities, and, to the extent that they may be in
            conflict or inconsistent with any other provisions of this subpart
            A, such additional terms and conditions shall prevail.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13158'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1488:A:1488.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1488.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Definition of terms.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          42 FR 10999
        </aref>
        . Feb. 25, 1977, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          42 FR 30833
        </aref>
        , June 17, 1977; Amdt. 5, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          43 FR 25992
        </aref>
        , June 16, 1978]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1488' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              1488.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definition of terms.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          As used in this subpart A and in the forms and documents related
          thereto, the following terms shall have the meanings assigned to them
          in this section:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Account receivable
            </E>
             means the contractual obligation of the foreign importer to the
            exporter for the port value of the commodity delivered for which the
            exporter is extending credit to the importer. The account receivable
            shall be evidenced by documents, in form and substance satisfactory
            to CCC, establishing the contractual obligation between the U.S.
            exporter and the foreign importer. The account receivable shall
            provide for (1) payment of principal and interest in U.S. dollars in
            the United States, (2) interest in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1488' sect='14' psec='' tq='N'>
                1488.14
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , and (3) acceleration of payment thereunder in accordance with
            these regulations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Agency or branch bank
            </E>
             means an agency or branch of a foreign bank, supervised by New York
            State banking authorities or the banking authorities of any other
            State providing similar supervision, and approved by the Controller,
            CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Assistant Sales Manager
            </E>
             means the Assistant Sales Manager, Commercial 
            <PRTPAGE P='926' />
            Export Programs, Office of the General Sales Manager.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Bank obligation
            </E>
             means an obligation, acceptable to CCC, of a U.S. bank, a foreign
            bank, an agency or branch bank, to pay to CCC in U.S. dollars the
            amount of the account receivable, plus interest in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1488' sect='14' psec='' tq='N'>
                1488.14
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . The bank obligation shall be in the form of an irrevocable letter
            of credit issued by a U.S. bank or a branch bank, or confirmed or
            advised by a U.S. bank or any agency or branch bank in accordance
            with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1488' sect='12' psec='' tq='N'>
                1488.12
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . The bank obligation shall provide for payment under the terms and
            conditions of the financing agreement and shall be payable not later
            than the date of expiration of the financing period or of the bank
            obligation, whichever occurs first, if payment is not received from
            other sources.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              CCC
            </E>
             means the Commodity Credit Corporation, U.S. Department of
            Agriculture.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Carrying charges
            </E>
             means storage, insurance, and interest charges involved in the cost
            of storing the commodity before delivery as provided for in the
            sales contract, and other incidental costs as may be approved by the
            Assistant Sales Manager.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Commercial risk
            </E>
             means risk of loss due to any cause other than specified as
            noncommercial risk in paragraph (u) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Date of delivery
            </E>
             means the on-board date of the ocean bill of lading, or the date of
            an airway bill, or, if exported by rail or truck, the date of entry
            shown on an authenticated landing certificate or similar document
            issued by an official of the government of the importing country. If
            delivery is before export, the date of delivery means (1) the
            date(s) of the warehouse receipt(s), or other evidence acceptable to
            CCC, covering the commodity in a warehouse acceptable to CCC, or (2)
            the onboard carrier (truck, rail car or lash or seabee barge) date
            of a through bill of lading covering commodities in a container or a
            lash or seabee barge at a U.S. inland or coastal point.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Date of sale
            </E>
             means the earliest date the exporter has knowledge that a
            contractual obligation exists with the foreign buyer under which a
            firm dollar and cent price has been established or a mechanism to
            establish the price has been agreed upon.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Delivery
            </E>
             means the delivery required by the export sale contract to transfer
            to the importer full or conditional title to the agricultural
            commodity. Delivery before export may be (1) in a warehouse in the
            United States acceptable to CCC by issuance or transfer of the
            warehouse receipt to the importer, or (2) f.a.s. or f.o.b. U.S.
            inland or coastal loading point, if the commodity is loaded in a
            container on a truck or rail car, or in a lash or seabee barge for
            shipment to a point of export under a through bill of lading.
            Delivery at point of export shall be f.a.s. or f.o.b. export carrier
            at U.S. ports, at U.S. airports, at U.S. border points of exit or,
            if transshipped through Canada, at ports on the Great Lakes or the
            St. Lawrence River.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Eligible commodities
            </E>
             means agricultural commodities, including eligible cotton, produced
            in the United States and designated as eligible for export under
            CCC&apos;s Export Credit Sales Program in a USDA announcement.
            Commodities which have been purchased from CCC are eligible for
            export as private stocks. Exports of commodities pursuant to any CCC
            barter contract, Pub. L. 480 or AID agreement, or direct loan by the
            Export-Import Bank are not eligible for financing under this
            program. Commodities delivered prior to CCC receiving the sale
            registration request in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1488' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
                1488.4
              </subref>
            </aref>
             are not eligible for financing under this program unless such
            financing is determined by the Vice President, CCC, or the Assistant
            Sales Manager, to be in the interest of CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='l'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (l)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Eligible cotton
            </E>
             means Upland and Extra Long staple cotton grown in the United
            States: 
            <E T='03'>
              Provided, however,
            </E>
             That reginned or repacked cotton, as defined in regulations of the
            U.S. Department of Agriculture under the U.S. Cotton Standards Act (
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR 
              <subref title='7' part='28' sect='40' psec='' tq='N'>
                28.40
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ), by-products of cotton such as cotton mill waste, motes, and
            linters, and any cotton that contains any by-products of cotton are
            not eligible for export financing hereunder. CCC&apos;s
            determination as to the eligibility of cotton shall be final.
            <PRTPAGE P='927' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='m'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (m)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Eligible destination
            </E>
             means the country which is named in the financing agreement and
            which meets the licensing requirements of the U.S. Department of
            Commerce.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='n'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (n)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Eligible exporter
            </E>
             or 
            <E T='03'>
              exporter
            </E>
             means a person (1) who is engaged in the business of buying or
            selling commodities and for this purpose maintains a bona fide
            business office in the United States, its territories or
            possessions, and has someone on whom service of judicial process may
            be had within the United States, (2) who is financially responsible,
            and (3) who is not suspended or debarred from contracting with or
            participating in any program financed by CCC on the date of issuance
            of the financing approval.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='o'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (o)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              OGSM
            </E>
             means the Office of the General Sales Manager, U.S. Department of
            Agriculture.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='p'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (p)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Financing agreement
            </E>
             means the exporter&apos;s request for a sale registration as
            approved by the Assistant Sales Manager, including the terms and
            conditions of the regulations in effect on the date of approval.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='q'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (q)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Financing period
            </E>
             means the number of months over which repayment is to be made. Such
            period shall start on the date of delivery or the weighted average
            delivery date of the commodities to be exported under the financing
            agreement, and shall expire on the expiration of the bank obligation
            or the specified period over which repayment is to be made,
            whichever occurs first.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='r'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (r)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Foreign bank
            </E>
             means a bank which is not a U.S. bank or an agency or branch bank,
            and includes a foreign branch of a U.S. bank.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='s'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (s)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Foreign importer
            </E>
             or 
            <E T='03'>
              importer
            </E>
             means the foreign buyer who purchases the commodities to be
            exported under a financing agreement and executes the documents
            evidencing the account receivable assigned to CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='t'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (t)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              GSM-5
            </E>
             means the regulations contained in this subpart A, and supplements
            thereto, setting forth the terms and conditions governing the CCC
            Export Credit Sales Program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='u'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (u)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Noncommercial risk
            </E>
             means risk of loss due to (1) inability of the foreign bank through
            no fault of its own to convert foreign currency to dollars, or (2)
            non-delivery into the eligible destination of the commodity covered
            by a financing agreement through no fault of the foreign bank or
            importer or exporter because of the cancellation by the government
            of the eligible destination of previously issued valid authority to
            import such shipment into the eligible destination or because of the
            imposition of any law or of any order, decree, or regulation having
            the force of law, which prevents the import of such shipment into
            the eligible destination, or (3) inability of the foreign bank to
            make payment due to war, hostilities, civil war, rebellion,
            revolution, insurrection, civil commotion, or other like disturbance
            occurring in the eligible destination, expropriation, or
            confiscation, or other like action by the government of the eligible
            destination country, or (4) failure of the foreign bank to make
            payment for any reason if it is an instrumentality of or is wholly
            owned by the foreign government.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Port value
            </E>
             means the net amount of the exporter&apos;s sales price of the
            commodity to be exported under the financing agreement, (1) basis
            f.a.s. or f.o.b. export carrier at U.S. ports, at U.S. border points
            of exit, at U.S. airports if shipped by air, or, if transshipped
            through Canada at ports on the Great Lakes, or on the St. Lawrence
            River, or (2) basis U.S. warehouse for commodities delivered to such
            warehouse before export, or (3) basis f.a.s. or f.o.b. U.S. inland
            or coastal loading point for commodities delivered before export
            under through bill of lading. The port value shall not include ocean
            freight for a c. &amp; f. sale or ocean freight and marine and war
            risk insurance for a c.i.f. sale but may include carrying charges as
            provided for in the sales contract. The net amount of the
            exporter&apos;s sales price means the exporter&apos;s contract price
            for the commodities, on the basis stated above, less any payments
            made to the exporter and less any discounts, credits, or allowances
            by the exporter.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='w'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (w)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Sale
            </E>
             means a contract to sell on credit U.S. agricultural commodities to
            be financed under GSM-5.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='x'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (x)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              United States
            </E>
             means the 50 States, the District of Columbia, and Puerto Rico.
            <PRTPAGE P='928' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='y'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (y)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              U.S. bank
            </E>
             means a bank organized under the laws of the United States, a
            State, or the District of Columbia.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='z'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (z)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              USDA announcement
            </E>
             means an announcement published monthly by the U.S. Department of
            Agriculture (USDA), and which includes the list of eligible
            commodities and interest rates under GSM-5.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='aa'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (aa)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Vice President, CCC
            </E>
             means the Vice President who is the General Sales Manager, Office
            of the General Sales Manager.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            42 FR 10999
          </aref>
          . Feb. 25, 1977, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            42 FR 30833
          </aref>
          , June 17, 1977; Amdt. 5, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            43 FR 25992
          </aref>
          , June 16, 1978]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13159'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1488:A:1488.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1488.3
      </num>
      <head>
        General.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1488' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              1488.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          When considering the extension of CCC credit for the purpose of
          financing agricultural commodities, CCC will take into account the
          extent to which CCC credit financing will:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Permit U.S. exporters to meet competition from other countries.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Prevent a decline in U.S. commercial export sales.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Substitute commercial dollar sales for sales made pursuant to Pub.
            L. 480 or other concessional programs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Result in a new use of the agricultural commodity in the importing
            country.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Permit expanded consumption of agricultural commodities in the
            importing country and thereby increase total commercial sales of
            agricultural commodities to the importing country.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13160'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1488:A:1488.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1488.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Submission of requests for sale registrations.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          42 FR 10999
        </aref>
        , Feb. 25, 1977, as amended by Amdt. 5, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          43 FR 25992
        </aref>
        , June 16, 1978]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1488' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              1488.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Submission of requests for sale registrations.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An eligible exporter shall submit a request for a sale registration
            for financing to the office specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1488' sect='22' psec='' tq='N'>
                1488.22
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Requests for sale registrations shall be in writing. If such a
            request is made by telephone, it must be confirmed by letter or
            wire.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The total amount requested to be registered under a sale shall not
            exceed the sale contract value, including the upward tolerance, if
            any.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Requests for sale registration shall incorporate by reference all
            terms and conditions of GSM-5. The following information shall also
            be included in the exporter&apos;s request for a sale registration:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The name, class, grade, or quality, as applicable, and quantity of
            the commodity to be exported.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The country of destination.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The port value of the commodity to be exported and the sale
            contract tolerance, if applicable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The date of sale and exporter&apos;s sale number.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The date of delivery or the period for delivery and the month in
            which application for payment will be submitted.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The financing period.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whether the bank obligation assuring payment of the account
            receivable will be issued by a U.S. bank, branch bank, or foreign
            bank. If it will be issued by a foreign bank, its name and address,
            and the name of the confirming U.S. bank, branch bank, or agency
            bank (if approved as provided in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1488' sect='12b' psec='' tq='N'>
                1488.12b
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ), and the percentage of confirmation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The name and address of the foreign importer.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If delivery of the commodity to be exported is before export in a
            warehouse, the name and address of the warehouse to which delivery
            is to be made.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the commodity will be sold through an intervening purchaser, the
            name and address of the intervening purchaser, and a statement that
            the sale of the commodity is or will be conditioned on its resale by
            the intervening purchaser and that the commodity will be shipped
            directly to the foreign importer in the destination country
            specified in paragraph (d)(2) of this section pursuant to a contract
            in which the foreign importer agrees to pay the U.S. exporter the
            amount to be financed in accordance with the terms of GSM-5
            financing agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_11'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (11)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any additional information as determined by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            42 FR 10999
          </aref>
          , Feb. 25, 1977, as amended by Amdt. 5, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            43 FR 25992
          </aref>
          , June 16, 1978]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13161'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1488:A:1488.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1488.5
      </num>
      <head>
        Acceptance of sale registrations.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          42 FR 10999
        </aref>
        , Feb. 25, 1977, as amended by Amdt. 6, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          43 FR 29933
        </aref>
        , July 12, 1978]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1488' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              1488.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Acceptance of sale registrations.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon receiving a request for a sale registration complying with the
            applicable provisions of this subpart, 
            <PRTPAGE P='929' />
            the Assistant Sales Manager may approve the registration of the
            sale. If approved, the exporter will be notified in writing of the
            financing agreement number which will constitute notice that the
            sale is registered and eligible for financing.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             [Reserved]
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC reserves the right to reject any and all requests for sale
            registration.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The registration of a sale shall create a financing agreement
            between the exporter and CCC which shall consist of the
            exporter&apos;s request for a sale registration, CCC&apos;s
            acceptance of the sale registration, the applicable terms and
            conditions of this subpart, including amendments and supplemental
            announcements hereunder which are in effect on the date of approval.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The financing agreement may contain such terms and conditions, not
            inconsistent with GSM-5, as are deemed necessary in the interest of
            CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An exporter shall promptly notify the Assistant Sales Manager when
            he is unable to fulfill his obligations under any sale registered
            with CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            42 FR 10999
          </aref>
          , Feb. 25, 1977, as amended by Amdt. 6, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            43 FR 29933
          </aref>
          , July 12, 1978]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13162'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1488:A:1488.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1488.6
      </num>
      <head>
        Amendments to financing agreement.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1488' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              1488.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Amendments to financing agreement.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The financing agreement may be amended provided such amendment is in
          conformity with GSM-5 at the time of amendment and is determined to be
          in the interest of CCC. Amendments may include extension of the period
          for delivery or the period for export, and change in the interest
          rate. After the commodity has been delivered, CCC will consider
          requests to increase the amount of the sale registration value for any
          quantity within the tolerance in the sales contract and for carrying
          charges provided such requests relate to the same sale as originally
          registered with CCC.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13163'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1488:A:1488.7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1488.7
      </num>
      <head>
        Expiration of period(s) for delivery and/or export.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1488' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              1488.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Expiration of period(s) for delivery and/or export.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Unless delivery by the exporter to the importer is made within such
            period as may be provided in the financing agreement or any
            amendment thereof, or under paragraph (b) of this section, the
            financing agreement will no longer be valid.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the Assistant Sales Manager determines that delay in delivery
            was due solely to causes without the fault or negligence of the
            exporter, the period for delivery may be extended by CCC by the
            period of such delay.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If delivery is made before export under the terms of the financing
            agreement, failure to export within the period specified therefor in
            the financing agreement shall constitute a breach of the financing
            agreement. In such case, if full payment under the bank obligation
            or account receivable has not been received, the account receivable
            and the bank obligation shall, at the option of the Assistant Sales
            Manager, become immediately due and payable, and liquidated damages
            shall be payable in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1488' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
                1488.11
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13164'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1488:A:1488.8
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1488.8
      </num>
      <head>
        Documents required after delivery.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          42 FR 10999
        </aref>
        , Feb. 25, 1977, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          42 FR 27569
        </aref>
        , May 31, 1977; Amdt. 5, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          43 FR 25992
        </aref>
        , June 16, 1978]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1488' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              1488.8
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Documents required after delivery.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC will purchase an exporter&apos;s account receivable only if the
            Treasurer, Commodity Credit Corporation, United States Department of
            Agriculture, Washington, DC 20250, receives the documents specified
            in paragraphs (b) through (e) of this section and any documentation
            and certifications required by any supplements to these regulations
            within forty-five days, or any extension thereof by the Treasurer or
            Assistant Treasurer, CCC, after date of delivery of commodities
            exported or to be exported under the financing agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The exporter shall submit a “Combined Application for Disbursement,
            Assignment of Account Receivable and Certification” which shall
            include:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A written application for disbursement, showing the financing
            agreement number and the port value of the commodity delivered.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An assignment of the account receivable arising from the export
            sale, in form and substance acceptable to CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The exporter&apos;s certification (i) that he has entered into a
            contract to sell an eligible commodity; (ii) of the 
            <PRTPAGE P='930' />
            date of sale, the grade, quality, quantity, agreed upon price for
            the commodity and payment terms and interest in accordance with the
            financing agreement; (iii) that he has in his files documents
            evidencing the export sale contract and the obligation of the
            importer to him for the financed portion of the export sale and will
            retain and furnish them to CCC on demand until 3 years after the end
            of the financing period; (iv) that agricultural commodities of the
            grade, quality, and quantity called for in the exporter&apos;s sale
            as registered with CCC have been delivered to the foreign importer;
            and (v) that he knows of no defenses to the account receivable
            assigned to CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A copy of the sales invoice to the foreign importer, or, if the
            commodity has been sold through an intervening purchaser, a copy of
            the exporter&apos;s sales invoice to the intervening purchaser and
            of the intervening purchaser&apos;s sales invoice to the foreign
            importer.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A copy of the document evidencing export provided for in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1488' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
                1488.9
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and, if the consignee is other than the foreign importer named in
            the financing agreement, such additional information as CCC may
            request to show that export was made in accordance with the
            instructions of, or the export sale contract with, the foreign
            importer. If delivery is before export in a warehouse acceptable to
            CCC, the warehouse receipt or other documents acceptable to CCC
            evidencing delivery of the commodity to the importer or his agent.
            If delivery is before export in a container or a lash or seabee
            barge at a U.S. inland or coastal point, for export shipment under a
            through bill of lading, one copy of the through bill of lading with
            an onboard (truck, rail car, or lash or seabee barge) endorsement,
            dated and signed or initialed on behalf of the export carrier. The
            through bill of lading must be certified by the exporter as being a
            true copy and must show the quantity, the date, and place of loading
            the commodity on a truck, or rail car, or lash or seabee barge, the
            name of the originating carrier, the destination of the commodity,
            and the name of both the exporter and the importer.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A bank obligation or obligations in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1488' sect='7' psec='#c' tq='N'>
                1488.7(c)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1488' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
                1488.10
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1488' sect='12' psec='' tq='N'>
                1488.12
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and paragraph (i) of this section, naming CCC as beneficiary, in
            form and substance acceptable to CCC, covering the amount of the
            application for disbursement, citing the financing agreement number;
            and providing for the payment of interest in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1488' sect='14' psec='' tq='N'>
                1488.14
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             On receipt of the documents described in paragraphs (b) through (e)
            of this section and any documentation and certifications required by
            any supplements to these regulations, the Treasurer, CCC will pay
            promptly to the exporter the amount of the account receivable or the
            dollar amount of sales registered in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1488' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
                1488.5
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , whichever is the lesser.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If an acceptable application for disbursement and the supporting
            documents described in paragraphs (b) through (e) of this section
            have not been received by CCC within 45 days from the date of the
            delivery, or any extension thereof by the Treasurer or Assistant
            Treasurer, CCC, the financing agreement shall be void.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             [Reserved]
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If for any reason a draft drawn under a foreign bank obligation is
            dishonored or if the issuing bank is insolvent, in bankruptcy, in
            receivership, or in liquidation, or has made an assignment for the
            benefit of creditors, or for any other reason discontinues or
            suspends payments to depositors or creditors, or otherwise ceases to
            operate on an unrestricted basis, any balance due on the account
            receivable assured by the obligation issued by such bank shall, at
            the option of CCC, become immediately due and payable. CCC may
            permit the substitution of another acceptable foreign bank
            obligation covering such balance due if confirmed in accordance with
            
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1488' sect='12' psec='' tq='N'>
                1488.12
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            42 FR 10999
          </aref>
          , Feb. 25, 1977, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            42 FR 27569
          </aref>
          , May 31, 1977; Amdt. 5, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            43 FR 25992
          </aref>
          , June 16, 1978]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13165'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1488:A:1488.9
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1488.9
      </num>
      <head>
        Evidence of export.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1488' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
              1488.9
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Evidence of export.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the commodity is exported by rail or truck, the exporter shall
            furnish to the Treasurer, CCC, one copy of the bill of lading
            covering the commodity exported, certified by the exporter as 
            <PRTPAGE P='931' />
            being a true copy, and an authenticated landing certificate or
            similar document issued by an official of the government of the
            country to which the commodity is exported, showing the quantity,
            the gross landed weight of the commodity, the place and date of
            entry, and the name and address of both the exporter and the
            importer.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the commodity is exported by ocean carrier, the exporter shall
            furnish to the Treasurer, CCC, one non-negotiable copy or photo copy
            or other type of copy of either (1) an on-board ocean bill of lading
            or (2) an ocean bill of lading with an onboard endorsement, dated
            and signed or initialed on behalf of the carrier. The bill of lading
            must be certified by the exporter as being a true copy and must show
            the quantity, the date and place of loading the commodity, the name
            of the vessel, the destination of the commodity and the name and
            address of both the exporter and the importer.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the commodity is exported by aircraft, the exporter shall
            furnish to the Treasurer, CCC, one non-negotiable copy of an airway
            bill, dated and signed or initialed on behalf of the carrier. The
            airway bill must be certified by the exporter as being a true copy
            and must show the date and place of loading the commodity, the name
            of the airline, the destination of the commodity, and the name and
            address of both the exporter and the importer.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the exporter is unable to supply documentary evidence of export
            as specified in this section, he shall submit such other documentary
            evidence as may be acceptable to CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For commodities transshipped through Canada via the Great Lakes or
            the St. Lawrence River, the exporter shall certify that the
            commodity transshipped was produced in the United States.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13166'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1488:A:1488.9a
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1488.9a
      </num>
      <head>
        Evidence of export for commodities delivered before export.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [Amdt. 5, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          43 FR 25992
        </aref>
        , June 16, 1978]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1488' sect='9a' psec='' tq='N'>
              1488.9a
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Evidence of export for commodities delivered before export.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          For commodities delivered before export under a financing agreement
          for which the financial period is 12 months or less, the exporter
          shall furnish a certification to the Treasurer, CCC, within 60 days
          from the date of delivery or such extension of time as may be granted
          by the Treasurer or Assistant Treasurer, CCC, certifying that the
          commodities have been exported. The certification must include the
          name of the ocean carrier, the date the commodities were loaded aboard
          the ocean carrier and the financing agreement number.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [Amdt. 5, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            43 FR 25992
          </aref>
          , June 16, 1978]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13167'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1488:A:1488.10
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1488.10
      </num>
      <head>
        Evidence of entry into country of destination.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1488' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
              1488.10
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Evidence of entry into country of destination.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Commodities exported under a financing agreement must enter the
            destination country specified in the financing agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For a financing agreement under which the financing period is in
            excess of 12 months, within 90 days, or such extension of time as
            may be granted in writing by the Assistant Sales Manager, following
            shipment from the United States of any agricultural commodity
            exported under the financing agreement, the exporter shall furnish
            to the office specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1488' sect='22' psec='' tq='N'>
                1488.22
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , documentary evidence verifying entry of the commodity into the
            country of destination specified in the financing agreement. The
            documentary evidence must:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Identify the agricultural commodity (or permit identification
            through supplementary documents also furnished) as that exported
            under the financing agreement,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State the quantity and date of entry of the commodity into the
            destination country, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be signed by (i) a customs official of the destination country, or
            (ii) the importer, or (iii) a representative of an independent
            superintending or controlling firm.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When the commodity enters the country of destination in bond, a
            statement by the importer will be acceptable which:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Identifies the commodity as that exported under the financing
            agreement,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             States the quantity of the commodity entered under bond and date of
            entry into the destination country, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Certifies that the commodity will be withdrawn from bonded storage
            at a later date for consumption in the destination country.
            <PRTPAGE P='932' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the evidence of entry is in other than the English language, the
            exporter shall also provide an English translation thereof.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Failure to furnish, within the time specified, evidence of entry of
            the commodity into the country of destination shall constitute prima
            facie evidence of failure to enter or to cause the entry of the
            commodity into such country as required. In such case, the financing
            agreement may be terminated by the Assistant Sales Manager, and if
            full payment under the bank obligation or account receivable has not
            yet been received, the bank obligation and the account receivable
            shall at the option of CCC, become due and payable and liquidated
            damages shall be payable in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1488' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
                1488.11
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . The remedy herein provided shall not be exclusive of other rights
            available to the Federal government if the commodity enters a
            country other than that specified in the financing agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13168'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1488:A:1488.11
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1488.11
      </num>
      <head>
        Liquidated damages.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1488' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
              1488.11
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Liquidated damages.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Failure of the exporter to export or cause to be exported, within the
          period provided therefor, any agricultural commodity financed, when
          delivery is made before export under the terms of the financing
          agreement, or failure of the exporter to enter or cause the entry of,
          such commodity into the country of destination, shall constitute a
          breach of the financing agreement which will result in serious and
          substantial damage to CCC and to its program. Since it will be
          difficult, if not impossible, to prove the exact amount of such
          damage, the exporter shall pay to CCC promptly on demand, as
          reasonable compensation and not as a penalty, liquidated damages in
          lieu of probable actual damages, as follows:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For each day of delay in exportation after the final date for
            exportation, when delivery is made before export under the terms of
            the financing agreement, .15 percent of the amount financed under
            the financing agreement for the commodity not exported; (b) for
            failure to export or cause exportation, when delivery is made before
            export under the terms of the financing agreement, 5 percent of the
            amount financed under the financing agreement for the commodity not
            exported; (c) for failure, after exportation, to enter or cause the
            entry of the commodity into the country of destination, at the rate
            of 5 percent a year of the amount financed under the financing
            agreement for such commodity from the start of the financing period
            until payment to CCC of the amount financed; 
            <E T='03'>
              Provided however,
            </E>
             That the aggregate of all amounts assessed under this 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1488' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
                1488.11
              </subref>
            </aref>
             with respect to the same commodity shall not exceed 5 percent of
            the amount financed for such commodity. Liquidated damages shall not
            be assessed: Under paragraph (a) of this section if the Assistant
            Sales manager determines that the delay was due to such causes as
            acts of God or government or public enemy, fires, floods, epidemics,
            quarantine restrictions, strikes, freight embargoes, or unusually
            severe weather; under paragraph (b) of this section if the Assistant
            Sales Manager determines that failure to export was due to loss,
            damage, destruction or deterioration of the commodity or act of God
            or government or public enemy; and under paragraph (c) of this
            section if the Assistant Sales Manager determines that failure to
            enter or cause the entry of the commodity into the country of
            destination was due to loss, damage, destruction or deterioration of
            the commodity or act of God or government or public enemy.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13169'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1488:A:1488.12
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1488.12
      </num>
      <head>
        Coverage of bank obligations.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          42 FR 10999
        </aref>
        , Feb. 25, 1977, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          42 FR 27569
        </aref>
        , May 31, 1977; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          42 FR 30833
        </aref>
        , June 17, 1977; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          43 FR 45551
        </aref>
        , Oct. 3, 1978; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          44 FR 51187
        </aref>
        , Aug. 31, 1979]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1488' sect='12' psec='' tq='N'>
              1488.12
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Coverage of bank obligations.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             U.S. banks and branch banks shall be liable without regard to risk
            (1) for payment of bank obligations issued by them or (2) for
            payment of bank obligations confirmed by them without regard to risk
            if a requirement for such confirmation is included in the financing
            agreement or (3) as provided in paragraphs (c) and (d) of this
            section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An obligation issued by a foreign bank must be confirmed and
            advised, as provided in paragraphs (a), (c), (d), (e), and (f) of
            this section, by a U.S. bank or a branch bank, or may be confirmed
            by an agency bank when determined by the President or Vice
            President, CCC after consultation with the 
            <PRTPAGE P='933' />
            Controller, CCC, to be in the interest of CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A U.S. bank must confirm the full amount of an obligation issued by
            its foreign branch. CCC will hold the U.S. bank liable for payment
            without regard to risks.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a branch bank confirms an obligation issued by its home office,
            or by another branch of its home office, it must confirm the full
            amount thereof. CCC will hold the branch bank liable for payment
            without regard to risks.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If CCC accepts an agency bank confirmation of a foreign bank
            obligation, it must be for the full amount thereof without regard to
            risks and will be subject to such terms and conditions as may be
            contained in the financing agreement. CCC will not accept an agency
            bank confirmation of an obligation issued by its home office, or by
            a branch of its home office.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as provided in paragraphs (a), (c), and (d) of this section,
            if a U.S. bank or a branch bank confirms an obligation issued by a
            foreign bank, it must confirm at least 10 percent pro rata and must
            advise the remainder of the foreign bank obligation. The percentage
            of confirmation shall be the same for both the account receivable
            and the interest portions of the obligation. For the confirmed
            amount, except as provided in paragraph (a)(2) of this section, CCC
            will hold the U.S. bank or branch bank liable for commercial risks
            but not for non-commercial risks. For the advised amount, CCC will
            not hold the U.S. bank or branch bank liable for commercial or
            non-commercial risks. CCC will hold the foreign bank liable without
            regard to risks for all amounts not recovered from the U.S. or
            branch bank.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Under special circumstances, on application in writing, the Vice
            President, CCC, may reduce or waive requirements for 10 percent
            confirmation by a U.S. or branch bank, but a bank will not be
            relieved of any obligation it undertakes.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any bank obligation which provides for a bank acceptance of a time
            draft by CCC (banker&apos;s acceptance) shall not be acceptable to
            CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC will consent to cancellation or reduction of a bank obligation
            to the extent of any payment it receives from other sources or
            amounts otherwise payable under such bank obligation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Collection of accounts receivable purchased under GSM-5 will be
            effected through the issuance by CCC of sight drafts against the
            bank obligations, but this method of collection shall not be
            exclusive of any other collection procedures or rights available to
            CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            42 FR 10999
          </aref>
          , Feb. 25, 1977, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            42 FR 27569
          </aref>
          , May 31, 1977; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            42 FR 30833
          </aref>
          , June 17, 1977; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            43 FR 45551
          </aref>
          , Oct. 3, 1978; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            44 FR 51187
          </aref>
          , Aug. 31, 1979]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13170'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1488:A:1488.13
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1488.13
      </num>
      <head>
        CCC drafts.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          42 FR 10999
        </aref>
        , Feb. 25, 1977, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          42 FR 27569
        </aref>
        , May 21, 1977; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          42 FR 30833
        </aref>
        , June 17, 1977]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1488' sect='13' psec='' tq='N'>
              1488.13
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          CCC drafts.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          CCC will draw one draft for each payment due under bank obligations.
          If any portion of a CCC draft is dishonored, the U.S. bank or branch
          bank shall return the dishonored draft together with its statement of
          the reason for nonpayment. If a draft which is drawn under a partially
          confirmed bank obligation is dishonored, CCC will replace the draft
          with separate drafts for the confirmed and unconfirmed portions at the
          request of the confirming bank. Such replacement shall not alter the
          confirming bank&apos;s obligation for timely payment to CCC of the
          confirmed portion of the credit. For confirmed amounts, except as
          provided in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1488' sect='12' psec='#a' tq='N'>
              1488.12(a), (c) and (d)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , a U.S. or branch bank may request refund from CCC of the amount paid
          if it certifies to CCC that it is unable to recover funds from the
          foreign bank due to a stipulated non-commercial risk which existed on
          the date payment was made to CCC under the draft. If CCC finds that
          inability to recover funds was due to such a non-commercial risk, the
          refund shall be promptly made together with interest at the Federal
          Reserve Bank of New York discount rate from and including the date
          payment was originally made to CCC but not include the date of refund
          by CCC. For unconfirmed amounts, remittance to CCC shall be considered
          final, and the U.S. bank or branch bank shall not thereafter have
          recourse to CCC.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            42 FR 10999
          </aref>
          , Feb. 25, 1977, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            42 FR 27569
          </aref>
          , May 21, 1977; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            42 FR 30833
          </aref>
          , June 17, 1977]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13171'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1488:A:1488.14
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1488.14
      </num>
      <head>
        Interest charges.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          42 FR 10999
        </aref>
        , Feb. 25, 1977, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          42 FR 27569
        </aref>
        , May 31, 1977]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='934' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1488' sect='14' psec='' tq='N'>
              1488.14
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Interest charges.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The account receivable assigned to CCC and the related bank
          obligation(s) shall bear interest as specified in this section. Rates
          of interest applicable to financing agreements shall be published in
          USDA announcement. The interest rate applicable to that portion of an
          account receivable for which payment is assured by a bank obligation
          issued or confirmed for all risks according to 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1488' sect='12' psec='#a_ii' tq='N'>
              1488.12(a)(ii)
            </subref>
          </aref>
           or pro rata confirmed by a U.S. bank shall be lower than the interest
          rate applicable for the remainder of the account receivable. The
          interest rate applicable to that portion of an account receivable the
          payment of which is assured by a bank obligation issued or pro rata
          confirmed by a branch bank shall, when determined by the President or
          Vice President, CCC after consultation with the Controller, CCC, to be
          in the interest of CCC, be lower than the interest rate applicable for
          the remainder of the account receivable. The interest rates applicable
          to accounts receivable the payment of which is assured by an agency
          bank confirmation may, when determined by the President or Vice
          President, CCC, after consultation with the Controller, CCC, to be in
          the interest of CCC, be lower than the interest rate applicable for
          the remainder of the account receivable. The interest rate applicable
          will be the rate in effect on the date CCC receives the sale
          registration request under 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1488' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              1488.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
          . Interest shall accrue on the account receivable from the date of
          delivery or the weighted average delivery date of the agricultural
          commodities delivered under the financing agreement to the date of
          payment, or to the date of expiration of the financing period, or to
          the date of expiration of the bank obligation, whichever occurs first,
          and shall be payable as specified in the financing agreement.
          Thereafter, interest shall accrue on any unpaid part of both the
          principal and interest due as of such expiration date.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            42 FR 10999
          </aref>
          , Feb. 25, 1977, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            42 FR 27569
          </aref>
          , May 31, 1977]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13172'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1488:A:1488.15
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1488.15
      </num>
      <head>
        Advance payment.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1488' sect='15' psec='' tq='N'>
              1488.15
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Advance payment.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          If, before expiration of the financing period, the exporter or the
          U.S. bank or the agency or branch bank accepts payment from or on
          behalf of the foreign importer of any part of the account receivable,
          it shall be remitted promptly to CCC. Such prepayment shall be applied
          first to interest on the unpaid balance of the account receivable to
          the date CCC receives such prepayment and then to the principal.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13173'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1488:A:1488.16
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1488.16
      </num>
      <head>
        Liability for payment.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1488' sect='16' psec='' tq='N'>
              1488.16
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Liability for payment.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          If delivery is made within the coverage of the bank obligation(s)
          submitted in accordance with 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1488' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              1488.8
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , CCC will look to the obligating bank or banks and the foreign
          importer, rather than to the exporter or intervening purchaser, for
          payment of all amounts due at maturity of the account receivable and
          of the bank obligation(s), but the exporter and the intervening
          purchaser shall remain liable for any loss arising from breach of any
          contractual obligation, certification or warranty made by them
          pursuant to the financing agreement, and the exporter shall remain
          liable for any amounts not covered by the bank obligation which are
          owing to CCC, and any remittance or refund required by 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1488' sect='15' psec='' tq='N'>
              1488.15
            </subref>
          </aref>
           and 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1488' sect='18' psec='' tq='N'>
              1488.18
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , together with interest thereon at the rate specified in the
          documents evidencing the account receivable, as well as for any
          liquidated damages provided for in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1488' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
              1488.11
            </subref>
          </aref>
          . The liability of the bank and the importer under their respective
          obligations shall be several.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13174'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1488:A:1488.17
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1488.17
      </num>
      <head>
        Assignment.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1488' sect='17' psec='' tq='N'>
              1488.17
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Assignment.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The exporter shall not assign any claim or rights or any amounts
          payable under the financing agreement, in whole or in part, without
          written approval of the Vice President, CCC, or the Controller, CCC.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13175'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1488:A:1488.18
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1488.18
      </num>
      <head>
        Covenant against contingent fees.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1488' sect='18' psec='' tq='N'>
              1488.18
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Covenant against contingent fees.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The exporter warrants that no person or selling agency has been
          employed or retained to solicit or secure the financing agreement on
          an agreement or understanding for a commission, percentage, brokerage,
          or contingent fee, except bona fide employees or bona fide established
          commercial or selling agencies maintained by the exporter for the 
          <PRTPAGE P='935' />
          purpose of securing business. For breach or violation of this
          warranty, CCC shall have the right, without limitation on any other
          rights it may have, to annul the financing agreement without liability
          to CCC. Should the financing agreement be annulled, CCC will promptly
          consent to the reduction or cancellation or related bank obligations
          except for amounts outstanding under a financing agreement. Such
          amounts shall, on demand, be refunded to CCC by the exporter.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13176'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1488:A:1488.19
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1488.19
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1488' sect='19' psec='' tq='N'>
              1488.19
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13177'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1488:A:1488.20
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1488.20
      </num>
      <head>
        Officials not to benefit.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1488' sect='20' psec='' tq='N'>
              1488.20
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Officials not to benefit.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          No member of or delegate to Congress, or Resident Commissioner, shall
          be admitted to any share or part of the financing agreement or to any
          benefit that may arise therefrom, but this provision shall not be
          construed to extend to the financing agreement if made with a
          corporation for its general benefit.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13178'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1488:A:1488.21
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1488.21
      </num>
      <head>
        Exporter&apos;s records and accounts.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1488' sect='21' psec='' tq='N'>
              1488.21
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Exporter&apos;s records and accounts.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          CCC shall have access to and the right to examine any directly
          pertinent books, documents, papers and records of the exporter
          involving transactions related to the financed export credit sale
          until the expiration of three years after the end of the financing
          period.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13179'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1488:A:1488.22
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1488.22
      </num>
      <head>
        Communications.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1488' sect='22' psec='' tq='N'>
              1488.22
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Communications.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Unless otherwise provided, written requests, notifications, or
            communications by the applicant pertaining to the financing
            agreement shall be addressed to the Assistant Sales Manager,
            Commercial Export Programs, Office of the General Sales Manager,
            U.S. Department of Agriculture, Washington, DC 20250.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             [Reserved]
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13180'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1488:A:1488.23
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1488.23
      </num>
      <head>
        OMB Control Numbers assigned pursuant to the Paperwork Reduction Act.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [Amdt. 8, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          50 FR 13967
        </aref>
        , Apr. 9, 1985]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1488' sect='23' psec='' tq='N'>
              1488.23
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          OMB Control Numbers assigned pursuant to the Paperwork Reduction Act.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The information collection requirements contained in these regulations
          (
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR part 
            <subref title='7' part='1488' tq='N'>
              1488
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ) have been approved by the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) in
          accordance with the provisions of 44 U.S.C. Chapter 35 and have been
          assigned OMB Control Number 0551-0021.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [Amdt. 8, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            50 FR 13967
          </aref>
          , Apr. 9, 1985]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>