<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol10'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1436
    </extid>
    <num>
      1436
    </num>
    <head>
      FARM STORAGE FACILITY LOAN PROGRAM REGULATIONS
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='7971' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/7971.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 7971
            </subref>
             and 
            <subref title='7' sect='8789' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/8789.html'>
              8789
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; and 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='15' sect='714-714p' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/15/714-714p.html'>
              15 U.S.C. 714-714p
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            66 FR 4612
          </aref>
          , Jan. 18, 2001, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='12781'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1436:-:1436.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1436.1
      </num>
      <head>
        Applicability.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          66 FR 4612
        </aref>
        , Jan. 18, 2001, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          74 FR 41587
        </aref>
        , Aug. 18, 2009]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1436' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              1436.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Applicability.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The regulations of this part provide the terms and conditions under
          which CCC may provide low-cost financing for producers to build or
          upgrade on-farm storage and handling facilities. Because liens and
          security interests related to this activity may be governed by State
          law, CCC may adapt certain procedures relating to those issues that
          may vary between States.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            66 FR 4612
          </aref>
          , Jan. 18, 2001, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            74 FR 41587
          </aref>
          , Aug. 18, 2009]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12782'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1436:-:1436.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1436.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Administration.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          66 FR 4612
        </aref>
        , Jan. 18, 2001, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          74 FR 41587
        </aref>
        , Aug. 18, 2009]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1436' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              1436.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Administration.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Farm Storage Facility Loan Program will be administered under
            the general supervision of the Executive Vice President, CCC or
            designee and will be carried out in the field by FSA State
            committees, FSA county committees and FSA employees.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FSA State committees, FSA county committees and FSA employees, do
            not have the authority to modify or waive any of the provisions of
            the regulations of this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The FSA State committee will take any action required by these
            regulations that has not been taken by the county committee. The FSA
            State committee will also:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Correct, or require the FSA county committee to correct, any action
            taken by such FSA county committee that is not in accordance with
            the regulations of this part; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Require the FSA county committee to withhold taking any action that
            is not in accordance with the regulations of this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No provision or delegation herein to a State or FSA county
            committee will preclude the Executive Vice President, CCC, or a
            designee, or the Administrator, FSA, or a designee, from determining
            any question arising under the program or from reversing or
            modifying any determination made by the State or FSA county
            committee.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Deputy Administrator, Farm Programs, FSA, may authorize State
            and FSA county committees to waive or modify deadlines and other
            program requirements in cases where lateness or failure to meet such
            other requirements does not adversely affect the operation of the
            Farm Storage Facility Loan Program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A representative of CCC may execute Farm Storage Facility Loan
            Program applications and related documents only under the terms and
            conditions determined and announced by CCC. Any such document that
            is not executed in accordance with such terms and conditions,
            including any purported execution prior to the date authorized by
            CCC, will be void.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The purpose of the Farm Storage Facility Loan program is to provide
            CCC funded loans for producers of grains, oilseeds, pulse crops,
            sugar, 
            <PRTPAGE P='709' />
            hay, renewable biomass, fruits and vegetables (including nuts), and
            other storable commodities, as determined by the Secretary, to
            construct or upgrade storage and handling facilities for the
            eligible facility loan commodities they produce.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            66 FR 4612
          </aref>
          , Jan. 18, 2001, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            74 FR 41587
          </aref>
          , Aug. 18, 2009]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12783'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1436:-:1436.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1436.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          66 FR 4612
        </aref>
        , Jan. 18, 2001, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          67 FR 54938
        </aref>
        , Aug. 26, 2002; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          74 FR 41587
        </aref>
        , Aug. 18, 2009]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1436' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              1436.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The following definitions will be applicable to the program authorized
          by this part and will be used in all aspects of administering this
          program:
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Aggregate outstanding balance
          </E>
           means the sum of the outstanding balances of all loans disbursed
          under this part to each borrower signing the note and security
          agreement.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Assumption
          </E>
           means the act or agreement by which one borrower takes over or
          assumes the debt of another borrower.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Cold storage facility
          </E>
           means a facility or rooms within a facility that are specifically
          designed and constructed for the cold temperature storage of
          perishable commodities. The temperature and humidity in these
          facilities must be able to be regulated to specified conditions
          required for the commodity requiring storage.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Collateral
          </E>
           means the storage structure; the drying, handling, and cold storage
          equipment; and any other equipment securing the loan.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Commercial facility
          </E>
           means any structure, used in connection with or by any commercial
          operation including, but not limited to, grain elevators, warehouses,
          dryers, processing plants, or cold storage facilities used for the
          storage and handling of any agricultural product, whether paid or
          unpaid. Any structure suitable for the storage of an agricultural
          product that is in working proximity to any commercial storage
          operation will be considered to be part of a commercial storage
          operation.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Commercial storage
          </E>
           means the storing of any agricultural product, whether paid or
          unpaid, for persons other than the owner of the structure, except for
          family members and tenants or landlords with a share in the eligible
          facility loan commodity requiring storage.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Crop of economic significance
          </E>
           means any insurable facility loan commodity that contributes 10
          percent or more of the total expected value of all crops grown by the
          loan applicant except if the expected liability under the catastrophic
          level of crop insurance for a crop is equal to or less than the
          administrative fee for the crop, that crop shall not be economically
          significant.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Facility loan commodity
          </E>
           means corn, grain sorghum, oats, wheat, barley, rice, raw or refined
          sugar, soybeans, sunflower seed, canola, rapeseed, safflower,
          flaxseed, mustard seed, crambe, sesame seed, other oilseeds as
          determined and announced by CCC, dry peas, lentils, or chickpeas
          harvested as whole grain, peanuts, hay, renewable biomass, and fruits
          and vegetables (including nuts). Corn, grain sorghum, wheat, and
          barley are included whether harvested as whole grain or other than
          whole grain.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Financing statement
          </E>
           means the appropriate document that gives legal notice of a security
          interest in personal property when properly filed or recorded.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Hay
          </E>
           means a grass or legume that has been cut and stored. Commonly used
          grass mixtures include rye grass, timothy, brome, fescue, coastal
          Bermuda, orchard grass, and other native species, depending on the
          region. Forage legumes include alfalfa and clovers.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Non-movable or non-salable collateral
          </E>
           means either collateral the county committee determines cannot be
          sold and moved to a new location because of the type of construction
          involved or because the collateral has deteriorated to the point that
          it has no sale recovery value.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Renewable biomass
          </E>
           means any organic matter that is available on a renewable or
          recurring basis including renewable plant material such as feed grains
          or other agricultural commodities (including, but not limited to,
          soybeans and switchgrass), other plants and trees (excluding
          old-growth timber), algae, crop residue (including, but not limited
          to, corn stover, various straws and hulls, and orchard prunings),
          other vegetative waste material (including, but not limited to, wood
          waste, wood residues, and food and yard waste) used for the production
          of energy in the form of heat, electricity, and liquid, 
          <PRTPAGE P='710' />
          solid, or gaseous fuels. Manure from any source is not included.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Resale collateral value
          </E>
           means collateral that can be sold and moved to a new location for
          which compensation equal to the outstanding loan value can be
          expected.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Satisfactory credit history
          </E>
           means a history of repaying debts as they came due unless the failure
          to repay or tardiness in payment was due to circumstance beyond the
          applicant&apos;s control as determined by CCC upon proof submitted by
          the applicant.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Severance agreement
          </E>
           means an agreement under which a party may consent to the security
          interest of another in property thereby allowing the severance of a
          fixture from the real estate.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Subordination agreement
          </E>
           means any agreement under which a party may subordinate a security
          interest in property to the interest of another party.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            66 FR 4612
          </aref>
          , Jan. 18, 2001, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            67 FR 54938
          </aref>
          , Aug. 26, 2002; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            74 FR 41587
          </aref>
          , Aug. 18, 2009]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12784'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1436:-:1436.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1436.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Application for loans.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          74 FR 41587
        </aref>
        , Aug. 18, 2009]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1436' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              1436.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Application for loans.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An application for a loan must be submitted:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For all loans, except loans for renewable biomass storage
            facilities and cold storage facilities for fruits and vegetables, to
            the administrative county office that maintains the records of the
            farm or farms to which the application applies. With State office
            approval, loans may be made or serviced by a county office other
            than the administrative county office.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For loans for renewable biomass storage facilities and cold storage
            facilities for fruits and vegetables, to the administrative county
            FSA office that maintains the records of the farm or farms to which
            the application applies, if the facility will be located on land
            that has farm records established at the county office. If the
            commodities will be produced on land that does not have farm records
            established at the county office, the application must be submitted
            to the county FSA office that services the county where the facility
            will be located.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon request, the applicant must furnish information and documents
            as the State or county committee deems reasonably necessary to
            support the application. This may include financial statements,
            receipts, bills, invoices, purchase orders, specifications,
            drawings, plats, or written authorization of access.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For sugar storage facility loans, a loan application must be
            submitted to the county FSA office that maintains the
            applicant&apos;s records. If no such records exist, loan
            applications must be submitted to the county office serving the
            headquarters location of the sugar processor.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Submitting an application does not ensure loan approval nor create
            any liability on behalf of CCC. Borrowers who authorize delivery,
            site preparation, or construction actions without an approved loan,
            do so at their own risk.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            74 FR 41587
          </aref>
          , Aug. 18, 2009]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12785'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1436:-:1436.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1436.5
      </num>
      <head>
        Eligible borrowers.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          66 FR 4612
        </aref>
        , Jan. 18, 2001; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          66 FR 17073
        </aref>
        , Mar. 29, 2001, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          67 FR 54938
        </aref>
        , Aug. 26, 2002; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          74 FR 41588
        </aref>
        , Aug. 18, 2008]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1436' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              1436.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Eligible borrowers.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Borrower
            </E>
             means a person who, as landowner, landlord, operator, producer,
            tenant, leaseholder, sharecropper, or processor of domestically
            produced sugarcane or sugar beets:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Has a satisfactory credit history according to the definition in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1436' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
                1436.3
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and as recommended to the approving committee by a FSA employee
            with FSA loan approval authority;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Demonstrates an ability to repay the debt arising under this
            program using a financial statement acceptable to CCC prepared
            within 90 days of the date of application, as recommended to the
            approving committee by a FSA employee with FSA loan approval
            authority;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Has no disqualifying delinquent Federal debt under the Debt
            Collection Improvement Act of 1996;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is a producer of a facility loan commodity as determined by CCC;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Demonstrates a need for increased storage capacity as determined by
            CCC if the applicant is applying for a loan for a storage structure.
            The Deputy Administrator, Farm Programs, may issue a waiver, if
            requested, on a case by case basis if a crop share landlord or
            tenant requests to construct a structure to store commodities
            produced on the farm but only one of the two wishes to accept loan
            liability;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Annually provides proof of crop insurance offered under the Federal
            
            <PRTPAGE P='711' />
            Crop Insurance Program for insurable crops of economic significance
            on all farms operated by the borrower in the county where the
            storage facility is located. Crop insurance or Noninsured Crop
            Disaster Assistance Program (NAP) coverage, if available, is
            required on all the commodities stored in the FSFL-funded facility,
            whether economically significant or not; crop insurance under the
            Federal Crop Insurance Program may not be available for certain
            renewable biomass commodities;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is in compliance with the U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA)
            provisions for highly erodible land and wetlands conservation
            provisions according to 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='12' tq='N'>
                12
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Demonstrates compliance with any applicable local zoning, land use,
            and building codes for the applicable farm storage facility
            structures;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Annually provides proof of flood insurance if CCC determines such
            insurance is necessary to protect the interests of CCC, and annually
            provides proof that the structures for which the loan is made has
            all peril structural insurance;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Demonstrates compliance with the National Environmental Policy Act
            regulations at 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              40 CFR parts 
              <subref title='40' part='1500-1508' tq='N'>
                1500-1508
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_11'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (11)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Has not been convicted under Federal or State law of a
            disqualifying controlled substance violation or a crop insurance
            violation under 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='718' tq='N'>
                718
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For sugar facility loans:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Paragraphs (a)(4), (6), and (7) of this section do not apply.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Sugar processors must be approved by CCC to store sugar owned by
            CCC or pledged as security to CCC for non-recourse loans.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            66 FR 4612
          </aref>
          , Jan. 18, 2001; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            66 FR 17073
          </aref>
          , Mar. 29, 2001, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            67 FR 54938
          </aref>
          , Aug. 26, 2002; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            74 FR 41588
          </aref>
          , Aug. 18, 2008]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12786'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1436:-:1436.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1436.6
      </num>
      <head>
        Eligible storage or handling equipment.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          66 FR 4612
        </aref>
        , Jan. 18, 2001, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          67 FR 54938
        </aref>
        , Aug. 26, 2002; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          74 FR 41588
        </aref>
        , Aug. 18, 2009; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          76 FR 4805
        </aref>
        , Jan. 27, 2011]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1436' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              1436.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Eligible storage or handling equipment.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For all eligible facility loan commodities, except sugar and fruits
            and vegetables, loans may be made only for the purchase and
            installation of eligible storage facilities, and permanently affixed
            drying and handling equipment, or for the remodeling of existing
            storage facilities or permanently affixed drying and handling
            equipment as provided in this section. The loan collateral must be
            used for the purpose for which it was delivered, erected,
            constructed, assembled, or installed for the entire term of the
            loan. Eligible storage and handling facilities include the
            following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             New conventional-type cribs or bins designed and engineered for
            whole grain storage and having a useful life of at least 15 years;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             New oxygen-limiting storage structures or remanufactured
            oxygen-limiting storage structures built to the original
            manufacturer&apos;s design specifications using original
            manufacturer&apos;s rebuild kits or kits from a supplier approved by
            the Deputy Administrator, Farm Programs, and other upright silo-type
            structures designed for whole grain storage or other than whole
            grain storage and with a useful life of at least 15 years; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             New flat-type storage structures including a permanent concrete
            floor, designed for and primarily used to store facility loan
            commodities for the term of the loan and having a useful life of at
            least 15 years;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             New structures that are bunker-type, horizontal, or open silo
            structures designed for whole grain storage or other than whole
            grain storage and having a useful life of at least 15 years;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             New structures suitable for storing hay that are built according to
            acceptable design guidelines from the National Institute of Food and
            Agriculture (NIFA) or land-grant universities and with a useful life
            of at least 15 years; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             New structures suitable for storing renewable biomass that are
            built according to acceptable industry guidelines and with a useful
            life of at least 15 years.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For all eligible facility loan commodities, except sugar and fruits
            and vegetables, the calculation of the loan amount may include costs
            associated with building, improving, or renovating an eligible
            storage or handling facility, including:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Permanently affixed grain handling equipment and grain drying
            equipment, including perforated floors 
            <PRTPAGE P='712' />
            determined by the approving committee to be needed and essential to
            the proper functioning of the grain storage system;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Safety equipment as required by CCC and meeting OSHA requirements
            such as lighting, and inside and outside ladders;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Equipment to improve, maintain, or monitor the quality of stored
            eligible facility loan commodity, such as cleaners, moisture
            testers, and heat detectors;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Electrical equipment, including labor and materials for
            installation, such as lighting, motors, and wiring integral to the
            proper operation of the eligible facility loan commodity storage and
            handling equipment;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Concrete foundations, aprons, pits, and pads (including site
            preparation, labor and materials) essential to the proper operation
            of the eligible facility loan commodity storage and handling
            equipment; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Flooring appropriate for storing hay and renewable biomass suitable
            for the region where the facility is located and designed according
            to acceptable guidelines from NIFA or land-grant universities.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For all eligible facility loan commodities, except sugar and fruits
            and vegetables, no loans will be made for installation or related
            costs of:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Portable grain drying equipment, portable handling equipment and
            portable augers;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Structures of a temporary nature that require the weight or bulk of
            the stored commodity to maintain its shape (such as fences or bags);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Used structures or handling equipment, not including remanufactured
            oxygen-limiting storage structures built to the manufacturer&apos;s
            original design specifications as specified in paragraph (a)(2) of
            this section;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Structures that are not suitable for storing the facility loan
            commodities for which a need is determined;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Storage structures to be used as a commercial facility. Any
            facility that is in working proximity to any commercial storage
            operation will be considered to be part of a commercial storage
            operation; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Portable or permanent weigh scales.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Loans for all eligible facility loan commodities, except sugar and
            fruits and vegetables, may be approved for financing additions to or
            modifications of an existing storage facility with an expected
            useful life of at least 15 years if the county committee determines
            there is a need for the capacity of the structure, but loans will
            not be approved solely for the replacement of worn out items such as
            motors, fans, or wiring.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Loans for all eligible facility loan commodities except sugar and
            fruits and vegetables may be approved for new storage and handling
            components of a pre-owned structure provided the completed facility
            has a useful life of at least 15 years. The pre-owned structure must
            be purchased and moved to a new storage location. Eligible items for
            such a loan include costs such as new bin rings or roof panels
            needed to make a purchased pre-owned structure useable, new aeration
            systems, site preparation, construction off-farm paid labor cost,
            foundation material and off-farm paid labor. Ineligible items for
            such a loan include the cost of purchasing and moving the used
            structure.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The provisions of this paragraph apply only to sugar storage
            facility loans.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The loan amount may include costs associated with the purchase,
            installation, building, improving, remodeling or renovating an
            eligible storage or handling facility. Eligible facilities include
            the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             New conventional-type bins or silos designed for and used to store
            raw or refined sugar, having a useful life of at least 15 years;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             New flat-type storage structures including a permanent concrete
            floor, designed for and used to store raw or refined sugar, having a
            useful life of at least 15 years;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             New storage structures designed for and used to store in-process
            sugar, having a useful life of at least 15 years.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Permanently affixed sugar handling equipment determined by the CCC
            to be needed and essential to the proper functioning of the sugar
            storage system;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_1_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Safety equipment CCC requires such as lighting, and inside and
            outside ladders;
            <PRTPAGE P='713' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_1_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Equipment to improve, maintain, or monitor the quality of stored
            sugar, such as moisture testers, and heat detectors;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_1_vii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Electrical equipment, including labor and materials for
            installation, such as lighting, motors, and wiring integral to the
            proper operation of the sugar storage and handling equipment; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_1_viii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (viii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Concrete foundations, aprons, pits, and pads (including site
            preparation, labor and materials) essential to the proper operation
            of the sugar storage and handling equipment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Sugar storage facility, loans may be approved for financing
            additions to or modifications of an existing storage facility with
            an expected useful life of at least 15 years if CCC determines there
            is a need for the capacity of the structure.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No sugar storage facility loans will be made for:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Portable handling equipment and portable augers;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Structures of a temporary natures that require the weight or bulk
            of the stored commodity to maintain its shape (such as fences or
            bags);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Used or pre-owned structures or handling equipment;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_3_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Structures that are not suitable for storing raw or refined sugar;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_3_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Weigh scales.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The provisions of this paragraph apply only to fruit and vegetable
            cold storage facility loans.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For cold storage facility loans, the loan amount may include costs
            associated with the purchase, installation, building, improving,
            remodeling, or renovating an eligible storage or handling facility.
            Costs associated with the construction of a permanently installed
            cold storage facility include, but are not limited to, the
            following: An insulated cement slab floor, insulation for walls and
            ceiling (including, but not limited to, loose fill cellulose, foam
            insulation sheets, sprayed-on and foam-in-place materials), and a
            vapor barrier.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Eligible facilities include, but are not limited to, the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A new cold storage facility of wood pole and post construction,
            steel, or concrete, that is suitable for storing the fruits and
            vegetables produced by the borrower and with a useful life of at
            least 15 years;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             New walk-in prefabricated permanently installed cold storage
            coolers that are suitable for storing the producer&apos;s fruits and
            vegetables and with a useful life of at least 15 years;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Permanently affixed equipment necessary for a cold storage facility
            such as refrigeration units or system and circulation fans;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_2_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Permanently installed equipment to maintain or monitor the quality
            of produce stored in a cold storage facility;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_2_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Electrical equipment, including labor and materials for
            installation, such as lighting, motors, and wiring integral to the
            proper operation of a cold storage facility.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For cold storage facility loans, loans may be approved for
            financing additions or modifications to an existing storage facility
            with an expected useful life of at least 15 years if CCC determines
            there is a need for the capacity of the structure.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No cold storage facility loans will be made for:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_4_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Portable structures;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_4_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Portable handling and cooling equipment;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_4_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Used or pre-owned structures, or cooling and handling equipment; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_4_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Structures that are not suitable for a fruit or vegetable cold
            storage facility.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            66 FR 4612
          </aref>
          , Jan. 18, 2001, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            67 FR 54938
          </aref>
          , Aug. 26, 2002; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            74 FR 41588
          </aref>
          , Aug. 18, 2009; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 4805
          </aref>
          , Jan. 27, 2011]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12787'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1436:-:1436.7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1436.7
      </num>
      <head>
        Loan term.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          74 FR 41589
        </aref>
        , Aug. 18, 2009]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1436' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              1436.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Loan term.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For eligible facility loan commodities other than sugar, the term
            of the loan will be 7, 10, or 12 years, based on the total loan
            principal, from the date a promissory note and security agreement is
            completed on both the partial and final loan disbursements. The
            applicant will choose, if applicable, a loan term when submitting
            the loan application and total cost estimates.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For a loan with the principal of $100,000 or less, the term is 7
            years.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For loans from $100,000.01 through $250,000, the borrower will
            choose a term of 7 or 10 years.
            <PRTPAGE P='714' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For loans from $250,000.01 through $500,000, the borrower will
            choose a loan term of 7, 10, or 12 years.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No extensions of the loan term will be granted. The loan balance
            and all related costs are due at the end of the loan term.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For a sugar-related loan:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC, at its discretion, may authorize a maximum loan term of 15
            years. The minimum loan term of a sugar-related loan is 7 years.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The loan balance and costs are due at the end of the loan term,
            which will be established on the date the promissory note and
            security agreement is executed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            74 FR 41589
          </aref>
          , Aug. 18, 2009]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12788'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1436:-:1436.8
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1436.8
      </num>
      <head>
        Security for loan.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          74 FR 41589
        </aref>
        , Aug. 18, 2009]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1436' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              1436.8
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Security for loan.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as agreed to by CCC, all loans must be secured by a
            promissory note and security agreement covering the farm storage
            facility and such other assurances as CCC may demand, subject to the
            following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The promissory note and security agreement must grant CCC a
            security interest in the collateral and must be perfected in the
            manner specified in the laws of the State where the collateral is
            located.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC&apos;s security interest in the collateral must be the sole
            security interest in such collateral except for prior liens on the
            underlying real estate that by operation of law attach to the
            collateral if it is or will become a fixture. If any such prior lien
            on the real estate will attach to the collateral, a severance
            agreement must be obtained in writing from each holder of such a
            lien, including all government or USDA agencies. No additional liens
            or encumbrances may be placed on the storage facility after the loan
            is approved unless CCC approves otherwise in writing.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For any loan amounts of $50,000 or less, CCC will not require a
            severance agreement from the holder of any prior lien on the real
            estate parcel on which the storage facility is located, if the
            borrower:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Agrees to increase the down payment on the storage facility loan
            from 15 percent to 20 percent; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provides other security such as an irrevocable letter of credit,
            bond, or other form of security, as approved by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For loan amounts exceeding $50,000, or when the aggregate
            outstanding balance will exceed $50,000 or for loans in which the
            approving county or State committee determines, as a result of
            financial analysis, that additional security is required, a lien on
            the real estate parcel on which the farm storage facility is located
            is required in the form of a real estate mortgage, deed of trust, or
            other security instrument approved by USDA&apos;s Office of the
            General Counsel, provided further that:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC&apos;s interest in the real estate must be superior to all
            other liens, except a loan may be secured by a junior lien on real
            estate when the loan is adequately secured and a severance agreement
            is obtained from prior lien holders.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A loan will be considered to be adequately secured when the real
            estate security for the loan is at least equal to the loan amount.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the real estate is covered by a prior lien, a lien waiver may be
            obtained by means of a subordination agreement approved for use in
            the State by USDA&apos;s Office of the General Counsel. CCC will not
            require such an agreement from any agency of USDA.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Title insurance or a title opinion is required for loans secured by
            real estate.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Real estate liens, with prior CCC approval, may cover land separate
            from the collateral if a lien on the underlying real estate is not
            feasible and if:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The borrower owns the separate acreage and the acreage is not
            subject to any other liens or mortgages that are superior to
            CCC&apos;s lien interest and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The acreage is of adequate size and value at the time of the
            application as determined by the county committee to adequately
            secure and insure repayment of the loan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A borrower, in lieu of such liens required by this section, may
            provide an irrevocable letter of credit, bond, or other form of
            security, as approved by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If an existing structure is remodeled and an addition becomes an
            attached, integral part of the existing 
            <PRTPAGE P='715' />
            storage structure, CCC&apos;s security interest will include the
            remodeled addition as well as the existing storage structure.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For all farm storage facility loans, except sugar loans, the
            borrower must pay the cost of loan closings by attorneys, title
            opinions, title insurance, title searches, filing, and recording all
            real estate liens, fixture filings, appraisals if requested by the
            borrower, and all subordinations. CCC will pay costs relating to
            credit reports, collateral lien searches, and filing and recording
            financing statements for the collateral.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All loans of $50,000 or less that are secured with collateral with
            no resale value, as determined by CCC, may require additional
            security.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For sugar storage facility loans, in addition to other requirements
            in this section, additional security, including real estate,
            chattels, crops in storage, and other assets owned by the applicant,
            is required if deemed necessary by CCC to adequately secure the
            loan. A sugar storage facility loan will generally be considered to
            be adequately secured when the CCC-determined value of security for
            the loan is equal to at least 125 percent of the loan amount.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For sugar storage facility loans, paragraph (h) of this section is
            not applicable. However, the borrower must pay all loan making fees
            and closing costs. This includes, but is not limited to, attorney
            fees for loan closings, environmental assessments and studies,
            chattel and real estate appraisals, title opinions, title insurance,
            title searches, and filing and recording all real estate liens,
            fixture filings, subordinations, credit reports, collateral lien
            searches, and filing and recording financing statements for the
            collateral.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            74 FR 41589
          </aref>
          , Aug. 18, 2009]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12789'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1436:-:1436.9
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1436.9
      </num>
      <head>
        Loan amount and loan application approvals.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          74 FR 41590
        </aref>
        , Aug. 18, 2009, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          76 FR 4805
        </aref>
        , Jan. 27, 2011]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1436' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
              1436.9
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Loan amount and loan application approvals.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The cost on which the loan will be based is the net cost of the
            eligible facility, accessories, and services to the applicant after
            discounts and rebates, not to exceed a maximum per-bushel, -ton or,
            -cubic foot cost established by the FSA State committee.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The net cost for all storage facilities and handling equipment:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             May include the following: All real estate lien related fees paid
            by the borrower, including attorney fees, except for filing fees;
            environmental and historic review fees including archaeological
            study fees; the facility purchase price; sales tax; shipping;
            delivery charges; site preparation costs; installation cost;
            material and labor for concrete pads and foundations; material and
            labor for electrical wiring; electrical motors; off-farm paid labor;
            on-farm site preparation and construction equipment costs not to
            exceed commercial rates approved by the county committee; and new
            on-farm material approved by the county committee.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             May not include secondhand material or any other item determined by
            the approving authority to be ineligible for loan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The maximum total principal amount of the farm storage facility
            loan is 85 percent of the net cost of the applicant&apos;s needed
            storage or handling facility, including equipment, not to exceed
            $500,000 per loan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The storage need requirement for eligible facility loan commodities
            will be determined as follows:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For facility loan commodities, except sugar and fruits and
            vegetables:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Multiply the average of the applicant&apos;s share of the acres
            farmed for the most recent three years for each type of facility
            loan commodity requiring suitable storage at the proposed facility;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             By a yield determined reasonable by the county committee;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Multiply by two (for 2 years production); and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subtract existing storage capacity in the units of measurement,
            such as bushels, tons, or cubic feet, for the type of storage needed
            to determine remaining storage need.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Compare capacity of proposed facility with storage need (calculated
            as specified in paragraphs (d)(1)(i)-(iv) of this section) to
            determine if applicant is eligible for additional storage.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For sugar storage facility loans,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Identify past processing volume and marketing allotments;
            <PRTPAGE P='716' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Use the processor&apos;s projection of processing volume, available
            storage capacity, volume not to be marketed due to marketing
            allotment, and other appropriate factors affecting the
            processor&apos;s storage need to estimate the storage need
            requirement, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Compare capacity of proposed facility with storage need (estimated
            as specified in paragraphs (d)(2)(i)-(ii) of this section) to
            determine if additional storage is required.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For cold storage facilities for fruits and vegetables:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Multiply the average of the applicant&apos;s share of the acres
            farmed for the most recent three years for each eligible fruit and
            vegetable commodity requiring cold storage at the proposed facility;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             By a yield determined reasonable by the county committee;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Determine cold storage needed (calculated as specified in
            paragraphs (d)(3)(i)-(ii) of this section) with the assistance of
            NIFA, land-grant university, or ARS publications; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_3_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subtract existing cold storage capacity to determine remaining
            storage need.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_3_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Compare capacity of proposed cold storage facility with cold
            storage need (calculated as specified in paragraphs (d)(3)(i)-(iv)
            of this section) to determine if applicant is eligible for
            additional cold storage.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For all eligible facility loan commodities, except sugar, if
            acreage data is not available, including prevented planted acres, or
            data is not applicable to the storage need, a reasonable acreage
            projection may be made for newly acquired farms, changes in cropping
            operations, or in facility loan commodity crops being grown for the
            first time.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When a storage structure has a larger capacity than the
            applicant&apos;s needed capacity, as determined by CCC, the net cost
            eligible for a loan will be prorated. Only costs associated with the
            applicant&apos;s needed storage capacity will be considered eligible
            for loan under this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any borrower with an outstanding loan must use the financed
            structure only for the storage of eligible facility loan
            commodities. If a borrower uses such structure for other purposes
            such as office space or display area, the loan amount will be
            adjusted for the ineligible space as determined by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The FSA county committee may approve applications, if loan funds
            are available, up to the maximum approval amount unless the Deputy
            Administrator, Farm Programs, or the FSA State committee establishes
            a lower limit for county committee approval authority.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Farm storage facility loan approvals, for all eligible facility
            loan commodities except sugar, will expire 4 months after the date
            of approval unless extended in writing for an additional 4 months by
            the FSA State Committee. A second 4 month extension, for a total of
            12 months from the original approval date, may be approved by the
            FSA State Committee. This authority will not be re-delegated. Sugar
            storage facility loan approvals will expire 8 months after the date
            of approval unless extended in writing for an additional 4 months by
            the FSA State Committee.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For sugar storage facility loans, paragraphs (c) and (g) of this
            section do not apply.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For sugar storage facility loans, the agency approval officials may
            only approve loans, subject to available funds.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            74 FR 41590
          </aref>
          , Aug. 18, 2009, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 4805
          </aref>
          , Jan. 27, 2011]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12790'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1436:-:1436.10
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1436.10
      </num>
      <head>
        Down payment.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          66 FR 4612
        </aref>
        , Jan. 18, 2001, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          74 FR 41590
        </aref>
        , Aug.18, 2009]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1436' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
              1436.10
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Down payment.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A minimum down payment representing the difference between the net
            cost of the storage facility and the amount of the loan determined
            in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1436' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
                1436.9
              </subref>
            </aref>
             will be made by the loan applicant to the supplier or contractor
            before either the partial or final loan disbursements.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The down payment must be in cash unless some other form of payment
            is approved by CCC. The down payment may be obtained by the borrower
            from another lending source.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The down payment may not include any trade-in, discount, rebate,
            credit, deferred payment, post-dated check, or promissory note to
            the supplier or contractor.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            66 FR 4612
          </aref>
          , Jan. 18, 2001, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            74 FR 41590
          </aref>
          , Aug.18, 2009]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12791'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1436:-:1436.11
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1436.11
      </num>
      <head>
        Disbursements and assignments.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          74 FR 41591
        </aref>
        , Aug. 18, 2009]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='717' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1436' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
              1436.11
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Disbursements and assignments.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             At the request of the borrower, one partial disbursement of loan
            principal and one final loan disbursement will be available. The
            partial loan disbursement will be made to facilitate the purchase
            and construction of an eligible facility and will be made after the
            approved applicant has completed construction on part of the
            structure. County FSA personnel will inspect and verify the amount
            of construction completed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The amount of the partial loan disbursement will be determined by
            CCC and made after the borrower provides acceptable documentation
            for that portion of the completed construction to the County
            Committee.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Security required for the amount of the partial loan disbursement
            will be required before the partial loan disbursement is finalized.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The final disbursement of the loan by CCC will be made after the
            farm storage facility has been completely and fully delivered,
            erected, constructed, assembled, or installed and a CCC
            representative has inspected and approved such facility.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All additional security needed to fully secure both the partial and
            final loan disbursements must be received before the final loan
            disbursement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Both the partial and final loan disbursements will be made only if
            the borrower furnishes satisfactory evidence of the total cost of
            the facility and payment of all debts on the facility in excess of
            the amount of the loan. If deemed appropriate by CCC, the partial
            and final disbursement may have separate notes and separate security
            instruments.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Both the partial and final loan disbursement will be made jointly
            to the borrower and the contractor or supplier, except disbursement
            may be made to the borrower solely where CCC determines, based upon
            information made available to CCC by the borrower, that the borrower
            has paid the contractor or supplier all amounts that are due and
            owing with respect to the facility and that all applicable liens,
            security interests, or other encumbrances have been released.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A release of liability will be required from all contractors and
            suppliers providing goods and services to the loan applicant.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Loan proceeds cannot be assigned.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For sugar storage facility loans, only one disbursement will be
            made and such disbursement will be regarded as a final disbursement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            74 FR 41591
          </aref>
          , Aug. 18, 2009]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12792'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1436:-:1436.12
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1436.12
      </num>
      <head>
        Interest and fees.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          73 FR 41591
        </aref>
        , Aug. 18, 2009]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1436' sect='12' psec='' tq='N'>
              1436.12
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Interest and fees.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Loans will bear interest at the rate equivalent, as determined by
            CCC, to the rate of interest charged on Treasury securities of
            comparable term and maturity on the date the loan is initially
            approved.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The interest rate for each loan will remain in effect for the term
            of the loan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each borrower on a loan application must pay a non-refundable
            application fee in such amount determined appropriate by CCC; the
            fee will be not less than $100 per borrower. The loan application
            fee is determined based on the cost of the fees associated with the
            loan, including, but not limited to, the cost to CCC for lien
            searches, security filings, and credit reports.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For sugar storage facility loans, paragraph (c) of this section
            does not apply.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            73 FR 41591
          </aref>
          , Aug. 18, 2009]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12793'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1436:-:1436.13
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1436.13
      </num>
      <head>
        Loan installments, delinquency, and acceleration of maturity date.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          66 FR 4612
        </aref>
        , Jan. 18, 2001, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          74 FR 41591
        </aref>
        , Aug. 18, 2009]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1436' sect='13' psec='' tq='N'>
              1436.13
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Loan installments, delinquency, and acceleration of maturity date.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Equal installments of principal plus interest will be amortized
            over the loan term for purposes of setting a payment schedule.
            Installments are due and payable not later than the last day of each
            12-month period of each of the partial and final loan disbursements,
            until the principal plus interest has been paid in full.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each installment may be paid in cash, money order, wire transfer,
            or by personal, certified, or cashier&apos;s check. Each payment
            will be applied first to accrued interest and then to principal.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When installments are not paid on the due date:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC will generally mail a demand for payment to the debtor after
            the due date has passed.
            <PRTPAGE P='718' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the installment is not paid within 30 calendar days of the due
            date or if a new due date acceptable to CCC has not been established
            based on a financial plan submitted by the debtor, CCC may send two
            subsequent written demands at approximately 30 calendar day
            intervals unless CCC needs to take other action to protect the
            interests of CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the debtor files an appeal according to 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1436' sect='18' psec='' tq='N'>
                1436.18
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , CCC will generally cease collection action until the appeal
            process is complete, however, CCC may withhold any payments due the
            debtor and, depending on the outcome of the appeal, any payments due
            the debtor may later be offset and applied to reduce the
            indebtedness.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In lieu of a foreclosure on the collateral or the land securing a
            loan in the case of a delinquency, CCC may permit a rescheduling of
            the debt or other measures consistent with the collection of other
            debts under the provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1403' tq='N'>
                1403 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . Any rescheduling or alternate repayment arrangements will be
            permitted only with prior approval from the Deputy Administrator,
            Farm Programs. Alternately, CCC may implement such other collection
            procedures as it deems appropriate.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A claim will be established against a borrower for any amounts
            remaining due after liquidation of the loan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC may declare the entire indebtedness immediately due and payable
            if the borrower violates any of the terms and conditions of this
            part, fails to pay any installment on time, or breaches any of the
            terms and conditions of any of the instruments executed in
            connection with the loan, or if , during the life of the loan, the
            collateral is used in connection with or by any unauthorized
            commercial facility including, but not limited to, elevators,
            warehouses, dryers, processing plants, or retail or wholesale cold
            storage facilities.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any action authorized by the provisions of this section may be
            taken:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Against a debtor&apos;s pro rata share of payments due any entity
            that the borrower participates in, either directly or indirectly, as
            determined by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Against related persons or entities, irrespective of the
            debtor&apos;s, share, when CCC determines that the debtor has
            established an entity, or reorganized, transferred ownership of, or
            changed in some other manner, their operation, for the purpose of
            avoiding the payment of the debt.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The loan may be paid in full or in part without penalty at any time
            before maturity.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon payment of a loan, CCC will release CCC&apos;s security
            interest in the collateral.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            66 FR 4612
          </aref>
          , Jan. 18, 2001, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            74 FR 41591
          </aref>
          , Aug. 18, 2009]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12794'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1436:-:1436.14
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1436.14
      </num>
      <head>
        Taxes.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          66 FR 4612
        </aref>
        , Jan. 18, 2001, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          74 FR 41591
        </aref>
        , Aug. 18, 2009]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1436' sect='14' psec='' tq='N'>
              1436.14
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Taxes.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The borrower must pay, when due, all real and personal property taxes
          that may affect CCC&apos;s security interest in all collateral or land
          securing the note evidencing the loan. To protect its interests, CCC
          may pay any unpaid taxes with respect to the collateral or land
          securing a loan made in accordance with this part, and if CCC does so,
          the borrower will reimburse CCC for such payment, and if unpaid by the
          borrower, such debt will become due immediately.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            66 FR 4612
          </aref>
          , Jan. 18, 2001, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            74 FR 41591
          </aref>
          , Aug. 18, 2009]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12795'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1436:-:1436.15
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1436.15
      </num>
      <head>
        Maintenance, liability, insurance, and inspections.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          66 FR 4612
        </aref>
        , Jan. 18, 2001, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          67 FR 54939
        </aref>
        , Aug. 26, 2002; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          74 FR 41591
        </aref>
        , Aug. 18, 2009]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1436' sect='15' psec='' tq='N'>
              1436.15
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Maintenance, liability, insurance, and inspections.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The borrower must maintain the loan collateral in a condition
            suitable for the storage of one or more of the facility loan
            commodities. For purpose of this section the term “loan collateral”
            will mean any property of any kind that was built or improved, or
            acquired using a loan made under this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Until the loan has been repaid, the borrower will be liable for all
            damages to or destruction of the loan collateral. CCC will not
            assume any loss of the loan collateral.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC may conduct annual collateral inspections to insure compliance
            with this part. The borrower must consent to such inspection as a
            term of the loan and failure to supply such access will put the
            borrower into default.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Structures must be insured against all perils in all cases and must
            also be insured against flooding if the 
            <PRTPAGE P='719' />
            structure is located in a flood plain, as determined by CCC. Proof
            of flood insurance, if required, and proof of all peril structural
            insurance, must be provided to CCC annually. CCC must be listed as a
            loss payee on all peril and flood insurance policies.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC will have rights of ingress and egress where the facility is
            located. Failure of the borrower to secure such access will render a
            borrower ineligible for the loan and, if a loan has already been
            made will constitute a loan default for which the remaining balance
            of the loan willbecome immediately due and payable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For sugar storage facility loans, in addition to the requirements
            of paragraph (d) of this section, sugar processors must also insure
            the contents of storage structures used as collateral for a sugar
            storage facility loan against all perils.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            66 FR 4612
          </aref>
          , Jan. 18, 2001, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            67 FR 54939
          </aref>
          , Aug. 26, 2002; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            74 FR 41591
          </aref>
          , Aug. 18, 2009]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12796'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1436:-:1436.16
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1436.16
      </num>
      <head>
        Foreclosure, liquidation, assumptions, sales or conveyance, or
        bankruptcy.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          66 FR 4612
        </aref>
        , Jan. 18, 2001, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          74 FR 41591
        </aref>
        , Aug. 18, 2009]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1436' sect='16' psec='' tq='N'>
              1436.16
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Foreclosure, liquidation, assumptions, sales or conveyance, or
          bankruptcy.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The collateral or land securing a loan may be sold by CCC whenever
            CCC has declared the entire indebtedness immediately due and payable
            under this part as follows:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a demand for payment is not received by the due date acceptable
            to CCC, CCC may call the loan and initiate foreclosure proceedings
            by issuing a liquidation letter to the borrower.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The debtor may voluntarily agree to allow removal of the collateral
            to facilitate sale by signing an agreement for sale. If the debtor
            objects to removal of collateral, the law of the State where the
            collateral exists will be used to foreclose on the property.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For loans with movable collateral and no real estate lien, CCC may
            sell the collateral for the best price obtainable. Sales proceeds
            will be distributed in the following order:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To CCC to satisfy the debtor&apos;s indebtedness including all
            costs associated with selling the collateral.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payment to junior lien holders if approved by USDA&apos;s Office of
            the General Counsel and then to the borrower or other persons as
            determined appropriate by that office.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For loans with non-movable or non-salable collateral, as determined
            by CCC, and no real estate lien, CCC may establish a claim according
            to 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1403' tq='N'>
                1403
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For loans secured with a real estate lien, CCC may obtain an
            appraisal of the property. Sales proceeds will be distributed in the
            following order:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_5_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To CCC to satisfy the debtor&apos;s indebtedness including all
            costs associated with selling the collateral and the appraisal.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_5_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To junior lien holders if approved by USDA&apos;s Office of the
            General Counsel; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_5_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To the borrower or other persons as determined appropriate by that
            office.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Assumption by another borrower of a farm storage facility loan is
            permitted subject to county committee approval and the subsequent
            borrower&apos;s ability to show a satisfactory credit history. An
            assumption of the loan may be approved when the collateral is sold
            by CCC to an otherwise eligible borrower, the current borrower will
            convey the collateral or property securing the loan to another
            eligible borrower, or the borrower is dead, incompetent, or missing
            and an eligible borrower wants to assume the loan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Requests for approval of assumptions must be made to the county
            committee by the borrower, the borrower&apos;s successors, or
            representatives of the borrower. If approval is granted, the
            borrower&apos;s successors or representatives must execute a new
            farm storage facility note and security agreement for the balance of
            the term of the loan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The principal amount of the loan will include the unpaid amount of
            the loan, interest computed to the date of assumption, all past due
            installments, and any other charges that may be required.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The borrower may voluntarily convey the collateral to CCC before
            repaying the loan. Before a borrower sells or conveys the facilities
            or other property securing a loan without repaying the loan in full,
            the borrower must obtain approval for the sale or conveyance from
            the FSA county committee with the understanding that 
            <PRTPAGE P='720' />
            sale proceeds must be paid to satisfy the borrower&apos;s
            indebtedness to CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If any significant changes are made to the legal or operating
            status of the farming operation with an outstanding Farm Storage
            Facility Loan, the borrower must do one of the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Find an eligible borrower or entity to assume the loan as specified
            in paragraph (b) of this section,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Repay the loan, or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Undergo new financial analysis, as approved and determined by CCC,
            to ensure CCC&apos;s interests are protected and that the current
            borrower is in a position to continue making the scheduled loan
            payments.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Remedies provided for in this section will, unless CCC determines
            otherwise, be subject to the administrative appeals provided for
            elsewhere in this part, including those that are found at 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1436' sect='13' psec='' tq='N'>
                1436.13
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            66 FR 4612
          </aref>
          , Jan. 18, 2001, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            74 FR 41591
          </aref>
          , Aug. 18, 2009]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12797'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1436:-:1436.17
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1436.17
      </num>
      <head>
        Environmental compliance.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1436' sect='17' psec='' tq='N'>
              1436.17
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Environmental compliance.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as otherwise specified in this section, prior to approval of
            any farm storage facility loan, an environmental evaluation will be
            completed to determine if the proposed action will have any adverse
            impacts on the environment and cultural resources.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If it is determined that a proposed action or group of proposed
            actions will not result in any adverse impact, the action will be
            considered as being categorically excluded for the purpose of
            compliance with the National Environmental Policy Act (NEPA), 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              40 CFR parts 
              <subref title='40' part='1500-1508' tq='N'>
                1500-1508
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If adverse environmental impacts (either direct or indirect) are
            identified, an environmental assessment will be completed in
            accordance with the Council on Environmental Quality&apos;s
            Regulations for Implementing the Procedural Provisions of NEPA.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The environmental assessment will be used to develop an action that
            results in no significant environmental impact on the human
            environment or cultural resources.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No action will be approved that has been determined to have
            significant impacts on the human environment or cultural resources.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In order to minimize the exposure to environmental liabilities from
            the presence of contamination on real estate collateral, an
            evaluation will be made of the economic and environmental risks to
            the real estate collateral posed by the presence of hazardous
            substances and petroleum products.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the evaluation made under paragraph (d)(1) of this section
            reveals that the collateral is or may be contaminated, then the
            applicant will be notified and given an option of offering as
            collateral other real estate that is free from contamination or
            remediating the contamination on the original site offered as
            collateral.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12798'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1436:-:1436.18
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1436.18
      </num>
      <head>
        Appeals.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1436' sect='18' psec='' tq='N'>
              1436.18
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Appeals.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The appeal, reconsideration, or review of all determinations made
          under this part, except for provisions for which there are no appeal
          rights because they are determined rules of general applicability,
          must be in accordance with 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            parts 
            <subref title='7' part='11' tq='N'>
              11
            </subref>
             and 
            <subref title='7' part='780' tq='N'>
              780 of this title
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12799'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1436:-:1436.19
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1436.19
      </num>
      <head>
        Equal Opportunity and Non-discrimination requirements.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          67 FR 54939
        </aref>
        , Aug. 26, 2002. Redesignated at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          67 FR 65690
        </aref>
        , Oct. 28, 2002; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          74 FR 41592
        </aref>
        , Aug. 18, 2009]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1436' sect='19' psec='' tq='N'>
              1436.19
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Equal Opportunity and Non-discrimination requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No recipient of a Storage Facility loan will directly, or through
            contractual or other arrangement, subject any person or cause any
            person to be subjected to discrimination on the basis of race,
            religion, color, national origin, gender, or other prohibited basis.
            Borrowers must comply with all applicable Federal laws and
            regulations regarding equal opportunity in hiring, procurement, and
            related matters. FSFL borrowers are subject to the nondiscrimination
            provisions applicable to Federally assisted programs contained in 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR parts 
              <subref title='7' part='15' tq='N'>
                15
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='15b' tq='N'>
                15b
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             With respect to any aspect of a credit transaction, CCC will not
            discriminate against any applicant on the basis of race, color,
            religion, national origin, disability, sex, marital status, familial
            status, parental status, sexual orientation, genetic information,
            political beliefs, reprisal, or age, provided the applicant can
            execute a legal contract. FSFL is subject to the nondiscrimination
            provisions applicable to Federally conducted programs contained in 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR parts 
              <subref title='7' part='15d' tq='N'>
                15d
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='15e' tq='N'>
                15e
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . Nor 
            <PRTPAGE P='721' />
            will CCC discriminate on the basis of whether all or a part of the
            applicant&apos;s income derives from any public assistance program,
            or whether the applicant in good faith, exercises any rights under
            the Consumer Protection Act.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            67 FR 54939
          </aref>
          , Aug. 26, 2002. Redesignated at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            67 FR 65690
          </aref>
          , Oct. 28, 2002; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            74 FR 41592
          </aref>
          , Aug. 18, 2009]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>