<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol10'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1415
    </extid>
    <num>
      1415
    </num>
    <head>
      GRASSLANDS RESERVE PROGRAM
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='16' sect='3838n-383' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/3838n-383.html'>
              16 U.S.C. 3838n-383
            </subref>
          </aref>
          8q.
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 73925
          </aref>
          , Nov. 29, 2010, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='12385'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1415:-:1415.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1415.1
      </num>
      <head>
        Purpose.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1415' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              1415.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Purpose.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The purpose of the Grassland Reserve Program (GRP) is to assist
            landowners and operators in protecting grazing uses and related
            conservation values by conserving and restoring grassland resources
            on eligible private 
            <PRTPAGE P='525' />
            lands through rental contracts, easements, and restoration
            agreements.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             GRP emphasizes:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Supporting grazing operations;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Maintaining and improving plant and animal biodiversity; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Protecting grasslands and shrublands from the threat of conversion
            to uses other than grazing.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12386'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1415:-:1415.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1415.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Administration.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1415' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              1415.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Administration.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The regulations in this part set forth policies, procedures, and
            requirements for program implementation of GRP, as administered by
            the Natural Resources Conservation Service (NRCS) and the Farm
            Service Agency (FSA). The regulations in this part are administered
            under the general supervision and direction of the NRCS Chief and
            the FSA Administrator. These two agency leaders:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Concur in the establishment of program policy and direction,
            development of the national allocation formula, and development of
            broad national ranking criteria;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Use a national allocation formula to provide GRP funds to NRCS
            State Conservationists and FSA State Executive Directors that
            emphasizes support for grazing operations, biodiversity of plants
            and animals, and grasslands under the greatest threat of conversion
            to uses other than grazing. The national allocation formula may also
            include additional factors related to improving program
            implementation, as determined by the NRCS Chief and the FSA
            Administrator. The allocation formula may be modified periodically
            to change the emphasis of any factor(s) in order to address a
            particular natural resource concern, such as the precipitous decline
            of a population of a grassland-dependent bird(s) or animal(s);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Ensure the national, State, and local-level information regarding
            program implementation is made available to the public;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Consult with USDA leaders at the State level and other Federal
            agencies with the appropriate expertise and information when
            evaluating program policies and direction; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Authorize NRCS State Conservationists and FSA State Executive
            Directors to determine how funds will be used and how the program
            will be implemented at the State level.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             At the State level, the NRCS State Conservationist and the FSA
            State Executive Director are jointly responsible for:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Determining how funds will be used and how the program will be
            implemented at the State level to achieve the program purposes;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Identifying State priorities for project selection based on input
            from the State Technical Committee;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Identifying Department of Agriculture (USDA) employees at the field
            level responsible for implementing the program by considering the
            nature and extent of natural resource concerns throughout the State
            and the availability of human resources to assist with activities
            related to program enrollment;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Developing, with advice from the State Technical Committee, program
            outreach materials at the State and local levels to help ensure
            landowners, operators, and tenants of eligible land are aware and
            informed that they may be eligible for the program;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Approving conservation practices eligible for cost-share and
            cost-share rates;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Developing GRP management plans and restoration agreements, when
            applicable;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Administering and enforcing the terms of easements and rental
            contracts unless this responsibility is transferred to an eligible
            entity as provided in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1415' sect='17' psec='' tq='N'>
                1415.17
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1415' sect='18' psec='' tq='N'>
                1415.18
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Developing, with advice from the State Technical Committee,
            criteria for ranking eligible land consistent with national criteria
            and program objectives and State priorities.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The funds, facilities, and authorities of the Commodity Credit
            Corporation (CCC) are available to NRCS and FSA to implement GRP.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subject to funding availability, the program may be implemented in
            any of the 50 States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of
            Puerto Rico, Guam, the Virgin Islands of the United States, American
            Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The NRCS Chief or the FSA Administrator may modify or waive a 
            <PRTPAGE P='526' />
            provision of this part if he or she deems the application of that
            provision to a particular limited situation to be inappropriate and
            inconsistent with the conservation purposes and sound administration
            of GRP. This authority cannot be further delegated. No provision of
            this part, which is required by law, may be waived.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No delegation in this part to lower organizational levels will
            preclude the NRCS Chief or the FSA Administrator from determining
            any issue arising under this part or from reversing or modifying any
            determination arising from this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The USDA Forest Service may hold GRP easements on properties
            adjacent to USDA Forest Service land, with the consent of the
            landowner.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Program participation is voluntary.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Applications for participation will be accepted on a continual
            basis at local USDA Service Centers. Eligible entities wishing to
            enter into a cooperative agreement under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1415' sect='17' psec='' tq='N'>
                1415.17
              </subref>
            </aref>
             in order to purchase, own, write, and hold easements may apply on a
            continuous basis to the NRCS State Conservationist. The NRCS State
            Conservationist and FSA State Executive Director will establish
            cut-off periods to rank and select applications for participation.
            These cut-off periods will be available in program outreach material
            provided by the local USDA Service Center. Once funding levels have
            been exhausted, unfunded eligible applications will remain on file
            until they are funded or the applicant chooses to be removed from
            consideration.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The services of third parties as provided for in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='652' tq='N'>
                652 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
             may be used to provide technical services to participants.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12387'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1415:-:1415.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1415.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1415' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              1415.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Activity
          </E>
           means an action other than a conservation practice that is included
          as a part of a GRP management or conservation plan that has the effect
          of alleviating problems or improving treatment of the resources,
          including ensuring proper management or maintenance of the functions
          and values restored, protected, or enhanced through an easement or
          rental contract.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Administrator
          </E>
           means the Administrator of FSA or the person delegated authority to
          act for the Administrator.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Applicant
          </E>
           means a person, legal entity, joint operator, or Indian Tribe who
          applies to participate in the program.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Chief
          </E>
           means the Chief of NRCS or designee.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Biological diversity
          </E>
           means the variety and variability among living organisms and the
          ecological complexes in which they live.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Commodity Credit Corporation
          </E>
           is a government-owned and operated entity that was created to
          stabilize, support, and protect farm income and prices. The CCC is
          managed by a Board of Directors, subject to the general supervision
          and direction of the Secretary of Agriculture, who is an ex-officio
          director and chairperson of the Board. The CCC provides the funding
          for GRP, and FSA and NRCS administer GRP on its behalf.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Common grazing practices
          </E>
           means those grazing practices, including those related to forage and
          seed production, common to the area of the subject ranching or farming
          operation. Included are routine management activities necessary to
          maintain the viability of forage or browse resources that are common
          to the locale of the subject ranching or farming operation.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Conservation district
          </E>
           means any district or unit of State, Tribal, or local government
          formed under State, Tribal, or territorial law for the express purpose
          of developing and carrying out a local soil and water conservation
          program. Such district or unit of government may be referred to as a
          conservation district, soil conservation district, soil and water
          conservation district, resource conservation district, natural
          resource district, land conservation committee, or similar name.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Conservation plan
          </E>
           means a record of the GRP participants&apos; decisions and supporting
          information that will be developed to address resource concerns in
          addition to grazing land uses. The conservation plan will describe the
          implementation and maintenance of GRP management and conservation
          practices directly related to any additional land eligibility criteria
          under which the land is enrolled. Additional land eligibility criteria
          may include, but is 
          <PRTPAGE P='527' />
          not limited to, significant animal or plant habitat and historical or
          archeological resources.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Conservation practice
          </E>
           means a specified treatment, such as a vegetative, structural, or
          land management practice, that is planned and applied according to
          NRCS Field Office Technical Guide (FOTG) standards and specifications.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Conservation values
          </E>
           means those natural resource attributes that sustain and enhance
          ecosystem functions and values of the grassland area including, but
          not limited to, habitat for grassland and shrubland dependent plants
          and animals, native plant and animal biodiversity, soil erosion
          control, forage production, and air and water quality protection.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Cost-share payment
          </E>
           means the payment made by USDA to a program participant or vendor to
          achieve the restoration, enhancement, and protection goals in
          accordance with the GRP restoration plan component of the restoration
          agreement.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Dedicated account
          </E>
           means a dedicated fund of the eligible entity held in a separate
          account for the management, monitoring, and enforcement of
          conservation easements and that cannot be used for other purposes.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Easement
          </E>
           means a conservation easement, which is an interest in land defined
          and delineated in a deed whereby the landowner conveys certain rights,
          title, and interests in a property to the United States, an eligible
          entity, or both for the purpose of protecting the grassland and other
          conservation values of the property. Under GRP, the property rights
          are conveyed by a conservation easement deed.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Easement area
          </E>
           means the land encumbered by an easement.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Easement payment
          </E>
           means the consideration paid to a landowner for an easement conveyed
          to the United States, an eligible entity, or both under GRP.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Eligible entity
          </E>
           means, for the purposes of entering into a cooperative agreement
          under 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='16' sect='3838q' note='' psec='#d' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/3838q.html#d'>
              16 U.S.C. 3838q(d)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , an agency of State or local government, an Indian Tribe, or a
          nongovernmental organization that has the relevant experience
          necessary, as appropriate for the application, to administer an
          easement on grassland, land that contains forbs, or shrubland; has a
          charter that describes a commitment to conserving ranchland,
          agricultural land, or grassland for grazing and conservation purposes;
          and has the resources necessary to effectuate the purposes of the
          charter.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Enhancement
          </E>
           means to increase or improve the viability of grassland and grazing
          resources, including habitat for declining species of grassland
          dependent birds and animals.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Farm Service Agency
          </E>
           is an agency of the Department of Agriculture.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            FSA State Executive Director
          </E>
           means the FSA employee authorized to implement GRP and direct and
          supervise FSA activities in a State, Caribbean Area, or the Pacific
          Islands Area.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Field Office Technical Guide
          </E>
           means the official local NRCS source of resource information and
          interpretations of guidelines, criteria, and requirements for planning
          and applying conservation practices and conservation management
          systems. It contains detailed information on the conservation of soil,
          water, air, plant, and animal resources applicable to the local area
          for which it is prepared.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Fire pre-suppression
          </E>
           means activities as outlined in a GRP management plan such as the
          establishment and maintenance of firebreaks and prescribed burning to
          prevent or limit the spread of fires.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Forb
          </E>
           means any herbaceous plant other than those in the grass family.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Functions and values of grasslands and shrublands
          </E>
           means ecosystem services provided, including domestic animal
          productivity, biological productivity, plant and animal richness and
          diversity, fish and wildlife habitat (including habitat for
          pollinators and native insects), water quality and quantity benefits,
          aesthetics, open space, and recreation.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Grantor
          </E>
           means the landowner who is transferring land rights to the United
          States or an eligible entity, or both through an easement.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Grassland
          </E>
           means land on which the vegetation is dominated by grasses,
          grass-like plants, shrubs, or forbs, including shrubland, land that
          contains forbs, pastureland, and rangeland, and improved pastureland
          and rangeland.
          <PRTPAGE P='528' />
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            GRP management plan
          </E>
           means the document developed by NRCS that describes the
          implementation of the grazing management system consistent with the
          prescribed grazing standard contained in the FOTG. The GRP management
          plan will include a description of the grazing management system,
          permissible and prohibited activities, any associated restoration plan
          or conservation plan, if applicable, and a description of USDA&apos;s
          right of ingress and egress.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Grazing value
          </E>
           means the financial worth of the land as used for grazing or forage
          production. The term is used in the calculation of compensation for
          rental contracts and easements. For easements, this value is
          determined by NRCS through an appraisal process or a market survey
          process. For rental contracts, FSA determines the grazing value based
          upon an administrative process.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Historical and archeological resources
          </E>
           mean resources that are:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Listed in the National Register of Historic Places (established
            under the National Historic Preservation Act (NHPA), 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='16' sect='470' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/470.html'>
                16 U.S.C. 470
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , 
            <E T='03'>
              et seq.
            </E>
            );
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Formally determined eligible for listing the National Register of
            Historic Places by the State Historic Preservation Officer (SHPO) or
            Tribal Historic Preservation Officer (THPO) and Keeper of the
            National Register in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 106
            </aref>
             or the NHPA);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Formally listed in the State or Tribal Register of Historic Places
            of the SHPO (designated under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 101(b)(1)(B) of
            </aref>
             the NHPA) or the Tribal Register of Historic Places (designated
            under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 101(d)(1)(C) of
            </aref>
             the NHPA); or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Included in the SPHO or THPO inventory with written justification
            as to why it meets National Register of Historic Places criteria.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Improved rangeland or pastureland
          </E>
           means grazing land permanently producing naturalized forage species
          that receives varying degrees of periodic cultural treatment to
          enhance forage quality and yields and is primarily harvested by
          grazing animals.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Indian Tribe
          </E>
           means any Indian Tribe, band, nation, or other organized group or
          community, including any Alaska Native village or regional or village
          corporation as defined in or established pursuant to the Alaska Native
          Claims Settlement Act (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='43' sect='1601' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/43/1601.html'>
              43 U.S.C. 1601
            </subref>
          </aref>
          <E T='03'>
            et seq.
          </E>
          ) that is eligible for the special programs and services provided by
          the United States to Indians because of their status as Indians.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Landowner
          </E>
           means a person, legal entity, or Indian Tribe having legal ownership
          of land and those who may be buying eligible land under a purchase
          agreement. The term landowner may include all forms of collective
          ownership including joint tenants, tenants-in-common, and life
          tenants. The term landowner includes Indian Tribes. State governments,
          local governments, and nongovernmental organizations that qualify as
          eligible entities are not eligible as landowners.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Legal entity
          </E>
           means an entity created under Federal or State law and that: (1) Owns
          land or an agricultural commodity, product, or livestock; or (2)
          produces an agricultural commodity, product, or livestock.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Maintenance
          </E>
           means work performed to keep the applied conservation practice
          functioning for the intended purpose during its life span. Maintenance
          includes work to manage and prevent deterioration, repair damage, or
          replace the practice to its original condition if one or more
          components fail.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Native
          </E>
           means a species that is indigenous and is a part of the original
          fauna or flora of the area.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Natural Resources Conservation Service
          </E>
           is an agency of the Department of Agriculture.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            NRCS State Conservationist
          </E>
           means the NRCS employee authorized to implement GRP and direct and
          supervise NRCS activities in a State, Caribbean Area, or the Pacific
          Islands Area.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Naturalized
          </E>
           means an introduced, desirable forage species that is ecologically
          adapted to the site and can perpetuate itself in the community without
          cultural treatment. The term naturalized does not include noxious
          weeds.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Nesting season
          </E>
           means the time of year that grassland dependent birds in significant
          decline in the local area build nests or otherwise find a place of
          refuge for purposes of reproduction.
          <PRTPAGE P='529' />
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Nongovernmental organization
          </E>
           means any organization that:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is organized for, and at all times since, the formation of the
            organization, and has been operated principally for one or more of
            the conservation purposes specified in clause (i), (ii), (iii), or
            (iv) of 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 170(h)(4)(A) of
            </aref>
             the Internal Revenue Code of 1986;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is an organization described in 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 501(c)(3) of
            </aref>
             that Code that is exempt from taxation under 501(a) of that Code;
            and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is described—
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 509(a)(1) or 509(a)(2) of
            </aref>
             that Code, or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is described in 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 509(a)(3) of
            </aref>
             that Code and is controlled by an organization described in 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 509(a)(2) of
            </aref>
             that Code.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Participant
          </E>
           means a person, legal entity, joint operation, or Indian Tribe who is
          accepted to participate in GRP through a rental contract or option
          agreement to purchase an easement.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Pastureland
          </E>
           means grazing lands comprised of introduced or domesticated native
          forage species that are used primarily for the production of
          livestock. These lands receive periodic renovation and cultural
          treatments, such as tillage, aeration, fertilization, mowing, and weed
          control, and may be irrigated. This term does not include lands that
          are in rotation with crops.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Permanent easement
          </E>
           means an easement that lasts in perpetuity or for the maximum
          duration allowed under the law of a State.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Private land
          </E>
           means land that is not owned by a governmental entity and includes
          Tribal lands.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Purchase price
          </E>
           means the amount paid to acquire an easement under a cooperative
          agreement between NRCS and an eligible entity. It is the fair market
          value of the easement.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Rangeland
          </E>
           means a land cover or use category with a climax or potential plant
          cover composed principally of native grasses, grass-like plants,
          forbs, or shrubs suitable for grazing and browsing, and introduced
          forage species that are managed like rangeland. Rangeland includes
          lands re-vegetated naturally or artificially when routine management
          of that vegetation is accomplished mainly through manipulation of
          grazing. This term includes areas where introduced hardy and
          persistent grasses are planted and such practices as deferred grazing,
          burning, chaining, and rotational grazing are used with little or no
          chemicals or fertilizer being applied. Grasslands, savannas, many
          wetlands, some deserts, and tundra are considered to be rangeland.
          Certain communities of low forbs and shrubs, such as mesquite,
          chaparral, mountain shrub, and pinyon juniper are also included as
          rangeland.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Rental contract
          </E>
           means the legal document that specifies the obligations and rights of
          a participant in GRP, including the annual rental payments to be
          provided to the participant for the length of the contract to maintain
          or restore grassland functions and values under GRP.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Restoration
          </E>
           means implementing any conservation practice, system of practices, or
          activities to restore functions and values of grasslands and
          shrublands. The restoration may re-establish grassland functions and
          values on degraded land, or on land that has been converted to another
          use.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Restoration agreement
          </E>
           means an agreement between the program participant and NRCS or
          eligible entity to carry out activities and conservation practices
          necessary to restore or improve the functions and values of that land.
          A restoration agreement will include a restoration plan.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Restoration plan
          </E>
           is the portion of the restoration agreement that includes the
          schedule and conservation practices and activities to restore the
          functions and values of grasslands and shrublands, including
          protection of associated streams, ponds, and wetlands. The restoration
          plan incorporates the requirement that program participants will
          maintain GRP-funded conservation practices and activities for their
          expected lifespan as described in the plan.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Right of enforcement
          </E>
           means a property interest in the easement the Chief may exercise on
          behalf of the United States under specific circumstances in order to
          enforce the terms of the conservation easement. The right of
          enforcement provides that the Chief has the right to inspect and
          enforce the easement if the eligible entity fails to uphold the
          easement or attempts to 
          <PRTPAGE P='530' />
          transfer the easement without first securing the consent of the
          Secretary.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Secretary
          </E>
           means the Secretary of the Department of Agriculture.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Shrubland
          </E>
           means land where the dominant plant species is shrubs, which are
          plants that are persistent, have woody stems, and a relatively low
          growth habit.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Significant decline
          </E>
           means a decrease of a species population to such an extent that it
          merits conservation priority as determined by the State
          Conservationist, in consultation with the State Technical Committee.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State Technical Committee
          </E>
           means a committee established by the Secretary in a State pursuant to
          
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='16' sect='3861' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/3861.html'>
              16 U.S.C. 3861
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Tribal land
          </E>
           means:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land held in trust by the United States for individual Indians or
            Indian Tribes; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land, the title to which is held by individual Indians or Indian
            Tribes subject to Federal restrictions against alienation or
            encumbrance; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land which is subject to rights of use, occupancy, and benefit of
            certain Indian Tribes; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land held in fee title by an Indian, Indian family, or Indian
            Tribe.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            USDA
          </E>
           means the Department of Agriculture and its agencies and offices, as
          applicable.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12388'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1415:-:1415.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1415.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Program requirements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1415' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              1415.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Program requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as provided for under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1415' sect='17' psec='' tq='N'>
                1415.17
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , only landowners may submit applications for easements. For rental
            contracts, applicants must own or provide written evidence of
            control of the property for the duration of the rental contract.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The easement or rental contract will require that the area be
            maintained in accordance with GRP goals and objectives for the term
            of the easement or rental contract, including the conservation,
            protection, enhancement, and if necessary, restoration of the
            grassland functions and values.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All participants in GRP are required to implement a GRP management
            plan approved by NRCS. When an eligible entity holds the GRP
            easement, NRCS will develop GRP management plans with eligible
            entities. In cases where a participant receives ranking points on
            the basis of resource concerns other than grazing land concerns, all
            such resource concerns will be addressed in an applicable
            conservation plan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The easement or rental contract must grant USDA or its
            representatives a right of ingress and egress to the easement or
            rental contract area. For easements, this access is legally
            described by the conservation easement deed and the GRP management
            plan. Access to rental contract areas is identified in the GRP
            management plan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Easement participants are required to convey unencumbered title
            that is acceptable to the United States and provide consent or
            subordination agreements from each holder of a security or other
            interest in the land. The landowner must warrant that the easement
            granted the United States or eligible entity is superior to the
            rights of all others, except for exceptions to the title that are
            deemed acceptable by USDA.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Landowners are required to use a standard GRP conservation easement
            deed developed by USDA or developed by an eligible entity and
            approved by USDA under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1415' sect='17' psec='' tq='N'>
                1415.17
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
            . The easement grants development rights, title, and interest in the
            easement area in order to protect grassland and other conservation
            values.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The program participant must comply with the terms of the easement
            or rental contract, and comply with all terms and conditions of the
            GRP management plan and any associated conservation plan or
            restoration agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Easements and rental contracts allow, consistent with their terms
            and the program purposes, the following activities as outlined in
            the GRP management plan:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Common grazing practices, including maintenance and necessary
            conservation practices and activities (
            <E T='03'>
              e.g.,
            </E>
             prescribed grazing; upland wildlife habitat management; prescribed
            burning; fencing, watering, and feeding necessary for the raising of
            livestock; and related forage and seed production) on the land in a
            manner that is consistent with maintaining the viability 
            <PRTPAGE P='531' />
            of grassland, forb, and shrub species common to the locality;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Haying, mowing, or harvesting for seed production subject to
            appropriate restrictions, as determined by the State
            Conservationist, during the nesting season for birds in the local
            area that are in significant decline, or are conserved in accordance
            with Federal or State law;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Fire pre-suppression, rehabilitation, and construction of
            firebreaks;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Grazing related activities, such as fencing and livestock watering
            facilities;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Facilities for power generation through renewable sources of energy
            production provided the scope and scale of the footprint of the
            facility and associated infrastructure is consistent with program
            purposes as determined by USDA through analysis of the potential
            site-specific environmental effects; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Other activities that USDA determines the manner, number,
            intensity, location, operation, and other features associated with
            the activity will not adversely affect the grassland resources or
            related conservation values protected under an easement or rental
            contract. This includes infrastructure development along existing
            right-of-ways where the easement deed allows the landowner to grant
            right-of-ways when it is determined by NRCS that granting such
            right-of-ways are in the public interest, that grassland resources
            and related conservation values will not be adversely impacted, and
            the landowner agrees to a restoration plan for the disturbed area as
            developed by NRCS, but at no cost to NRCS. This also includes
            undeveloped, passive, recreational uses such as hiking, camping,
            bird watching, hunting, and fishing as long as such uses, as
            determined by the grantee, do not impair the grazing uses and other
            conservation values.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Easement and rental contracts prohibit the following activities:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The production of crops (other than hay), orchards, vineyards, or
            other agricultural commodity that is inconsistent with maintaining
            grazing land and related conservation values; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as permitted under a restoration plan, the conduct of any
            other activity that would be inconsistent with maintaining grazing
            uses and related conservation values protected under an easement or
            rental contract.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Rental contracts may be terminated by USDA without penalty or
            refund if the original participant dies, is declared legally
            incompetent, or is otherwise unavailable during the contract period.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Participants, with the agreement of USDA, may convert a rental
            contract to an easement, provided that funds are available and the
            project meets conditions established by USDA. Land cannot be
            enrolled in both a rental contract option and an easement enrollment
            option at the same time. The rental contract will be terminated
            prior to the date the easement is recorded in the local land records
            office.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='l'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (l)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Rental contract participants are required to suspend any existing
            cropland base and allotment history for the land under another
            program administered by the Secretary.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='m'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (m)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Easement participants are required to eliminate any existing
            cropland base and allotment history for the land under another
            program administered by the Secretary.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12389'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1415:-:1415.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1415.5
      </num>
      <head>
        Land eligibility.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1415' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              1415.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Land eligibility.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             GRP is available on privately owned lands, which include private
            and Tribal land. Publicly owned land is not eligible.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land is eligible for funding consideration if the State
            Conservationist determines that the land is:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Grassland, land that contains forbs or shrubland (including
            improved rangeland and pastureland) for which grazing is the
            predominant use; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Located in an area that has been historically dominated by
            grassland, forbs, or shrubland, and the State Conservationist, with
            advice from the State Technical Committee, determines that it is
            compatible with grazing uses and related conservation values, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Could provide habitat for animal or plant populations of
            significant ecological value if the land is retained in its current
            use or is restored to a natural condition,
            <PRTPAGE P='532' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Contains historical or archeological resources, or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Would address issues raised by State, regional, and national
            conservation priorities.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Incidental lands, in conjunction with eligible land, may also be
            considered for enrollment to allow for the efficient administration
            of an easement or rental contract. Incidental lands may include
            relatively small areas that do not specifically meet the eligibility
            requirements, but as a part of the land unit, may contribute to
            grassland functions and values and related conservation values, or
            its inclusion may increase efficiencies in land surveying, easement
            management, and monitoring by reducing irregular boundaries.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land will not be enrolled if the functions and values of the
            grassland are already protected under an existing contract,
            easement, or deed restriction, or if the land already is in
            ownership by an entity whose purpose is to protect and conserve
            grassland and related conservation values. This land becomes
            eligible for enrollment in GRP if the existing contract, easement,
            or deed restriction expires or is terminated, and the grassland
            values and functions are no longer protected.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land on which gas, oil, earth, or other mineral rights exploration
            has been leased or is owned by someone other than the applicant may
            be offered for participation in the program. However, if an
            applicant submits an offer for an easement project, USDA will assess
            the potential impact that the third party rights may have upon the
            grassland resources. USDA reserves the right to deny funding for any
            application where there are exceptions to clear title on the
            property.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12390'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1415:-:1415.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1415.6
      </num>
      <head>
        Participant eligibility.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1415' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              1415.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Participant eligibility.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          To be eligible to participate in GRP, an applicant, except as
          otherwise described in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1415' sect='17' psec='' tq='N'>
              1415.17
            </subref>
          </aref>
          :
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Must be a landowner for easement participation or be a landowner or
            have control of the eligible acreage being offered for rental
            contract participation;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Agree to provide such information to USDA that is necessary or
            desirable to assist in its determination of eligibility for program
            benefits and for other program implementation purposes;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Meet the Adjusted Gross Income requirements in 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
                1400 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , unless exempted under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
                1400 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Meet the conservation compliance requirements found in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='12' tq='N'>
                12 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Comply with applicable registration and reporting requirements of
            the Federal Funding Accountability and Transparency Act of 2006 (
            <aref target='_blank' title='Pub. L. 109-282' alt='Pub. L. 109-282' href='http://www.gpo.gov/fdsys/pkg/PLAW-109publ282/html/PLAW-109publ282.htm'>
              Pub. L. 109-282
            </aref>
            , as amended) and 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              3 CFR parts 
              <subref title='3' part='25' tq='N'>
                25
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='3' part='170' tq='N'>
                170
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12391'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1415:-:1415.7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1415.7
      </num>
      <head>
        Application procedures.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1415' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              1415.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Application procedures.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Applicants, except as otherwise described under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1415' sect='17' psec='' tq='N'>
                1415.17
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , may submit an application through a USDA Service Center for
            participation in GRP. Applications may be submitted throughout the
            year.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             By filing an application for participation, the applicant consents
            to a USDA representative entering upon the land offered for
            enrollment for purposes of assessing the grassland functions and
            values and for other activities that are necessary for USDA to make
            an offer of enrollment. Generally, the applicant will be notified
            prior to a USDA representative entering upon their property.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Applicants submit applications that identify the duration of the
            easement or rental contract for which they seek to enroll their
            land. Rental contracts may be for the duration of 10-years,
            15-years, or 20-years; easements may be permanent in duration or for
            the maximum duration authorized by State law.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12392'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1415:-:1415.8
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1415.8
      </num>
      <head>
        Establishing priority for enrollment of properties.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1415' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              1415.8
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Establishing priority for enrollment of properties.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             USDA, at the national level, will provide to NRCS State
            Conservationists and FSA State Executive Directors, national
            guidelines for establishing State-specific ranking criteria for
            selection of applications for funding.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS State Conservationists and FSA State Executive Directors, with
            advice from State Technical Committees, establish criteria to
            evaluate and rank applications for easement and rental contract
            enrollment, including 
            <PRTPAGE P='533' />
            applications from eligible entities under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1415' sect='17' psec='' tq='N'>
                1415.17
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , following the guidance established in paragraph (a) of this
            section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Ranking criteria will emphasize support for:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Grazing operations;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Protection of grassland, land that contains forbs, and shrubland at
            the greatest risk from the threat of conversion to uses other than
            grazing;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Plant and animal biodiversity; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In ranking parcels offered by eligible entities, these additional
            criteria will also be considered—
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_4_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Leveraging of non-Federal funds, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_4_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Entity contributions in excess of 50 percent of the purchase price,
            as defined in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1415' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
                1415.3
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When funding is available, NRCS State Conservationists and FSA
            State Executive Directors will periodically select for funding the
            highest ranked applications, including applications from entities
            under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1415' sect='17' psec='' tq='N'>
                1415.17
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , based on applicant and land eligibility and the State-developed
            ranking criteria.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS State Conservationists and FSA State Executive Directors may
            establish separate ranking pools to address, for example, specific
            conservation issues raised by State, regional, and national
            conservation priorities.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The NRCS State Conservationist and FSA State Executive Director,
            with advice from the State Technical Committee, may emphasize
            enrollment of unique grasslands or specific geographic areas of the
            State.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The NRCS State Conservationist and the FSA State Executive
            Director, with advice from the State Technical Committee, will
            select applications for funding.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If available funds are insufficient to accept the highest ranked
            application, and the applicant is not interested in reducing the
            acres offered to match available funding, the State Conservationist
            or State Executive Director may select a lower ranked application
            that can be fully funded.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land enrolled in a Conservation Reserve Program (CRP) contract that
            is within one year of the scheduled expiration date will receive a
            priority for enrollment. To receive this priority, the following
            criteria must be met:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The land must be eligible as defined in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1415' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
                1415.5
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             USDA, with advice from the State Technical Committee, must
            determine it is of high ecological value and under significant
            threat of conversion to uses other than grazing;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The land must be offered for easement or 20-year rental contract
            enrollment;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Expired CRP land enrolled under this priority will not exceed 10
            percent of the total number of acres accepted for national
            enrollment in GRP in any year; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This priority applies only up to 12 months before the scheduled
            expiration of the CRP contract.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             USDA will manage the program nationally to ensure that, to the
            extent practicable, 60 percent of funds are used for the purchase of
            easements, either directly or through cooperative agreements with
            eligible entities as set forth in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1415' sect='17' psec='' tq='N'>
                1415.17
              </subref>
               and 40
            </aref>
             percent of funds are used for rental contracts.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12393'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1415:-:1415.9
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1415.9
      </num>
      <head>
        Enrollment of easements and rental contracts.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1415' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
              1415.9
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Enrollment of easements and rental contracts.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Based on the priority ranking, NRCS or FSA, as appropriate, will
            notify applicants in writing of their tentative acceptance into the
            program for either rental contract or conservation easement options.
            The letter notifies the applicant of the intent to continue the
            enrollment process unless otherwise notified by the applicant.
            Enrollment under cooperative agreements is described under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1415' sect='17' psec='' tq='N'>
                1415.17
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An offer of tentative acceptance into the program neither binds
            USDA to acquire an easement or enter into a rental contract, nor
            binds the applicant to convey an easement, enter into a rental
            contract, or agree to restoration activities.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Offer of enrollment will be through either:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An agreement to purchase an easement presented by NRCS to the
            applicant which will describe the easement, the easement terms and
            conditions, and other terms and conditions that may be required by
            NRCS; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A rental contract will be presented by FSA to the applicant which 
            <PRTPAGE P='534' />
            will describe the contract area, the contract terms and conditions,
            and other terms and conditions that may be required by FSA.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For rental contracts, land will be considered to be enrolled in GRP
            once an FSA representative approves the GRP rental contract. FSA may
            withdraw the offer before approval of the contract due to lack of
            available funds or other reasons.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For easements, after the option agreement to purchase an easement
            is executed by NRCS and the participant, the land will be considered
            enrolled in GRP. NRCS will proceed with the development of the GRP
            management plan, conservation or restoration plan if applicable, and
            various easement acquisition activities, which may include
            conducting a legal survey of the easement area, securing necessary
            subordination agreements, procuring title insurance, and conducting
            other activities necessary to record the easement or implement GRP.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Prior to closing an easement, NRCS may withdraw the land from
            enrollment at any time due to lack of available funds, title
            concerns, or other reasons.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12394'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1415:-:1415.10
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1415.10
      </num>
      <head>
        Compensation for easements and rental contracts acquired by the
        Secretary.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1415' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
              1415.10
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Compensation for easements and rental contracts acquired by the
          Secretary.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Chief will not pay more than the fair market value of the land,
            less the grazing value of the land encumbered by the easement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To determine this amount, the Chief will pay as compensation the
            lowest of:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The fair market value of the land encumbered by the easement as
            determined by the Chief using—
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Uniform Standards of Professional Appraisal Practice, or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An area-wide market analysis or market survey;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The amount corresponding to a geographical cap, as determined by
            the State Conservationist, with advice from the State Technical
            Committee; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An offer made by the landowner.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For 10-, 15-, and 20-year rental contracts, the participant will
            receive not more than 75 percent of the grazing value in an annual
            payment for the length of the contract, as determined by FSA. As
            provided by the regulations at 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
                1400 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , payments made under one or more rental contracts to a person or
            legal entity, directly or indirectly, may not exceed, in the
            aggregate, $50,000 per year.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In order to provide for better uniformity among States, the NRCS
            Chief and FSA Administrator may review and adjust, as appropriate,
            State or other geographically based payment rates for rental
            contracts.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Easement or rental contract payments received by a participant will
            be in addition to, and not affect, the total amount of payments that
            the participant is otherwise eligible to receive under other USDA
            programs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Easement payments will be made in a single payment to the landowner
            unless otherwise requested by the landowner.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             USDA may accept and use contributions of non-Federal funds to
            support the purposes of the program. These funds are available to
            USDA without further appropriation and until expended, to carry out
            the program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             USDA recognizes that environmental benefits will be achieved by
            implementing conservation practices and activities funded through
            GRP, and that ecosystem credits may be gained as a result of
            implementing activities compatible with the purposes of a GRP
            easement, rental contract, or associated restoration agreement. USDA
            asserts no direct or indirect interest in these credits except:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the event the participant sells or trades credits arising from
            GRP funded activities, USDA retains the authority to ensure that the
            requirements for GRP rental contracts, easements, or restoration
            agreements are met and maintained consistent with this part; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If activities required under an ecosystem credit agreement may
            affect land covered under a GRP rental contract, easement, or
            restoration agreement, participants are required to obtain an
            assessment from USDA about the compatibility of the activity prior
            to entering into such agreements.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12395'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1415:-:1415.11
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1415.11
      </num>
      <head>
        Restoration agreements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='535' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1415' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
              1415.11
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Restoration agreements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Restoration agreements are only authorized to be used in
            conjunction with easements and rental contracts. NRCS, in
            consultation with the program participant, determines if the
            grassland resources are adequate to meet the participant&apos;s
            objectives and the purposes of the program, or if a restoration
            agreement is needed. Such a determination is also subject to the
            availability of funding. USDA may condition participation in the
            program upon the execution of a restoration agreement depending on
            the condition of the grassland resources. When the functions and
            values of the grassland are determined adequate by NRCS, a
            restoration agreement is not required. However, if a restoration
            agreement is required, NRCS will set the terms of the restoration
            agreement. The restoration plan component of the restoration
            agreement identifies conservation practices and activities necessary
            to restore or improve the functions and values of the grassland to
            meet both USDA and the participant&apos;s objectives and purposes of
            the program. If the functions and values of the grassland decline
            while the land is subject to a GRP easement or rental contract
            through no fault of the participant, the participant may enter into
            a restoration agreement at that time to improve the functions and
            values with USDA approval and when funds are available.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The NRCS State Conservationist, with advice from the State
            Technical Committee and in consultation with FSA, determines the
            conservation practices and activities and the cost-share
            percentages, not to exceed statutory limits available under GRP. A
            list of conservation practices and activities approved for
            cost-share assistance under GRP restoration plans is available to
            the public through the local USDA Service Center. NRCS may work
            through the local conservation district with the program participant
            to determine the terms of the restoration plan. The conservation
            district may assist NRCS with determining eligible conservation
            practices and activities and approving restoration agreements.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Only approved conservation practices and activities are eligible
            for cost-sharing. Payments under the GRP restoration agreements may
            be made to the participant of not more than 50 percent for the cost
            of carrying out the conservation practices or activities. As
            provided by the regulations at 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
                1400 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , payments made under one or more restoration agreements to a person
            or legal entity, directly or indirectly, may not exceed, in the
            aggregate, $50,000 per year.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The participant is responsible for the operation and maintenance of
            conservation practices in accordance with the restoration agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All conservation practices must be implemented in accordance with
            the FOTG.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Technical assistance is provided by NRCS, or an NRCS approved third
            party.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the participant is receiving cost-share for the same
            conservation practice or activity from another conservation program,
            USDA will adjust the GRP cost-share rate proportionately so that the
            amount received by the participant does not exceed 100 percent of
            the costs of restoration.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The participant cannot receive cost-share from more than one USDA
            cost-share program for the same conservation practice or activity on
            the same land.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Cost-share payments may be made only upon a determination by a
            qualified individual approved by the NRCS State Conservationist that
            an eligible restoration practice has been established in compliance
            with appropriate standards and specifications.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Conservation practices and activities identified in the restoration
            plan may be implemented by the participant or other designee.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Cost-share payments will not be made for conservation practices or
            activities implemented or initiated prior to the approval of a
            rental contract or easement acquisition unless a written waiver is
            granted by the NRCS State Conservationist or FSA State Executive
            Director, as appropriate, prior to installation of the practice.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='l'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (l)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon transfer of an easement with a restoration agreement to an
            eligible entity as described in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1415' sect='18' psec='' tq='N'>
                1415.18
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , the entity will be responsible for administration of the agreement
            and providing 
            <PRTPAGE P='536' />
            funds for payment of any costs associated with the completion of the
            restoration agreement. The eligible entity may, with participant
            consent, revise an existing restoration agreement or develop a new
            restoration agreement. Restoration plans must be consistent with the
            GRP management plan or any associated conservation plan as described
            in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1415' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
                1415.4
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='m'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (m)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Cooperating entities under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1415' sect='17' psec='' tq='N'>
                1415.17
              </subref>
            </aref>
             will be responsible for development, administration, and
            implementation costs of restoration plans.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12396'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1415:-:1415.12
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1415.12
      </num>
      <head>
        Modifications to easements and rental contracts.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1415' sect='12' psec='' tq='N'>
              1415.12
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Modifications to easements and rental contracts.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             After an easement has been recorded, no substantive modification
            will be made to the easement. Modifications that would not result in
            acquisition or divestiture of additional property rights may be
            made.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State Conservationists may approve modifications for restoration
            agreements and GRP management plans or conservation plans where
            applicable, as long as the modifications do not affect the
            provisions of the easement and meet program objectives.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             USDA may approve modifications to rental contracts, including
            corresponding changes to conservation plans, GRP management plans,
            and restoration plans to facilitate the practical administration and
            management of the enrolled area so long as the modification will not
            adversely affect the grassland functions and values for which the
            land was enrolled.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12397'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1415:-:1415.13
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1415.13
      </num>
      <head>
        Transfer of land.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1415' sect='13' psec='' tq='N'>
              1415.13
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Transfer of land.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any transfer of the property prior to an applicant&apos;s
            acceptance into the program will void the offer of enrollment,
            unless at the option of the State Conservationist or State Executive
            Director, as appropriate, an offer is extended to the new landowner
            and the new landowner agrees to the same easement or rental contract
            terms and conditions.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             After acreage is accepted in the program, for easements with
            multiple payments, any remaining easement payments will be made to
            the original participant unless NRCS receives an assignment of
            proceeds.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Future annual rental payments will be made to the successor
            participant.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The new landowner is responsible for complying with the terms of
            the recorded easement, and the contract successor is responsible for
            complying with the terms of the rental contract and for assuring
            completion of all activities and practices required by any
            associated restoration agreement. Eligible cost-share payments will
            be made to the new participant upon presentation that the successor
            assumed the costs of establishing the practices.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             With respect to any and all payments owed to participants, the
            United States bears no responsibility for any full payments or
            partial distributions of funds between the original participant and
            the participant&apos;s successor. In the event of a dispute or claim
            on the distribution of cost-share payments, USDA may withhold
            payments, without the accrual of interest, pending an agreement or
            adjudication on the rights to the funds.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The rights granted to the United States in an easement will apply
            to any of its agents or assigns. All obligations of the participant
            under the GRP conservation easement deed also bind the
            participant&apos;s heirs, successors, agents, assigns, lessees, and
            any other person claiming under them.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Rental contracts may be transferred to another landowner, operator,
            or tenant that acquires an interest in the land enrolled in GRP. The
            successor must be determined by FSA to be eligible to participate in
            GRP and must assume full responsibility under the contract. FSA may
            require a participant to refund all or a portion of any financial
            assistance awarded under GRP, plus interest, if the participant
            sells or loses control of the land under a GRP rental contract, and
            the new landowner, operator, or tenant is not eligible to
            participate in the program or declines to assume responsibility
            under the contract.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12398'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1415:-:1415.14
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1415.14
      </num>
      <head>
        Misrepresentation and violations.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1415' sect='14' psec='' tq='N'>
              1415.14
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Misrepresentation and violations.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The following provisions apply to violations of rental contracts:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Rental contract violations, determinations, and appeals are handled
            in 
            <PRTPAGE P='537' />
            accordance with the terms of the rental contract;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A participant who is determined to have erroneously represented any
            fact affecting a program determination made in accordance with this
            part may not be entitled to rental contract payments and must refund
            to CCC all payments, plus interest, in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1403' tq='N'>
                1403 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the event of a violation of a rental contract, the participant
            will be given notice and an opportunity to voluntarily correct the
            violation within 30 days of the date of the notice, or such
            additional time as CCC may allow. Failure to correct the violation
            may result in termination of the rental contract.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The following provisions apply to violations of easement deeds:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Easement violations are handled under the terms of the easement
            deed;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon notification of the participant, NRCS has the right to enter
            upon the easement area at any time to monitor compliance with the
            terms of the GRP conservation easement deed or remedy deficiencies
            or violations;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When NRCS believes there may be a violation of the terms of the GRP
            conservation easement deed, NRCS may enter the property without
            prior notice; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The participant will be liable for any costs incurred by the United
            States as a result of the participant&apos;s negligence or failure
            to comply with the easement terms and conditions.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             USDA may require the participant to refund all or part of any
            payments received by the participant under the program contract or
            agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In addition to any and all legal and equitable remedies available
            to the United States under applicable law, USDA may withhold any
            easement payment, rental payment, or cost-share payments owing to
            the participant at any time there is a material breach of the
            easement covenants, rental contract, or any contract. Such withheld
            funds may be used to offset costs incurred by the United States in
            any remedial actions or retained as damages pursuant to court order
            or settlement agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Under a GRP conservation easement, the United States will be
            entitled to recover any and all administrative and legal costs,
            including attorney&apos;s fees or expenses, associated with any
            enforcement or remedial action.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12399'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1415:-:1415.15
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1415.15
      </num>
      <head>
        Payments not subject to claims.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1415' sect='15' psec='' tq='N'>
              1415.15
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Payments not subject to claims.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Any cost-share, rental, or easement payment or portion thereof due any
          person under this part will be allowed without regard to any claim or
          lien in favor of any creditor, except agencies of the United States
          Government.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12400'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1415:-:1415.16
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1415.16
      </num>
      <head>
        Assignments.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1415' sect='16' psec='' tq='N'>
              1415.16
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Assignments.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any person entitled to any cash payment under this program may
            assign the right to receive such cash payments, in whole or in part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a participant that is entitled to a payment dies, is declared
            legally incompetent, or is otherwise unable to receive the payment,
            or is succeeded by another person who renders or completes the
            required performance, such a participant may be eligible to receive
            payment in such a manner as USDA determines is fair and reasonable
            in light of all the circumstances.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12401'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1415:-:1415.17
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1415.17
      </num>
      <head>
        Cooperative agreements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1415' sect='17' psec='' tq='N'>
              1415.17
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Cooperative agreements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS may enter into cooperative agreements which establish terms
            and conditions under which an eligible entity will use funds
            provided by NRCS to own, write, and enforce a grassland protection
            easement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be eligible to receive GRP funding, an eligible entity must
            demonstrate:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A commitment to long-term conservation of agricultural lands, ranch
            land, or grassland for grazing and conservation purposes;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A capability to acquire, manage, and enforce easements;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Sufficient number of staff dedicated to monitoring and easement
            stewardship;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The availability of funds; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For nongovernmental organizations, the existence of a dedicated
            account and funds for the purposes of easement management,
            monitoring, and enforcement of each easement held by the eligible
            entity.
            <PRTPAGE P='538' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS enters into a cooperative agreement with those eligible
            entities selected for funding. Once a proposal is selected by the
            State Conservationist, the eligible entity must work with the
            appropriate State Conservationist to finalize and sign the
            cooperative agreement, incorporating all necessary GRP requirements.
            The cooperative agreement addresses:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The interests in land to be acquired, including the form of the
            easement deeds to be used and terms and conditions;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The management and enforcement of the interests acquired;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The responsibilities of NRCS;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The responsibilities of the eligible entity on lands acquired with
            the assistance of GRP;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The parcels accepted by the State Conservationist, landowners&apos;
            names, addresses, location map(s), and other relevant information in
            an a attachment to the cooperative agreement;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The allowance of parcel substitution upon mutual agreement of the
            parties;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The manner in which violations are addressed;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The right of the Secretary to conduct periodic inspections to
            verify the eligible entity&apos;s enforcement of the easements;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The manner in which the eligible entity will evaluate and report
            the use of funds to the Secretary;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The eligible entity&apos;s agreement to assume the costs incurred
            in administering and enforcing the easement, including the costs of
            restoration and rehabilitation of the land as specified by the owner
            and eligible entity. The entity will also assume the responsibility
            for enforcing the GRP management plan or conservation plan, as
            applicable. The eligible entity must incorporate any required plan
            into the conservation easement deed by reference or otherwise;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_11'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (11)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The source of funding. The eligible entity may include a charitable
            donation or qualified conservation contribution (as defined by 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 170(h) of
            </aref>
             the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) from the landowner as part of
            the entity&apos;s share of the purchase price;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_12'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (12)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The schedule of payments to an eligible entity, as agreed to by
            NRCS and the eligible entity;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_13'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (13)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             GRP funds may not be used for expenditures such as appraisals,
            surveys, title insurance, legal fees, costs of easement monitoring,
            and other related administrative and transaction costs incurred by
            the entity;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_14'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (14)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS may provide a share of the purchase price of an easement under
            the program. The eligible entity will be required to provide a share
            of the purchase price at least equivalent to that provided by NRCS.
            The Federal share will be no more than 50 percent of the purchase
            price, as defined in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1415' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
                1415.3
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_15'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (15)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The eligible entity&apos;s succession plan, which describes how its
            successors or assigns will hold, manage, and enforce the interests
            in land acquired in the event that the eligible entity is no longer
            able to fulfill its obligations under the cooperative agreement
            entered into with NRCS; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_16'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (16)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Other requirements deemed necessary by NRCS to protect the
            interests of the United States.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Easements funded under the cooperative agreement option will be in
            perpetuity, except where State law prohibits a permanent easement,
            and will require that the easement area be maintained in accordance
            with GRP goals and objectives for the term of the easement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The entity may use its own terms and conditions in the conservation
            easement deed, but a conservation easement deed template used by the
            eligible entity will be submitted to the Chief within 30 days of the
            signing of the cooperative agreement. The conservation easement deed
            templates will be reviewed and approved by the Chief. NRCS reserves
            the right to require additional specific language or to remove
            language in the conservation easement deed to protect the interests
            of the United States.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In order to protect the public investment, the conveyance document
            must contain a right of enforcement. NRCS will specify the terms for
            the right of enforcement clause to read as set forth in the GRP
            cooperative agreement. This right is a vested property right and
            cannot be condemned or terminated by State or local government;
            <PRTPAGE P='539' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The eligible entity will acquire, hold, manage, and enforce the
            easement. The eligible entity may have the option to enter into an
            agreement with governmental or private organizations to carry out
            easement stewardship responsibilities if approved by NRCS;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Prior to closing, NRCS must sign an acceptance of the conservation
            easement, concurring with the terms of the conservation easement and
            accepting its interest in the conservation easement deed;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All conservation easement deeds acquired with GRP funds must be
            recorded in the appropriate land records. Proof of recordation will
            be provided to NRCS by the eligible entity; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The conservation easement deed must include an indemnification
            clause requiring the participant (grantor) to indemnify and hold
            harmless the United States from any liability arising from or
            related to the property enrolled in GRP.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12402'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1415:-:1415.18
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1415.18
      </num>
      <head>
        Easement transfer to eligible entities.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1415' sect='18' psec='' tq='N'>
              1415.18
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Easement transfer to eligible entities.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS may transfer title of ownership to an easement to an eligible
            entity to hold and enforce an easement if:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Chief determines that transfer will promote protection of
            grassland, land that contains forbs, or shrubland;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The owner authorizes the eligible entity to hold and enforce the
            easement; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The eligible entity agrees to assume the costs incurred in
            administering and enforcing the easement, including the costs of
            restoration or rehabilitation of the land as specified by the owner
            and the eligible entity, and the entity assumes responsibility for
            enforcing the GRP management plan or conservation plan, as
            applicable, as approved by NRCS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS has the right to conduct periodic inspections to verify the
            eligible entities enforcement of the easement, which includes the
            terms and requirements set forth in the GRP management plan and any
            associated restoration or conservation plan for any easements
            transferred pursuant to this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An eligible entity that seeks to hold and enforce an easement will
            apply to the NRCS State Conservationist for approval.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Chief may approve an application if the eligible entity:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Has relevant experience necessary, as appropriate for the
            application, to administer an easement on grassland, land that
            contains forbs, or shrublands;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Has a charter that describes the commitment of the eligible entity
            to conserving ranch land, agricultural land, or grassland for
            grazing and conservation purposes;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Possesses the human and financial resources necessary, as
            determined by the Chief, to effectuate the purposes of the charter;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Has sufficient financial resources to carry out easement
            administrative and enforcement activities;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Presents proof of a dedicated fund for enforcement as described in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1415' sect='17' psec='#b_5' tq='N'>
                1415.17(b)(5)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , if the entity is a nongovernmental organization; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Presents documentation that the landowner has concurred in the
            transfer.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Chief or his or her successors and assigns, will retain a right
            of enforcement in any transferred GRP funded easement, which
            provides the Secretary the right to inspect the easement for
            violations and enforce the terms of this easement through any and
            all authorities available under Federal or State law, in the event
            that the eligible entity fails to enforce the terms of the easement,
            as determined by NRCS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Should an easement be transferred pursuant to this section, all
            warranties and indemnifications provided for in the deed will
            continue to apply to the United States. Upon transfer of the
            easement, the easement holder will be responsible for enforcement of
            the GRP management plan, as approved by NRCS, and implementation of
            any associated conservation or restoration plans and costs of such
            restoration as agreed to by the landowner and entity.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Due to the Federal interest in the GRP easement, GRP-funded
            easements cannot be condemned.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12403'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1415:-:1415.19
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1415.19
      </num>
      <head>
        Appeals.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1415' sect='19' psec='' tq='N'>
              1415.19
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Appeals.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Applicants or participants may obtain a review of any
            administrative 
            <PRTPAGE P='540' />
            determination concerning eligibility for participation utilizing the
            administrative appeal regulations provided in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              parts 
              <subref title='7' part='614' tq='N'>
                614
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='780' tq='N'>
                780 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Before a person may seek judicial review of any administrative
            action concerning eligibility for program participation under this
            part, the person must exhaust all administrative appeal procedures
            set forth in paragraph (a) of this section, and for the purposes of
            judicial review, no decision will be a final agency action except a
            decision of the NRCS Chief or the FSA Administrator, as applicable,
            under these procedures.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any appraisals, market analysis, or supporting documentation that
            may be used by NRCS in determining property value are considered
            confidential information, and will only be disclosed as determined
            at the sole discretion of NRCS in accordance with applicable law.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Enforcement actions undertaken by NRCS in furtherance of its
            Federally held property rights are under the jurisdiction of the
            Federal District Courts and are not subject to review under
            administrative appeal regulations.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12404'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1415:-:1415.20
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1415.20
      </num>
      <head>
        Scheme or device.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1415' sect='20' psec='' tq='N'>
              1415.20
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Scheme or device.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If it is determined by USDA that a participant has employed a
            scheme or device to defeat the purposes of this part, any part of
            any program payment otherwise due or paid to such participant during
            the applicable period may be withheld or be required to be refunded
            with interest thereon, as determined appropriate by USDA.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A scheme or device includes, but is not limited to, coercion,
            fraud, misrepresentation, depriving any other person of payments for
            cost-share practices, rental contracts, or easements for the purpose
            of obtaining a payment to which a person would otherwise not be
            entitled.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A participant who succeeds to the responsibilities under this part
            will report in writing to USDA any interest of any kind in enrolled
            land that is held by a predecessor or any lender. A failure of full
            disclosure will be considered a scheme or device under this section.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>