<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol15'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXV:-:2500
    </extid>
    <num>
      2500
    </num>
    <head>
      OAO FEDERAL FINANCIAL ASSISTANCE PROGRAMS—GENERAL AWARD ADMINISTRATIVE
      PROCEDURES
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='6934' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/6934.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 6934
            </subref>
            , 
            <subref title='7' sect='7' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/7.html'>
              7
            </subref>
          </aref>
           U.S.C. 2279.
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 66170
          </aref>
          , Oct. 26, 2011, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='15853'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXV:-:2500:A:2500.001
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2500.001
      </num>
      <head>
        Applicability of regulations.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2500' sect='001' psec='' tq='N'>
              2500.001
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Applicability of regulations.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The regulations in subparts A through E of this part apply to the
          programs authorized under 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 14013 of
          </aref>
           the FCEA to be administered within the Office of Advocacy and
          Outreach (OAO). The purpose of this part is to set forth regulations
          for competitive and noncompetitive grants, cooperative agreements, and
          other assistance agreements awarded through OAO.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15854'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXV:-:2500:A:2500.002
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2500.002
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2500' sect='002' psec='' tq='N'>
              2500.002
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Applicant
          </E>
           means the entity that has submitted a proposal in response to an OAO
          Request For Proposal (RFP).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Authorized Departmental Officer (ADO)
          </E>
           means the Secretary or any employee of the Department with delegated
          authority to issue or modify award instruments on behalf of the
          Secretary.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Authorized Organizational Representative (AOR)
          </E>
           means the President or Chief Executive Officer of the applicant
          organization or the official, designated by the President or Chief
          Executive Officer of the applicant organization, who has the authority
          to commit the resources of the organization to the project.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Award
          </E>
           means financial assistance that provides support to accomplish a
          public purpose. Awards may be grants, cooperative agreements, or other
          assistance agreements.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Award agreement
          </E>
           means the agreement between OAO and the awardee which sets forth the
          terms and conditions under which the OAO funds will be made available.
          Award agreement is used as a general term to describe grant
          agreements, cooperative agreements, and other assistance agreements.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Award closeout
          </E>
           means the process by which the award operation is concluded 
          <PRTPAGE P='62' />
          at the expiration of the award period or following a decision to
          terminate the award.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Award period
          </E>
           means the timeframe of the award from the beginning date to the
          ending date as defined in the award agreement.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Awardee
          </E>
           means the entity designated in the grant agreement, cooperative
          agreement, or other assistance agreement as the legal entity to which
          the award is given.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Baseline monitoring
          </E>
           is the minimum, basic monitoring that will take place on an ongoing
          basis throughout the lifetime of every award.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Beginning date
          </E>
           means the date the award agreement is executed by the awardee and OAO
          and from which costs can be incurred.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Community-based organization
          </E>
           means a nongovernmental organization with a well-defined constituency
          that includes all or part of a particular community.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Cooperative agreement
          </E>
           means the award of funds to an eligible awardee to assist in meeting
          the costs of conducting a project which is intended and designed to
          accomplish the purpose of the program as identified in the RFP, and
          where substantial involvement is expected between OAO and the awardee
          when carrying out the activities included in the agreement. This
          agreement may also be referred to more generally as an award.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Department
          </E>
           means the U.S. Department of Agriculture.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Disallowed costs
          </E>
           means the use of Federal financial assistance funds for unauthorized
          activities or items as stipulated in the applicable Federal cost
          principles (
          <aref type='CFR'>
            2 CFR part 
            <subref title='2' part='220' tq='N'>
              220, 2
            </subref>
          </aref>
           CFR 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='225' tq='N'>
              225
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , and 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            2 CFR part 
            <subref title='2' part='230' tq='N'>
              230
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Ending date
          </E>
           means the date the award agreement is scheduled to be completed. It
          is also the latest date award funds will be provided under the award
          agreement, without an approved time extension.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Participant
          </E>
           means an individual or entity that participates in awardee-led
          activities funded under the award agreement. Furthermore, a
          participant is any individual or entity who has applied for, otherwise
          participated in, or received a payment, or other benefit as a result
          of participating in an activity funded by an OAO award.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Partnering
          </E>
           means a joint effort among two or more eligible entities with the
          capacity to conduct projects intended and designed to accomplish the
          purpose of the program.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Program leader
          </E>
           means the program supervisor within OAO.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Project
          </E>
           means activities supported under an OAO award.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Project Director (PD)
          </E>
           means the individual designated by the awardee in the proposal and
          award documentation, and approved by the ADO who is responsible for
          the direction and management of the award.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Project Officer (PO)
          </E>
           means an individual within OAO who is responsible for the
          programmatic oversight of the award on behalf of the Department.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Request for Proposals (RFP)
          </E>
           means an official USDA funding opportunity. At OAO discretion,
          funding opportunities may be referred to as request for proposals,
          request for applications, notice of funding availability, or funding
          opportunity.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Review panel
          </E>
           means an evaluation process involving qualified individuals within
          the relevant field to give advice on the merit of proposals submitted
          to OAO.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Secretary
          </E>
           means the Secretary of Agriculture and any other officer or employee
          of the Department of Agriculture to whom authority may be delegated.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Terminate funding
          </E>
           means the cancellation of Federal assistance, in whole or in part, at
          any time before the ending date.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15855'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXV:-:2500:A:2500.003
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2500.003
      </num>
      <head>
        Other applicable statutes and regulations.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2500' sect='003' psec='' tq='N'>
              2500.003
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Other applicable statutes and regulations.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Several Federal statutes and regulations apply to proposals for
          Federal assistance considered for review and to grants and cooperative
          agreements awarded by OAO. These include, but are not limited to:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR Part 
              <subref title='7' part='1' tq='N'>
                1
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , Subpart A—USDA implementation of the Freedom of Information Act;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR Part 
              <subref title='7' part='3' tq='N'>
                3
              </subref>
            </aref>
            —USDA implementation of OMB Circular No. A-129, regarding debt
            management;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (Pub. L. 88-352), as
            amended, which prohibits discrimination on the basis of race, color,
            or national origin, and 7 
            <PRTPAGE P='63' />
            CFR 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='15' tq='N'>
                15
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , subpart A (USDA implementation);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR Part 
              <subref title='7' part='3015' tq='N'>
                3015
              </subref>
            </aref>
            —USDA Uniform Federal Assistance Regulations, implementing OMB
            directives and incorporating provisions of the Federal Grant and
            Cooperative Agreement Act of 1977, 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 95-224' alt='Public Law 95-224' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d95:./list/bd/d95pl.lst:224%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 95-224
            </aref>
            , 31 U.S.C. 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 6301-6308
            </aref>
            , as well as general policy requirements applicable to awardees of
            Departmental financial assistance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR Part 
              <subref title='7' part='3016' tq='N'>
                3016
              </subref>
            </aref>
            —USDA implementation of Administrative Requirements for Grants and
            Cooperative Agreements to State and Local Governments.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR Part 
              <subref title='7' part='3017' tq='N'>
                3017
              </subref>
            </aref>
            —USDA implementation of Governmentwide Debarment and Suspension
            (Nonprocurement).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR Part 
              <subref title='7' part='3018' tq='N'>
                3018
              </subref>
            </aref>
            —USDA implementation of Restrictions on Lobbying. Imposes
            prohibitions and requirements for disclosure and certification
            related to lobbying on awardees of Federal contracts, grants,
            cooperative agreements, and loans.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR Part 
              <subref title='7' part='3019' tq='N'>
                3019
              </subref>
            </aref>
            —USDA implementation of OMB Circular No. A-110, Uniform
            Administrative Requirements for Grants and Agreements with
            Institutions of Higher Education, Hospitals and Other Non-Profit
            Organizations (now relocated at 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              2 CFR part 
              <subref title='2' part='215' tq='N'>
                215
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR Part 
              <subref title='7' part='3021' tq='N'>
                3021
              </subref>
            </aref>
            —USDA implementation of Governmentwide Requirements for Drug-Free
            Workplace (Financial Assistance).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR Part 
              <subref title='7' part='3052' tq='N'>
                3052
              </subref>
            </aref>
            —USDA implementation of OMB Circular No. A-133, Audits of States,
            Local Governments, and Non-Profit Organizations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='3318' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/3318.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 3318
              </subref>
            </aref>
            —conferring upon the Secretary general authority to enter into
            contracts, grants, and cooperative agreements to further the
            research, extension, or teaching programs in the food and
            agricultural sciences of the Department of Agriculture.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='l'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (l)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='29' sect='794' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/29/794.html'>
                29 U.S.C. 794
              </subref>
            </aref>
             (
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              Section 504
            </aref>
            , Rehabilitation Act of 1973) and 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='15b' tq='N'>
                15b
              </subref>
            </aref>
             (USDA implementation of statute)—prohibiting discrimination based
            upon physical or mental handicap in Federally assisted programs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='m'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (m)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='35' sect='200' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/35/200.html'>
                35 U.S.C. 200
              </subref>
            </aref>
            <E T='03'>
              et seq.
            </E>
            —Bayh-Dole Act, promoting the utilization of inventions arising from
            federally supported research or development; encouraging maximum
            participation of small business firms in federally supported
            research and development efforts; and promoting collaboration
            between commercial concerns and nonprofit organizations, including
            universities, while ensuring that the Government obtains sufficient
            rights in federally supported inventions to meet the needs of the
            Government and protect the public against nonuse or unreasonable use
            of inventions (implementing regulations are contained in 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              37 CFR part 
              <subref title='37' part='401' tq='N'>
                401
              </subref>
            </aref>
            )
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='n'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (n)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Title IX of the Education Amendment of 1972 (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='20' sect='1681-168' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/20/1681-168.html'>
                20 U.S.C. 1681-168
              </subref>
            </aref>
            3 and 1685-1686), as amended, which prohibits discrimination on the
            basis of sex;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='o'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (o)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Age Discrimination Act of 1975 (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='42' sect='6101-610' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/42/6101-610.html'>
                42 U.S.C. 6101-610
              </subref>
            </aref>
            7), as amended, which prohibits discrimination on the basis of age;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='p'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (p)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Drug Abuse Office and Treatment Act of 1972 (Pub. L. 92-255), as
            amended, relating to nondiscrimination on the basis of drug abuse;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='q'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (q)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Comprehensive Alcohol Abuse and Alcoholism Prevention, Treatment
            and Rehabilitation Act of 1970 (Pub. L. 91-616), as amended,
            relating to nondiscrimination on the basis of alcohol abuse or
            alcoholism;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='r'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (r)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              Sections 523 and 527 of
            </aref>
             the Public Health Service Act of 1912 (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='42' sect='290dd-3' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/42/290dd-3.html'>
                42 U.S.C. 290dd-3
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='42' sect='290ee-3' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/42/290ee-3.html'>
                290ee-3
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ), as amended, relating to confidentiality of alcohol and drug abuse
            patient records;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='s'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (s)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Title VIII of the Civil Rights Act of 1968 (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='42' sect='3601' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/42/3601.html'>
                42 U.S.C. 3601
              </subref>
            </aref>
            <E T='03'>
              et seq.
            </E>
            ), as amended, relating to nondiscrimination in the sale, rental or
            financing of housing;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='t'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (t)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any other nondiscrimination provisions in the specific statute(s)
            under which proposals for Federal assistance are made, and the
            requirements of any other nondiscrimination statute(s) which may
            apply to the proposal.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15856'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXV:-:2500:B:2500.011
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2500.011
      </num>
      <head>
        Competition.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2500' sect='011' psec='' tq='N'>
              2500.011
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Competition.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Standards for competition.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as provided in paragraph (b) of this section, OAO will enter
            into discretionary grants or cooperative agreement only after
            competition, unless restricted by statute.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Exception.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The OAO ADO may make a determination in writing that 
            <PRTPAGE P='64' />
            competition is not deemed appropriate for a particular transaction.
            Such determination shall be limited to transactions where it can be
            adequately justified that a noncompetitive award is in the best
            interest of the Federal Government and necessary to the goals of the
            program. Non-competitive determinations will comply with regulations
            established in 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR 
              <subref title='7' part='3015' sect='158' psec='#d' tq='N'>
                3015.158(d)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15857'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXV:-:2500:B:2500.012
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2500.012
      </num>
      <head>
        Requests for proposals.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2500' sect='012' psec='' tq='N'>
              2500.012
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Requests for proposals.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For each competitive grant or cooperative agreement, OAO will
            prepare a program solicitation (also called a request for proposals
            (RFP)). The RFP may include all or a portion of the following items:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Contact information.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Catalog of Federal Domestic Assistance (CFDA) number.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Legislative authority and background information.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Purpose, priorities, and fund availability.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Program-specific eligibility requirements.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Program-specific restrictions on the use of funds, if applicable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Matching requirements, if applicable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Acceptable types of proposals.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Types of projects to be given priority consideration, including
            maximum anticipated awards and maximum project lengths, if
            applicable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Program areas, if applicable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_11'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (11)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Funding restrictions, if applicable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_12'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (12)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Directions for obtaining additional requests for proposals and
            proposal forms.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_13'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (13)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Information about how to obtain proposal forms and the instructions
            for completing such forms.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_14'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (14)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Instructions and requirements for submitting proposals, including
            submission deadline(s).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_15'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (15)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Explanation of the proposal evaluation process.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_16'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (16)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Specific evaluation criteria used in the review process.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_17'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (17)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Type of Federal assistance awards (
            <E T='03'>
              i.e.
            </E>
            , grants or cooperative agreements).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              RFP variations.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Where program-specific requirements differ from the requirements
            established in this part, program solicitations will also address
            any such variation(s). Variations may occur in the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Award management guidelines.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Restrictions on the delegation of fiscal responsibility.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Required approval for changes to project plans.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Expected program outputs and reporting requirements, if applicable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Applicable Federal statutes and regulations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Confidential aspects of proposals and awards, if applicable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Regulatory information.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Definitions.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Minimum and maximum budget requests and whether proposals outside
            of these limits will be returned without further review.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Program announcements.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Occasionally, OAO will issue a program announcement (PA) to alert
            potential applicants and the public about new and ongoing funding
            opportunities. These PAs may provide tentative due dates and are
            released without associated proposal packages. No proposals are
            solicited under a PA. PAs will be announced in the 
            <E T='04'>
              Federal Register
            </E>
             or on the OAO Web site.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15858'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXV:-:2500:B:2500.013
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2500.013
      </num>
      <head>
        Types of proposals.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2500' sect='013' psec='' tq='N'>
              2500.013
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Types of proposals.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The type of proposal acceptable may vary by funding opportunity. The
          RFP will stipulate what will be required for submission to OAO in
          response to the funding opportunity.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15859'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXV:-:2500:B:2500.014
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2500.014
      </num>
      <head>
        Eligibility requirements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2500' sect='014' psec='' tq='N'>
              2500.014
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Eligibility requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Program-specific eligibility requirements appear in the subpart
          applicable to each program and in the corresponding RFPs.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15860'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXV:-:2500:B:2500.015
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2500.015
      </num>
      <head>
        Content of a proposal.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2500' sect='015' psec='' tq='N'>
              2500.015
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Content of a proposal.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The RFP provides instructions on how to access a funding opportunity.
          The funding opportunity contains the proposal package, which includes
          the forms necessary for completion of a proposal in response to the
          RFP. The RFP will be posted on 
          <E T='03'>
            http://www.Grants.gov.
          </E>
           OAO may also publish the RFP in the 
          <E T='04'>
            Federal Register
          </E>
          .
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15861'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXV:-:2500:B:2500.016
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2500.016
      </num>
      <head>
        Submission of a proposal.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2500' sect='016' psec='' tq='N'>
              2500.016
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Submission of a proposal.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The RFP will provide deadlines for the submission of proposals. OAO
          may issue separate RFPs and/or establish 
          <PRTPAGE P='65' />
          separate deadlines for different types of proposals, different award
          instruments, or different topics or phases of the assistance programs.
          If proposals are not received by applicable deadlines, they will not
          be considered for funding. Exceptions will be considered only when
          extenuating circumstances exist, as determined by OAO, and
          justification and supporting documentation are provided by the
          applicant. Conformance with preparation and submission instructions is
          required and will be strictly enforced unless a deviation has been
          approved. OAO may establish additional requirements. OAO may return
          without review proposals that are not consistent with the RFP
          instructions.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15862'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXV:-:2500:B:2500.017
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2500.017
      </num>
      <head>
        Confidentiality of proposals and awards.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2500' sect='017' psec='' tq='N'>
              2500.017
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Confidentiality of proposals and awards.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Names of entities submitting proposals, as well as proposal
            contents and evaluations, except to those involved in the review
            process, will be kept confidential to the extent permissible by law.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Identifying confidential and proprietary information in a
              proposal.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a proposal contains proprietary information that constitutes a
            trade secret, proprietary commercial or financial information,
            confidential personal information, or data affecting the national
            security, it will be treated in confidence to the extent permitted
            by law, provided that the information is clearly marked by the
            applicant with the term “confidential and proprietary information.”
            In addition, the following statement must be included at the bottom
            of the project narrative or any other attachment included in the
            proposal that contains such information: “The following pages
            (specify) contain proprietary information which (name of proposing
            organization) requests not to be released to persons outside the
            Government, except for purposes of evaluation.”
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Disposition of proposals.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             By law, OAO is required to make the final decisions as to whether
            the information is required to be kept in confidence. Information
            contained in unsuccessful proposals will remain the property of the
            applicant. However, the Department will retain for three years one
            file copy of each proposal received; extra copies will be destroyed.
            Public release of information from any proposal submitted will be
            subject to existing legal requirements. Any proposal that is funded
            will be considered an integral part of the award and normally will
            be made available to the public upon request, except for information
            designated proprietary by OAO.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Submission of proprietary information.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The inclusion of proprietary information is discouraged unless it
            is necessary for the proper evaluation of the proposal. If
            proprietary information is to be included, it should be limited, set
            apart from other text on a separate page, and keyed to the text by
            numbers. It should be confined to a few critical technical items
            that, if disclosed, could jeopardize the obtaining of foreign or
            domestic patents. Trade secrets, salaries, or other information that
            could jeopardize commercial competitiveness should be similarly
            keyed and presented on a separate page. Proposals or reports that
            attempt to restrict dissemination of large amounts of information
            may be found unacceptable by OAO and constitute grounds for return
            of the proposal without further consideration. Without assuming any
            liability for inadvertent disclosure, OAO will limit dissemination
            of such information to its employees and, where necessary for the
            evaluation of the proposal, to outside reviewers on a confidential
            basis.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15863'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXV:-:2500:B:2500.018
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2500.018
      </num>
      <head>
        Electronic submission.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2500' sect='018' psec='' tq='N'>
              2500.018
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Electronic submission.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Applicants and awardees are encouraged, but not required, to submit
          proposals and reports in electronic form as prescribed in the RFP
          issued by OAO and in the applicable award agreement.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15864'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXV:-:2500:C:2500.021
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2500.021
      </num>
      <head>
        Guiding principles.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2500' sect='021' psec='' tq='N'>
              2500.021
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Guiding principles.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The guiding principle for Federal assistance proposal review and
          evaluation is to ensure that each proposal is treated in a consistent
          and fair manner. After the evaluation process by the review panel, OAO
          will provide an opportunity for applicant feedback in as timely a
          manner as possible.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15865'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXV:-:2500:C:2500.022
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2500.022
      </num>
      <head>
        Preliminary proposal review.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='66' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2500' sect='022' psec='' tq='N'>
              2500.022
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Preliminary proposal review.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Prior to technical examination, a preliminary review will be made of
          all proposals for responsiveness to the administrative requirements
          set forth in the RFP. Proposals that do not meet the administrative
          requirements may be eliminated from program competition. However, OAO
          retains the right to conduct discussions with applicants to resolve
          technical and/or budget issues, as deemed necessary by OAO.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15866'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXV:-:2500:C:2500.023
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2500.023
      </num>
      <head>
        Selection of reviewers.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2500' sect='023' psec='' tq='N'>
              2500.023
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Selection of reviewers.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Requirement.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             OAO is responsible for performing a review of proposals submitted
            to OAO competitive award programs. The RFP will identify the
            criteria that OAO will use for the selection of the proposal review
            panel.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Confidentiality.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The identities of reviewers will remain confidential to the maximum
            extent possible. Therefore, the names of reviewers will not be
            released to applicants. Names of applicants, as well as proposal
            content and evaluation comments will be kept confidential to the
            extent permitted by law, except to those involved in the review
            process. Reviewers will comply with the above-mentioned
            confidentiality guidelines.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Conflicts of interest.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             During the evaluation process, extreme care will be taken to
            prevent any actual or perceived conflicts of interest that may
            impact review or evaluation. Reviewers are expected to be in
            compliance with the Conflict-of-Interest process made a part of the
            RFP.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15867'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXV:-:2500:C:2500.024
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2500.024
      </num>
      <head>
        Evaluation criteria.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2500' sect='024' psec='' tq='N'>
              2500.024
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Evaluation criteria.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To ensure any project receiving funds from OAO is consistent with
            the broad goals of the funding program, the content of each proposal
            submitted to OAO will be evaluated based on a pre-determined set of
            review criteria as indicated in the RFP.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Guidance for reviewers.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In order that all potential applicants for a program have similar
            opportunities to compete for funds, all reviewers will receive an
            orientation from the Program Leader of the review criteria.
            Reviewers are instructed to use those same evaluation criteria, and
            only those criteria, to judge the merit of the proposals they
            review.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15868'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXV:-:2500:C:2500.025
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2500.025
      </num>
      <head>
        Procedures to minimize or eliminate duplication of effort.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2500' sect='025' psec='' tq='N'>
              2500.025
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Procedures to minimize or eliminate duplication of effort.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          OAO may implement appropriate business processes to minimize or
          eliminate the awarding of Federal assistance to projects that
          unnecessarily duplicate activities already being sponsored under other
          awards, including awards made by other Federal agencies.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15869'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXV:-:2500:C:2500.026
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2500.026
      </num>
      <head>
        Applicant feedback.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2500' sect='026' psec='' tq='N'>
              2500.026
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Applicant feedback.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Unsuccessful applicants may submit a request for applicant feedback in
          writing to OAO within 10 days after receiving written notice of not
          being selected for further processing. Applicant feedback requests are
          to be mailed to the Program Leader at the address below, unless
          otherwise stated in the “Notice of Non-Selection” or in the RFP. At
          OAO&apos;s discretion, either written or oral feedback will be
          provided to unsuccessful applicants.
        </P>
        <P>
          U.S. Department of Agriculture, Departmental Management, Office of
          Advocacy and Outreach, 
          <E T='03'>
            Attn:
          </E>
           Program Leader (Applicant Feedback), Whitten Building, Rm. 520-A,
          stop 9821, 1400 Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC 20250-9821.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15870'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXV:-:2500:D:2500.031
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2500.031
      </num>
      <head>
        Administration.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2500' sect='031' psec='' tq='N'>
              2500.031
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Administration.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Within the limit of funds available for such purpose, the OAO ADO
            shall make Federal assistance awards to those responsible, eligible
            applicants whose proposals are judged most meritorious under the
            procedures set forth in the RFP. The date specified by the OAO ADO
            as the effective date of the award shall be no later than September
            30th of the Federal fiscal year in which the project is approved for
            support and funds are appropriated for such purpose, unless
            otherwise permitted by law. It should be noted that the project need
            not be initiated on the award effective date, but as soon thereafter
            as practical so that project goals may be attained within the funded
            project period. All funds awarded by OAO shall be expended solely
            for the 
            <PRTPAGE P='67' />
            purpose for which the funds are awarded in accordance with the
            approved statement of work and budget, the regulations, the terms
            and conditions of the OAO award agreement, the applicable Federal
            cost principles, and the Department&apos;s assistance regulations
            (e.g., 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR parts 
              <subref title='7' part='3015' tq='N'>
                3015, 3016
              </subref>
              , and 
              <subref title='7' part='3019' tq='N'>
                3019
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Award agreement.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The award agreement and accompanying terms and conditions will
            provide pertinent instructions and information including, at a
            minimum, the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Legal name and address of performing organization or institution to
            which OAO has awarded a grant or cooperative agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Title of project.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Name(s) of Project Director(s).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Identifying award number assigned by OAO.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Project period.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Total amount of OAO financial assistance approved.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Legal authority under which the grant or cooperative agreement is
            awarded.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Appropriate CFDA number.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Approved budget plan (that may be referenced).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Terms and Conditions
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15871'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXV:-:2500:E:2500.041
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2500.041
      </num>
      <head>
        Payment.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2500' sect='041' psec='' tq='N'>
              2500.041
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Payment.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All payments will be made in advance unless a deviation is accepted
            or as specified in paragraph (b) of this section. All payments to
            the awardee shall be made via the approved electronic funds transfer
            (EFT) method. Awardees are expected to request funds via the
            federally-approved electronic payment system for reimbursement in a
            timely manner. Exact payment method will be described in the terms
            and conditions of the award agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Reimbursement method.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             OAO shall use the reimbursement method if it determines that
            advance payment is not feasible or that the awardee does not
            maintain or demonstrate the willingness to maintain written
            procedures that minimize the elapse of time between the transfer of
            funds and disbursement by the awardee, and financial management
            systems that meet the standards for fund control and accountability.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15872'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXV:-:2500:E:2500.042
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2500.042
      </num>
      <head>
        Cost sharing and matching.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2500' sect='042' psec='' tq='N'>
              2500.042
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Cost sharing and matching.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Awardees may be required to match the Federal funds received under
            an OAO award. The required percentage of matching, type of matching
            (e.g., cash and/or in-kind contributions), sources of match (e.g.,
            non-Federal), and whether OAO has any authority to waive the match
            will be specified in the subpart applicable to the specific Federal
            assistance program, as well as in the RFP.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Indirect costs as in-kind matching contributions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Indirect costs may be claimed under the Federal portion of the
            award budget. However, unless explicitly authorized in the RFP,
            indirect costs may not be claimed on both the Federal and nonfederal
            portion of the award budget.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15873'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXV:-:2500:E:2500.043
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2500.043
      </num>
      <head>
        Program income.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2500' sect='043' psec='' tq='N'>
              2500.043
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Program income.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             OAO shall apply the standards set forth in this subpart in
            requiring awardee organizations to account for program income
            related to projects financed in whole or in part with Federal funds.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Addition method.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Unless otherwise provided in the authorizing statute, in accordance
            with the terms and conditions of the award, program income earned
            during the project period shall be retained by the awardee and shall
            be added to funds committed to the project by OAO and the awardee
            and used to further eligible project or program objectives. Any
            specific program deviations will be identified in the individual
            subparts.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Award terms and conditions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Unless the program regulations identified in the individual subpart
            provide otherwise, awardees shall follow the terms and conditions of
            the OAO award. Such terms and conditions will be made a part of the
            OAO award agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15874'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXV:-:2500:E:2500.044
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2500.044
      </num>
      <head>
        Indirect costs.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2500' sect='044' psec='' tq='N'>
              2500.044
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Indirect costs.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Indirect cost rates for grants and cooperative agreements shall be
          determined in accordance with the applicable assistance regulations
          and cost principles, unless superseded by another authority.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15875'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXV:-:2500:E:2500.045
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2500.045
      </num>
      <head>
        Technical reporting.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='68' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2500' sect='045' psec='' tq='N'>
              2500.045
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Technical reporting.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          All projects supported with Federal funds under this part must be
          documented according to the terms and conditions of the OAO award
          agreement.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15876'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXV:-:2500:E:2500.046
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2500.046
      </num>
      <head>
        Financial reporting.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2500' sect='046' psec='' tq='N'>
              2500.046
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Financial reporting.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              SF-425, Federal Financial Report.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             As stated in the award terms and conditions of the OAO award
            agreement, a final SF-425, Federal Financial Report, is due 90 days
            after the expiration of the award and should be submitted to OAO
            electronically. The awardee shall report program outlays and program
            income on the same accounting basis (
            <E T='03'>
              i.e.
            </E>
            , cash or accrual) that it uses in its normal accounting system.
            When submitting a final SF-425, Federal Financial Report, the total
            matching contribution, if required, should be shown in the report.
            The final SF-425 must not show any unliquidated obligations. If the
            awardee still has valid obligations that remain unpaid when the
            report is due, it shall request an extension of time for submitting
            the report pursuant to paragraph (c) of this section; submit a
            provisional report (showing the unliquidated obligations) by the due
            date; and submit a final report when all obligations have been
            liquidated, but no later than the approved extension date. SF-425,
            Federal Financial Reports, must be submitted by all awardees,
            including Federal agencies and national laboratories.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Awards with required matching.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For awards requiring a matching contribution, an annual SF-425,
            Federal Financial Report, is required and this requirement will be
            indicated in the terms and conditions of the OAO award agreement, in
            which case it must be submitted no later than 45 days following the
            end of the budget or reporting period.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              After the due date.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Requests are considered late when they are submitted after the
            90-day period following the award expiration date. Requests to
            submit a late final SF-425, Federal Financial Report, will only be
            considered, up to 30 days after the due date, in extenuating
            circumstances. This request should include a provisional report
            pursuant to paragraph (a) of this section, as well as an anticipated
            submission date, a justification for the late submission, and a
            justification for the extenuating circumstances. If an awardee needs
            to request additional funds, procedures in paragraph (d) of this
            section apply.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Overdue SF-425, Federal Financial Reports.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Awardees with overdue SF-425, Federal Financial Reports, or other
            required financial reports (as identified in the award terms and
            conditions), will have their applicable balances in the approved
            federal electronic funds transfer system restricted or placed on
            “manual review,” which restricts the awardee&apos;s ability to draw
            funds, thus requiring prior approval from OAO. If any remaining
            available balances are needed by the awardee (beyond the 90-day
            period following the award expiration date) and the awardee has not
            requested an extension to submit a final SF-425, Financial Status
            Report, the awardee will be required to contact OAO to request
            permission to draw any additional funds and will be required to
            provide justification and documentation to support the draw.
            Awardees also will need to comply with procedures in paragraph (c)
            of this section. OAO will approve these draw requests only in
            extenuating circumstances.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Additional reporting requirements.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             OAO may require forecasts of Federal cash requirements in the
            “Remarks” section of the report; and when practical and deemed
            necessary, OAO may require awardees to report in the “Remarks”
            section the amount of cash advances received in excess of three days
            (
            <E T='03'>
              i.e.
            </E>
            , short narrative with explanations of actions taken to reduce the
            excess balances). When OAO needs additional information or more
            frequent reports, a special provision will be added to the award
            terms and conditions and identified in the OAO award agreement.
            Should OAO determine that an awardee&apos;s accounting system is
            inadequate, additional pertinent information to further monitor
            awards may be requested from the awardee until such time as the
            system is brought up to standard, as determined by OAO. This
            additional reporting requirement will be required via a special
            provision to the award terms and conditions of the OAO award
            agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15877'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXV:-:2500:E:2500.047
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2500.047
      </num>
      <head>
        Project meetings.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='69' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2500' sect='047' psec='' tq='N'>
              2500.047
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Project meetings.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          In addition to reviewing and monitoring the status of progress and
          final technical reports and financial reports, OAO Project Officers
          may use regular and periodic conference calls to monitor the
          awardee&apos;s performance as well as conferences, workshops,
          meetings, and symposia to not only monitor the awards, but to
          facilitate communication and the sharing of project results. These
          opportunities also serve to eliminate or minimize OAO funding of
          unneeded duplicative project activities. Required attendance at these
          conference calls, conferences, workshops, meetings, and symposia will
          be identified in the RFP or award document.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15878'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXV:-:2500:E:2500.048
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2500.048
      </num>
      <head>
        Review of disallowed costs.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2500' sect='048' psec='' tq='N'>
              2500.048
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Review of disallowed costs.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Notice.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the OAO Project Officer (PO) determines that there is a basis
            for disallowing a cost, OAO shall provide the awardee written notice
            of its intent to disallow the cost. The written notice shall state
            the amount of the cost and the factual and legal basis for
            disallowing it.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Awardee response.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Within 60 days of receiving written notice of the PO&apos;s intent
            to disallow the cost, the awardee may respond with written evidence
            and arguments to show the cost is allowable, or that, for equitable,
            practical, or other reasons, shall not recover all or part of the
            amount, or that the recovery should be made in installments. An
            extension of time will be granted only in extenuating circumstances.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Decision.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Within 60 days of receiving the awardee&apos;s written response to
            the notice of intent to disallow the cost, the PO shall issue a
            management decision stating whether or not the cost has been
            disallowed, the reasons for the decision, and the method of appeal
            that has been provided under this section. If the awardee does not
            respond to the written notice under paragraph (a) of this section
            within the time frame specified in paragraph (b) of this section,
            the PO shall issue a management decision on the basis of the
            information available to it. The management decision shall
            constitute the final action with respect to whether the cost is
            allowed or disallowed. In the case of a questioned cost identified
            in the context of an audit subject to 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3052' tq='N'>
                3052
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , the management decision will constitute the management decision
            under 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR 
              <subref title='7' part='3052' sect='405' psec='#a' tq='N'>
                3052.405(a)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Demand for payment.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the management decision under paragraph (c) of this section
            constitutes a finding that the cost is disallowed and, therefore,
            that a debt is owed to the Government, the PO shall provide the
            required demand and notice pursuant to 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR 
              <subref title='7' part='3' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
                3.11
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Review process.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Within 60 days of receiving the demand and notice referred to in
            paragraph (d) of this section, the awardee may submit a written
            request to the OAO Director for a review of the final management
            decision that the debt exists and the amount of the debt. Within 60
            days of receiving the written request for a review, the OAO Director
            will issue a final decision regarding the debt. A review by the OAO
            Director or designee constitutes an administrative review for debts
            under 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3' tq='N'>
                3
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , subpart F.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15879'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXV:-:2500:E:2500.049
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2500.049
      </num>
      <head>
        Prior approvals.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2500' sect='049' psec='' tq='N'>
              2500.049
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Prior approvals.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Subcontracts.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No more than 50 percent of the award may be subcontracted to other
            parties without prior written approval of the ADO. Any subcontract
            awarded to a Federal agency under an award must have prior written
            approval of the ADO. To request approval, a justification for the
            proposed subcontractual arrangements, a performance statement, and a
            detailed budget for the subcontract must be submitted to the ADO.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              No-cost extensions of time—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Awardees may initiate a one-time no-cost extension of the
            expiration date of the award of up to 12 months unless one or more
            of the following conditions apply: the terms and conditions of the
            award prohibit the extension; the extension requires additional
            Federal funds; and the extension involves any change in the approved
            objectives or scope of the project. For the first no-cost extension,
            the awardee must notify OAO in writing with the supporting reasons
            and revised expiration date at least 10 days before the expiration
            date specified in the award.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Additional requests for no-cost extensions of time before
              expiration date.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When more than one no-cost extension 
            <PRTPAGE P='70' />
            of time or an extension of more than 12 months is required, the
            extension(s) must be approved in writing by the PO. The awardee must
            submit a written request, which must be received no later than 10
            days prior to the expiration date of the award, to the PO. The
            request must contain, at a minimum, the following information: The
            length of the additional time required to complete the project
            objectives and a justification for the extension; a summary of the
            progress to date; an estimate of the funds expected to remain
            unobligated on the scheduled expiration date; a projected timetable
            to complete the portion(s) of the project for which the extension is
            being requested; and signature of the AOR and the PD.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Requests for no-cost extensions of time after expiration date.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             OAO may consider and approve requests for no-cost extensions of
            time up to 120 days following the expiration of the award. These
            will be approved only for extenuating circumstances, as determined
            by OAO. The awardee&apos;s AOR must submit the requirements
            identified under paragraph (b)(2) of this section as well as an
            “extenuating circumstance” justification and a description of the
            actions taken by the awardee to minimize these requests in the
            future.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Other requirements.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No-cost extensions of time may not be exercised merely for the
            purpose of using unobligated balances.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15880'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXV:-:2500:E:2500.050
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2500.050
      </num>
      <head>
        Suspension, termination, and withholding of support.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2500' sect='050' psec='' tq='N'>
              2500.050
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Suspension, termination, and withholding of support.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If an awardee has failed to materially comply with the terms and
            conditions of the award, OAO may take certain enforcement actions,
            including, but not limited to, suspending the award pending
            corrective action and terminating the award for cause.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Suspension.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             OAO generally will suspend (rather than immediately terminate) an
            award to allow the awardee an opportunity to take appropriate
            corrective action before OAO makes a termination decision. OAO may
            decide to terminate the award if the awardee does not take
            appropriate corrective action during the period of suspension. OAO
            may terminate, without first suspending, the award if the deficiency
            is so serious as to warrant immediate termination. Termination for
            cause may be appealed under the terms and conditions identified in
            the OAO award agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Termination.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An award also may be terminated, partially or wholly, by the
            awardee or by OAO with the consent of the awardee. If the awardee
            decides to terminate a portion of the award, OAO may determine that
            the remaining portion of the award will not accomplish the purposes
            for which the award was originally made. In any such case, OAO will
            advise the awardee of the possibility of termination of the entire
            award and allow the awardee to withdraw its termination request. If
            the awardee does not withdraw its request for partial termination,
            OAO may initiate procedures to terminate the entire award for cause.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15881'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXV:-:2500:E:2500.051
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2500.051
      </num>
      <head>
        Debt collection.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2500' sect='051' psec='' tq='N'>
              2500.051
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Debt collection.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The collection of debts owed to OAO by awardees, including those
          resulting from cost disallowances, recovery of funds, unobligated
          balances, or other circumstances, are subject to the Department&apos;s
          debt collection procedures as set forth in 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR part 
            <subref title='7' part='3' tq='N'>
              3
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , and, with respect to cost disallowances, 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2500' sect='048' psec='' tq='N'>
              2500.048
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15882'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXV:-:2500:E:2500.052
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2500.052
      </num>
      <head>
        Award appeals procedures.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2500' sect='052' psec='' tq='N'>
              2500.052
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Award appeals procedures.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             OAO permits awardees to appeal certain adverse post-award
            administrative decisions made by OAO. Such adverse decisions
            include: Termination, in whole or in part, and determination that an
            award is void. An award may be terminated for failure of the awardee
            to carry out its approved project in accordance with the applicable
            law and the terms and conditions of award; or for failure of the
            awardee otherwise to comply with any law, regulation, assurance,
            term, or condition applicable to the award. Additionally, an award
            may be determined to be void if, for example, it was not authorized
            by statute or regulation or because it was fraudulently obtained.
            Appeals of determinations regarding the allowability of costs are
            subject to the procedures in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='2500' sect='048' psec='' tq='N'>
                2500.048
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Appeal Procedures.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The formal notification of an adverse determination will contain a
            statement of the awardee&apos;s appeal rights. To appeal an adverse 
            <PRTPAGE P='71' />
            determination, the awardee must submit a request for review to the
            OAO official specified in the notification, detailing the nature of
            the disagreement with the adverse determination and providing
            supporting documents in accordance with the procedures contained in
            the notification. The awardee&apos;s request to OAO for review must
            be received within 60 days after receipt of the written notification
            of the adverse determination; however, an extension may be granted
            if the awardee can show good cause why an extension is warranted.
            OAO will carefully consider the merits of all requests for appeals
            and further reviews. However, at the conclusion of the OAO appeal
            review process, the OAO decision rendered on the appeal is
            considered final. The awardee will be notified in writing by OAO of
            final appeal review determinations.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15883'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXV:-:2500:E:2500.053
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2500.053
      </num>
      <head>
        Expiring appropriations.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2500' sect='053' psec='' tq='N'>
              2500.053
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Expiring appropriations.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              OAO awards supported with office appropriations.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Most OAO awards are supported with annual appropriations. On
            September 30th of the 5th fiscal year after the period of
            availability for obligation ends, the funds for these appropriations
            accounts expire per 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='31' sect='1552' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/31/1552.html'>
                31 U.S.C. 1552
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and the account is closed, unless otherwise specified by law. Funds
            that have not been drawn through the approved electronic funds
            transfer system, by the awardee or disbursed through any other
            system or method by August 31st of that fiscal year are subject to
            be returned to the U.S. Department of the Treasury after that date.
            The August 31st requirement also applies to awards with a 90-day
            period concluding on a date after August 31st of that fifth year.
            Appropriations cannot be restored after expiration of the accounts.
            More specific instructions are provided in the OAO award terms and
            conditions.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              OAO awards supported with funds from other Federal agencies
              (reimbursable funds).
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             OAO may require that all draws and reimbursements for awards
            supported with reimbursable funds (from other Federal agencies) be
            completed prior to June 30th of the 5th fiscal year after the period
            of availability for obligation ends to allow for the proper billing,
            collection, and close-out of the associated interagency agreement
            before the appropriations expire. The June 30th requirement also
            applies to awards with a 90-day period concluding on a date after
            June 30th of that fifth year. Appropriations cannot be restored
            after expiration of the accounts. More specific instructions are
            provided in the terms and conditions of the OAO award agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15884'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXV:-:2500:E:2500.055
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2500.055
      </num>
      <head>
        Audit.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2500' sect='055' psec='' tq='N'>
              2500.055
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Audit.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Awardees must comply with the audit requirements of 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR part 
            <subref title='7' part='3052' tq='N'>
              3052
            </subref>
          </aref>
          . The audit requirements apply to the years in which Federal financial
          assistance funds are received and years in which work is accomplished
          using these funds.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15885'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXV:-:2500:E:2500.056
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2500.056
      </num>
      <head>
        Civil rights.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2500' sect='056' psec='' tq='N'>
              2500.056
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Civil rights.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Awardees must comply with the civil rights requirements of 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR part 
            <subref title='7' part='15' tq='N'>
              15
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , subpart A—USDA implementation of Title VI of the Civil Rights Act of
          1964, as amended. In accordance, no person in the United States shall,
          on the ground of race, color, or national origin, be excluded from
          participation in, be denied the benefits of, or be otherwise subjected
          to discrimination under any program or activity for which the
          recipient receives Federal financial assistance and will immediately
          take any measures necessary to effectuate this agreement.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15886'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXV:-:2500:F:2500.101
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2500.101
      </num>
      <head>
        Applicability of regulations.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2500' sect='101' psec='' tq='N'>
              2500.101
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Applicability of regulations.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The regulations in this subpart apply to the Outreach and Assistance
          for Socially Disadvantaged Farmers and Ranchers (OASDFR) Program
          authorized under 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 2501 of
          </aref>
           the Food, Agriculture, Conservation and Trade Act of 1990 (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='2279' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/2279.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 2279
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ), as amended. Unless otherwise specified in this subpart, the
          requirements of 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR part 
            <subref title='7' part='2500' tq='N'>
              2500
            </subref>
          </aref>
           subparts A through E will apply in addition to the requirements
          discussed in this subpart.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15887'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXV:-:2500:F:2500.102
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2500.102
      </num>
      <head>
        Purpose.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='72' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2500' sect='102' psec='' tq='N'>
              2500.102
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Purpose.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The purpose of the OASDFR Program is to make competitive awards to
            provide outreach and technical assistance to encourage and assist
            socially disadvantaged farmers and ranchers in:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Owning and operating farms, ranches and non-industrial forest
            lands; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In participating equitably in the full range of agricultural
            programs offered by the Department.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The OASDFR Program awards shall be used exclusively to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Enhance coordination of the outreach, technical assistance, and
            education efforts authorized under agriculture programs;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Assist in reaching current and prospective socially disadvantaged
            farmers, ranchers or forest landowners in a linguistically
            appropriate manner; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Improve the participation of those farmers and ranchers in
            agricultural programs.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15888'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXV:-:2500:F:2500.103
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2500.103
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2500' sect='103' psec='' tq='N'>
              2500.103
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The definitions provided in subpart A apply to this subpart. In
          addition, the definitions that apply specifically to the OASDFR
          Program under this subpart include:
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Agriculture programs
          </E>
           means those programs administered within the Department, by agencies
          including but not limited to: Forest Service (FS), Natural Resources
          Conservation Service (NRCS), Farm Service Agency (FSA), Risk
          Management Agency (RMA), Rural Development (RD), Rural Business
          Cooperative Service (RBCS), National Institute of Food and Agriculture
          (NIFA), and Agricultural Marketing Service (AMS), and other such
          programs as determined by the Department on a case-by-case basis
          either at the OAO Director&apos;s initiative or in response to a
          written request with supporting explanation for inclusion of a
          program. (For further details on specific programs included under this
          subpart see 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='2279' note='' psec='#e_3' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/2279.html#e_3'>
              7 U.S.C. 2279(e)(3)
            </subref>
          </aref>
           or the RFP).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Alaska Native
          </E>
           means a citizen of the United States who is a person of one-fourth or
          more Alaska Indian, Eskimo, or Aleut blood, or combination thereof.
          (For further specification, see 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='43' sect='1602' note='' psec='#b' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/43/1602.html#b'>
              43 U.S.C 1602(b)
            </subref>
          </aref>
           or the RFP).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Alaska Native cooperative colleges
          </E>
           means an eligible post-secondary educational institution that has an
          enrollment of undergraduate full-time equivalent students that is at
          least 20 percent Alaska Native students at the time of submission of a
          proposal.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Assistance
          </E>
           means providing educational and technical assistance to socially
          disadvantaged farmers, ranchers, and forest landowners in (1) owning
          and operating farms, ranches, and non-industrial forest lands; and (2)
          in participating equitably in the full range of agricultural programs
          offered by the Department through workshops, site visits and other
          means of contact in a linguistically appropriate manner.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Farmer, rancher, or forest landowner
          </E>
           means the person who primarily cultivates, operates, or manages a
          farm, ranch, or forest for profit, either as owner or tenant. A farm
          includes livestock, dairy, poultry, fish, fruit, and truck farms. It
          also includes plantations, ranches, ranges, and orchards.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Hispanic-serving institution
          </E>
           means an eligible institution of higher education that has an
          enrollment of undergraduate full-time equivalent students that is at
          least 25 percent Hispanic students at the end of the award year
          immediately preceding the date of submission of a proposal (see 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='20' sect='1101a' note='' psec='#5' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/20/1101a.html#5'>
              20 U.S.C. 1101a(5)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Indian tribe
          </E>
           means any Indian tribe, band, nation, or other organized group or
          community, including any Alaska Native village or regional or village
          corporation as defined in or established pursuant to the Alaska Native
          Claims Settlement Act (
          <aref target='_blank' href='http://frwebgate.access.gpo.gov/cgi-bin/getpage.cgi?dbname=92_statutes_at_large&amp;position=all&amp;page=688'>
            85 Stat. 688
          </aref>
          ) (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='43' sect='1601' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/43/1601.html'>
              43 U.S.C. 1601
            </subref>
          </aref>
          <E T='03'>
            et seq.
          </E>
          ), which is recognized as eligible for the special programs and
          services provided by the United States to Indians because of their
          status as Indians. (For further specification, see 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='25' sect='450b' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/25/450b.html'>
              25 U.S.C. 450b
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Indian tribal community college
          </E>
           means a post-secondary education institution which is formally
          controlled, or has been officially sanctioned, or chartered, by the
          governing body of an Indian tribe or tribes. (See 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='25' sect='1801' note='' psec='#a_4' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/25/1801.html#a_4'>
              25 U.S.C. 1801(a)(4)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Institution of higher education
          </E>
           means an educational institution in any State that is a public or
          other nonprofit institution that is legally authorized and 
          <PRTPAGE P='73' />
          accredited by a nationally recognized accrediting agency or
          association to provide a program of education beyond secondary
          education for which the institution awards a bachelor&apos;s degree.
          (For further specification, see 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='20' sect='1001' note='' psec='#a' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/20/1001.html#a'>
              20 U.S.C. 1001(a)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Outreach
          </E>
           means the use of formal and informal educational materials and
          activities in a linguistically appropriate manner that serve to
          encourage and assist socially disadvantaged farmers and ranchers in:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Owning and operating farms and ranches; and in
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Participating equitably in the full range of agricultural programs
            offered by the Department.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Socially disadvantaged farmer, rancher or forest landowner
          </E>
           means a farmer, rancher, or forest landowner who is a member of a
          socially disadvantaged group. (See 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='2279' note='' psec='#e_2' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/2279.html#e_2'>
              7 U.S.C. 2279(e)(2)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Socially disadvantaged group
          </E>
           means a group whose members have been subjected to racial or ethnic
          prejudice because of their identity as members of a group without
          regard to their individual qualities. (See 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='2279' note='' psec='#e_1' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/2279.html#e_1'>
              7 U.S.C. 2279(e)(1)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State
          </E>
           means any of the 50 States of the United States, the District of
          Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, the Virgin Islands of
          the United States, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern
          Mariana Islands, and federally recognized Indian tribes.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Supplemental funding
          </E>
           means funding to an existing awardee in addition to the amount of the
          original award contained in the grant or cooperative agreement. Such
          additional funding is intended to continue or expand work that is
          within the scope of the original agreement and statement of work.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Tribal organization
          </E>
           means the recognized governing body of any Indian tribe. A tribal
          organization is any legally established organization of Indians which
          is controlled, sanctioned, or chartered by such governing body or
          which is democratically elected by the adult members of the Indian
          community. In any case where an award is made to an organization to
          perform services benefiting more than one Indian tribe, the approval
          of each participating Indian tribe shall be a prerequisite to the
          making of such an award. (See 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='25' sect='1603' note='' psec='#25' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/25/1603.html#25'>
              25 U.S.C. 1603(25)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15889'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXV:-:2500:F:2500.104
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2500.104
      </num>
      <head>
        Eligibility requirements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2500' sect='104' psec='' tq='N'>
              2500.104
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Eligibility requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Proposals may be submitted by any of the following:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any community-based organization, network, or coalition of
            community-based organizations that:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Has demonstrated experience in providing agricultural education or
            other agriculturally related services to socially disadvantaged
            farmers, ranchers, and forest landowners;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Has provided to the Secretary documentary evidence of work with,
            and on behalf of socially disadvantaged farmers, ranchers, or forest
            landowners during the three-year period preceding the submission of
            a proposal for assistance under this program; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Does not engage in activities prohibited under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              Section 501(c)(3) of
            </aref>
             the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An 1890 institution or 1994 institution (as defined in 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='7601' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/7601.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 7601
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ), including West Virginia State University.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An Indian tribal community college or an Alaska Native cooperative
            college.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A Hispanic-serving institution (as defined in 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='3103' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/3103.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 3103
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any other institution of higher education (as defined in 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='20' sect='1001' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/20/1001.html'>
                20 U.S.C. 1001
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) that has demonstrated experience in providing agriculture
            education or other agriculturally related services to socially
            disadvantaged farmers, ranchers, and forest landowners in a region.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An Indian tribe (as defined in 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='25' sect='450b' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/25/450b.html'>
                25 U.S.C. 450b
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) or a national tribal organization that has demonstrated experience
            in providing agriculture education or other agriculturally-related
            services to socially disadvantaged farmers, ranchers, and forest
            landowners in a region.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Other organizations or institutions that received funding under
            this program before January 1, 1996, but only with respect to
            projects that the Secretary considers are similar to projects
            previously carried out by the entity under this program.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15890'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXV:-:2500:F:2500.105
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2500.105
      </num>
      <head>
        Project types and priorities.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2500' sect='105' psec='' tq='N'>
              2500.105
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Project types and priorities.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          For each RFP, OAO may develop and include the appropriate project
          types 
          <PRTPAGE P='74' />
          and focus areas based on the critical needs of the socially
          disadvantaged farmer and rancher community. For standard OASDFR
          projects, competitive grants or cooperative agreements will be awarded
          to support programs and services, as appropriate, to encourage and
          assist socially disadvantaged farmers and ranchers in the following
          focus areas:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Owning and operating farms and ranches;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Participating equitably in the full range of agricultural programs
            offered by the Department; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Other areas as specified by the Secretary in the RFP.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15891'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXV:-:2500:F:2500.106
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2500.106
      </num>
      <head>
        Funding restrictions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2500' sect='106' psec='' tq='N'>
              2500.106
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Funding restrictions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Funds made available under this subpart shall not be used for the
          construction of a new building or facility or the acquisition,
          expansion, remodeling, or alteration of an existing facility
          (including site grading and improvement, and architect fees).
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15892'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXV:-:2500:F:2500.107
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2500.107
      </num>
      <head>
        Matching.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2500' sect='107' psec='' tq='N'>
              2500.107
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Matching.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Matching funds are not required as a condition of receiving awards
          under this subpart.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15893'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXV:-:2500:F:2500.108
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2500.108
      </num>
      <head>
        Term of award.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2500' sect='108' psec='' tq='N'>
              2500.108
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Term of award.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The award term will be defined in the OAO award agreement, and can be
          later amended upon approval of OAO.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15894'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXV:-:2500:F:2500.109
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2500.109
      </num>
      <head>
        Program requirements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2500' sect='109' psec='' tq='N'>
              2500.109
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Program requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Grants and cooperative agreements under this subpart shall address the
          priorities in the Department that involve providing outreach and
          technical assistance to socially disadvantaged farmers, ranchers, and
          forest landowners to own and operate farms and participate equitably
          in agricultural programs; and other priorities as determined by the
          Secretary.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>