<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol3'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:59
    </extid>
    <num>
      59
    </num>
    <head>
      LIVESTOCK MANDATORY REPORTING
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='1635-163' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1635-163.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 1635-163
            </subref>
          </aref>
          6i.
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            73 FR 28633
          </aref>
          , May 16, 2008, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='3669'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:59:A:59.10
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        59.10
      </num>
      <head>
        General administrative provisions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='59' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
              59.10
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General administrative provisions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Reporting by packers and importers.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A packer or importer shall report all information required under
            this part on an individual lot basis.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Reporting schedule.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whenever a packer or importer is required to report information on
            transactions of livestock and livestock products under this part by
            a set time, all covered transactions up to within one half hour of
            the reporting deadline shall be reported. Transactions completed
            during the one half hour prior to the previous reporting time, but
            not reported in the previous report, shall be reported at the next
            scheduled reporting time.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Regional reporting and aggregation.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Secretary shall make information obtained under this part
            available to the public only in a manner that:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Ensures that the information is published on a national and a
            regional or statewide basis as the Secretary determines to be
            appropriate;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Ensures that the identity of a reporting person or the entity which
            they represent is not disclosed; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Market information reported to the Secretary by packers and
            importers shall be aggregated in such a manner that the market
            reports issued will not disclose the identity of persons, packers
            and importers, including parties to a contract and packer&apos;s and
            importer&apos;s proprietary information.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Adjustments.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Prior to the publication of any information required under this
            part, the Secretary may make reasonable adjustments in information
            reported by packers and importers to reflect price aberrations or
            other unusual or unique occurrences that the Secretary determines
            would distort the published information to the detriment of
            producers, packers, or other market participants.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Reporting of activities on weekends and holidays.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Livestock and livestock products committed to a packer, or
            importer, or purchased, sold, or slaughtered by a packer or importer
            on a weekend day or holiday shall be reported to the Secretary in
            accordance with the provisions of this Part and reported by the
            Secretary on the immediately following reporting day. A packer shall
            not be required to report such actions more than once on the
            immediately following reporting day.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Reporting methods.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whenever information is required to be reported under this part, it
            shall be reported by electronic means and shall adhere to a
            standardized format established by the Secretary to achieve the
            objectives of this part, except in emergencies or in cases when an
            alternative method is agreeable to the entity required to report and
            AMS.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3670'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:59:A:59.20
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        59.20
      </num>
      <head>
        Recordkeeping.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='59' sect='20' psec='' tq='N'>
              59.20
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Recordkeeping.
        </SUBJECT>
        <EXT-XREF HREF='20120525' REFID='1'>
          Link to an amendment published at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            77 FR 50573
          </aref>
          , Aug. 22, 2012.
        </EXT-XREF>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              In general.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each packer or importer required to report information to the
            Secretary under the Act and this Part shall maintain for 2 years and
            make available to the Secretary the following information on
            request:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The original contracts, agreements, receipts, and other records
            associated with any transaction relating to the purchase, sale,
            pricing, transportation, delivery, weighing, slaughter, or carcass
            characteristics of all livestock or livestock products; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Such records or other information as is necessary or appropriate to
            verify the accuracy of the information required to be reported under
            the Act and this Part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Purchases of cattle and swine and sales of boxed beef cuts.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A record of a purchase of a lot of cattle or swine, or a sale of a
            unit of boxed beef cuts, by a packer shall evidence whether the
            purchase or sale occurred:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Before 10 a.m. central time;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Between 10 a.m. and 2 p.m. central time; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             After 2 p.m. central time.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Purchases of lambs.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A record of a purchase of a lot of lambs by a packer shall evidence
            whether the purchase occurred:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Before 2 p.m. central time; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             After 2 p.m. central time.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Sales of lamb carcasses and sales of boxed lamb cuts.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A record of a sale by a packer of lamb carcasses and cuts, shall
            evidence time and date the sale occurred:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Before 2 p.m. central time; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             After 2 p.m. central time.
            <PRTPAGE P='157' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <FP>
          A record of sale by an importer of lamb cuts shall evidence the date
          the sale occurred.
        </FP>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Reporting sales of boxed beef cuts and sales of boxed lamb cuts.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Beef packers must report all sales of boxed beef items by the
            applicable Institutional Meat Purchase Specifications (IMPS) item
            number or the boxed beef items&apos; cutting and trimming
            specifications.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Lamb packers and importers must report all sales of boxed lamb
            items by the applicable Institutional Meat Purchase Specifications
            (IMPS) item number or the boxed lamb items&apos; cutting and
            trimming specifications.
          </text>
        </P>
        <EFFDNOTP>
          <HD SOURCE='HED'>
            Effective Date Note:
          </HD>
          <P>
            At 
            <aref type='FREGIST'>
              77 FR 50573
            </aref>
            , Aug. 22, 2012, 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='59' sect='20' psec='' tq='N'>
                59.20
              </subref>
            </aref>
             was amended by adding paragraph (f), effective Jan. 7, 2013. For
            the convenience of the user, the added text is set forth as follows:
          </P>
          <REVTXT>
            <SECTION>
              <SECTNO>
                <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
                  § 
                  <subref title='7' part='59' sect='20' psec='' tq='N'>
                    59.20
                  </subref>
                </aref>
              </SECTNO>
              <SUBJECT>
                Recordkeeping.
              </SUBJECT>
              <STARS />
              <P>
                (f) 
                <E T='03'>
                  Reporting sales of wholesale pork.
                </E>
                 A record of a sale of wholesale pork by a packer shall evidence
                whether the sale occurred:
              </P>
              <P>
                (1) Before 10:00 a.m. central time;
              </P>
              <P>
                (2) Between 10:00 a.m. and 2:00 p.m. central time; or
              </P>
              <P>
                (3) After 2:00 p.m. central time.
              </P>
            </SECTION>
          </REVTXT>
        </EFFDNOTP>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3671'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:59:A:59.30
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        59.30
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='59' sect='30' psec='' tq='N'>
              59.30
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The following definitions apply to this part.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Act.
          </E>
           The term “Act” means Subtitle B of the Agricultural Marketing Act of
          1946, as amended; 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='1635-163' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1635-163.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 1635-163
            </subref>
          </aref>
          6h.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Base price.
          </E>
           The term “base price” means the price paid for livestock, delivered
          at the packing plant, before application of any premiums or discounts,
          expressed in dollars per hundred pounds of hot carcass weight.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Basis level.
          </E>
           The term “basis level” means the agreed on adjustment to a future
          price to establish the final price paid for livestock.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Current slaughter week.
          </E>
           The term “current slaughter week” means the period beginning Monday,
          and ending Sunday, of the week in which a reporting day occurs.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Discount.
          </E>
           The term “discount” means the adjustment, expressed in dollars per
          one hundred pounds, subtracted from the base price due to weight,
          quality characteristics, yield characteristics, livestock class, dark
          cutting, breed, dressing percentage, or other characteristic.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Exported.
          </E>
           The term “exported” means livestock or livestock products that are
          physically shipped to locations outside of the 50 States.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            F.O.B.
          </E>
           The term “F.O.B.” means free on board, regardless of the mode of
          transportation, at the point of direct shipment by the seller to the
          buyer (e.g., F.O.B. Plant, F.O.B. Feedlot).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Imported.
          </E>
           The term “imported” means livestock that are raised to slaughter
          weight outside of the 50 States or livestock products produced outside
          of the 50 States.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Institutional Meat Purchase Specifications.
          </E>
           Specifications describing various meat cuts, meat products, and meat
          food products derived from all livestock species, commonly abbreviated
          “IMPS”, and intended for use by any meat procuring activity. Copies of
          the IMPS may be obtained from the U.S. Department of Agriculture,
          Agricultural Marketing Service, Livestock and Seed Program located at
          Room 2603 South Building, 1400 Independence Ave., SW., Washington, DC
          20250. Phone (202) 720-4486 or Fax (202) 720-1112. Copies may also be
          obtained over the Internet at: 
          <E T='03'>
            http://www.ams.usda.gov/lsg/stand/st-pubs.htm.
          </E>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Livestock.
          </E>
           The term “livestock” means cattle, swine, and lambs.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Lot.
          </E>
           (1) When used in reference to livestock, the term “lot” means a group
          of one or more livestock that is identified for the purpose of a
          single transaction between a buyer and a seller;
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When used in reference to lamb carcasses, the term “lot” means a
            group of one or more lamb carcasses sharing a similar weight range
            category and comprising a single transaction between a buyer and
            seller; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When used in reference to boxed beef and lamb, the term “lot” means
            a group of one or more boxes of beef or lamb items sharing cutting
            and trimming specifications and comprising a single transaction
            between a buyer and seller.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Marketing.
          </E>
           The term “marketing” means the sale or other disposition of
          livestock, livestock products, or meat or meat food products in
          commerce.
          <PRTPAGE P='158' />
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Negotiated purchase.
          </E>
           The term “negotiated purchase” means a cash or spot market purchase
          by a packer of livestock from a producer under which the base price
          for the livestock is determined by seller-buyer interaction and
          agreement on a delivery day. The livestock are scheduled for delivery
          to the packer not more than 14 days after the date on which the
          livestock are committed to the packer.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Negotiated grid purchase.
          </E>
           The term “negotiated grid purchase” in reference to cattle means the
          negotiation of a base price, from which premiums are added and
          discounts are subtracted, determined by seller-buyer interaction and
          agreement on a delivery day. The livestock are scheduled for delivery
          to the packer not more than 14 days after the date on which the
          livestock are committed to the packer.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Negotiated sale.
          </E>
           The term “negotiated sale” means a cash or spot market sale by a
          producer of livestock to a packer under which the base price for the
          livestock is determined by seller-buyer interaction and agreement on a
          delivery day. The livestock are scheduled for delivery to the packer
          not later than 14 days after the date on which the livestock are
          committed to the packer. When used in reference to sales of boxed beef
          or lamb cuts or lamb carcasses the term “negotiated sale” means a sale
          by a packer selling boxed beef or lamb cuts or lamb carcasses to a
          buyer of boxed beef or lamb cuts or lamb carcasses under which the
          price for the boxed beef or lamb cuts or lamb carcasses is determined
          by seller-buyer interaction and agreement on a day.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Origin.
          </E>
           The term “origin” means the State where the livestock were fed to
          slaughter weight.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Percent lean.
          </E>
           The term “percent lean” means the value equal to the average
          percentage of the carcass weight comprised of lean meat.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Person.
          </E>
           The term “person” means any individual, group of individuals,
          partnership, corporation, association, or other entity.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Premium.
          </E>
           The term “premium” means the adjustment, expressed in dollars per one
          hundred pounds, added to the base price due to weight, quality
          characteristics, yield characteristics, livestock class, and breed.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Priced.
          </E>
           The term “priced” means the time when the final price is determined
          either through buyer-seller interaction and agreement or as a result
          of some other price determining method.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Prior slaughter week.
          </E>
           The term prior “slaughter week” means the Monday through Sunday prior
          to a reporting day.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Producer.
          </E>
           The term “producer” means any person engaged in the business of
          selling livestock to a packer for slaughter (including the sale of
          livestock from a packer to another packer).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Purchased.
          </E>
           The term “purchased” means the agreement on a price, or the method
          for calculating a price, determined through buyer-seller interaction
          and agreement.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Reporting day.
          </E>
           The term “reporting day” means a day on which a packer conducts
          business regarding livestock committed to the packer, or livestock
          purchased, sold, or slaughtered by the packer; the Secretary is
          required to make such information available to the public; and the
          Department of Agriculture is open to conduct business.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Secretary.
          </E>
           The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Agriculture of the United
          States or any other officer or employee of the Department of
          Agriculture to whom authority has been delegated or may hereafter be
          delegated to act in the Secretary&apos;s stead.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State.
          </E>
           The term “State” means each of the 50 States.
        </P>
        <EFFDNOTP>
          <HD SOURCE='HED'>
            Effective Date Note:
          </HD>
          <P>
            At 
            <aref type='FREGIST'>
              77 FR 50573
            </aref>
            , Aug. 22, 2012, 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='59' sect='30' psec='' tq='N'>
                59.30
              </subref>
            </aref>
             was amended by revising the definition of “F.O.B.”, the last two
            sentences in the definition of “Institutional Meat Purchase
            Specifications”, and paragraph (3) of the definition of “Lot”,
            effective Jan. 7, 2013. For the convenience of the user, the revised
            text is set forth as follows:
          </P>
          <REVTXT>
            <SECTION>
              <SECTNO>
                <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
                  § 
                  <subref title='7' part='59' sect='30' psec='' tq='N'>
                    59.30
                  </subref>
                </aref>
              </SECTNO>
              <SUBJECT>
                Definitions.
              </SUBJECT>
              <STARS />
              <P>
                <E T='03'>
                  F.O.B.
                </E>
                 The term “F.O.B.” means free on board, regardless of the mode
                of transportation, at the point of direct shipment by the seller
                to the buyer (e.g., F.O.B. Plant, F.O.B. Feedlot) or from a
                common basis point to the buyer (e.g., F.O.B. Omaha).
                <STARS />
              </P>
              <P>
                <E T='03'>
                  Institutional Meat Purchase Specifications.
                </E>
                 * * * Phone (202) 260-8295 or Fax (202) 720-
                <PRTPAGE P='159' />
                1112. Copies may also be obtained over the Internet at 
                <E T='03'>
                  http://www.ams.usda.gov/AMSv1.0/LivestockStandardizationIMPS.
                </E>
                <STARS />
              </P>
              <P>
                <E T='03'>
                  Lot.
                </E>
                 * * *
              </P>
              <P>
                (3) When used in reference to boxed beef, wholesale pork, and
                lamb, the term `lot&apos; means a group of one or more boxes of
                beef, wholesale pork, or lamb items sharing cutting and trimming
                specifications and comprising a single transaction between a
                buyer and seller.
                <STARS />
              </P>
            </SECTION>
          </REVTXT>
        </EFFDNOTP>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3672'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:59:B:59.100
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        59.100
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='59' sect='100' psec='' tq='N'>
              59.100
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The following definitions apply to this subpart.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Boxed beef.
          </E>
           The term “boxed beef” means those carlot-based portions of a beef
          carcass including fresh and frozen primals, subprimals, cuts
          fabricated from subprimals (excluding portion-control cuts such as
          chops and steaks similar to those portion cut items described in the
          Institutional Meat Purchase Specifications (IMPS) for Fresh Beef
          Products Series 100), thin meats (e.g. inside and outside skirts,
          pectoral meat, cap and wedge meat, and blade meat), and fresh and
          frozen ground beef, beef trimmings, and boneless processing beef.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Branded.
          </E>
           The term “branded” means boxed beef cuts produced and marketed under
          a corporate trademark (for example, products that are marketed on
          their quality, yield, or breed characteristics), or boxed beef cuts
          produced and marketed under one of USDA&apos;s Meat Grading and
          Certification Branch, Certified Beef programs.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Carcass characteristics.
          </E>
           The term “carcass characteristics” means the range and average
          carcass weight in pounds, the quality grade and yield grade (if
          applicable), and the average cattle dressing percentage.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Carlot-based.
          </E>
           The term “carlot-based” means any transaction between a buyer and a
          seller destined for two or less delivery stops consisting of one or
          more individual boxed beef items. When used in reference to cow and
          bull boxed beef items, the term “carlot-based” means any transaction
          between a buyer and seller consisting of 2,000 pounds or more of one
          or more individual items.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Cattle committed.
          </E>
           The term “cattle committed” means cattle that are scheduled to be
          delivered to a packer within the 7-day period beginning on the date of
          an agreement to sell the cattle.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Cattle type.
          </E>
           The term “cattle type” means the following types of cattle purchased
          for slaughter:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Fed steers;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Fed heifers;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Fed Holsteins and other fed dairy steers and heifers;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Cows; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bulls.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Established
          </E>
          . The term “established”, when used in connection with prices, means
          that point in time when the buyer and seller agree upon a net price.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Formula marketing arrangement
          </E>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When used in reference to live cattle, the term “formula marketing
            arrangement” means the advance commitment of cattle for slaughter by
            any means other than through a negotiated purchase or a forward
            contract, using a method for calculating price in which the price is
            determined at a future date.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When used in reference to boxed beef, the term “formula marketing
            arrangement” means the advance commitment of boxed beef by any means
            other than through a negotiated purchase or a forward contract,
            using a method for calculating price in which the price is
            determined at a future date.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Forward contract.
          </E>
           (1) When used in reference to live cattle, the term “forward
          contract” means an agreement for the purchase of cattle, executed in
          advance of slaughter, under which the base price is established by
          reference to prices quoted on the Chicago Mercantile Exchange, or
          other comparable publicly available prices.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When used in reference to boxed beef, the term “forward contract”
            means an agreement for the sale of boxed beef, executed in advance
            of manufacture, under which the base price is established by
            reference to publicly available quoted prices.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Packer
          </E>
          . The term “packer” means any person engaged in the business of 
          <PRTPAGE P='160' />
          buying cattle in commerce for purposes of slaughter, of manufacturing
          or preparing meats or meat food products from cattle for sale or
          shipment in commerce, or of marketing meats or meat food products from
          cattle in an unmanufactured form acting as a wholesale broker, dealer,
          or distributor in commerce. For any calendar year, the term “packer”
          includes only a federally inspected cattle processing plant that
          slaughtered an average of 125,000 head of cattle per year during the
          immediately preceding 5 calendar years. Additionally, in the case of a
          cattle processing plant that did not slaughter cattle during the
          immediately preceding 5 calendar years, it shall be considered a
          packer if the Secretary determines the processing plant should be
          considered a packer under this subpart after considering its capacity.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Packer-owned cattle
          </E>
          . The term “packer-owned cattle” means cattle that a packer owns for
          at least 14 days immediately before slaughter.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Prices for cattle
          </E>
          . The term “prices for cattle” includes the price per hundredweight;
          the purchase type; the quantity on a live and a dressed weight basis;
          the estimated live weight range; the average live weight; the
          estimated percentage of cattle of a USDA quality grade Choice or
          better; beef carcass classification; any premiums or discounts
          associated with weight, quality grade, yield grade, or type of
          purchase; cattle State of origin; estimated cattle dressing
          percentage; and price basis as F.O.B. feedlot or delivered at the
          plant.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Terms of trade
          </E>
          . The term “terms of trade” means, with respect to the purchase of
          steers and heifers for slaughter:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whether a packer provided any financing agreement or arrangement
            with regard to the steers and heifers;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whether the delivery terms specified the location of the producer
            or the location of the packer&apos;s plant;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whether the producer is able to unilaterally specify the date and
            time during the business day of the packer that the cattle are to be
            delivered for slaughter; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The percentage of steers and heifers purchased by a packer as a
            negotiated purchase that are scheduled to be delivered to the plant
            for slaughter not later than 14 days and the percentage of slaughter
            steers and heifers purchased by a packer as a negotiated purchase
            that are scheduled to be delivered to the plant for slaughter more
            than 14 days, but fewer than 30 days.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Type of purchase
          </E>
          . The term “type of purchase” with respect to cattle, means a
          negotiated purchase, negotiated grid purchase, a formula market
          arrangement, and a forward contract.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Type of sale
          </E>
          . The term “type of sale” with respect to boxed beef, means a
          negotiated sale, a formula market arrangement, and a forward contract.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            White cow
          </E>
          . Cow on a ration that tends to produce white fat.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3673'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:59:B:59.101
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        59.101
      </num>
      <head>
        Mandatory daily reporting for steers and heifers.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='59' sect='101' psec='' tq='N'>
              59.101
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Mandatory daily reporting for steers and heifers.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              In general.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The corporate officers or officially designated representatives of
            each steer and heifer packer processing plant shall report to the
            Secretary at least two times each reporting day not later than 10
            a.m. central time and not later than 2 p.m. central time the
            following information, inclusive since the last reporting,
            categorized to clearly delineate domestic from imported market
            purchases as described in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='59' sect='10' psec='#b' tq='N'>
                59.10(b)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The prices for cattle (per hundredweight) established on that day,
            categorized by:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The type of purchase;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The quantity of cattle purchased on a live weight basis;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The quantity of cattle purchased on a dressed weight basis;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The estimated weights of cattle purchased;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An estimate of the percentage of the cattle purchased that were of
            a quality grade of Choice or better; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any premiums or discounts associated with weight, quality grade,
            yield grade, or other characteristic expressed in dollars per
            hundredweight on a dressed basis.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The quantity of cattle delivered to the packer (quoted in numbers
            of head) on that day, categorized by:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The type of purchase;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The quantity of cattle delivered on a live weight basis; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The quantity of cattle delivered on a dressed weight basis.
            <PRTPAGE P='161' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The quantity of cattle committed to the packer (quoted in numbers
            of head) as of that day, categorized by:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The type of purchase;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The quantity of cattle committed on a live weight basis; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The quantity of cattle committed on a dressed weight basis.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The terms of trade regarding the cattle, as applicable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Publication.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Secretary shall make the information available to the public
            not less frequently than three times each reporting day.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3674'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:59:B:59.102
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        59.102
      </num>
      <head>
        Mandatory daily reporting for cows and bulls.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='59' sect='102' psec='' tq='N'>
              59.102
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Mandatory daily reporting for cows and bulls.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              In General.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The corporate officers or officially designated representatives of
            each cow and bull packer processing plant shall report to the
            Secretary each reporting day the following information for each
            cattle type, inclusive since the last reporting, categorized to
            clearly delineate domestic from imported market purchases as
            described in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='59' sect='10' psec='#b' tq='N'>
                59.10(b)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The base bid price (per hundredweight) intended to be paid for
            slaughter cow and bull carcasses on that day not later than 10 a.m.
            central time categorized by:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Weight; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For slaughter cows, percent lean (e.g., breaker, boner, cutter
            (lean)).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The prices for cattle (per hundredweight) purchased during the
            previous day not later than 2 p.m. central time categorized by:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The type of purchase;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The quantity of cattle purchased on a live weight basis;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The quantity of cattle purchased on a dressed weight basis;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The estimated weight of the cattle purchased;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The quality classification; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any premiums or discounts associated with weight or quality
            expressed in dollars per hundredweight on a dressed basis.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The volume of cows and bulls slaughtered the previous day.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Publication.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Secretary shall make the information available to the public
            within one hour of the required reporting time on the reporting day
            on which the information is received from the packer.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3675'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:59:B:59.103
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        59.103
      </num>
      <head>
        Mandatory weekly reporting for steers and heifers.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='59' sect='103' psec='' tq='N'>
              59.103
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Mandatory weekly reporting for steers and heifers.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              In general.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The corporate officers or officially designated representatives of
            each steer and heifer packer processing plant shall report to the
            Secretary on the first reporting day of each week, not later than 9
            a.m. central time, the following information applicable to the prior
            slaughter week, categorized to clearly delineate domestic from
            imported market purchases:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The quantity of cattle purchased through a negotiated basis that
            were slaughtered;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The quantity of cattle purchased through a negotiated grid basis
            that were slaughtered;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The quantity of cattle purchased through forward contracts that
            were slaughtered;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The quantity of cattle delivered under a formula marketing
            arrangement that were slaughtered;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The quantity and carcass characteristics of packer-owned cattle
            that were slaughtered;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The quantity, basis level, basis level month, and delivery month
            and year for all cattle purchased through forward contracts;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The range and average of intended premiums and discounts (including
            those associated with weight, quality grade, yield grade, or type of
            cattle) that are expected to be in effect for the current slaughter
            week.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Publication.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Secretary shall make available to the public the information
            obtained under paragraph (a) of this section on the first reporting
            day of the current slaughter week by 10 a.m. central time.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3676'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:59:B:59.104
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        59.104
      </num>
      <head>
        Mandatory reporting of boxed beef sales.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='59' sect='104' psec='' tq='N'>
              59.104
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Mandatory reporting of boxed beef sales.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Daily reporting.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The corporate officers or officially designated representatives of
            each packer processing plant shall report to the Secretary at least
            twice each reporting day (once by 10 a.m. central time, and once by
            2 p.m. central time) the following information on total boxed beef
            domestic and export sales established on that day inclusive since
            the last reporting as described in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='59' sect='10' psec='#b' tq='N'>
                59.10(b)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            :
            <PRTPAGE P='162' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The price for each lot of each boxed beef sale, quoted in dollars
            per hundredweight on a F.O.B. plant basis;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The quantity for each lot of each sale, quoted by number of pounds
            sold; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The information regarding the characteristics of each sale is as
            follows:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The type of sale;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The branded product characteristics, if applicable;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The grade for steer and heifer beef (e.g., USDA Prime, USDA Choice
            or better, USDA Choice, USDA Select, ungraded no-roll product);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The grade for cow beef or packer yield and/or quality sort for cow
            beef (e.g., Breakers, Boners, White Cow, Cutters (lean));
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The cut of beef, referencing the most recent version of the
            Institutional Meat Purchase Specifications (IMPS), when applicable;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The trim specification;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_vii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The weight range of the cut;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_viii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (viii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The product delivery period; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_ix'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ix)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The beef type (steer/heifer, dairy steer/heifer, or cow).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Publication.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Secretary shall make available to the public the information
            obtained under paragraph (a) of this section not less frequently
            than twice each reporting day.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3677'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:59:C:59.200
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        59.200
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='59' sect='200' psec='' tq='N'>
              59.200
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The following definitions apply to this subpart.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Affiliate.
          </E>
           The term “affiliate”, with respect to a packer, means:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A person that directly or indirectly owns, controls, or holds with
            power to vote, 5 percent or more of the outstanding voting
            securities of the packer;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A person 5 percent or more of whose outstanding voting securities
            are directly or indirectly owned, controlled, or held with power to
            vote, by the packer; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A person that directly or indirectly controls, or is controlled by
            or under common control with, the packer.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Applicable reporting period
          </E>
          . The term “applicable reporting period” means the period of time
          prescribed by the prior day report, the morning report, and the
          afternoon report, as provided in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='59' sect='202' psec='' tq='N'>
              59.202
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Average carcass weight
          </E>
          . The term “average carcass weight” means the weight obtained by
          dividing the total carcass weight of the swine slaughtered at the
          packing plant during the applicable reporting period by the number of
          these same swine.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Average lean percentage
          </E>
          . The term “average lean percentage” means the value equal to the
          average percentage of the carcass weight comprised of lean meat for
          the swine slaughtered during the applicable reporting period. Whenever
          the packer changes the manner in which the average lean percentage is
          calculated, the packer shall make available to the Secretary the
          underlying data, applicable methodology and formulae, and supporting
          materials used to determine the average lean percentage, which the
          Secretary may convert either to the carcass measurements or lean
          percentage of the swine of the individual packer to correlate to a
          common percent lean measurement.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Average net price
          </E>
          . The term “average net price” means the quotient (stated per hundred
          pounds of carcass weight of swine) obtained by dividing the total
          amount paid for the swine slaughtered at a packing plant during the
          applicable reporting period (including all premiums and less all
          discounts) by the total carcass weight of the swine (in hundred pound
          increments).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Average sort loss
          </E>
          . The term “average sort loss” means the average discount (in dollars
          per hundred pounds carcass weight) for swine slaughtered during the
          applicable reporting period, resulting from the fact that the swine
          did not fall within the individual packer&apos;s established carcass
          weight range or lot variation range.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Backfat
          </E>
          . The term “backfat” means the fat thickness (in inches) measured
          between the third and fourth rib from the last rib, 7 centimeters from
          the carcass split (or adjusted from the individual packer&apos;s
          measurement to that reference point using an adjustment made by the
          Secretary) of the swine slaughtered during the applicable reporting
          period.
          <PRTPAGE P='163' />
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Barrow
          </E>
          . The term “barrow” means a neutered male swine, with the neutering
          performed before the swine reached sexual maturity.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Base market hog
          </E>
          . The term “base market hog” means a barrow or gilt for which no
          discounts are subtracted from and no premiums are added to the base
          price.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Base price
          </E>
          . The term “base price” means the price from which no discounts are
          subtracted and no premiums are added.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Boars
          </E>
          . The term “boar” means a sexually-intact male swine.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Bred female swine
          </E>
          . The term “bred female swine” means any female swine, whether a sow
          or gilt, that has been mated or inseminated, or has been confirmed, to
          be pregnant.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Formula price
          </E>
          . The term “formula price” means a price determined by a mathematical
          formula under which the price established for a specified market
          serves as the basis for the formula.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Gilt
          </E>
          . The term “gilt” means a young female swine that has not produced a
          litter.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Hog Class
          </E>
          . The term “hog class” means, as applicable, barrows or gilts; sows;
          or boars or stags.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Inferior swine
          </E>
          . The term “inferior swine” means swine that are discounted in the
          market place due to light-weight, health, or physical conditions that
          affects their value.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Loin depth
          </E>
          . The term “loin depth” means the muscle depth (in inches) measured
          between the third and fourth ribs from the last rib, 7 centimeters
          from the carcass split (or adjusted from the individual packer&apos;s
          measurement to that reference point using an adjustment made by the
          Secretary) of the swine slaughtered during the applicable reporting
          period.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Net price
          </E>
          . The term “net price” means the total amount paid by a packer to a
          producer (including all premiums, less all discounts) per hundred
          pounds of carcass weight of swine delivered at the plant. The total
          amount paid shall include any sum deducted from the price (per
          hundredweight) paid to a producer that reflects the repayment of a
          balance owed by the producer to the packer or the accumulation of a
          balance to later be repaid by the packer to the producer. The total
          amount paid shall exclude any sum earlier paid to a producer that must
          be repaid to the packer.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Noncarcass merit premium
          </E>
          . The term “noncarcass merit premium” means an increase in the base
          price of the swine offered by an individual packer or packing plant,
          based on any factor other than the characteristics of the carcass, if
          the actual amount of the premium is known before the sale and delivery
          of the swine.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Other market formula purchase
          </E>
          . The term “other market formula purchase” means a purchase of swine
          by a packer in which the pricing mechanism is a formula price based on
          any market other than the market for swine, pork, or a pork product.
          The term “other market formula purchase” includes a formula purchase
          in a case which the price formula is based on 1 or more futures or
          options contracts.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Other purchase arrangement
          </E>
          . The term “other purchase arrangement” means a purchase of swine by a
          packer that is not a negotiated purchase, swine or pork market formula
          purchase, or other market formula purchase; and does not involve
          packer-owned swine.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Packer
          </E>
          . The term “packer” means any person engaged in the business of buying
          swine in commerce for purposes of slaughter, of manufacturing or
          preparing meats or meat food products from swine for sale or shipment
          in commerce, or of marketing meats or meat food products from swine in
          an unmanufactured form acting as a wholesale broker, dealer, or
          distributor in commerce. For any calendar year, the term “packer”
          includes only a federally inspected swine processing plant that
          slaughtered an average of 100,000 head of swine per year during the
          immediately preceding 5 calendar years and a person that slaughtered
          an average of 200,000 head of sows, boars, or combination thereof per
          year during the immediately preceding 5 calendar years. Additionally,
          in the case of a swine processing plant or person that did not
          slaughter swine during the immediately preceding 5 calendar years, it
          shall be considered a packer if the Secretary determines the
          processing plant or person should be considered a packer under this
          subpart after considering its capacity.
          <PRTPAGE P='164' />
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Packer-owned swine
          </E>
          . The term “packer-owned swine” means swine that a packer (including a
          subsidiary or affiliate of the packer) owns for at least 14 days
          immediately before slaughter.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Packer-sold swine
          </E>
          . The term “packer-sold swine” means the swine that are owned by a
          packer (including a subsidiary or affiliate of the packer) for more
          than 14 days immediately before sale for slaughter; and sold for
          slaughter to another packer.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Pork
          </E>
          . The term “pork” means the meat of a porcine animal.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Pork product
          </E>
          . The term “pork product” means a product or byproduct produced or
          processed in whole or in part from pork.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Purchase data
          </E>
          . The term “purchase data” means all of the applicable data, including
          base price and weight (if purchased live), for all swine purchased
          during the applicable reporting period, regardless of the expected
          delivery date of the swine, reported by:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Hog class;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Type of purchase; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Packer-owned swine.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Slaughter data
          </E>
          . The term “slaughter data” means all of the applicable data for all
          swine slaughtered by a packer during the applicable reporting period,
          regardless of whether the price of the swine was negotiated or
          otherwise determined, reported by:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Hog class;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Type of purchase; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Packer-owned swine.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Sow
          </E>
          . The term “sow” means an adult female swine that has produced 1 or
          more litters.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Stag
          </E>
          . The term “stag” means a male swine that was neutered after reaching
          sexual maturity.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Swine
          </E>
          . The term “swine” means a porcine animal raised to be a feeder pig,
          raised for seedstock, or raised for slaughter.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Swine committed
          </E>
          . The term “swine committed” means swine scheduled and delivered to a
          packer within the 14-day period beginning on the date of an agreement
          to sell the swine.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Swine or pork market formula purchase
          </E>
          . The term “swine or pork market formula purchase” means a purchase of
          swine by a packer in which the pricing mechanism is a formula price
          based on a market for swine, pork, or a pork product, other than a
          future or option for swine, pork, or a pork product.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Type of purchase
          </E>
          . The term “type of purchase”, with respect to swine, means:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A negotiated purchase;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Other market formula purchase;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A swine or pork market formula purchase; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Other purchase arrangement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <EFFDNOTP>
          <HD SOURCE='HED'>
            Effective Date Note:
          </HD>
          <P>
            At 
            <aref type='FREGIST'>
              77 FR 50573
            </aref>
            , Aug. 22, 2012, 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='59' sect='200' psec='' tq='N'>
                59.200
              </subref>
            </aref>
             was amended by adding definitions for “Formula marketing
            arrangement”, “Forward sale”, “Negotiated sale”, “Pork class”,
            “Specialty pork product”, “Type of sale”, “Variety meats”, and
            “Wholesale pork”, effective Jan. 7, 2013. For the convenience of the
            user, the added text is set forth as follows:
          </P>
          <REVTXT>
            <SECTION>
              <SECTNO>
                <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
                  § 
                  <subref title='7' part='59' sect='200' psec='' tq='N'>
                    59.200
                  </subref>
                </aref>
              </SECTNO>
              <SUBJECT>
                Definitions.
              </SUBJECT>
              <STARS />
              <P>
                <E T='03'>
                  Formula marketing arrangement.
                </E>
                 When used in reference to wholesale pork, the term `formula
                marketing arrangement&apos; means an agreement for the sale of
                pork under which the price is established in reference to
                publicly-available quoted prices.
                <STARS />
              </P>
              <P>
                <E T='03'>
                  Forward sale.
                </E>
                 When used in reference to wholesale pork, the term `forward
                sale&apos; means an agreement for the sale of pork where the
                delivery is beyond the timeframe of a “negotiated sale” and
                means a sale by a packer selling wholesale pork to a buyer of
                wholesale pork under which the price is determined by
                seller-buyer interaction and agreement.
                <STARS />
              </P>
              <P>
                <E T='03'>
                  Negotiated sale.
                </E>
                 The term `negotiated sale&apos; means a sale by a packer
                selling wholesale pork to a buyer of wholesale pork under which
                the price is determined by seller-buyer interaction and
                agreement, and scheduled for delivery not later than 14 days for
                boxed product and 10 days for combo product after the date of
                agreement. The day after the seller-buyer agreement shall be
                considered day one for reporting delivery periods.
                <STARS />
              </P>
              <P>
                <E T='03'>
                  Pork class.
                </E>
                 The term “pork class” means the following types of swine
                purchased for slaughter:
              </P>
              <P>
                (1) Barrow/gilt;
              </P>
              <P>
                (2) Sow;
                <PRTPAGE P='165' />
              </P>
              <P>
                (3) Boar.
                <STARS />
              </P>
              <P>
                <E T='03'>
                  Specialty pork product.
                </E>
                 The term `specialty pork product&apos; means wholesale pork
                produced and marketed under any specialty program such as, but
                not limited to, genetically-selected pork, certified programs,
                or specialty selection programs for quality or breed
                characteristics.
                <STARS />
              </P>
              <P>
                <E T='03'>
                  Type of sale.
                </E>
                 The term “type of sale” with respect to wholesale pork means a
                negotiated sale, forward sale, or formula marketing arrangement.
              </P>
              <P>
                <E T='03'>
                  Variety meats.
                </E>
                 The term `variety meats&apos; with respect to wholesale pork
                means cut/processing floor items, such as neck bones, tails,
                skins, feet, hocks, jowls, and backfat.
              </P>
              <P>
                <E T='03'>
                  Wholesale pork.
                </E>
                 The term `wholesale pork&apos; means fresh and frozen primals,
                sub-primals, cuts fabricated from sub-primals, pork trimmings,
                pork for processing, and variety meats (excluding
                portion-control cuts, cuts flavored above and beyond normal
                added ingredients that are used to enhance products, cured,
                smoked, cooked, and tray packed products). When referring to
                wholesale pork, added ingredients are used to enhance the
                product&apos;s performance (e.g. tenderness, juiciness) through
                adding a solution or emulsion via an injection or immersion
                process. The ingredients shall be limited to water, salt, sodium
                phosphate, antimicrobials, or any other similar combination of
                foresaid or similar ingredients and in accordance with
                established USDA regulations.
              </P>
            </SECTION>
          </REVTXT>
        </EFFDNOTP>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3678'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:59:C:59.201
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        59.201
      </num>
      <head>
        General reporting provisions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='59' sect='201' psec='' tq='N'>
              59.201
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General reporting provisions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Packer-owned swine.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Information required under this section for packer-owned swine
            shall include quantity and carcass characteristics, but not price.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Type of purchase.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If information regarding the type of purchase is required under
            this section, the information shall be reported according to the
            numbers and percentages of each type of purchase comprising:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Packer-sold swine; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All other swine.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3679'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:59:C:59.202
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        59.202
      </num>
      <head>
        Mandatory daily reporting for barrows and gilts.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='59' sect='202' psec='' tq='N'>
              59.202
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Mandatory daily reporting for barrows and gilts.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Prior day report.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The corporate officers or officially designated representatives of
            each packer that processes barrows and gilts shall report to the
            Secretary for each business day of the packer not later than 7 a.m.
            central time on each reporting day information regarding all barrows
            and gilts purchased or priced, during the prior business day of the
            packer, and not later than 9 a.m. central time on each reporting day
            information regarding all barrows and gilts slaughtered, excluding
            inferior swine, as specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='59' sect='10' psec='#b' tq='N'>
                59.10(b)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            :
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All purchase data, reported by lot, including:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The total number of barrows and gilts purchased;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The total number of barrows and gilts scheduled for delivery to a
            packer for slaughter;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The base price and weight for all barrows and gilts purchased on a
            live weight basis; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The base price and premiums and discounts paid for carcass
            characteristics for all barrows and gilts purchased on a carcass
            basis for which a price has been established. For barrows and gilts
            that were not priced, this information shall be reported on the next
            prior day report after the price is established.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The following slaughter data for the total number of barrows and
            gilts slaughtered:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The average net price;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The average carcass weight;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The average sort loss;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The average backfat;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The average loin depth;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The average lean percentage; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_vii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Total quantity slaughtered.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Packer purchase commitments, which shall be equal to the number of
            barrows and gilts scheduled for delivery to a packer for slaughter
            for each of the next 14 calendar days.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Secretary shall publish the information obtained in paragraph
            (a) of this section in a prior day report not later than 8 a.m.
            central time for all barrows and gilts purchased and 10 a.m. central
            time for all barrows and gilts slaughtered on the reporting day on
            which the information is received from the packer. In addition, the
            Secretary shall publish a net price distribution for all barrows and
            gilts slaughtered on the previous day not later than 3 p.m. central
            time.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Morning report.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The corporate officers or officially designated representatives of
            each packer processing plant that processes barrows and gilts shall
            report to the Secretary not later than 
            <PRTPAGE P='166' />
            10 a.m. central time each reporting day as described in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='59' sect='10' psec='#b' tq='N'>
                59.10(b)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            :
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The packer&apos;s best estimate of the total number of barrows and
            gilts, and barrows and gilts that qualify as packer-owned swine,
            expected to be purchased throughout the reporting day through each
            type of purchase;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The total number of barrows and gilts, and barrows and gilts that
            qualify as packer-owned swine, purchased up to that time of the
            reporting day through each type of purchase;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All purchase data for base market hogs purchased up to that time of
            the reporting day through negotiated purchases; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All purchase data for base market hogs purchased through each type
            of purchase other than negotiated purchase up to that time of the
            reporting day, unless such information is unavailable due to pricing
            that is determined on a delayed basis. The packer shall report
            information on such purchases on the first reporting day or
            scheduled reporting time on a reporting day after the price has been
            determined.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Secretary shall publish the information obtained in paragraph
            (b) of this section in the morning report as soon as practicable,
            but not later than 11 a.m. central time, on each reporting day.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Afternoon report.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The corporate officers or officially designated representatives of
            each packer processing plant that processes barrows and gilts shall
            report to the Secretary not later than 2 p.m. central time each
            reporting day as described in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='59' sect='10' psec='#b' tq='N'>
                59.10(b)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            :
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The packer&apos;s best estimate of the total number of barrows and
            gilts, and barrows and gilts that qualify as packer-owned swine
            expected to be purchased throughout the reporting day through each
            type of purchase;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The total number of barrows and gilts, and barrows and gilts that
            qualify as packer-owned swine, purchased up to that time of the
            reporting day through each type of purchase;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The base price paid for all base market hogs purchased up to that
            time of the reporting day through negotiated purchases; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The base price paid for all base market hogs purchased through each
            type of purchase other than negotiated purchase up to that time of
            the reporting day, unless such information is unavailable due to
            pricing that is determined on a delayed basis. The packer shall
            report information on such purchases on the first reporting day or
            scheduled reporting time on a reporting day after the price has been
            determined.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Secretary shall publish the information obtained in paragraph
            (c) of this section in the afternoon report as soon as practicable,
            but not later than 3 p.m. central time, on each reporting day.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3680'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:59:C:59.203
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        59.203
      </num>
      <head>
        Mandatory daily reporting for sows and boars.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='59' sect='203' psec='' tq='N'>
              59.203
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Mandatory daily reporting for sows and boars.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Prior day report.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The corporate officers or officially designated representatives of
            each packer of sows and boars shall report to the Secretary for each
            business day of the packer not later than 7 a.m. central time on
            each reporting day information regarding all sows and boars
            purchased or priced, excluding inferior swine, during the prior
            business day of the packer all purchase data, reported by lot,
            including:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The total number of sows and boars purchased divided into at least
            three weight groups as specified by the Secretary;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The average price paid by each purchase type for all sows in each
            weight class specified by the Secretary; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The average price paid by each purchase type for all boars in each
            weight class specified by the Secretary.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The packer is required to report only the volume of sows and boars
            that qualify as packer owned swine and shall omit packer owned sows
            and boars from all average price calculations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Publication.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Secretary shall publish the information obtained in paragraph
            (a) of this section as soon as practicable, but not later than 8
            a.m. central time, on the reporting day on which the information is
            received from the packer.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3681'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:59:C:59.204
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        59.204
      </num>
      <head>
        Mandatory weekly reporting for swine.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='167' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='59' sect='204' psec='' tq='N'>
              59.204
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Mandatory weekly reporting for swine.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Weekly noncarcass merit premium report.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Not later than 4 p.m. central time in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='59' sect='10' psec='#b' tq='N'>
                59.10(b)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             on the first reporting day of each week, the corporate officers or
            officially designated representatives of each packer processing
            plant shall report to the Secretary a noncarcass merit premium
            report that lists:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each category of standard noncarcass merit premiums used by the
            packer in the prior slaughter week; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The dollar value (in dollars per hundred pounds of carcass weight)
            paid to producers by the packer, by category.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Premium list.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A packer shall maintain and make available to a producer, on
            request, a current listing of the dollar values (per hundred pounds
            of carcass weight) of each noncarcass merit premium used by the
            packer during the current or the prior slaughter week.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Publication.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Secretary shall publish the information obtained under this
            subsection as soon as practicable, but not later than 5 p.m. central
            time, on the first reporting day of each week.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3682'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:59:C:59.205
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        59.205
      </num>
      <head>
        Mandatory reporting of wholesale pork sales.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='59' sect='205' psec='' tq='N'>
              59.205
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Mandatory reporting of wholesale pork sales.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Daily reporting.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The corporate officers or officially designated representatives of
            each packer processing plant shall report to the Secretary at least
            twice each reporting day for barrows and gilts (once by 10 a.m.
            central time, and once by 2 p.m. central time) and once each
            reporting day for sows and boars (by 2 p.m. central time) the
            following information on total pork sales established on that day
            inclusive since the last reporting as described in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='59' sect='10' psec='#b' tq='N'>
                59.10(b)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            :
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The price for each wholesale pork sale, as defined herein, quoted
            in dollars per hundredweight on an F.O.B. Plant and an F.O.B. Omaha
            basis as outlined in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='59' sect='205' psec='#d' tq='N'>
                59.205(d)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . The price shall include brokerage fees, if applicable. All direct,
            specific, and identifiable marketing costs (such as point of
            purchase material, marketing funds, accruals, rebates, and export
            costs) shall be deducted from the net price if applicable and known
            at the time of sale;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The quantity for each pork sale, quoted by number of pounds sold;
            and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The information regarding the characteristics of each sale is as
            follows:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The type of sale;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Pork item description;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Pork item product code;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The product delivery period, in calendar days;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The pork class (barrow/gilt, sow, boar);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Destination (Domestic, Export/Overseas, NAFTA);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_vii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Type of Refrigeration (Fresh, Frozen, age range of fresh product);
            and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_viii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (viii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Specialty pork product, if applicable
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Publication.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Secretary shall make available to the public the information
            obtained under paragraph (a) of this section not less frequently
            than twice each reporting day for gilt and barrow product and once
            each reporting day for sow and boar product.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Secretary shall obtain product specifications upon request.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Secretary shall provide freight information for the purpose of
            calculating prices on an F.O.B. Omaha basis. The Secretary shall
            provide this information periodically, but not less than quarterly.
          </text>
        </P>
        <EFFDNOTP>
          <HD SOURCE='HED'>
            Effective Date Note:
          </HD>
          <P>
            At 
            <aref type='FREGIST'>
              77 FR 50574
            </aref>
            , Aug. 22, 2012, 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='59' sect='205' psec='' tq='N'>
                59.205
              </subref>
            </aref>
             was added, effective Jan. 7, 2013.
          </P>
        </EFFDNOTP>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3683'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:59:D:59.300
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        59.300
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='59' sect='300' psec='' tq='N'>
              59.300
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The following definitions apply to this subpart.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Boxed lamb
          </E>
          . The term “boxed lamb” means those carlot-based portions of a lamb
          carcass including fresh primals, subprimals, cuts fabricated from
          subprimals excluding portion-control cuts such as chops and steaks
          similar to those portion cut items described in the Institutional Meat
          Purchase Specifications (IMPS) for Fresh Lamb and Mutton Series 200,
          and thin meats (e.g., inside and outside skirts, pectoral meat, cap
          and wedge meat, and blade meat) not older than 14 days from date of
          manufacture; fresh ground lamb, lamb trimmings, and boneless
          processing lamb not older than 7 days from 
          <PRTPAGE P='168' />
          date of manufacture; frozen primals, subprimals, cuts fabricated from
          subprimals, and thin meats not older than 180 days from date of
          manufacture; and frozen ground lamb, lamb trimmings, and boneless
          processing lamb not older than 90 days from date of manufacture.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Branded
          </E>
          . The term “branded” means boxed lamb cuts produced and marketed under
          a corporate trademark (for example, products that are marketed on
          their quality, yield, or breed characteristics), or boxed lamb cuts
          produced and marketed under one of USDA&apos;s Meat Grading and
          Certification Branch, Certified programs.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Carcass characteristics
          </E>
          . The term “carcass characteristics” means the range and average
          carcass weight in pounds, the quality grade and yield grade (if
          applicable), and the lamb average dressing percentage.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Carlot-based
          </E>
          . The term “carlot-based” means any transaction between a buyer and a
          seller destined for three or less delivery stops consisting of any
          combination of carcass weights. When used in reference to boxed lamb
          cuts the term “carlot-based” means any transaction between a buyer and
          seller consisting of 1,000 pounds or more of one or more individual
          boxed lamb items.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Established
          </E>
          . The term “established”, when used in connection with prices, means
          that point in time when the buyer and seller agree upon a net price.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Formula marketing arrangement
          </E>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When used in reference to live lambs, the term “formula marketing
            arrangement” means the advance commitment of lambs for slaughter by
            any means other than through a negotiated purchase or a forward
            contract, using a method for calculating price in which the price is
            determined at a future date.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When used in reference to boxed lamb, the term “formula marketing
            arrangement” means the advance commitment of boxed lamb by any means
            other than through a negotiated purchase or a forward contract,
            using a method for calculating price in which the price is
            determined at a future date.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Forward contract
          </E>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When used in reference to live lambs, the term “forward contact”
            means an agreement for the purchase of lambs, executed in advance of
            slaughter, under which the base price is established by reference to
            publicly available prices.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When used in reference to boxed lamb, the term “forward contract”
            means an agreement for the sale of boxed lamb, executed in advance
            of manufacture, under which the base price is established by
            reference to publicly available quoted prices.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Importer
          </E>
          . The term “importer” means any person engaged in the business of
          importing lamb meat products who takes ownership of such lamb meat
          products with the intent to sell or ship in U.S. commerce. For any
          calendar year, the term includes only those that imported an average
          of 2,500 metric tons of lamb meat products per year during the
          immediately preceding 5 calendar years. Additionally, the term
          includes those that did not import an average of 2,500 metric tons of
          lamb meat products during the immediately preceding 5 calendar years,
          if the Secretary determines that the person should be considered an
          importer based on their volume of lamb imports.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Packer
          </E>
          . The term “packer” means any person engaged in the business of buying
          lambs in commerce for purposes of slaughter, of manufacturing or
          preparing meat products from lambs for sale or shipment in commerce,
          or of marketing meats or meat products from lambs in an unmanufactured
          form acting as a wholesale broker, dealer, or distributor in commerce.
          For any calendar year, the term includes only a federally inspected
          lamb processing plant which slaughtered or processed the equivalent of
          an average of 75,000 head of lambs per year during the immediately
          preceding 5 calendar years. Additionally, the term includes a lamb
          processing plant that did not slaughter or process an average of
          75,000 lambs during the immediately preceding 5 calendar years if the
          Secretary determines that the processing plant should be considered a
          packer after considering its capacity.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Packer-owned lambs
          </E>
          . The term “packer-owned lambs” means lambs that a 
          <PRTPAGE P='169' />
          packer owns for at least 14 days immediately before slaughter.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Type of purchase
          </E>
          . The term “type of purchase” means a negotiated purchase, a formula
          market arrangement, and a forward contract.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Type of sale
          </E>
          . The term “type of sale” with respect to boxed lamb, means a
          negotiated sale, a formula market arrangement, and a forward contract.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Yield grade lamb carcass reporting
          </E>
          . The term “yield grade lamb carcass reporting” means if the lot
          includes 80 percent or more of one yield grade, the lot will be
          considered a single yield grade lot. If the lot contains less than 80
          percent of one yield grade, the lot will be considered a mixed grade
          lot and all yield grades comprising 10 percent or more will be used to
          describe the lot.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3684'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:59:D:59.301
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        59.301
      </num>
      <head>
        Mandatory Daily Reporting for Lambs.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='59' sect='301' psec='' tq='N'>
              59.301
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Mandatory Daily Reporting for Lambs.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              In general.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The corporate officers or officially designated representatives of
            each packer processing plant shall report to the Secretary at least
            once each reporting day not later than 2 p.m. central time the
            prices for lambs (per hundredweight) established on that day as
            F.O.B. feedlot or delivered at the plant, categorized to clearly
            delineate domestic from imported market purchases as described in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='59' sect='10' psec='#b' tq='N'>
                59.10(b)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and categorized by:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The type of purchase;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The class of lamb;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The quantity of lambs purchased on a live weight basis;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The quantity of lambs purchased on a dressed weight basis;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A range and average of estimated live weights of lambs purchased;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An estimate of the percentage of the lambs purchased that were of a
            quality grade of Choice or better;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any premiums or discounts associated with weight, quality grade,
            yield grade, or any type of purchase;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Lamb state of origin;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The pelt type; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The estimated lamb dressing percentage.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Publication.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Secretary shall make the information available to the public
            not less than once each reporting day.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3685'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:59:D:59.302
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        59.302
      </num>
      <head>
        Mandatory weekly reporting for lambs.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='59' sect='302' psec='' tq='N'>
              59.302
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Mandatory weekly reporting for lambs.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              In general.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The corporate officers or officially designated representatives of
            each packer processing plant shall report to the Secretary the
            following information applicable to the prior slaughter week
            contained in paragraphs (a)(1) through (a)(5) and (a)(7) of this
            section not later than 9 a.m. central time on the second reporting
            day of the current slaughter week, and the following information
            applicable to the prior slaughter week contained in paragraph (a)(6)
            of this section not later than 9 a.m. central time on the first
            reporting day of the current slaughter week categorized to clearly
            delineate domestic from imported market purchases:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The quantity of lambs purchased through a negotiated purchase that
            were slaughtered;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The quantity of lambs purchased through forward contracts that were
            slaughtered;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The quantity of lambs delivered under a formula marketing
            arrangement that were slaughtered;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The quantity and carcass characteristics of packer-owned lambs that
            were slaughtered;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The quantity, basis level, and delivery month for all lambs
            purchased through forward contracts;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The following information applicable to the current slaughter week.
            The range and average of intended premiums and discounts (including
            those associated with weight, quality grade, yield grade, or type of
            lamb) that are expected to be in effect for the current slaughter
            week; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The following information for lambs purchased through a formula
            marketing arrangement and slaughtered during the prior slaughter
            week, categorized to clearly delineate domestic from imported market
            purchases:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_7_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The quantity (quoted in both numbers of head and pounds) of lambs;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_7_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The weighted average price paid for a carcass, including applicable
            premiums and discounts;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_7_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The range of premiums and discounts paid;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_7_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The weighted average of premiums and discounts paid; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_7_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The range of prices paid.
            <PRTPAGE P='170' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Publication.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Secretary shall make available to the public the information
            obtained in paragraphs (a)(1) through (a)(5) and (a)(7) of this
            section on the second reporting day of the current slaughter week
            and information obtained in paragraph (a)(6) of this section on the
            first reporting day of the current slaughter week.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3686'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:59:D:59.303
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        59.303
      </num>
      <head>
        Mandatory reporting of lamb carcasses and boxed lamb.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='59' sect='303' psec='' tq='N'>
              59.303
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Mandatory reporting of lamb carcasses and boxed lamb.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Daily reporting of lamb carcass transactions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The corporate officers or officially designated representatives of
            each packer shall report to the Secretary each reporting day the
            following information on total carlot-based lamb carcass
            transactions not later than 3 p.m. central time in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='59' sect='10' psec='#b' tq='N'>
                59.10(b)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            :
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The price for each lot of each lamb carcass transaction, quoted in
            dollars per hundredweight on an F.O.B. plant basis;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The quantity for each lot of each transaction, quoted by number of
            carcasses sold and purchased; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The following information regarding the characteristics of each
            transaction:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The type of transaction;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The USDA quality grade of lamb;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The USDA yield grade;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The estimated weight range of the carcasses; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The product delivery period.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Daily reporting of domestic boxed lamb sales.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The corporate officers or officially designated representatives of
            each packer shall report to the Secretary each reporting day the
            following information on total domestic boxed lamb cut sales not
            later than 2:30 p.m. central time as described in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='59' sect='10' psec='#b' tq='N'>
                59.10(b)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            :
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The price for each lot of each boxed lamb cut sale, quoted in
            dollars per hundredweight on a F.O.B. plant basis;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The quantity for each lot of each sale, quoted by product weight
            sold; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The following information regarding the characteristics of each
            transaction:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The type of sale;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The branded product characteristics, if applicable;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The USDA quality grade of lamb;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The cut of lamb, referencing the most recent version of the
            Institutional Meat Purchase Specifications (IMPS), when applicable;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             USDA yield grade, if applicable;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The product state of refrigeration;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_vii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The weight range of the cut; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_viii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (viii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The product delivery period.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Weekly Reporting of Imported Boxed Lamb Sales.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The corporate officers or officially designated representatives of
            each lamb importer shall report to the Secretary on the first
            reporting day of each week the following information applicable to
            the prior week for imported boxed lamb cut sales not later than 10
            a.m. central time:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The price for each lot of a boxed lamb cut sale, quoted in dollars
            per hundredweight on a F.O.B. plant basis;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The quantity for each lot of a transaction, quoted by product
            weight sold; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The following information regarding the characteristics of each
            transaction:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The type of sale;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The branded product characteristics, if applicable;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The cut of lamb, referencing the most recent version of the
            Institutional Meat Purchase Specifications (IMPS), when applicable;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_3_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The product state of refrigeration;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_3_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The weight range of the cut; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_3_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The product delivery period.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Publication.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Secretary shall make available to the public the information
            required to be reported in paragraphs (a) and (b) of this section
            not less frequently than once each reporting day and the information
            required to be reported in paragraph (c) of this section on the
            first reporting day of the current slaughter week.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3687'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:59:E:59.400
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        59.400
      </num>
      <head>
        OMB control number assigned pursuant to the Paperwork Reduction Act.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='59' sect='400' psec='' tq='N'>
              59.400
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          OMB control number assigned pursuant to the Paperwork Reduction Act.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The information collection and recordkeeping requirements of this part
          have been approved by the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) under
          the provisions of 44 U.S.C. Chapter 35 
          <PRTPAGE P='171' />
          and have been assigned OMB Control Number 0581-0186.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>