<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol11'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1751
    </extid>
    <num>
      1751
    </num>
    <head>
      TELECOMMUNICATIONS SYSTEM PLANNING AND DESIGN CRITERIA, AND PROCEDURES
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='901' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/901.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 901
            </subref>
          </aref>
          <E T='03'>
            et seq.,
          </E>
           1921 
          <E T='03'>
            et seq.
          </E>
          ; 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Pub. L. 103-354' alt='Pub. L. 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Pub. L. 103-354
          </aref>
          , 
          <aref target='_blank' href='http://frwebgate.access.gpo.gov/cgi-bin/getpage.cgi?dbname=103_statutes2_at_large&amp;position=all&amp;page=3178'>
            108 Stat. 3178
          </aref>
           (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='6941' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/6941.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 6941
            </subref>
          </aref>
          <E T='03'>
            et seq.
          </E>
          ).
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            60 FR 8174
          </aref>
          , Feb. 13, 1995, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='14092'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1751:A:1751.1-1751.99
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1751.1-1751.99
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1751' sect='1-1751' psec='' tq='N'>
              1751.1-1751
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .99
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14093'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1751:B:1751.100
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1751.100
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1751' sect='100' psec='' tq='N'>
              1751.100
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          As used in this subpart:
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Bit rate.
          </E>
           The rate of transmission of telecommunications signals or
          intelligence in binary (two state) form in bits per unit time, e.g.,
          Mb/s (megabits per second), kb/s (kilobits per second), etc.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Borrower.
          </E>
           Any organization that has received an RUS loan designation number and
          which has an outstanding telephone loan made by RUS or the Rural
          Telephone Bank, or guaranteed by RUS, or which has a completed loan
          application with RUS.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Emerging technologies.
          </E>
           New or not fully developed methods of telecommunications.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Modernization Plan (State Telecommunications Modernization Plan).
          </E>
           A State plan, which has been approved by RUS, for improving the
          telecommunications network of those Telecommunications Providers
          covered by the plan. A Modernization Plan must conform to the
          provisions of this subpart.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            New facilities.
          </E>
           Facilities which are wholly or partially constructed or reconstructed
          after a short- or medium-term requirements start date, as appropriate.
          This does not include connections or capacity extensions within the
          wired capacity of existing plant such as adding line cards to existing
          equipment.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Plan Developer.
          </E>
           The entity creating the Modernization Plan for the State, which may
          be the State PUC, the State legislature, or a numeric majority of the
          RUS Borrowers within the State. When this part refers to the PUC as
          the Plan Developer, this includes the State legislature.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            PUC (Public Utilities Commission).
          </E>
           The public utilities commission, public service commission or other
          State body with such jurisdiction over rates, service areas or other
          aspects of the services and operation of providers of
          telecommunications services as vested in the commission or other body
          authority, to the extent provided by the State, to guide development
          of telecommunications services in the State. When this part refers to
          the PUC as the Plan Developer, this includes the State legislature.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            RE Act.
          </E>
           The Rural Electrification Act of 1936, as amended (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='901' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/901.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 901
            </subref>
          </aref>
          <E T='03'>
            et seq.
          </E>
          ).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            REA.
          </E>
           The Rural Electrification Administration, formerly an agency of the
          United States Department of Agriculture and predecessor agency to RUS
          with respect to administering certain electric and telephone loan
          programs.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            RELRA.
          </E>
           The Rural Electrification Loan Restructuring Act of 1993 (
          <aref target='_blank' href='http://frwebgate.access.gpo.gov/cgi-bin/getpage.cgi?dbname=103_statutes_at_large&amp;position=all&amp;page=1356'>
            107 Stat. 1356
          </aref>
          ).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            RUS.
          </E>
           The Rural Utilities Service, an agency of the United States
          Department of Agriculture established pursuant to 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            Section 232 of
          </aref>
           the Federal Crop Insurance Reform and Department of Agriculture
          Reorganization Act of 1994 (
          <aref target='_blank' title='Pub. L. 103-354' alt='Pub. L. 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Pub. L. 103-354
          </aref>
          , 
          <aref target='_blank' href='http://frwebgate.access.gpo.gov/cgi-bin/getpage.cgi?dbname=103_statutes2_at_large&amp;position=all&amp;page=3178'>
            108 Stat. 3178
          </aref>
           (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='6941' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/6941.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 6941
            </subref>
          </aref>
          <E T='03'>
            et seq.
          </E>
          )), successor to REA with respect to administering certain electric
          and telephone programs. See 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR 
            <subref title='7' part='1700' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              1700.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            RUS cost-of-money loan.
          </E>
           A loan made under 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 305(d)(2) of
          </aref>
           the RE Act bearing interest as determined under 7 
          <PRTPAGE P='403' />
          CFR 1735.31(c). RUS cost-of-money loans are made concurrently with RTB
          loans.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            RUS hardship loan.
          </E>
           A loan made by RUS under 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 305(d)(1) of
          </aref>
           the RE Act bearing interest at a rate of 5 percent per year.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            RTB loan.
          </E>
           A loan made by the Rural Telephone Bank (RTB) under 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 408 of
          </aref>
           the RE Act bearing interest as determined under 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR 
            <subref title='7' part='1610' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
              1610.10
            </subref>
          </aref>
          . RTB loans are made concurrently with RUS cost-of-money loans.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State.
          </E>
           Each of the 50 states of the United States, the District of Columbia,
          and the territories and insular possessions of the United States. This
          does not include countries in the Compact of Free Association.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Telecommunications.
          </E>
           The transmission or reception of voice, data, sounds, signals,
          pictures, writings, or signs of all kinds, by wire, fiber, radio,
          light, or other visual or electromagnetic means.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Telecommunications providers.
          </E>
           RUS Borrowers and if the Plan Developer is a PUC, such other entities
          providing telecommunications services as the developer of the
          Modernization Plan (See 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1751' sect='101' psec='' tq='N'>
              1751.101
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ) may determine.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Wireline Service.
          </E>
           Telecommunica-tions service provided over telephone lines. It is
          characterized by a wire or wirelike connection carrying electricity or
          light between the subscriber and the rest of the telecommunications
          network. Wireline Service implies a physical connection. Although
          radio may form part of the circuit, it is not the major method of
          transmission as in radiotelephone.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14094'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1751:B:1751.101
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1751.101
      </num>
      <head>
        General.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1751' sect='101' psec='' tq='N'>
              1751.101
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             It is the policy of RUS that every State have a Modernization Plan
            which provides for the improvement of the State&apos;s
            telecommunications network.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A proposed Modernization Plan must be submitted to RUS for
            approval. RUS will approve the proposed Modernization Plan if it
            conforms to the provisions of this subpart. Once obtained,
            RUS&apos;s approval of a Modernization Plan cannot be rescinded.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Modernization Plan shall not interfere with RUS&apos;s
            authority to issue such other telecommunications standards,
            specifications, requirements, and procurement rules as may be
            promulgated from time to time by RUS including, without limitation,
            those set forth in 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1755' tq='N'>
                1755
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Modernization Plan must, at a minimum, apply to RUS
            Borrowers&apos; wireline service areas. If a Modernization Plan is
            developed by the PUC, RUS encourages, but does not require, that the
            Modernization Plan&apos;s requirements apply to the rural service
            areas of all providers of telecommunications services in the State.
            A PUC&apos;s decision not to include non-RUS Borrowers will not
            prejudice RUS approval of that PUC&apos;s Modernization Plan. The
            PUC may also, at its option, extend coverage of the Modernization
            Plan to all service areas of all providers of telecommunications
            services in the State. In addition, while the requirements and goals
            contained in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1751' sect='106' psec='' tq='N'>
                1751.106
              </subref>
            </aref>
             apply only to wireline services, the PUC, at its discretion, may
            extend coverage of Modernization Plans to wireless or other
            communications services in the State as it deems appropriate.
            Borrower-developed Modernization Plans apply only to Borrowers.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14095'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1751:B:1751.102
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1751.102
      </num>
      <head>
        Modernization Plan Developer; eligibility.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1751' sect='102' psec='' tq='N'>
              1751.102
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Modernization Plan Developer; eligibility.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each PUC is eligible until February 13, 1996 to develop a proposed
            Modernization Plan and deliver it to RUS. RUS will review and
            consider for approval all PUC-developed Modernization Plans received
            by RUS within this one year period. The review and approval, if any,
            may occur after the one year period ends even though the PUC is no
            longer eligible to submit a proposed Modernization Plan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The PUC must notify all Telecommunications Providers in the State
            and other interested parties of its intent to develop a proposed
            Modernization Plan. The PUC is encouraged to consider all
            Telecommunications Providers&apos; and interested parties&apos;
            views and incorporate these views into the Modernization Plan. In
            the event that the PUC does not intend to develop a proposed
            Modernization Plan, RUS requests that the PUC inform RUS of this
            decision as soon as possible.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the PUC is no longer eligible to develop a Modernization Plan or
            has informed RUS that it will not develop a Modernization Plan, as
            described in 
            <PRTPAGE P='404' />
            paragraphs (a) and (b) of this section, a majority of the Borrowers
            within the State may develop the Modernization Plan. If a majority
            of Borrowers develops the Modernization Plan, the following apply:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All Borrowers shall be given reasonable notice of and shall be
            encouraged to attend and contribute to all meetings and other
            proceedings relating to the development of the Modernization Plan;
            and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Borrowers developing a Modernization Plan are encouraged to solicit
            the views of other providers of telecommunications services and
            interested parties in the State.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             There is no time limit placed on Borrowers to develop a
            Modernization Plan. Borrowers should be aware that certain types of
            loans may be restricted until a Modernization Plan is approved. See 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1751' sect='103' psec='' tq='N'>
                1751.103
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14096'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1751:B:1751.103
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1751.103
      </num>
      <head>
        Loan and loan advance requirements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1751' sect='103' psec='' tq='N'>
              1751.103
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Loan and loan advance requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For information about loan eligibility requirements in relation to
            the Modernization Plan, see 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1735' tq='N'>
                1735
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . In particular, beginning February 13, 1996, RUS will make RUS
            hardship loans, RUS cost-of-money loans, and RTB loans for
            facilities and other RE Act purposes in a State only if:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State has an RUS approved Modernization Plan; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Borrower to whom the loan is to be made is participating in the
            Modernization Plan for the State. A Borrower is considered to be
            participating if, in RUS&apos;s opinion, the purposes of the loan
            requested by the Borrower are consistent with the Borrower achieving
            the requirements stated in the Modernization Plan within the
            timeframe stated in the Modernization Plan unless RUS has determined
            that achieving the requirements is not technically or economically
            feasible.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             With regard to the three types of loans discussed in paragraph (a),
            only loans approved after the date the State has an RUS approved
            Modernization Plan are subject to complying with the Modernization
            Plan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For loans subject to complying with the Modernization Plan,
            advances will not be made if, in RUS&apos;s opinion, the advances
            are not consistent with achieving the requirements of the
            Modernization Plan.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14097'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1751:B:1751.104
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1751.104
      </num>
      <head>
        Obtaining RUS approval of a proposed Modernization Plan.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1751' sect='104' psec='' tq='N'>
              1751.104
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Obtaining RUS approval of a proposed Modernization Plan.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To obtain RUS approval of a proposed Modernization Plan, the Plan
            Developer must submit the following to RUS:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A certified copy of the statute or PUC order, if the PUC is the
            Plan Developer, or a written request for RUS approval of the
            proposed Modernization Plan signed by an authorized representative
            of the Plan Developer, if a majority of Borrowers is the Plan
            Developer; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Three copies of the proposed Modernization Plan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Generally, RUS will review the proposed Modernization Plan within
            (30) days and either:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Approve the Modernization Plan if it conforms to the provisions of
            this subpart in which case RUS will return a copy of the
            Modernization Plan with notice of approval to the Plan Developer; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Not approve the proposed Modernization Plan if it does not conform
            to the provisions of this subpart. In this event, RUS will return
            the proposed Modernization Plan to the Plan Developer with specific
            written comments and suggestions for modifying the proposed
            Modernization Plan so that it will conform to the provisions of this
            subpart. If the Plan Developer remains eligible, RUS will invite the
            Plan Developer to submit a modified proposed Modernization Plan for
            RUS consideration. This process can continue until the Plan
            Developer gains approval of a proposed Modernization Plan unless the
            Plan Developer is a PUC whose eligibility has expired. If a
            PUC&apos;s eligibility has expired, RUS will return the proposed
            Modernization Plan unapproved. Because RUS does not have authority
            to extend the term of a PUC&apos;s eligibility, RUS recommends that
            the PUC submit a proposed Modernization Plan at least 90 days in
            advance of February 13, 1996 to allow time for this process.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14098'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1751:B:1751.105
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1751.105
      </num>
      <head>
        Amending a Modernization Plan.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='405' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1751' sect='105' psec='' tq='N'>
              1751.105
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Amending a Modernization Plan.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             RUS understands that changes in standards, technology, regulation,
            and the economy could indicate that an RUS-approved Modernization
            Plan should be amended.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Plan Developer of the Modernization Plan may amend the
            Modernization Plan if RUS finds the proposed changes continue to
            conform to the provisions of this subpart.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The procedure for requesting approval of an amended Modernization
            Plan is identical to the procedure for a proposed Modernization Plan
            except that there are no time limits on the eligibility of the Plan
            Developer.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The existing Modernization Plan remains in force until RUS has
            approved the proposed amended Modernization Plan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             RUS may from time to time revise these regulations to incorporate
            newer technological and economic standards that RUS believes
            represent more desirable goals for the future course of
            telecommunications services. Such revisions will be made in
            accordance with the Administrative Procedure Act. These revisions
            shall not invalidate Modernization Plans approved by RUS but shall
            be used by RUS to determine whether to approve amendments to
            Modernization Plans presented for RUS approval after March 15, 1995.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14099'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1751:B:1751.106
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1751.106
      </num>
      <head>
        Modernization Plan; requirements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1751' sect='106' psec='' tq='N'>
              1751.106
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Modernization Plan; requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The requirements for a Modernization Plan as stated in RELRA are:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The plan must provide for the elimination of party line service.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The plan must provide for the availability of telecommunications
            services for improved business, educational, and medical services.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The plan must encourage and improve computer networks and
            information highways for subscribers in rural areas.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The plan must provide for—
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subscribers in rural areas to be able to receive through telephone
            lines—
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_4_i_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Conference calling;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_4_i_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Video images; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_4_i_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Data at a rate of at least 1,000,000 bits of information per
            second; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_4_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The proper routing of information to subscribers.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The plan must provide for uniform deployment schedules to ensure
            that advanced services are deployed at the same time in rural and
            nonrural areas.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The plan must provide for such additional requirements for service
            standards as may be required by the Administrator.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To implement the requirements of the law described in paragraph (a)
            of this section, RUS has set minimum requirements as described in
            paragraphs (i) and (j) of this section. They are grouped into
            short-term and medium-term requirements. RUS has also included
            long-term goals which are not requirements. The Modernization Plan
            must meet all of the statutory requirements of RELRA and shall
            provide that short- and medium-term requirements be implemented as
            set forth in this section of the regulation except that the PUC, if
            it is the Plan Developer, or RUS, if a majority of Borrowers is the
            Plan Developer, may approve extensions of time if the required
            investment is not economically feasible or if the best available
            telecommunications technology lacks the capability to enable the
            Telecommunications Provider receiving the extension to comply with
            the Modernization Plan. Extensions shall be granted only on a
            case-by-case basis and generally shall not exceed a total of five
            years from the first such extension granted to the
            Telecommunications Provider.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each State&apos;s Modernization Plan shall be a strategic
            development proposal for modernizing the telecommunications network
            of the Telecommunications Providers covered by the Modernization
            Plan. In addition to implementing the requirements described in
            paragraphs (a), (i), and (j) of this section, the Modernization Plan
            shall include a short engineering description of the characteristics
            of a future telecommunications structure that would enable all
            Telecommunications Providers to achieve the requirements and goals
            of the Modernization Plan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Within the scope of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1751' sect='101' psec='#d' tq='N'>
                1751.101(d)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , if the Plan Developer is the PUC, the 
            <PRTPAGE P='406' />
            Modernization Plan shall name the Telecommunications Providers in
            the State, in addition to Borrowers, that are covered by the
            Modernization Plan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Modernization Plan must require that the design of the network
            provided by Telecommunications Providers allow for the expeditious
            deployment and integration of such emerging technologies as may from
            time to time become commercially feasible.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Modernization Plan must provide guidelines to
            Telecommunications Providers for the development of affordable
            tariffs for medical links and distance learning services.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             With regard to the uniform deployment requirement of the law
            restated in paragraph (a)(5) of this section, if services cannot be
            deployed at the same time, only the minimum feasible interval of
            time shall separate availability of the services in rural and
            nonrural areas.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Modernization Plan must make provision for reliable powering of
            ordinary voice telephone service operating over those portions of
            the telecommunications network which are not network powered. In the
            event of electric utility power outages, an alternative source of
            power must be available to ensure reliable voice service.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Short-term requirements.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The “short-term requirements start date” is the date one year after
            the date RUS approves the Modernization Plan for the State.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All New Facilities providing Wireline Service after the short-term
            requirements start date, even if the construction began before such
            date, shall be constructed so that:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Every subscriber can be provided 1-party service.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The New Facilities are suitable, as built or with additional
            equipment, to provide transmission and reception of data at a rate
            no lower than 1 Mb/sec.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All switching equipment installed by a Telecommunications Provider
            after the short-term requirements start date shall be capable of:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Providing custom calling features. At a minimum, custom calling
            features must include call waiting, call forwarding, abbreviated
            dialing, and three-way calling; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Providing E911 service for areas served by the Telecommunication
            Provider when requested by the government responsible for this
            service.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Medium-term requirements.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The “medium-term requirements start date” is the date six years
            after the date RUS approves the Modernization Plan for the State, or
            such earlier date as the Modernization Plan shall provide.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All New Facilities providing Wireline Service after the medium-term
            requirements start date, even if the construction began before such
            date, shall be capable, as built or with additional equipment, of
            transmitting video to a subscriber. The video must be capable of
            depicting a reasonable representation of motion. The frame rate,
            resolution, and other measures of audio and video quality shall be
            determined by the Plan Developer.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No later than the medium-term requirements start date, all
            switching equipment of Telecommunications Providers covered by the
            Modernization Plan must be capable of providing E911 service when
            requested by the government responsible for this service.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No later than five years after the medium-term requirements start
            date, one-party service must be provided upon demand to any
            subscriber of a Telecommunications Provider covered by the
            Modernization Plan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Long-term goals.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             RUS suggests, but does not require, that the provisions of each
            Modernization Plan be consistent with the accomplishment of the
            following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='k_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The elimination of party line service.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='k_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For subscribers that desire the service, universal availability of:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='k_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Digital voice and data service (56-164 kb/sec).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='k_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Service that provides transmission and reception of high bit rate
            (no less than 1 Mb/sec) data.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='k_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Service that provides reception of video as described in paragraph
            (j)(2) of this section.
            <PRTPAGE P='407' />
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>