<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol10'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1484
    </extid>
    <num>
      1484
    </num>
    <head>
      PROGRAMS TO HELP DEVELOP FOREIGN MARKETS FOR AGRICULTURAL COMMODITIES
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='15' sect='714c' note='' psec='#f' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/15/714c.html#f'>
              15 U.S.C. 714c(f)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            64 FR 52630
          </aref>
          , Sept. 30, 1999, unless otherwise noted. Redesignated at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            65 FR 9995
          </aref>
          , Feb. 25, 2000.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='13051'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1484:A:1484.10
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1484.10
      </num>
      <head>
        What is the effective date of this part?
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          64 FR 52630
        </aref>
        , Sept. 30, 1999. Redesignated and amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          65 FR 9995
        </aref>
        , Feb. 25, 2000]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1484' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
              1484.10
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          What is the effective date of this part?
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          This part applies to activities that are conducted in accordance with
          the Cooperators&apos; FY 2000 and subsequent marketing plan years. The
          Cooperator Program is administered by personnel of the Foreign
          Agricultural Service.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            64 FR 52630
          </aref>
          , Sept. 30, 1999. Redesignated and amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            65 FR 9995
          </aref>
          , Feb. 25, 2000]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13052'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1484:A:1484.11
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1484.11
      </num>
      <head>
        Has the Office of Management and Budget reviewed the paperwork and
        record keeping requirements contained in this part?
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1484' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
              1484.11
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Has the Office of Management and Budget reviewed the paperwork and
          record keeping requirements contained in this part?
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The paperwork and record keeping requirements imposed by this part
          have been submitted to the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) for
          emergency review and reinstatement under the Paperwork Reduction Act
          of 1995 (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='44' sect='3501' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/44/3501.html'>
              44 U.S.C. 3501
            </subref>
          </aref>
          <E T='03'>
            et seq.
          </E>
          ). OMB has previously assigned control number 0551-0026 for this
          information collection.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13053'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1484:A:1484.12
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1484.12
      </num>
      <head>
        What is the Cooperator program?
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='870' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1484' sect='12' psec='' tq='N'>
              1484.12
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          What is the Cooperator program?
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Under the Foreign Market Development Cooperator (Cooperator)
            Program, FAS enters into project agreements with eligible nonprofit
            U.S. trade organizations to share the costs of certain overseas
            marketing and promotion activities that are intended to create,
            expand, or maintain foreign markets for U.S. agricultural
            commodities and products. FAS does not provide brand promotion
            assistance to Cooperators under this program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FAS enters into project agreements with those eligible nonprofit
            U.S. trade organizations that have the broadest possible producer
            representation of the commodity being promoted and gives priority to
            those organizations that are nationwide in membership and scope.
            Project agreements involve the promotion of agricultural commodities
            on a generic basis. Project agreements do not involve activities
            targeted directly toward consumers purchasing as individuals.
            Activities must contribute to the maintenance or growth of demand
            for the agricultural commodities and generally address long-term
            foreign import constraints and export growth opportunities by
            focusing on matters such as reducing infra-structural or historical
            market impediments; improving processing capabilities; modifying
            codes and standards; and identifying new markets or new applications
            or uses for the agricultural commodity or product in the foreign
            market.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Cooperator program generally operates on a reimbursement basis.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FAS policy is to ensure that benefits generated by Cooperator
            agreements are broadly available throughout the relevant
            agricultural sector and no one entity gains an undue advantage or
            sole benefit from program activities.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13054'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1484:A:1484.13
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1484.13
      </num>
      <head>
        What special definitions apply to the Cooperator program?
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          64 FR 52630
        </aref>
        , Sept. 30, 1999. Redesignated and amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          65 FR 9995
        </aref>
        , Feb. 25, 2000]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1484' sect='13' psec='' tq='N'>
              1484.13
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          What special definitions apply to the Cooperator program?
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          For purposes of this part the following definitions apply:
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Activity
          </E>
          —a specific market development effort undertaken by a Cooperator to
          address a constraint or opportunity.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Administrator
          </E>
          —the Vice President, CCC, who also serves as Administrator, FAS, USDA,
          or designee.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Agricultural commodity
          </E>
          —an agricultural commodity, food, feed, fiber, wood, livestock or
          insect, and any product thereof; and fish harvested from a U.S.
          aquaculture farm, or harvested by a vessel as defined in title 46,
          United States Code, in waters that are not waters (including the
          territorial sea) of a foreign country.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Attache/Counselor
          </E>
          —the FAS employee representing USDA interests in the foreign country
          in which promotional activities are conducted.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Commodity Division
          </E>
          —the office within the Foreign Agricultural Service responsible for
          the commodity covered by the project agreement.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Compliance Review Staff
          </E>
          —the office within the Foreign Agricultural Service responsible for
          performing periodic reviews of Cooperators to ensure compliance with
          this part.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Constraint
          </E>
          —a condition in a particular country or region which needs to be
          addressed in order to develop, expand, or maintain exports of a
          specific U.S. agricultural commodity.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Consumer promotion
          </E>
          —activities that are designed to directly influence consumers by
          changing attitudes or purchasing behaviors towards U.S. agricultural
          products.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Contribution
          </E>
          —the cost-share expenditure made by a Cooperator or the U.S. industry
          in support of an activity; e.g., money, personnel, materials,
          services, facilities, or supplies.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Cooperator
          </E>
           or 
          <E T='03'>
            U.S. Cooperator
          </E>
          —a nonprofit U.S. agricultural trade organization which has entered
          into a foreign market development agreement with FAS.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Cooperator Program
          </E>
          —the Foreign Market Development Cooperator Program.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Deputy Administrator
          </E>
          —the Deputy Administrator, Commodity and Marketing Programs, FAS,
          USDA, or designee.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Division Director
          </E>
          —the director of a commodity division, Commodity and Marketing
          Programs, FAS, USDA.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Eligible commodity
          </E>
          —an agricultural commodity that is comprised of at least 50 percent
          U.S. origin content by weight, exclusive of added water.
          <PRTPAGE P='871' />
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Eligible trade organization
          </E>
          —a United States trade organization that promotes the exports of one
          or more United States agricultural commodities or products and does
          not have a business interest in or receive remuneration from specific
          sales of agricultural commodities or products.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Expenditure
          </E>
          —transfer of funds.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            FAS
          </E>
          —Foreign Agricultural Service, USDA.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Foreign third party
          </E>
          —a foreign entity that assists, in accordance with this part, in
          promoting the export of a U.S. agricultural commodity.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Generic promotion
          </E>
          —a promotion that does not involve the exclusive or predominant use of
          a single company name or logo(s) or brand name(s) of a single company.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Market
          </E>
          —a country or region in which an activity is conducted.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Marketing plan year
          </E>
          —the program year beginning on October 1 and ending on September 30,
          during which Cooperators can undertake activities, consistent with
          this part and their agreements with FAS, and seek reimbursement. For
          example, marketing plan year 2000 begins on October 1, 1999, and ends
          on September 30, 2000.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Project agreement
          </E>
          —a contract between FAS and a Cooperator in which the basic working
          relationship is described including the program and financial
          obligations of each.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Project funds
          </E>
          —the funds made available to a Cooperator under a project agreement,
          and authorized for expenditure in accordance with this part.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Property
          </E>
          —furniture or equipment having a useful life of over one year and an
          acquisition cost of $500 or more.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            STRE
          </E>
          —sales and trade relations expenditures.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Trade team
          </E>
          —a group of individuals engaged in an activity intended to promote the
          interests of an entire agricultural sector rather than to result in
          specific sales by any of its members.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            USDA
          </E>
          —the United States Department of Agriculture.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            64 FR 52630
          </aref>
          , Sept. 30, 1999. Redesignated and amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            65 FR 9995
          </aref>
          , Feb. 25, 2000]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13055'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1484:A:1484.14
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1484.14
      </num>
      <head>
        Is my organization eligible to participate in the Cooperator program?
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1484' sect='14' psec='' tq='N'>
              1484.14
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Is my organization eligible to participate in the Cooperator program?
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To participate in the Cooperator program, an entity must be a
            nonprofit U.S. agricultural trade organization and contribute at
            least 50 percent of the value of resources provided by FAS for
            activities conducted under the project agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FAS may require that a project agreement include a contribution
            level greater than that specified in paragraph (a) of this section.
            In requiring a higher contribution level, FAS will take into account
            such factors as past Cooperator contributions, previous Cooperator
            program funding levels, the length of time an entity participates in
            the program, and the entity&apos;s ability to increase its
            contribution.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FAS will enter into Cooperator agreements only for the promotion of
            eligible commodities.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13056'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1484:B:1484.20
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1484.20
      </num>
      <head>
        How can my organization apply to the Cooperator program?
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1484' sect='20' psec='' tq='N'>
              1484.20
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          How can my organization apply to the Cooperator program?
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          FAS will publish a Notice in the 
          <E T='04'>
            Federal Register
          </E>
           that it is accepting applications for participation in the Cooperator
          program for a specified marketing plan year. Applications shall be
          submitted in accordance with the terms and requirements specified in
          the Notice. An application shall contain basic information about the
          applicant and the proposed program, a strategic plan, and performance
          measures. FAS may request any additional information which it deems
          necessary to evaluate a Cooperator program application.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Basic applicant and program information.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All Cooperator program applications shall contain:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The name and address of the applicant;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The name of the Chief Executive Officer (or designee);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The name and telephone number of the applicant&apos;s primary
            contact person;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A description of management and administrative capability;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The name(s) of the person(s) responsible for managing the program;
            <PRTPAGE P='872' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A description of prior export promotion experience;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A description of the organization, its membership, and membership
            criteria;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A list of affiliated organizations;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The applicant&apos;s Federal Tax Identification Number;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The dollar amount of FAS resources requested under the Cooperator
            program;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_11'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (11)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The value of the applicant&apos;s contribution, stated in dollars
            or as a percentage of paragraph (a)(10) of this section;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_12'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (12)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The value of contributions from other sources, stated in dollars or
            as a percentage of paragraph (a)(10) of this section;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_13'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (13)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A description of the eligible commodity(s); the associated
            commodity aggregate code(s), obtained from FAS; and the percentage
            of U.S. origin content by weight, exclusive of added water; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_14'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (14)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A certification statement, and, if requested by the Deputy
            Administrator, a written explanation supporting the certification,
            that any funds received will supplement, but not supplant, any
            private or industry funds or other contributions to program
            activities. The written explanation, if necessary, shall indicate
            why the Cooperator is unlikely to carry out the activities without
            Federal financial assistance. The certification shall also state
            that information contained in the application is true and accurate
            and that all records supporting the claim that project funds do not
            supplant other funds will be made available to authorized officials
            of the U.S. Government.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Strategic plan and performance measures.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All Cooperator program applications shall also contain:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A description of the U.S. and world market situation for the
            eligible commodity;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Data summarizing historical and projected U.S. production, U.S.
            exports to the world, world trade, and U.S. market share;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A summary of proposed activity budgets by country or region;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A summary of proposed administrative budgets by country or region;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A list of all countries that define any designated region;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For each country or region for which activities are proposed:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_6_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A market assessment, including the constraint(s) impeding U.S.
            exports, the export growth opportunities, the performance of
            competing suppliers, expected changes in demand, etc.;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_6_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The long-term strategy that will be used to counteract the
            constraints and achieve additional U.S. exports;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_6_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Previous activities, performance, and evaluation results;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_6_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Projected export goals and U.S. market share; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_6_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Performance indicators against which future success in addressing
            the constraint(s) or opportunities may be measured;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A description of all proposed activities, including the requested
            FAS resources and the specific goals and benchmarks to be used to
            measure the effectiveness of each activity;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A justification for any new overseas office, including a list of
            job titles, corresponding position descriptions, salary ranges, and
            any request for approval of salaries above the Foreign Service
            National (FSN) salary plan. To request approval of a salary above
            the FSN salary plan, the Cooperator shall include a detailed
            description of both the duties and responsibilities of the position,
            and of the qualifications and background of the individual
            concerned. The Cooperator shall also justify, based on a verifiable
            local salary survey or other documented local salary information,
            why the highest FSN salary level is inappropriate.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13057'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1484:B:1484.21
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1484.21
      </num>
      <head>
        How does FAS determine which Cooperator program applications are
        approved?
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1484' sect='21' psec='' tq='N'>
              1484.21
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          How does FAS determine which Cooperator program applications are
          approved?
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FAS allocates funds in a manner that effectively supports the
            strategic decision-making initiatives of the Government Performance
            and Results Act (GPRA) of 1993. In deciding whether a proposed
            project will contribute to the effective creation, expansion, or
            maintenance of foreign markets, FAS seeks to identify those projects
            that would demonstrate a clear, long-term agricultural trade
            strategy by market or product and a 
            <PRTPAGE P='873' />
            program effectiveness time line against which results can be
            measured at specific intervals using quantifiable product or country
            or region goals. These performance indicators are part of FAS&apos;
            resource allocation strategy to fund applicants which can
            demonstrate performance based on a long-term strategic plan and
            address the performance measurement objectives of the GPRA.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Approval criteria.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FAS will consider a number of factors when reviewing proposed
            projects, including:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The ability of the organization to provide an experienced
            U.S.-based staff with technical and international trade expertise to
            ensure adequate development, supervision, and execution of the
            proposed project;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The organization&apos;s willingness to contribute resources,
            including cash and goods and services of the U.S. industry and
            foreign third parties;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The conditions or constraints affecting the level of U.S. exports
            and market share for the agricultural commodities and products;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The degree to which the proposed project is likely to contribute to
            the creation, expansion, or maintenance of foreign markets;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The degree to which the strategic plan is coordinated with other
            private or U.S. government-funded market development projects;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Past program results and evaluations, if applicable; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Previous Cooperator program funding.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13058'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1484:B:1484.22
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1484.22
      </num>
      <head>
        How are Cooperator program funds allocated?
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1484' sect='22' psec='' tq='N'>
              1484.22
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          How are Cooperator program funds allocated?
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          After determining which applications to recommend for approval, the
          Commodity Divisions recommend funding levels for the approved
          applicants within their respective divisions. Applications then
          compete for funds on the basis of the following allocation criteria
          (the number in parentheses represents a percentage weight factor).
          Data used in the calculations for contribution levels, past export
          performance and past demand expansion performance will cover not more
          than a 6-year period, to the extent such data is available. The method
          for applying the following criteria will be described in the
          Cooperator program announcement in the 
          <E T='04'>
            Federal Register
          </E>
          :
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Contribution Level (40%).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Past Export Performance (20%).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Past Demand Expansion Performance (20%).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Future Demand Expansion Goals (10%).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Accuracy of Past Demand Expansion Projections (10%).
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13059'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1484:C:1484.30
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1484.30
      </num>
      <head>
        How does FAS formalize its working relationship with approved
        Cooperators?
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1484' sect='30' psec='' tq='N'>
              1484.30
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          How does FAS formalize its working relationship with approved
          Cooperators?
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          FAS will notify each applicant in writing of the final disposition of
          its application. FAS will send a program agreement, allocation
          approval letter, and a signature card to each approved applicant. The
          allocation approval letter will specify any special terms and
          conditions applicable to a Cooperator&apos;s program, including the
          required level of Cooperator contribution. An applicant that accepts
          the terms and conditions contained in the program agreement and
          allocation approval letter should so indicate by having its Chief
          Executive Officer sign the program agreement and submit the signed
          agreement to the Director, Marketing Operations Staff, FAS, USDA.
          Final agreement shall occur when the Administrator signs the agreement
          on behalf of FAS. The application, the program agreement, the
          allocation approval letter, and this part shall establish the terms
          and conditions of a Cooperator agreement between FAS and the approved
          applicant.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13060'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1484:C:1484.31
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1484.31
      </num>
      <head>
        Who acts on behalf of each Cooperator?
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1484' sect='31' psec='' tq='N'>
              1484.31
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Who acts on behalf of each Cooperator?
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The Cooperator shall designate at least two individuals in its
          organization to sign program agreements, reimbursement claims, and
          requests. The Cooperator shall submit the signature card signed by
          those designated individuals and by the Cooperator&apos;s Chief
          Executive Officer to the Director, Marketing Operations Staff, FAS,
          USDA, prior to the start of the marketing plan year. The Cooperator
          shall immediately notify the Director of any changes in signatories
          (e.g., removal or addition of individuals, name changes, 
          <PRTPAGE P='874' />
          etc.), and shall submit a revised signature card accordingly.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13061'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1484:C:1484.32
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1484.32
      </num>
      <head>
        Must Cooperators follow specific employment practices?
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1484' sect='32' psec='' tq='N'>
              1484.32
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Must Cooperators follow specific employment practices?
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A Cooperator shall enter into written contracts with all overseas
            employees and shall ensure that all terms, conditions, and related
            formalities of such contracts conform to governing local law.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A Cooperator shall, in its overseas offices, conform its office
            hours, work week, and holidays to local law and to the custom
            generally observed by U.S. commercial entities in the local business
            community.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A Cooperator may pay salaries or fees in any currency (U.S. or
            foreign) in conformance with contract specifications. Cooperators
            are cautioned to consult local laws regarding currency restrictions.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13062'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1484:C:1484.33
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1484.33
      </num>
      <head>
        Must Cooperators follow certain financial management guidelines?
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1484' sect='33' psec='' tq='N'>
              1484.33
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Must Cooperators follow certain financial management guidelines?
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A Cooperator shall implement and maintain a financial management
            system that conforms to generally accepted accounting principles.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A Cooperator shall institute internal controls and provide written
            guidance to commercial entities participating in its activities to
            ensure their compliance with these provisions. Each Cooperator shall
            maintain all original records and documents relating to program
            activities for 5 calendar years following the end of the applicable
            marketing plan year and shall make such records and documents
            available upon request to authorized officials of the U.S.
            Government. A Cooperator shall also maintain all documents related
            to employment, such as employment applications, contracts, position
            descriptions, leave records, and salary changes; and all records
            pertaining to contractors. A Cooperator shall also maintain adequate
            documentation related to the proper disposition of all property
            purchased by the Cooperator and for which the Cooperator is
            reimbursed with program funds.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A Cooperator shall maintain its records of expenditures and
            contributions in a manner that allows it to provide information by
            marketing plan year, country or region, activity number, and cost
            category. Such records shall include:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Receipts for all STRE (actual vendor invoices or restaurant checks,
            rather than credit card receipts);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Original receipts for any other program related expenditure in
            excess of $25.00;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The exchange rate used to calculate the dollar equivalent of each
            expenditure made in a foreign currency and the basis for such
            calculation;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Copies of reimbursement claims;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An itemized list of claims charged to the Cooperator&apos;s FMD
            account;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Documentation with accompanying English translation supporting each
            reimbursement claim, including original evidence to support the
            financial transactions, such as canceled checks, receipted paid
            bills, contracts or purchase orders, per diem calculations, and
            travel vouchers; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Documentation supporting contributions including: the date(s),
            purpose, and location(s) of each activity for which cash, goods, or
            services were claimed as a contribution; who conducted the activity;
            the participating groups or individuals; and the method of computing
            the claimed contributions. Cooperators must retain, and make
            available for audit, documentation related to claimed contributions.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon request, a Cooperator shall provide to FAS the original
            documents which support the Cooperator&apos;s reimbursement claims.
            FAS may deny a claim for reimbursement if the claim is not supported
            by adequate documentation.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13063'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1484:C:1484.34
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1484.34
      </num>
      <head>
        Must Cooperators adhere to specific standards of ethical conduct?
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1484' sect='34' psec='' tq='N'>
              1484.34
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Must Cooperators adhere to specific standards of ethical conduct?
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A Cooperator shall conduct its business in accordance with the laws
            and regulations of the country(s) in which each activity is carried
            out.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Neither a Cooperator nor its affiliates shall make export sales of
            agricultural commodities covered under the terms of a project
            agreement. Neither a Cooperator nor its affiliates 
            <PRTPAGE P='875' />
            shall charge a fee for facilitating an export sale. For the purposes
            of this paragraph, “affiliate” means any partnership, association,
            company, corporation, trust, or any other such party in which the
            Cooperator has an investment, other than a mutual fund. A Cooperator
            may collect check-off funds and membership fees that are required
            for membership in the Cooperator&apos;s organization.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Cooperator shall not use program activities or program funds to
            promote private self interests or conduct private business, except
            as members of sales teams.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A Cooperator shall select U.S. agricultural industry
            representatives to participate in activities such as trade teams or
            trade fairs based on criteria that ensure participation on an
            equitable basis by a broad cross section of the U.S. industry. If
            requested, a Cooperator shall submit such selection criteria to FAS
            for approval.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All Cooperators should endeavor to ensure fair and accurate
            fact-based advertising. Deceptive or misleading promotions may
            result in cancellation or termination of a project agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Cooperator must report any actions or circumstances that have a
            bearing on the propriety of program activities to the
            Attache/Counselor and the Cooperator&apos;s U.S. office shall report
            such actions in writing to the appropriate Division Director.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13064'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1484:C:1484.35
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1484.35
      </num>
      <head>
        Must Cooperators follow specific contracting procedures?
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          64 FR 52630
        </aref>
        , Sept. 30, 1999. Redesignated and amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          65 FR 9995
        </aref>
        , Feb. 25, 2000]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1484' sect='35' psec='' tq='N'>
              1484.35
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Must Cooperators follow specific contracting procedures?
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Cooperators have full and sole responsibility for the legal
            sufficiency of all contracts and assume financial liability for any
            costs or claims resulting from suits, challenges, or other disputes
            based on contracts entered into by the Cooperator. Neither FAS nor
            any other agency of the United States Government or any official or
            employee of FAS or the United States Government has any obligation
            or responsibility with respect to Cooperator contracts with third
            parties.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Cooperators are responsible for ensuring to the extent possible
            that the terms, conditions, and costs of contracts constitute the
            most economical and effective use of project funds.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All fees for professional and consulting services paid in any part
            with project funds must be covered by written contracts.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A Cooperator shall:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Ensure that all expenditures for goods and services in excess of
            $25.00, which are reimbursed with project funds, are documented by a
            purchase order, invoice, or contract;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Ensure that no employee or officer participates in the selection or
            award of a contract in which such employee or officer, or the
            employee&apos;s or officer&apos;s family or partners has a financial
            interest;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Conduct all contracting in an open manner. Individuals who develop
            or draft specifications, requirements, statements of work,
            invitations for bids, or requests for proposals for procurement of
            any goods or services shall be excluded from competition for such
            procurement;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Base each solicitation for professional or consulting services on a
            clear and accurate description of the requirements for the services
            to be procured;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Perform some form of price or cost analysis, such as a comparison
            of price quotations to market prices or other price indicia, to
            determine the reasonableness of the offered prices; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Document the decision-making process.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            64 FR 52630
          </aref>
          , Sept. 30, 1999. Redesignated and amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            65 FR 9995
          </aref>
          , Feb. 25, 2000]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13065'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1484:C:1484.36
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1484.36
      </num>
      <head>
        How do Cooperators dispose of disposable property?
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          64 FR 52630
        </aref>
        , Sept. 30, 1999. Redesignated and amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          65 FR 9995, 9996
        </aref>
        , Feb. 25, 2000]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1484' sect='36' psec='' tq='N'>
              1484.36
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          How do Cooperators dispose of disposable property?
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Property purchased by the Cooperator, and for which the Cooperator
            is reimbursed with project funds, that is unusable, unserviceable,
            or no longer needed for project purposes shall be disposed of in one
            of the following ways. The Cooperator may:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Exchange or sell the property, provided that it applies any
            exchange allowance, insurance proceeds, or sales proceeds toward the
            purchase of other property needed in the project;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             With FAS approval, transfer the goods to other Cooperators for
            their activities, or to a foreign third party; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon Attache/Counselor approval, donate the goods to a local
            charity, or 
            <PRTPAGE P='876' />
            convey the goods to the Attache/Counselor, along with an itemized
            inventory list and any documents of title.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A Cooperator shall maintain an inventory of all property valued at
            $500 or more which was acquired in furtherance of program
            activities. The inventory shall list and number each item and
            include the date of purchase or acquisition, cost of purchase,
            replacement value, serial number, make, model, and electrical
            requirements.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Cooperator shall insure all property which was acquired with
            program funds and safeguard such property against theft, damage, and
            unauthorized use. The Cooperator shall promptly report any loss,
            theft, or damage of such property to the insurance company.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Cooperator is responsible for reimbursing FAS for the value of
            any uninsured property at the time of the loss or theft of the
            property.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            64 FR 52630
          </aref>
          , Sept. 30, 1999. Redesignated and amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            65 FR 9995, 9996
          </aref>
          , Feb. 25, 2000]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13066'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1484:C:1484.37
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1484.37
      </num>
      <head>
        Must Cooperators adhere to Federal Travel Regulations?
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1484' sect='37' psec='' tq='N'>
              1484.37
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Must Cooperators adhere to Federal Travel Regulations?
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Travel shall conform to the U.S. Federal Travel Regulation (41 CFR
          Chapters 300 through 304) and air travel shall conform to the
          requirements of the “Fly America Act” (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='49' sect='1517' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/49/1517.html'>
              49 U.S.C. 1517
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ). The Cooperator shall notify the Attache/Counselor in the
          destination countries in writing in advance of any proposed travel.
          The timing of such notice should be far enough in advance to enable
          the Attache/Counselor to schedule appointments, make preparations, or
          otherwise provide any assistance being requested. Failure to provide
          advance notification of travel may result in disallowance of the
          expenses related to the travel.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13067'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1484:C:1484.38
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1484.38
      </num>
      <head>
        Can a Cooperator keep proceeds generated from an activity?
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          64 FR 52630
        </aref>
        , Sept. 30, 1999. Redesignated and amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          65 FR 9995, 9996
        </aref>
        , Feb. 25, 2000]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1484' sect='38' psec='' tq='N'>
              1484.38
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Can a Cooperator keep proceeds generated from an activity?
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Any income or refunds generated from an activity, 
          <E T='03'>
            i.e.
          </E>
          , participation fees, proceeds of sales, refunds of value added taxes
          (VAT), the expenditures for which have been wholly or partially
          reimbursed, shall be repaid by submitting a check payable to Commodity
          Credit Corporation or by offsetting the Cooperator&apos;s next
          reimbursement claim.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            64 FR 52630
          </aref>
          , Sept. 30, 1999. Redesignated and amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            65 FR 9995, 9996
          </aref>
          , Feb. 25, 2000]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13068'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1484:D:1484.50
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1484.50
      </num>
      <head>
        What cost share contributions are eligible?
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1484' sect='50' psec='' tq='N'>
              1484.50
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          What cost share contributions are eligible?
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Cooperator shall pay all costs necessary for the operation of
            the Cooperator&apos;s U.S. office.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In calculating the amount of contributions that it will make, and
            the contributions it will receive from a U.S. industry or a State
            agency, a Cooperator program applicant may include the costs (or
            such prorated costs) listed under paragraph (c) of this section if:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Expenditures will be made in furtherance of the Cooperator&apos;s
            overall foreign market development program;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The contributor has not been or will not be reimbursed by any other
            source for such costs; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The contribution is made during the period covered by the project
            agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subject to paragraph (b) of this section, eligible contributions
            are:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Cash;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Compensation paid to personnel;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The cost of acquiring materials, supplies, or services;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The cost of office space;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A reasonable and justifiable proportion of general administrative
            costs and overhead;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payments for indemnity and fidelity bond expenses;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The cost of business cards;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The cost of seasonal greeting cards;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Fees for office parking;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The cost of subscriptions to publications;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_11'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (11)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The cost of activities conducted overseas;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_12'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (12)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Credit card fees;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_13'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (13)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The cost of any independent evaluation or audit that is not
            required by FAS to ensure compliance with program requirements;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_14'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (14)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The cost of giveaways, awards, prizes and gifts;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_15'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (15)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The cost of product samples;
            <PRTPAGE P='877' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_16'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (16)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Fees for participating in U.S. government activities;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_17'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (17)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The cost of air and local travel in the United States related to a
            foreign market development effort;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_18'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (18)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Transportation and shipping costs;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_19'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (19)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The cost of displays and promotional materials;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_20'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (20)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Advertising costs;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_21'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (21)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Reasonable travel costs and expenses related to undertaking a
            foreign market development activity;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_22'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (22)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payment of employee&apos;s or contractor&apos;s share of personal
            taxes;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_23'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (23)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The cost associated with trade shows, seminars, entertainment and
            STRE conducted in the United States;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_24'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (24)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Product research that is undertaken to benefit an industry and has
            a specific export application; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_25'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (25)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Consumer promotions.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13069'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1484:D:1484.51
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1484.51
      </num>
      <head>
        What are ineligible contributions?
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1484' sect='51' psec='' tq='N'>
              1484.51
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          What are ineligible contributions?
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The following are not eligible contributions:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any portion of salary or compensation of an individual who is the
            target of a promotional activity;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any land costs other than allowable costs for office space;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Depreciation;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The cost of refreshments and related equipment provided to office
            staff;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The cost of insuring articles owned by private individuals;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The cost of any arrangement which has the effect of reducing the
            selling price of an agricultural commodity;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The cost of product development or product modifications;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Slotting fees or similar sales expenditures;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Funds, services, or personnel provided by any U.S. government
            agency;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Capital investments made by a third party, such as permanent
            structures, real estate, and the purchase of office equipment and
            furniture;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_11'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (11)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The value of any services generated by a Cooperator or third party
            which involve no expenditure by the Cooperator or third party, e.g.,
            free publicity;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_12'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (12)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Membership fees in clubs and social organizations; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_13'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (13)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             costs included as contributions for any other federally-assisted
            project or program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Deputy Administrator shall determine, at the Deputy
            Administrator&apos;s discretion, whether any cost not expressly
            listed in this section may be included by the Cooperator as an
            eligible contribution.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13070'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1484:D:1484.52
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1484.52
      </num>
      <head>
        What are the guidelines for computing the value of non-cash
        contributions?
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1484' sect='52' psec='' tq='N'>
              1484.52
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          What are the guidelines for computing the value of non-cash
          contributions?
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Computing the value of an individual&apos;s time.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If an individual&apos;s salary is known, allocate the
            individual&apos;s salary on the basis of time spent on foreign
            market development activities. If the individual&apos;s salary is
            unknown, claim up to the equivalent of a step 10, GS-15 for
            professional personnel and up to the current estimated industry rate
            at the person&apos;s level of employment for nonprofessional
            personnel.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Computing the value of indirect expenditures.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Allocate value on the basis of sound management and accounting
            procedures when considering indirect expenditures, such as overhead
            and facilities, which are furnished by the industry.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13071'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1484:D:1484.53
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1484.53
      </num>
      <head>
        What are the requirements for documenting and reporting contributions?
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1484' sect='53' psec='' tq='N'>
              1484.53
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          What are the requirements for documenting and reporting contributions?
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each claimed contribution must be documented by the Cooperator,
            showing the method of computing non-cash contributions, salaries,
            and travel expenses.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each Cooperator must keep records of the methods used to compute
            the value of non-cash contributions, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Copies of invoices or receipts for expenses paid by the U.S.
            industry and not reimbursed by the Cooperator for the joint
            activity; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If invoices are not available, an itemized statement from the U.S.
            industry as to what costs it incurred pursuant to the joint
            activity; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If neither of the foregoing is available, a statement from the U.S.
            industry as to what goods and services it provided; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If none of the foregoing are available, a memo to the files of the
            U.S. 
            <PRTPAGE P='878' />
            Cooperator&apos;s estimate of what contributions were made by the
            U.S. industry, item by item, and the method used to assign a value
            to each.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each Cooperator must report its contributions as described in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1550' sect='70' psec='#a' tq='N'>
                1550.70 (a)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13072'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1484:D:1484.54
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1484.54
      </num>
      <head>
        What expenditures may FAS reimburse under the Cooperator program?
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1484' sect='54' psec='' tq='N'>
              1484.54
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          What expenditures may FAS reimburse under the Cooperator program?
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A Cooperator may seek reimbursement for an expenditure if:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The expenditure is reasonable and has been made in furtherance of a
            market development activity; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Cooperator has not been or will not be reimbursed for such
            expenditure by any other source.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subject to paragraph (a) of this section, FAS will reimburse, in
            whole or in part, the cost of:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Production and placement of advertising in print or electronic
            media or on billboards or posters;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Production and distribution of banners, recipe cards, table tents,
            shelf talkers, and similar point of sale materials;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Direct mail advertising;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Food service promotions, product demonstrations to the trade, and
            distribution of promotional samples;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Temporary displays and rental of space for temporary displays;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Fees for participation in retail and trade exhibits and shows, and
            booth construction and transportation of related materials to such
            exhibits and shows;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Trade seminars, including space rental, equipment rental, and
            duplication of seminar materials;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Production and distribution of publications;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Part-time contractors, such as interpreters, translators, and
            receptionists, to help with the implementation of promotional
            activities, such as trade shows, food service promotions, and trade
            seminars;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Giveaways, awards, prizes, gifts, and other similar promotional
            materials, subject to the limitation that FAS will not reimburse
            more than $1.00 per item;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_11'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (11)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Compensation and allowances for housing, educational tuition, and
            cost of living adjustments paid to U.S. citizen employees or U.S.
            citizen contractors stationed overseas, subject to the limitation
            that FAS shall not reimburse that portion of:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_11_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The total of compensation and allowances that exceed 125 percent of
            the level of a GS-15, Step 10 salary for U.S. Government employees,
            and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_11_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Allowances that exceed the rate authorized for U.S. Embassy
            personnel;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_12'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (12)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Foreign transfer, temporary lodging, and post hardship differential
            allowances for U.S. citizen employees;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_13'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (13)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Approved salaries or compensation for non-U.S. citizens and
            non-U.S. contractors. Generally, FAS will not reimburse any portion
            of a non-U.S. citizen employee&apos;s compensation that exceeds the
            compensation prescribed for the most comparable position in the
            Foreign Service National (FSN) salary plan applicable to the country
            in which the employee works. However, if the local FSN salary plan
            is inappropriate, a Cooperator may request a higher level of
            reimbursement for a non-U.S. citizen in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1550' sect='20' psec='#b_8' tq='N'>
                1550.20 (b)(8)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_14'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (14)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A retroactive salary adjustment that conforms to a change in FSN
            salary plans, effective as of the date of such change;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_15'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (15)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Accrued annual leave at such time when employment is terminated or
            when required by local law;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_16'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (16)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Overtime paid to clerical staff;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_17'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (17)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Fees for professional and consultant services;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_18'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (18)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Air travel, plus passports, visas, and inoculations, subject to the
            limitation that FAS will not reimburse any portion of air travel in
            excess of the full fare economy rate or when the Cooperator fails to
            notify the Attaché/Counselor in the destination country in advance
            of the travel, unless the Deputy Administrator determines it was
            impractical to provide such notification;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_19'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (19)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Per diem, subject to the limitation that FAS will not reimburse per
            diem in excess of the rates allowed under the U.S. Federal Travel
            Regulation (41 CFR Chapters 300 through 304);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_20'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (20)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Automobile mileage at the local U.S. Embassy rate, or rental cars
            while in travel status;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_21'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (21)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Other allowable expenditures while in travel status as authorized
            by 
            <PRTPAGE P='879' />
            the U.S. Federal Travel Regulation (41 CFR Chapters 300 through
            304);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_22'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (22)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An overseas office, including rent, utilities, communications
            originating overseas, office supplies, accident liability insurance
            premiums, and legal and accounting services;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_23'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (23)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The purchase, lease, or repair of, or insurance premiums for,
            property that has an expected useful life of at least one year, such
            as furniture, equipment, machinery, removable fixtures, floor
            coverings, and computer hardware and software;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_24'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (24)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Office decor, such as draperies or blinds;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_25'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (25)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Premiums for health or accident insurance or other benefits for
            foreign national employees that the employer is required by law to
            pay;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_26'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (26)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Accident liability insurance premiums for facilities used jointly
            with third party participants for Cooperator program activities, or
            such insurance premiums for travel of non-Cooperator personnel;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_27'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (27)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Market research;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_28'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (28)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Evaluations, if not required by FAS to ensure compliance with
            program requirements;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_29'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (29)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Legal fees to obtain advice on the host country&apos;s labor laws;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_30'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (30)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Employment agency fees;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_31'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (31)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             STRE, including breakfast, lunch, dinner, receptions, and
            refreshments at activities; miscellaneous courtesies such as
            checkroom fees, taxi fares, and tips; and decorations for a special
            promotional occasion;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_32'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (32)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Educational travel of dependent children, visitation travel, rest
            and recuperation travel, home leave travel, and emergency visitation
            travel for U.S. overseas employees as allowed under the Foreign
            Affairs Manual;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_33'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (33)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Evacuation payments (safe haven), and shipment and storage of
            household goods and motor vehicles;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_34'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (34)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Demonstration projects;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_35'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (35)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Purchase of trade and business periodicals containing material
            related to market development activities for use by overseas staffs;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_36'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (36)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Training expenses in the U.S. for FSNs;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_37'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (37)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Language training for U.S. citizen employees at the foreign post of
            assignment;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_38'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (38)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Forward year financial obligations required by local law or custom;
            such as severance pay, attributable to employment of foreign
            nationals; or forfeiture of rent or deposits, attributable to the
            closure of an office;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_39'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (39)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Fees for storage of necessary program materials;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_40'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (40)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Shipment of samples or other program materials from the U.S. to
            foreign countries; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_41'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (41)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             That portion of airtime for wireless phones that is devoted to
            program activities and monthly service fees prorated at the
            proportion of program-related airtime to total airtime.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13073'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1484:D:1484.55
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1484.55
      </num>
      <head>
        What expenditures may not be reimbursed under the Cooperator program?
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1484' sect='55' psec='' tq='N'>
              1484.55
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          What expenditures may not be reimbursed under the Cooperator program?
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FAS will not reimburse expenditures made prior to approval of a
            Cooperator&apos;s program, unreasonable expenditures, or any cost
            of:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Expenses, fines, settlements, or claims resulting from suits,
            challenges, or disputes emanating from employment terms, conditions,
            contract provisions, or related formalities;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Product development, product modification, or product research;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Product samples;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Slotting fees or similar sales expenditures;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The purchase, construction, or lease of space for permanent
            displays, 
            <E T='03'>
              i.e.
            </E>
            , displays lasting beyond one marketing plan year;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Office parking fees;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Coupon redemption or price discounts;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Refundable deposits or advances;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Giveaways, awards, prizes, gifts, and other similar promotional
            materials in excess of $1.00 per item;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Alcoholic beverages that are not an integral part of a promotional
            activity;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_11'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (11)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The purchase, lease (except for use in authorized travel status),
            or repair of motor vehicles;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_12'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (12)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Travel of applicants for employment interviews;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_13'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (13)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Unused non-refundable airline tickets or associated penalty fees,
            except where travel is restricted by U.S. government action or
            advisory;
            <PRTPAGE P='880' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_14'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (14)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any arrangement which has the effect of reducing the selling price
            of an agricultural commodity;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_15'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (15)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Goods and services and salaries of third party personnel;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_16'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (16)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Membership fees in clubs and social organizations;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_17'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (17)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Indemnity and fidelity bonds;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_18'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (18)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Fees for participating in U.S. Government sponsored activities,
            other than trade fairs, shows, and exhibits;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_19'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (19)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Business cards;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_20'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (20)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Seasonal greeting cards;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_21'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (21)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subscriptions to non-trade related publications;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_22'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (22)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Credit card fees;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_23'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (23)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Refreshments, or related equipment, for office staff;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_24'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (24)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Insurance on household goods and personal effects, including
            privately-owned automobiles, whether overseas or stored in the U.S.,
            belonging to U.S. citizen employees;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_25'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (25)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Home office domestic administrative expenses, including
            communication costs;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_26'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (26)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payment of U.S. or foreign employee&apos;s or contractor&apos;s
            share of personal taxes, except as legally required in a foreign
            country;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_27'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (27)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Wireless phone equipment, equipment repair, insurance, and other
            related charges;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_28'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (28)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             STRE expenses incurred in the U.S;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_29'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (29)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Entertainment, e.g., amusements, diversions, cover charges,
            personal gifts, or tickets to theatrical or sporting events;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_30'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (30)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Functions (including receptions and meals at Cooperator staff
            conferences) at which target groups, such as members of the overseas
            trade, opinion leaders, foreign government officials, and other
            similar groups, are not present; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_31'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (31)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Promotions directed at consumers purchasing in their individual
            capacity.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Deputy Administrator may determine, at the Deputy
            Administrator&apos;s discretion, whether any cost not expressly
            listed in this section will be reimbursed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FAS will reimburse for expenses incurred up to 30 calendar days
            beyond the conclusion of the marketing plan year.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13074'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1484:D:1484.56
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1484.56
      </num>
      <head>
        How are Cooperators reimbursed?
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1484' sect='56' psec='' tq='N'>
              1484.56
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          How are Cooperators reimbursed?
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A format for reimbursement claims is available from the Director,
            Marketing Operations Staff, FAS, USDA. Claims for reimbursement
            shall contain at least the following information:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Activity code;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Country code;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Cost category;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Amount to be reimbursed or credited;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If applicable, any reduction in the amount of reimbursement claimed
            to offset FAS demand for refund of amounts previously reimbursed,
            and reference to the relevant Compliance Report; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If applicable, any amount previously claimed that has not been
            reimbursed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All claims for reimbursement shall be submitted by the
            Cooperator&apos;s U.S. office to the Director, Marketing Operations
            Staff, FAS, USDA.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FAS will not reimburse claims submitted later than 6 months after
            the end of a marketing plan year.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If FAS overpays a reimbursement claim, the Cooperator shall repay
            FAS within 30 days the amount of the overpayment either by
            submitting a check payable to FAS or by offsetting its next
            reimbursement claim.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a Cooperator receives a reimbursement or offsets an advanced
            payment which is later disallowed, the Cooperator shall within 30
            days of such disallowance repay FAS the amount owed either by
            submitting a check payable to FAS or by offsetting its next
            reimbursement claim.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Cooperator shall report any actions having a bearing on the
            propriety of any claims for reimbursement to the Attache/Counselor
            and its U.S. office shall report such actions in writing to the
            Division Director(s).
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13075'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1484:D:1484.57
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1484.57
      </num>
      <head>
        Will FAS make advance payments to a Cooperator?
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1484' sect='57' psec='' tq='N'>
              1484.57
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Will FAS make advance payments to a Cooperator?
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Policy.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In general, FAS operates the Cooperator program on a reimbursable
            basis.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Exception.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon request, FAS may make two types of advance payments to a
            Cooperator. The first is a revolving fund operating advance provided
            by 
            <PRTPAGE P='881' />
            FAS only to Cooperators with foreign offices supported with project
            funds. The second is a special advance payment used to pay an
            impending large cost item. FAS will provide this type of advance
            expense payment in lieu of direct payments by FAS to vendors or
            other third parties. All Cooperators, with or without project
            fund-supported foreign offices, are eligible to request special
            advance payments. Normally, special advance payments received from
            FAS must be liquidated by the Cooperator within 90 days from the
            date of receipt. Prior to making an advance, FAS may require the
            participant to submit security in a form and amount acceptable to
            FAS to protect FAS&apos; financial interests. FAS will not make any
            special advance payment to a Cooperator where a special advance is
            outstanding from a prior marketing plan year. Cooperators shall
            deposit and maintain advances in insured, interest-bearing accounts,
            unless such accounts are prohibited by law or custom of a host
            country.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Refunds due FAS.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A participant shall return any unexpended portion of an advance,
            plus any interest earned, either by submitting a check payable to
            FAS or by offsetting its next reimbursement claim. All checks shall
            be mailed to the Director, Marketing Operations Staff, FAS, USDA.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13076'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1484:E:1484.70
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1484.70
      </num>
      <head>
        Must Cooperators report to FAS?
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1484' sect='70' psec='' tq='N'>
              1484.70
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Must Cooperators report to FAS?
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              End-of-year contribution report.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Not later than January 31 of the year following the completion of
            the marketing plan year, a Cooperator shall submit two copies of a
            report which identifies contributions made by the Cooperator and the
            U.S. industry during that marketing plan year. A suggested format of
            a contribution report is available on the FAS home page (
            <E T='03'>
              http://www.fas.usda.gov/mos/programs/fnotice.html
            </E>
            ) on the Internet or from the Director, Marketing Operations Staff,
            FAS, USDA.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Trip reports.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Not later than 45 days after completion of travel (other than local
            travel), a Cooperator shall submit a trip report. The report must
            include the name(s) of the traveler(s), purpose of travel,
            itinerary, names and affiliations of contacts, and a brief summary
            of findings, conclusions, recommendations, or specific
            accomplishments.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Research reports.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Not later than 6 months after the end of its marketing plan year, a
            Cooperator shall submit a report on any research conducted in
            accordance with its application.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Submission of reports.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A Cooperator shall submit the reports required by this section to
            the appropriate Division Director. Trip reports and research reports
            shall also be submitted to the appropriate Attache/Counselor(s). All
            reports shall be in English and include the Cooperator&apos;s
            agreement number, the countries and period covered, and the date of
            the report.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Additional reports.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FAS may require the submission of additional reports.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Independent audit reports.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A Cooperator shall provide to the FAS Compliance Review Staff, upon
            request, any audit reports by independent public accountants.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13077'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1484:E:1484.71
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1484.71
      </num>
      <head>
        Are Cooperator documents subject to the provisions of the Freedom of
        Information Act?
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1484' sect='71' psec='' tq='N'>
              1484.71
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Are Cooperator documents subject to the provisions of the Freedom of
          Information Act?
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Documents submitted to FAS by Cooperators are subject to the
            provisions of the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA), 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='5' sect='552' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/5/552.html'>
                5 U.S.C. 552
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1' tq='N'>
                1
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , Subpart A—Official Records, and, specifically, 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR 
              <subref title='7' part='1' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
                1.11
              </subref>
            </aref>
            —Handling Information from a Private Business.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If requested by a person located in the United States, a Cooperator
            shall provide to such person a copy of any document in its
            possession or control containing market information developed and
            produced under the terms of its agreement. The Cooperator may charge
            a fee not to exceed the costs for assembling, duplicating, and
            distributing the materials.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The results of any research conducted by a Cooperator under an
            agreement shall be the property of the U.S. Government.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13078'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1484:E:1484.72
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1484.72
      </num>
      <head>
        How is program effectiveness measured?
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1484' sect='72' psec='' tq='N'>
              1484.72
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          How is program effectiveness measured?
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Government Performance and Results Act (GPRA) of 1993 (5 U.S.C.
            
            <PRTPAGE P='882' />
            306; 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='31' sect='1105' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/31/1105.html'>
                31 U.S.C. 1105
              </subref>
              , 
              <subref title='31' sect='1115-111' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/31/1115-111.html'>
                1115-111
              </subref>
            </aref>
            9, 3515, 9703-9704) requires performance measurement of Federal
            programs, including the Cooperator program. Evaluation of the
            Cooperator program&apos;s effectiveness will depend on a clear
            statement by each Cooperator of the constraints and opportunities
            facing U.S. exports, goals to be met within a specified time, a
            schedule of measurable milestones for gauging success, a plan for
            achievement, and reports of activity results.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Evaluation is an integral element of program planning and
            implementation, providing the basis for the strategic plan. The
            evaluation results guide the development and scope of a
            Cooperator&apos;s program, contribute to program accountability, and
            provide evidence of program effectiveness.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A Cooperator shall conduct periodic evaluations of its program and
            activities and may contract with an independent evaluator to satisfy
            this requirement. FAS reserves the right to have direct input and
            control over design, scope, and methodology of any such evaluation,
            including direct contact with and provision of guidance to the
            independent evaluator.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A Cooperator shall complete at least one program evaluation each
            year. Actual scope and timing of the program evaluation shall be
            determined by the Cooperator and the Division Director and specified
            in the Cooperator&apos;s application approval letter. A program
            evaluation shall contain:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The name of the party conducting the evaluation;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The activities covered by the evaluation;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A concise statement of the constraint(s) and opportunities and the
            goals specified in the application;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A description of the evaluation methodology;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A description of additional export sales achieved, including the
            ratio of additional export sales in relation to Cooperator program
            funding received;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A summary of the findings, including an analysis of the strengths
            and weaknesses of the program(s); and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Recommendations for future programs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A Cooperator shall submit, via a cover letter to the Division
            Director, an executive summary which assesses the program
            evaluation&apos;s findings and recommendations and proposes changes
            in program strategy or design as a result of the evaluation.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13079'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1484:E:1484.73
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1484.73
      </num>
      <head>
        Are Cooperators penalized for failing to make required contributions?
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          64 FR 52630
        </aref>
        , Sept. 30, 1999. Redesignated and amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          65 FR 9995, 9996
        </aref>
        , Feb. 25, 2000]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1484' sect='73' psec='' tq='N'>
              1484.73
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Are Cooperators penalized for failing to make required contributions?
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          A Cooperator&apos;s contribution requirement is specified in the
          Cooperator program allocation letter. If a Cooperator fails to
          contribute the amount specified in its allocation approval letter, the
          Cooperator shall pay to Commodity Credit Corporation in U.S. dollars
          the difference between the amount it has contributed and the amount
          specified in the allocation approval letter. A Cooperator shall remit
          such payment by December 31 following the end of the marketing plan
          year.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            64 FR 52630
          </aref>
          , Sept. 30, 1999. Redesignated and amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            65 FR 9995, 9996
          </aref>
          , Feb. 25, 2000]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13080'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1484:E:1484.74
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1484.74
      </num>
      <head>
        How is Cooperator program compliance monitored?
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          64 FR 52630
        </aref>
        , Sept. 30, 1999. Redesignated and amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          65 FR 9995, 9996
        </aref>
        , Feb. 25, 2000]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1484' sect='74' psec='' tq='N'>
              1484.74
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          How is Cooperator program compliance monitored?
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Compliance Review Staff (CRS), FAS, performs periodic on-site
            reviews of Cooperators to ensure compliance with this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In order to verify that federal funds received by a Cooperator do
            not supplant private or U.S. industry funds or contributions
            pursuant to 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1550' sect='20' psec='#a_14' tq='N'>
                1550.20(a)(14)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , FAS will consider the Cooperator&apos;s overall marketing budget
            from year to year, variations in promotional strategies within a
            country or region, and new markets.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Director, CRS, will notify a Cooperator through a compliance
            report when it appears that Commodity Credit Corporation may be
            entitled to recover funds from that Cooperator. The compliance
            report will state the basis for this action.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            64 FR 52630
          </aref>
          , Sept. 30, 1999. Redesignated and amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            65 FR 9995, 9996
          </aref>
          , Feb. 25, 2000]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13081'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1484:E:1484.75
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1484.75
      </num>
      <head>
        How does a Cooperator respond to a compliance report?
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          64 FR 52630
        </aref>
        , Sept. 30, 1999. Redesignated and amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          65 FR 9995, 9996
        </aref>
        , Feb. 25, 2000]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1484' sect='75' psec='' tq='N'>
              1484.75
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          How does a Cooperator respond to a compliance report?
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A Cooperator shall, within 60 days of the date of the compliance
            report, submit a written response to the Director, CRS. This
            response shall include any money owed to Commodity Credit
            Corporation if the Cooperator does not wish to contest the
            compliance report. The Director, CRS, at the Director&apos;s 
            <PRTPAGE P='883' />
            discretion, may extend the period for response up to an additional
            30 days. If the Cooperator does not respond to the compliance report
            within the required time period or, if after review of the
            Cooperator&apos;s response, the Director, CRS, determines that
            Commodity Credit Corporation may be entitled to recover funds from
            the Cooperator, the Director, CRS, will refer the compliance report
            to the Deputy Administrator.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If, after review of the compliance report and response, the Deputy
            Administrator determines that the Cooperator owes money to FAS, the
            Deputy Administrator will so inform the Cooperator. The Deputy
            Administrator may initiate action to collect such amount pursuant to
            
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR Part 
              <subref title='7' part='1403' tq='N'>
                1403
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , Debt Settlement Policies and Procedures. Determinations of the
            Deputy Administrator will be in writing and in sufficient detail to
            inform the Cooperator of the basis for the determination. The
            Cooperator has 30 days from the date of the Deputy
            Administrator&apos;s initial determination to submit any money owed
            to Commodity Credit Corporation or to request reconsideration.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            64 FR 52630
          </aref>
          , Sept. 30, 1999. Redesignated and amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            65 FR 9995, 9996
          </aref>
          , Feb. 25, 2000]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13082'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:C:1484:E:1484.76
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1484.76
      </num>
      <head>
        Can a Cooperator appeal the determinations of the Deputy Administrator?
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1484' sect='76' psec='' tq='N'>
              1484.76
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Can a Cooperator appeal the determinations of the Deputy
          Administrator?
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Cooperator may appeal the determinations of the Deputy
            Administrator to the Administrator. An appeal must be in writing and
            be submitted to the Office of the Administrator within 30 days
            following the date of the initial determination by the Deputy
            Administrator or the determination on reconsideration. The
            Cooperator may request a hearing.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the Cooperator submits its appeal and requests a hearing, the
            Administrator, or the Administrator&apos;s designee, will set a date
            and time, generally within 60 days. The hearing will be an informal
            proceeding. A transcript will not ordinarily be prepared unless the
            Cooperator bears the cost of a transcript; however, the
            Administrator may have a transcript prepared at FAS&apos;s expense.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Administrator will base the determination on appeal upon
            information contained in the administrative record and will endeavor
            to make a determination within 60 days after submission of the
            appeal, hearing, or receipt of any transcript, whichever is later.
            The determination of the Administrator will be the final
            determination of FAS. The Cooperator must exhaust all administrative
            remedies contained in this section before pursuing judicial review
            of a determination by the Administrator.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>