<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol6'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:C:623
    </extid>
    <num>
      623
    </num>
    <head>
      EMERGENCY WETLANDS RESERVE PROGRAM
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='16' sect='3837-383' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/3837-383.html'>
              16 U.S.C. 3837-383
            </subref>
          </aref>
          7f; 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Pub. L. 103-75' alt='Pub. L. 103-75' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:75%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Pub. L. 103-75
          </aref>
          , Chapter 1, 
          <aref target='_blank' href='http://frwebgate.access.gpo.gov/cgi-bin/getpage.cgi?dbname=103_statutes_at_large&amp;position=all&amp;page=739'>
            107 Stat. 739, 742
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 62497
          </aref>
          , Nov. 29, 1993, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='6224'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:C:623:-:623.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        623.1
      </num>
      <head>
        Purpose and scope.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='623' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              623.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Purpose and scope.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The regulations in this part set forth the policies, procedures,
            and requirements for the Emergency Wetlands Reserve Program (EWRP).
            Under the EWRP, NRCS will make offers to purchase wetland
            conservation easements from persons owning croplands that were
            damaged by the 1993 Midwest floods if those lands have the potential
            for restoration to wetland conditions and if the owner voluntarily
            agrees to restore and maintain those conditions. The easements are
            to be purchased to promote the restoration and maintenance of
            wetland characteristics, such as hydrologic conditions of inundation
            or saturation of the soil and hydrophytic vegetation. The functions
            and values of the wetlands for wildlife habitat, water quality
            improvement, flood water retention, floodway enhancement, ground
            water recharge, open space, aesthetic values, and environmental
            education will thus be promoted. The wetland conservation easements
            will permanently prohibit use of 
            <PRTPAGE P='475' />
            the affected land as cropland. Additionally, the easement shall
            require permanent maintenance of the wetland conditions, except in
            the case of natural disaster.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The EWRP is available only in the following States: Illinois, Iowa,
            Kansas, Minnesota, Missouri, Nebraska, South Dakota, and Wisconsin.
            Certain cropland areas within these States have been determined to
            have been inundated by the Midwest floods of 1993. As more fully
            defined and described in this part, eligible land may include farmed
            wetlands or prior converted wetlands (wetlands converted prior to
            December 23, 1985), together with adjacent lands on which the
            wetlands are functionally dependent so long as the likelihood of
            successful restoration of such land and the potential wetland values
            merit inclusion in the program with reasonable costs.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6225'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:C:623:-:623.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        623.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='623' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              623.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The following definitions shall be applicable for the purposes of this
          part:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Agricultural commodity—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            means any crop planted and produced by annual tilling of the soil,
            or on an annual basis by one trip planters, or alfalfa and other
            multiyear grasses and legumes in rotation as approved by the
            Secretary. For purposes of determining crop history, as relevant to
            eligibility to enroll land in the program, land shall be “considered
            planted to an agricultural commodity” during a crop year if, as
            determined by ASCS, as action of the Secretary prevented land from
            being planted to the commodity during the crop year.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Applicant—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            means a person who submits to NRCS an application to participate in
            the EWRP.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Commodity Credit Corporation—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            a wholly owned government corporation within the U.S. Department of
            Agriculture.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Conservation District
            </E>
             (CD)—means a subdivision of a State or local government organized
            pursuant to applicable State law to promote soil and water
            conservation practices.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Conservation Reserve Program—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            means the program under which long-term payments and cost-share
            assistance is provided to individuals to establish permanent
            vegetative cover on cropland that is highly erodible or
            environmentally sensitive.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Prior converted wetland—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            means wetland that has been drained, dredged, filled, leveled, or
            otherwise manipulated (including any activity that results in
            impairing or reducing the flow, circulation, or reach of water)
            prior to December 23, 1985, for the purpose, or that has the effect,
            of making the production of agricultural commodities possible if
            such production would not have been possible but for such action.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Cost-share payment—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            means the payment made by NRCS to assist program participants in
            establishing the practices required in a WRPO.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Chief—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            means the Chief of the Natural Resources Conservation Service, or
            the Chief&apos;s designee.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Easement—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            means the real property interest acquired by NRCS under this part
            for wetland restoration and maintenance and which is properly filed
            with the appropriate local or State government official.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Easement area—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            means the land to which the approved wetland restoration practices
            and wetland conservation restrictions are to be applied.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Fair market value (FMV)—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            means the price that a willing seller would accept and a willing
            buyer would pay in an open, informed transaction.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='l'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (l)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Farmed wetland—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            means wetland that was drained, dredged, filled, or otherwise
            manipulated prior to December 23, 1985 to the extent that the
            production of agricultural commodities was made possible, but which
            continues to meet wetland criteria [refer to 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR 
              <subref title='7' part='12' sect='32' psec='#a_3' tq='N'>
                12.32(a)(3)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             for descriptions of farmed wetlands].
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='m'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (m)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Floodwater control systems—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            means dikes, levees, or other similar structural measures for the
            protection of cropland from flooding.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='n'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (n)
            </enum>
            <head>
              FWS—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            means the Fish and Wildlife Service of the United States Department
            of the Interior.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='o'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (o)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Local NRCS office—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            means the office of the Natural Resources Conservation Service
            serving the county or combination of counties in which the
            landowner&apos;s farm or ranch is located.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='p'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (p)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Participant—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            means a person(s) owning land subject to a perfected 
            <PRTPAGE P='476' />
            easement purchased by the Natural Resources Conservation Service
            under this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='q'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (q)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Offer—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            means the total payment NRCS will make to a landowner to purchase an
            easement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='r'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (r)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Permanent easement—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            means an easement in perpetuity.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='s'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (s)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Substantially altered lands—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            means lands which have not been and are not now wetlands but could
            likely develop wetland characteristics in the future, as a result of
            the Midwest floods of 1993.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='t'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (t)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Practice—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            means the wetland and easement area development restoration measures
            agreed to in the WRPO to accomplish the desired program objectives.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='u'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (u)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Technical assistance—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            means the assistance provided to land owners to facilitate
            implementation of the WRPO.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Wetland—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            means land that (1) has a predominance of hydric soils; (2) is
            inundated or saturated by surface or groundwater at a frequency and
            duration sufficient to support a prevalence of hydrophytic
            vegetation typically adapted for life in saturated soil conditions;
            and (3) does support a prevalence of such vegetation under normal
            circumstances.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6226'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:C:623:-:623.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        623.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Eligible person.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='623' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              623.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Eligible person.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          To be eligible to participate in the EWRP, a person must be the owner
          of eligible land for which enrollment is sought and must have been the
          owner of such land for at least the preceding 12 months prior to the
          time the enrollment offer is declared by NRCS, as provided in this
          part. The person shall provide to NRCS adequate proof of ownership of
          the land. NRCS may waive the 12 month ownership requirement if:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The land was acquired by will or succession as a result of the
            death of the previous owner; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Adequate assurances have been presented that the new owner of such
            land did not acquire such land for the purpose of placing it in the
            EWRP.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6227'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:C:623:-:623.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        623.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Eligible land.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='623' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              623.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Eligible land.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as otherwise provided in this section, land is eligible for
            enrollment in the EWRP only if NRCS determines that the land:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Was inundated by the Midwest floods of 1993;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If restored to productive condition, would have a fair market value
            that is less than the estimated costs of restoring the land to
            productive condition and repairing related floodwater control
            systems;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is likely to have its wetland value restored with minimal costs;
            and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is wetland farmed under natural conditions, a farmed wetland or
            prior converted wetland, or substantially altered lands which are
            cropland; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is wetland that has been restored on the land under a CRP contract,
            or under a Federal or State wetland restoration program with an
            easement for a period of less than 30 years.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be eligible for enrollment in the EWRP, land must also:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be determined by ASCS to have been annually planted or considered
            planted to an agricultural commodity in at least 1 of the 5 previous
            crop years; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be land under a CRP contract, in which case, the land need only to
            have been planted to an agricultural commodity during 2 of the 1981
            through 1985 crop years.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Other lands may be considered eligible if the inclusion of such
            lands in the EWRP easement would significantly add to the functions
            and values of the wetlands to be restored under this part, as
            determined by NRCS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The criteria and procedures contained in 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='12' tq='N'>
                12
              </subref>
            </aref>
             will be used to identify wetlands, converted wetlands, and farmed
            wetlands.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6228'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:C:623:-:623.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        623.5
      </num>
      <head>
        Ineligible land.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='623' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              623.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Ineligible land.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Notwithstanding any other provisions of this part, the following land
          is not eligible for enrollment in the EWRP:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land that contains either timber stands or trees established in
            connection with a CRP contract;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Lands owned or acquired by an agency of the Federal Government;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land already subject to a deed restriction prohibiting the
            production of agricultural commodities or the alternation of
            existing wetland hydrologic conditions;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land located between the pre-flood mainstem levees and the river;
            or
            <PRTPAGE P='477' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land that was restored to wetland conditions, as required under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              Part 
              <subref title='7' part='12' tq='N'>
                12 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , to mitigate the conversion of wetland to cropland use.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6229'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:C:623:-:623.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        623.6
      </num>
      <head>
        Transfer of lands from the CRP to the EWRP.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='623' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              623.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Transfer of lands from the CRP to the EWRP.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Land that is subject to an existing CRP contract administered under 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR parts 
            <subref title='7' part='704' tq='N'>
              704
            </subref>
             and 
            <subref title='7' part='1410' tq='N'>
              1410
            </subref>
          </aref>
           may be transferred into the EWRP only if:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The land and landowner(s) meet the requirements of this part; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The application for transfer into the EWRP is approved by Commodity
            Credit Corporation (CCC), if found to be in the interest of the
            program. If such transfer is requested by the owner and approved by
            CCC, the CRP contract for the property will be terminated or
            otherwise modified subject to such terms and conditions as are
            mutually agreed by the landowner, CCC, and NRCS.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6230'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:C:623:-:623.7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        623.7
      </num>
      <head>
        Terms of the easement.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='623' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              623.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Terms of the easement.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Landowners will grant to NRCS an easement which shall run with the
          land and be in favor of NRCS and its assigns or delegates. The
          easement shall require the land to be monitored as specified by the
          WRPO to promote the purposes of this part, including but not limited
          to maintenance of the restored wetland for entire length of the
          easement. Such easement shall: (a) be a permanent reserve interest
          easement; (b) require that the maintenance of the land be in
          accordance with the terms of the easement and with the terms of the
          WRPO and shall be the responsibility of the owners of the property and
          their successors of any kind, including, but not limited to, the
          owners&apos; heirs and assigns; (c) grant to NRCS a right of access in
          favor of NRCS and its delegates, assigns and successors of any kind,
          to the portion of the property which is subject to the provisions of
          the easement. Maintenance of such access shall be the responsibility
          of the owner and their successors of any kind; (d) reserve to NRCS the
          right to permit such compatible uses of the easement area as may be
          identified in the WRPO; (e) reserve to the landowner those compatible
          uses identified in the WRPO that are permitted to be pursued by the
          landowner; (f) be signed by each person with an interest of any kind
          in the land covered by the easement; (g) permanently prohibit use of
          the easement area for cropland, except to harvest an agricultural
          commodity planted before the easement is perfected; and (h) require
          permanent maintenance of the wetland conditions, except in the case of
          natural disaster.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6231'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:C:623:-:623.8
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        623.8
      </num>
      <head>
        Easement value.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='623' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              623.8
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Easement value.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          NRCS offers for easements will be based on the fair market value, as
          determined by the NRCS State Conservationist, of the land covered by
          the easements. Fair market value will be based on post-flood
          conditions as if reclaimed. Land easement values will be determined by
          the State Conservationist in consultation with a technical committee.
          A technical committee shall included representatives of: ASCS,
          Extension Service, and FWS. Additionally, the State Conservationist
          may collect information from other sources as he deems necessary.
          Coordination between States will be provided by the Chief, NRCS.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6232'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:C:623:-:623.9
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        623.9
      </num>
      <head>
        Easement priority.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='623' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
              623.9
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Easement priority.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The State Conservationist, in consultation with the FWS and with input
          from a technical committee and other interested Federal agencies, will
          establish a ranking process to establish the priority of parcels
          offered into the EWRP. This process will rank the floodway enhancement
          and environmental benefits per dollar of government expenditure on
          restoration and easement purchase. The factors for determining the
          priority for selection will consider the following:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Protection and enhancement of habitat for migratory birds and
            wildlife, including the contribution the restoration may make to the
            recovery of threatened and endangered species,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Floodway expansion,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Proximity to other protected wetlands,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Level of hydrology restored,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Wetland function or values,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Likelihood of successful restoration of wetland values,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Cost of restoration and easement purchase, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Other factors as determined appropriate by NRCS.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6233'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:C:623:-:623.10
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        623.10
      </num>
      <head>
        Application to participate.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='478' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='623' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
              623.10
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Application to participate.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A person seeking to enroll land in the EWRP must apply for
            enrollment on an approved NRCS form. The application to participate
            must be filed with the local NRCS field office during an announced
            period for such submissions.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A person submitting an application to participate shall not be
            obligated to accept an NRCS offer to purchase an easement if one is
            forthcoming.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An application to participate must be signed by all owners of the
            property or their duly authorized representative(s).
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6234'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:C:623:-:623.11
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        623.11
      </num>
      <head>
        Obligations of the landowner.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='623' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
              623.11
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Obligations of the landowner.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All owners of land who accept an EWRP offer from NRCS shall:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Comply with the terms of the easement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Comply with all terms and conditions of the WRPO for the full life
            of the easement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Ensure that the easement granted to NRCS is superior to the
            interest of all other parties who may have an interest in the
            easement area, except as authorized by NRCS. Such action shall
            include, but not be limited to, obtaining a written statement of
            consent to such a superior easement from those holding a security
            interest or any other encumbrance or the land covered by the
            easement. Additionally, the landowner shall perfect the easement
            with superior NRCS interest in accordance with State law.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Agree to the permanent retirement of the aggregate total of crop
            acreage bases, and allotment and mandatory quota on the farm or
            ranch in order to maintain the base allotment on quota acres at or
            below the number of acres of cropland after the easement has been
            perfected.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Not allow grazing or commercial use of the land covered by an
            easement except as provided for in the WRPO, or harvesting of any
            agricultural commodity produced on the land subject to the EWRP
            easement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Comply with Federal or State noxious week laws in the manner
            specified in the WRPO.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Control other identified weed and pest species, in the manner
            specified in the WRPO.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be responsible for repairs, improvements, and inspections of the
            WRPO practices as necessary to maintain existing public drainage
            systems when the land is restored to the condition required by the
            terms of the easement, the contract, and the easement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be permitted to control public access, in accordance with the WRPO,
            on the land enrolled in the program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Implement any additional provisions that are required by NRCS in
            consultation with FWS in the contract, WRPO, or easement, in order
            to, as determined by NRCS, facilitate the administration of the
            EWRP.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_11'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (11)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Not alter the vegetation, except to harvest already planted crops
            or forage, or hydrology on such acres subsequent to perfection of
            the easement by the landowner, except as provided for in the
            easement or WRPO.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_12'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (12)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be responsible for the long-term management of the easement in
            accordance with the terms of the easement and related agreements
            including the WRPO. Owners may enter into agreements with Federal or
            State agencies or private organizations to assist in the management
            of the easement area. No NRCS funds will be provided to these
            agencies or organizations for management expenses. Responsibility
            for management of the easement shall in all cases remain with the
            owner and the owner&apos;s successors of any kind regardless of
            whether arrangements are made for third-party management.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_13'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (13)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Agree that each person with an interest in the land covered by an
            easement under EWRP shall be jointly and severally responsible for
            compliance with the WRPO, the easement, the provisions of this part,
            and for any refunds or payment adjustment which may be required for
            violation of any terms or conditions of the WRPO, the easement, or
            provisions of this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_14'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (14)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Refrain from taking any action on the easement area unless
            specifically authorized in the reserve interest easement or the
            WRPO; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_15'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (15)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Secure any necessary local, State and Federal permits prior to
            commencing restoration of the designated area.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In addition, program participants and their successors of any kind
            may:
            <PRTPAGE P='479' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Not alter wildlife habitat and other natural land features of the
            enrolled land unless authorized by the WRPO.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Apply pesticides or fertilizers on enrolled land or mow such land,
            only as provided for in the WRPO.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Not engage in any activities on other land on the farm on which the
            easement exists that will, as determined by NRCS; (i) alter the flow
            of surface or subsurface water into or out of the easement area
            except as specified in the WRPO; or (ii) be otherwise inconsistent
            with the terms of the easement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The activities of any person on the property shall be considered
            for purposes of this section to be the actions of the program
            participant. However, if the NRCS determines that the activities of
            the person were beyond the control of the program participants, NRCS
            may adjust the remedies provided for in this part to the extent
            determined consistent with program goals. Obligations created by the
            easement shall run with the land and shall bind all persons having
            an interest in the property at any time whether such interest is
            created by death of the owner, sale, assignment, or otherwise.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6235'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:C:623:-:623.12
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        623.12
      </num>
      <head>
        Payments to landowners by NRCS.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='623' sect='12' psec='' tq='N'>
              623.12
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Payments to landowners by NRCS.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS will share the cost with landowners of rehabilitating the
            enrolled land in the EWRP as provided in the WRPO. The amount of the
            cost-share assistance shall be specified in the contract. Eligible
            costs for such cost-share assistance by NRCS shall only include
            those costs which NRCS determines are appropriate and shall be
            subject to the following restrictions:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State Conservationist will establish cost-share rates of
            between 75 to 100 percent of the historical cost of establishing or
            installing the practices specified in the WRPO; or pay the average
            cost of establishing the practices specified in the WRPO, based on
            the historical cost of establishing the practices in the State;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Cost-share payments may be made only upon a determination that an
            approved practice or an identifiable unit of the practice has been
            completed in compliance with NRCS approved standards and
            specifications; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Cost-share payments may not be made for the maintenance of the
            practice except as specifically permitted in writing by the State
            Conservationist.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notwithstanding paragraph (a)(3) of this section, cost share
            payments may be authorized for the replacement or restoration of
            practices for which cost share assistance has been previously
            allowed under the EWRP, but only if:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Replacement or restoration of the practice is needed to meet the
            objectives for which the easement was established; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The failure of the original practice was due to reasons beyond the
            control of the participant.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS shall pay the amount agreed upon by NRCS and the landowner for
            the purchase of the easement in a lump-sum amount after the easement
            is perfected in compliance with State law, except in the case of
            paragraph (c)(2) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For all easements, NRCS shall pay no more than 75 percent of the
            total easement price pending completion of the practices to restore
            the wetlands as provided under the WRPO. The remaining amount shall
            be paid when NRCS determines the restoration is complete.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             After an easement is perfected, NRCS will reimburse landowners for
            fair and reasonable expenses incurred for title searches, filing
            expenses, and related costs, as determined by NRCS.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6236'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:C:623:-:623.13
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        623.13
      </num>
      <head>
        Wetlands reserve plan of operations.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='623' sect='13' psec='' tq='N'>
              623.13
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Wetlands reserve plan of operations.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             After NRCS has accepted the applicant for enrollment in the
            program, a WRPO will be developed by the landowner and NRCS, in
            consultation with FWS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The WRPO shall:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Include an aerial photo displaying the land offered for enrollment;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Specify the manner in which the eligible land shall be restored,
            operated, and maintained to accomplish the goal of the program,
            including, but not limited to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Measures to control noxious weeds and insect pests in order to
            comply with applicable Federal, or State noxious weed and pest
            control laws; and
            <PRTPAGE P='480' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Measures to control other specified species of weeds, insects or
            pests;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Specify compatible land uses for personal enjoyment for which the
            landowner may be compensated. These compatible land uses shall be
            reserved to the landowner in the easement. Such uses may include,
            among others:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Recreational use, hunting and fishing;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Manage timber production including harvesting; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Managed haying or grazing consistent with the goals of the program;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Set out cost estimates of the practices required by the WRPO, the
            offer for the easement, and other reimbursement costs;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Identify access routes to be maintained for wetland restoration
            activities and future management and easement monitoring in
            connection with the land to be enrolled;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Make provisions deemed necessary for maintaining public drainage
            systems if present on lands subject to the WRPO;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Contain scheduled implementation dates for restoration practices;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Contain other provisions or limitations as NRCS, in consultation
            with the FWS, determines to be necessary.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS in consultation with FWS will collect from State or Federal
            agencies whatever additional information is deemed necessary for the
            development of the WRPO with the landowner.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The WRPO must be signed by NRCS, FWS, Conservation District (CD),
            and the landowner(s). However, if agreement between NRCS and FWS, or
            CD at the local level is not reached within 20 calendar days, the
            WRPO shall be developed by the State Conservationist of NRCS in
            consultation with FWS or CD.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The WRPO may require that a temporary vegetative or water cover be
            established on the property if immediate establishment of a
            permanent cover is not practicable or otherwise desirable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The terms of an approved WRPO shall not relieve the program
            participant of any obligation or term imposed or provided for in the
            contract, the easement, or this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             WRPO, where appropriate, will provide for the development of a tree
            planting plan with the assistance of the FS or State forestry
            agency.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The WRPO, where appropriate, will provide for the development by
            NRCS of detailed plans for weed control, structural measures and
            their operation, vegetation establishment and management, and other
            measures as needed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Revisions of the WRPO to enhance or protect the value for which the
            easement was established may be made at any time at the request of
            either NRCS, FWS, the owner and upon the concurrence of all three
            parties.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6237'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:C:623:-:623.14
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        623.14
      </num>
      <head>
        Easement modifications.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='623' sect='14' psec='' tq='N'>
              623.14
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Easement modifications.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          After the easement has been perfected, no change will be made in the
          easement without a written request by the participant and the written
          consent of the Chief. Approval may be granted to achieve the goals of
          EWRP or facilitate the practical administration and management of the
          easement area or the program and the approval will not adversely
          affect the functions and values for which the easement was
          established. A modified easement shall be perfected in accordance with
          State law and NRCS superior interest shall be reserved by the
          landowner in accordance with 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='623' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              623.7
            </subref>
             and 
            <subref title='7' part='623' sect='11' psec='#a_3' tq='N'>
              623.11(a)(3)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6238'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:C:623:-:623.15
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        623.15
      </num>
      <head>
        Transfer of land.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='623' sect='15' psec='' tq='N'>
              623.15
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Transfer of land.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a new owner purchases or obtains the right and interest in, or
            right to occupancy of, the land subject to a EWRP easement, such new
            owner shall be subject to the terms and conditions of the easement.
            The participant who is the signatory to the easement shall be
            entitled to receive all remaining payments, if any, for the purchase
            of the easement. Eligible cost-share payments shall be made to the
            participants. with respect to costs actually incurred.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon the transfer of the property subject to an EWRP easement, any
            remaining cost-share payments shall be paid to the new owner or
            purchaser only if the new owner or purchaser becomes a party to the
            WRPO within 60 days of the perfection of the deed transferring title
            to the new owner. Such payments shall be paid in the 
            <PRTPAGE P='481' />
            manner agreed to by the participant and the buyer. The new owner or
            purchaser shall be responsible for assuring completion of all
            measures and practices required by the contract and the WRPO.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any transfer of the property prior to the perfection of the
            easement shall void any NRCS offer or WRPO unless the new owner
            agrees to accept the offer within 60 days of the perfection of the
            deed transferring the land to the new owner.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6239'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:C:623:-:623.16
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        623.16
      </num>
      <head>
        Monitoring and enforcement of easement terms and conditions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='623' sect='16' psec='' tq='N'>
              623.16
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Monitoring and enforcement of easement terms and conditions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS or its representative shall be permitted to inspect each
            easement area at any and all times determined necessary by NRCS to
            ensure that:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Structural and vegetative restoration work are properly maintained;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The wetlands and adjacent upland habitat of the easement area is
            being managed as required in the WRPO and the terms of the easement;
            and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Uses of the area are consistent with the terms and conditions of
            the easement and the WRPO.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If an owner or other interested party is unwilling to voluntarily
            correct, in a timely manner, deficiencies in compliance with the
            terms of the WRPO, the EWRP easement, or any related agreements,
            NRCS may at the expense of any person who is subject to the EWRP
            easement correct such deficiency. Such NRCS action shall be in
            addition to other remedies available to NRCS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Monitoring and enforcement responsibilities may be delegated by
            NRCS at any time to other Federal or State agencies. Landowners may
            transfer management responsibilities only to Federal, State, or
            local agencies or private organizations that have been approved by
            NRCS in advance as having the appropriate authority, expertise, and
            resources necessary to carry out such delegated responsibilities.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6240'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:C:623:-:623.17
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        623.17
      </num>
      <head>
        Violations and remedies.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='623' sect='17' psec='' tq='N'>
              623.17
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Violations and remedies.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a violation of the terms and conditions of the contract, the
            WRPO, or the recorded EWRP easement occurs, the easement shall
            remain in force and NRCS may:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Require the owner to fully restore the easement area to fulfill the
            terms and conditions of the easement and WRPO; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Require the owner, who received payments from NRCS for any purpose
            under this part, to refund all or part of such payments received
            together with interest, as determined appropriate by NRCS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If an owner fails to carry out the terms and conditions of an
            easement, appropriate legal action may be initiated. The owner of
            the property shall reimburse NRCS for all costs incurred including,
            but not limited to, legal fees.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6241'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:C:623:-:623.18
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        623.18
      </num>
      <head>
        Access to land.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='623' sect='18' psec='' tq='N'>
              623.18
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Access to land.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          In order to determine eligibility and compliance with respect to this
          part, representatives of the Department, or designee thereof, shall
          have the right of access to:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land which is the subject of an application made in accordance with
            this part,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land which is subject to an easement made in accordance with this
            part, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Records of the participant showing status of all ownership interest
            in lands subject to this part.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6242'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:C:623:-:623.19
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        623.19
      </num>
      <head>
        Assignments.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='623' sect='19' psec='' tq='N'>
              623.19
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Assignments.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Any participant entitled to any cash payment under this program may
          assign the right to receive such cash payments, in whole or in part.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6243'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:C:623:-:623.20
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        623.20
      </num>
      <head>
        Appeals.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          60 FR 67316
        </aref>
        , Dec. 29, 1995]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='623' sect='20' psec='' tq='N'>
              623.20
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Appeals.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          A participant in the EWRP may obtain a review of any administrative
          determination concerning land eligibility, development of a WRPO, or
          any adverse determination under this part in accordance with the
          administrative appeal regulations provided in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='614' tq='N'>
              614 of this title
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            60 FR 67316
          </aref>
          , Dec. 29, 1995]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6244'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:C:623:-:623.21
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        623.21
      </num>
      <head>
        Scheme and device.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='623' sect='21' psec='' tq='N'>
              623.21
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Scheme and device.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If it is determined by NRCS that a landowner has employed a scheme
            or device to defeat the purposes of this part, any part of any
            program payment otherwise due or paid such landowner during the
            applicable period may be 
            <PRTPAGE P='482' />
            withheld or be required to be refunded with interest thereon, as
            determined appropriate by NRCS, and the contract with the landowner
            may be terminated. In such a case, NRCS may also continue to hold
            the easement interest acquired under this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A scheme or device includes, but is not limited to, coercion,
            fraud, misrepresentation, depriving any other person of payments for
            cost-share practices or easements for the purpose of obtaining a
            payment to which a person would otherwise not be entitled.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An owner of land subject to this part who succeeds to the
            responsibilities under this part shall report in writing to NRCS any
            interest of any kind in the land subject to this part that is
            retained by a previous participant. Such interest includes a
            present, future or conditional interest, reversionary interest or
            any option, future or present, with respect to such land and any
            interest of any lender in such land where the lender has, will, or
            can obtain, a right of occupancy to such land or an interest in the
            equity in such land other than an interest in the appreciation in
            the value of such land occurring after the loan was made. A failure
            of full disclosure will be considered a scheme or device under this
            section.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6245'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:C:623:-:623.22
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        623.22
      </num>
      <head>
        Filing of false claims.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='623' sect='22' psec='' tq='N'>
              623.22
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Filing of false claims.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          If it is determined by NRCS that any participant has knowingly
          supplied false information or has knowingly filed a false claim, such
          participant shall be ineligible for any payment under this part. False
          information or false claims include claims for payment for practices
          which do not meet the specifications of the applicable WRPO. Any
          amounts paid under these circumstances shall be refunded, together
          with interest as determined by NRCS, and any amounts otherwise due
          such participant shall be withheld.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>