<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol10'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1470
    </extid>
    <num>
      1470
    </num>
    <head>
      CONSERVATION STEWARDSHIP PROGRAM
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='16' sect='3838d-383' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/3838d-383.html'>
              16 U.S.C. 3838d-383
            </subref>
          </aref>
          8g.
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 31653
          </aref>
          , June 3, 2010, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='13027'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1470:A:1470.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1470.1
      </num>
      <head>
        Applicability.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1470' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              1470.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Applicability.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This part sets forth the policies, procedures, and requirements for
            the Conservation Stewardship Program (CSP) as administered by the
            Natural Resources Conservation Service (NRCS), for enrollment during
            fiscal year (FY) 2009 and thereafter.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The purpose of CSP is to encourage producers to address resource
            concerns in a comprehensive manner by:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Undertaking additional conservation activities; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Improving, maintaining, and managing existing conservation
            activities.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CSP is applicable in any of the 50 States, District of Columbia,
            Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, Virgin Islands of the United
            States, American Samoa, and Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana
            Islands.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS provides financial assistance and technical assistance to
            participants for the conservation, protection, and improvement of
            soil, water, and other related natural resources, and for any
            similar conservation purpose as determined by NRCS.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13028'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1470:A:1470.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1470.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Administration.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1470' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              1470.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Administration.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The regulations in this part will be administered under the general
            supervision and direction of the Chief, NRCS, who is a Vice
            President of the Commodity Credit Corporation (CCC).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Chief is authorized to modify or waive a provision of this part
            if the Chief deems the application of that provision to a particular
            limited situation to be inappropriate and inconsistent with the
            purposes of the program. This authority cannot be further delegated.
            The Chief may not modify or waive any provision of this part which
            is required by applicable law.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To achieve the conservation goals of CSP, NRCS will:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Make the program available nationwide to eligible applicants on a 
            <PRTPAGE P='854' />
            continuous application basis with one or more ranking periods to
            determine enrollments. One of the ranking periods will occur in the
            first quarter of each fiscal year, to the extent practicable; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Develop conservation measurement tools (CMT) for the purpose of
            carrying out the program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             During the period beginning on October 1, 2008, and ending on
            September 30, 2017, NRCS will, to the maximum extent practicable:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Enroll in CSP an additional 12,769,000 acres for each fiscal year;
            and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Manage CSP to achieve a national average rate of $18 per acre,
            which includes the costs of all financial and technical assistance
            and any other expenses associated with program enrollment and
            participation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State Conservationist will:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Obtain advice from the State Technical Committee and local working
            groups on the development of State-level technical, outreach, and
            program matters, including:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Establishment of ranking pools appropriate for the conduct of CSP
            within the State to ensure program availability and prioritization
            of conservation activities. Ranking pools may be based on
            watersheds, geographic areas, or other appropriate regions within a
            State and may consider high-priority regional and State-level
            resource concern areas;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Identification of not less than three, nor more than five priority
            resource concerns in particular watersheds, geographic areas, or
            other appropriate regions within a State;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Identification of resource-conserving crops that will be part of
            resource-conserving crop rotations;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Development of design protocols and participation procedures for
            participation in on-farm research, and demonstration and pilot
            projects; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_1_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Evaluation of Cooperative Conservation Partnership Initiative
            (CCPI) projects and allowable program adjustments for the conduct of
            projects.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Assign NRCS employees as designated conservationists to be
            responsible for CSP at the local level; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be responsible for the program in their assigned State.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS may enter into agreements with Federal, State, and local
            agencies, conservation districts, Indian tribes, private entities,
            and individuals to assist NRCS with program implementation.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13029'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1470:A:1470.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1470.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1470' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              1470.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The following definitions will apply to this part and all documents
          issued in accordance with this part, unless specified otherwise:
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Agricultural land
          </E>
           means cropland, rangeland, and pastureland on which agricultural
          products or livestock are produced and resource concerns may be
          addressed. Agricultural lands may also include other land and
          incidental areas included in the agricultural operation as determined
          by NRCS. Other agricultural lands include cropped woodland, marshes,
          incidental areas included in the agricultural operation, and other
          types of agricultural land used for production of livestock.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Agricultural operation
          </E>
           means all agricultural land and other land, as determined by NRCS,
          whether contiguous or noncontiguous:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Which is under the effective control of the applicant; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Which is operated by the applicant with equipment, labor,
            management, and production or cultivation practices that are
            substantially separate from other operations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Animal waste storage or treatment facility
          </E>
           means a structural conservation practice used for storing or treating
          animal waste.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Applicant
          </E>
           means a person, legal entity, joint operation, or Indian tribe that
          has an interest in an agricultural operation, as defined in 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR part 
            <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
              1400
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , who has requested in writing to participate in CSP.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Beginning farmer or rancher
          </E>
           means:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An individual or legal entity who:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Has not operated a farm, ranch, or nonindustrial private forest
            land (NIPF), or who has operated a farm, ranch, or NIPF for not more
            than 10 consecutive years (this requirement applies to all members
            of a legal entity); and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Will materially and substantially participate in the operation of
            the farm or ranch.
            <PRTPAGE P='855' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the case of a contract with an individual, individually, or with
            the immediate family, material and substantial participation
            requires that the individual provide substantial day-to-day labor
            and management of the farm or ranch, consistent with the practices
            in the county or State where the farm is located.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the case of a contract with a legal entity or joint operation,
            all members must materially and substantially participate in the
            operation of the farm or ranch. Material and substantial
            participation requires that each of the members provide some amount
            of the management or labor and management necessary for day-to-day
            activities, such that if each of the members did not provide these
            inputs, operation of the farm or ranch would be seriously impaired.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Chief
          </E>
           means the Chief of NRCS, or designee.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Conservation activities
          </E>
           means conservation systems, practices, or management measures needed
          to address a resource concern or improve environmental quality through
          the treatment of natural resources, and includes structural,
          vegetative, and management activities as determined by NRCS.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Conservation district
          </E>
           means any district or unit of State, tribal, or local government
          formed under State, tribal, or territorial law for the express purpose
          of developing and carrying out a local soil and water conservation
          program. Such district or unit of government may be referred to as a
          “conservation district,” “soil conservation district,” “soil and water
          conservation district,” “resource conservation district,” “land
          conservation committee,” “natural resource district,” or similar name.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Conservation measurement tool
          </E>
           means procedures developed by NRCS to estimate the level of
          environmental benefit to be achieved by a producer using the proxy of
          conservation performance.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Conservation planning
          </E>
           means using the planning process outlined in the applicable National
          Planning Procedures Handbook (NPPH).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Conservation practice
          </E>
           means a specified treatment, such as a structural or vegetative
          practice or management technique, commonly used to meet a specific
          need in planning and carrying out conservation programs for which
          standards and specifications have been developed. Conservation
          practices are in the NRCS Field Office Technical Guide, section IV,
          which is based on the National Handbook of Conservation Practices.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Conservation stewardship plan
          </E>
           means a record of the participant&apos;s decisions that describes the
          schedule of conservation activities to be implemented, managed, or
          improved. Associated supporting information that identifies and
          inventories resource concerns and existing conservation activities,
          establishes benchmark data, and documents the participant&apos;s
          conservation objectives will be maintained with the plan.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Conservation system
          </E>
           means a combination of conservation practices, management measures,
          and enhancements used to address natural resource and environmental
          concerns in a comprehensive, holistic, and integrated manner.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Contract
          </E>
           means a legal document that specifies the rights and obligations of
          any participant who has been accepted into the program. A CSP contract
          is an agreement for the transfer of assistance from NRCS to the
          participant for installing, adopting, improving, managing, and
          maintaining conservation activities.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Designated conservationist
          </E>
           means an NRCS employee whom the State Conservationist has designated
          as responsible for CSP at the local level.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Effective control
          </E>
           means possession of the land by ownership, written lease, or other
          legal agreement and authority to act as decisionmaker for the
          day-to-day management of the operation both at the time the applicant
          enters into a stewardship contract and for the required period of the
          contract.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Enhancement
          </E>
           means a type of conservation activity used to treat natural resources
          and improve conservation performance. Enhancements are installed at a
          level of management intensity that exceeds the sustainable level for a
          given resource concern, and those enhancements directly related to a
          practice standard are applied in a manner that exceeds the minimum
          treatment requirements of the standard.
          <PRTPAGE P='856' />
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Enrollment
          </E>
           means for the initial sign-up for FY 2009, NRCS will consider a
          participant “enrolled” in CSP based on the fiscal year the application
          is submitted, once NRCS approves the participant&apos;s contract. For
          subsequent ranking cut-off periods, NRCS will consider a participant
          enrolled in CSP based on the fiscal year the contract is approved.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Field office technical guide
          </E>
           means the official local NRCS source of resource information and
          interpretations of guidelines, criteria, and standards for planning
          and applying conservation practices and conservation management
          systems. It contains detailed information on the conservation of soil,
          water, air, plant, and animal resources applicable to the local area
          for which it is prepared.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Indian lands
          </E>
           means all lands held in trust by the United States for individual
          Indians or Indian tribes, or all land titles held by individual
          Indians or tribes, subject to Federal restrictions against alienation
          or encumbrance, or lands subject to the rights of use, occupancy, or
          benefit of certain Indian tribes. This term also includes lands for
          which the title is held in fee status by Indian tribes and the U.S.
          Government-owned land under the Bureau of Indian Affairs (BIA)
          jurisdiction.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Indian Tribe
          </E>
           means any Indian tribe, band, nation, pueblo, or other organized
          group or community, including any Alaska Native village or regional or
          village corporation as defined in or established pursuant to the
          Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='43' sect='1601' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/43/1601.html'>
              43 U.S.C. 1601
            </subref>
          </aref>
          <E T='03'>
            et seq.
          </E>
          ), which is recognized as eligible for the special programs and
          services provided by the United States to Indians because of their
          status as Indians.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Joint operation
          </E>
           means, as defined in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
              1400 of this chapter
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , a general partnership, joint venture, or other similar business
          arrangement in which the members are jointly and severally liable for
          the obligations of the organization.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Legal entity
          </E>
           means, as defined in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
              1400 of this chapter
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , an entity created under Federal or State law.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Limited Resource Farmer or Rancher
          </E>
           means:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A person with direct or indirect gross farm sales not more than the
            current indexed value in each of the previous 2 years ($142,000 is
            the amount for 2010, adjusted for inflation using Prices Paid by
            Farmer Index as compiled by the National Agricultural Statistical
            Service); and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Has a total household income at or below the national poverty level
            for a family of four, or less than 50 percent of county median
            household income in each of the previous 2 years (to be determined
            annually using Department of Commerce Data).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Liquidated damages
          </E>
           means a sum of money stipulated in the CSP contract that the
          participant agrees to pay NRCS if the participant fails to fulfill the
          terms of the contract. The sum represents an estimate of the technical
          assistance expenses incurred to service the contract, and reflects the
          difficulties of proof of loss and the inconvenience or non-feasibility
          of otherwise obtaining an adequate remedy.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Local working group
          </E>
           means the advisory body as described in 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR part 
            <subref title='7' part='610' tq='N'>
              610
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Management measure
          </E>
           means one or more specific actions that is not a conservation
          practice, but has the effect of alleviating problems or improving the
          treatment of the natural resources.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            National Organic Program
          </E>
           means the program, administered by the Department of Agriculture
          (USDA) Agricultural Marketing Service, which regulates the standards
          for any farm, wild crop harvesting, or handling operation that wants
          to market an agricultural product as organically produced.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Natural Resources Conservation Service
          </E>
           means an agency of USDA which has responsibility for administering
          CSP using the funds, facilities, and authorities of the CCC.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Nonindustrial private forest land
          </E>
           means rural land that has existing tree cover or is suitable for
          growing trees, and is owned by an individual, group, association,
          corporation, Indian tribe, or other private legal entity that has
          definitive decisionmaking authority over the land.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Operation and maintenance
          </E>
           means work performed by the participant to 
          <PRTPAGE P='857' />
          maintain existing conservation activities to at least the level of
          conservation performance identified at the time the application is
          obligated into a contract, and maintain additional conservation
          activities installed and adopted over the contract period.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Participant
          </E>
           means a person, legal entity, joint operation, or Indian tribe that
          is receiving payment or is responsible for implementing the terms and
          conditions of a CSP contract.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Payment
          </E>
           means financial assistance provided to the participant under the
          terms of the CSP contract.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Person
          </E>
           means, as defined in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
              1400 of this chapter
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , an individual, natural person and does not include a legal entity.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Priority resource concern
          </E>
           means a resource concern that is identified by the State
          Conservationist, in consultation with the State Technical Committee
          and local working groups, as a priority for a State, or the specific
          geographic areas within a State.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Producer
          </E>
           means a person, legal entity, joint operation, or Indian tribe who
          has an interest in the agricultural operation, as defined in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
              1400 of this chapter
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , or who is engaged in agricultural production or forest management.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Resource concern
          </E>
           means a specific natural resource problem that is likely to be
          addressed successfully through the implementation of conservation
          activities by producers.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Resource-conserving crop
          </E>
           means a crop that is one of the following:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A perennial grass;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A legume grown for use as forage, seed for planting, or green
            manure;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A legume-grass mixture;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A small grain grown in combination with a grass or legume, whether
            inter-seeded or planted in rotation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Resource-conserving crop rotation
          </E>
           means a crop rotation that:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Includes at least one resource-conserving crop as determined by the
            State Conservationist;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Reduces erosion;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Improves soil fertility and tilth;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Interrupts pest cycles; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In applicable areas, reduces depletion of soil moisture or
            otherwise reduces the need for irrigation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Secretary
          </E>
           means the Secretary of USDA.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Socially disadvantaged farmer or rancher
          </E>
           means a producer who has been subjected to racial or ethnic
          prejudices because of their identity as a member of a group without
          regard to their individual qualities. A socially disadvantaged group
          is a group whose members have been subject to racial or ethnic
          prejudice because of their identity as members of a group, without
          regard to their individual qualities. These groups consist of American
          Indians or Alaskan Natives, Asians, Blacks or African Americans,
          Native Hawaiians or other Pacific Islanders, and Hispanics. A socially
          disadvantaged applicant is an individual or entity who is a member of
          a socially disadvantaged group. For an entity, at least 50 percent
          ownership in the farm business must be held by socially disadvantaged
          individuals.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State Conservationist
          </E>
           means the NRCS employee authorized to implement CSP and direct and
          supervise NRCS activities in a State, Caribbean Area, or Pacific
          Islands Area.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State Technical Committee
          </E>
           means a committee established by the Secretary in a State pursuant to
          
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='16' sect='3861' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/3861.html'>
              16 U.S.C. 3861
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Stewardship threshold
          </E>
           means the level of natural resource conservation and environmental
          management required, as determined by NRCS using the CMT, to conserve
          and improve the quality and condition of a natural resource.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Technical assistance
          </E>
           means technical expertise, information, and tools necessary for the
          conservation of natural resources on land active in agricultural,
          forestry, or related uses. The term includes the following:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Technical services provided directly to farmers, ranchers, forest
            producers, and other eligible entities, such as conservation
            planning, technical consultation, preparation of forest stewardship
            management plans, and assistance with the design and implementation
            of conservation activities; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Technical infrastructure, including processes, tools, and agency
            functions needed to support delivery of technical services, such as
            technical standards, resource inventories, training, data,
            technology, monitoring, and effects analyses.
            <PRTPAGE P='858' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Technical Service Provider
          </E>
           means an individual, private-sector entity, or public agency
          certified by NRCS to provide technical services to program
          participants in lieu of, or on behalf of, NRCS as referenced in 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR part 
            <subref title='7' part='652' tq='N'>
              652
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13030'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1470:A:1470.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1470.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Allocation and management.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1470' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              1470.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Allocation and management.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Chief will allocate acres and associated funds to State
            Conservationists:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Primarily on each State&apos;s proportion of eligible land to the
            total amount of eligible land in all States; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             On consideration of:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The extent and magnitude of the conservation needs associated with
            agricultural production in each State based on natural resource
            factors that consider national, regional, and State-level priority
            ecosystem areas,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The degree to which implementation of the program in the State is,
            or will be, effective in helping producers address those needs, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Other considerations determined by the Chief to achieve equitable
            geographic distribution of program participation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State Conservationist will allocate acres to ranking pools, to
            the extent practicable, based on the same factors the Chief
            considers in making allocations to States.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Of the acres made available for each of fiscal years 2009 through
            2012 to carry out CSP, NRCS will use, as a minimum:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Five percent to assist beginning farmers or ranchers, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Five percent to assist socially disadvantaged farmers or ranchers.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In any fiscal year, allocated acres that are not enrolled by a date
            determined by NRCS may be reallocated with associated funds for use
            in that fiscal year under CSP. As part of the reallocation process,
            NRCS will consider several factors, including demand from
            applicants, national and regional conservation priorities, and
            prior-year CSP performance in States.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Of the CSP funds and acres made available for each fiscal year:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Chief will reserve 6 percent of funds and acres to ensure an
            adequate source of funds and acres for the CCPI. Of the funds and
            acres reserved, the Chief will allocate:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Ninety percent to projects based on the direction of State
            Conservationists, with the advice of State Technical Committees; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Ten percent to projects based on a national competitive process
            established by the Chief. In determining funding allocation
            decisions for these projects, NRCS will consider the extent to which
            they address national and regional conservation priorities.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any funds and acres reserved for the CCPI in a fiscal year that are
            not obligated by April 1 of that fiscal year may be used to carry
            out other CSP activities during the remainder of that fiscal year.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13031'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1470:A:1470.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1470.5
      </num>
      <head>
        Outreach activities.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1470' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              1470.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Outreach activities.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS will establish program outreach activities at the national,
            State, and local levels to ensure that potential applicants who
            control eligible land are aware and informed that they may be
            eligible to apply for program assistance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Special outreach will be made to eligible producers with
            historically low participation rates, including but not restricted
            to, beginning farmers or ranchers, limited resource farmers or
            ranchers, and socially disadvantaged farmers or ranchers.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS will ensure that outreach is provided so as not to limit
            producer participation because of size or type of operation or
            production system, including specialty crop and organic production.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS will conduct focused outreach in regions of national
            significance in order to maximize program participation. These areas
            could include landscapes such as the Chesapeake Bay watershed and
            Great Lakes basin.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13032'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1470:A:1470.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1470.6
      </num>
      <head>
        Eligibility requirements.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 31653
        </aref>
        , June 3, 2010, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          76 FR 19684
        </aref>
        , Apr. 8, 2011]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1470' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              1470.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Eligibility requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Eligible applicant.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be an eligible applicant for CSP, a producer must be the
            operator in the Farm Service Agency (FSA) farm records management
            system. Potential applicants that are not in the FSA farm records
            management system must establish records with FSA. Potential
            applicants whose records are not current in the FSA 
            <PRTPAGE P='859' />
            farm records management system must update those records prior to
            the close of the evaluation period to be considered eligible. NRCS
            may grant exceptions to the “operator of record” requirement for
            producers, tenants, and owners in the FSA farm records management
            system that can demonstrate, to the satisfaction of NRCS, they will
            operate and have effective control of the land. Applicants must also
            meet all of the following requirements:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Have effective control of the land unless an exception is made by
            the Chief in the case of land administered by the BIA, Indian lands,
            or other instances in which the Chief determines that there is
            sufficient assurance of control;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be in compliance with the highly erodible land and wetland
            conservation provisions found at 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='12' tq='N'>
                12
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be in compliance with Adjusted Gross Income provisions found at 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
                1400
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Supply information, as required by NRCS, to determine eligibility
            for the program, including but not limited to, information related
            to eligibility requirements and ranking factors, conservation
            activity and production system records, information to verify the
            applicant&apos;s status as a historically underserved producer, if
            applicable, and payment eligibility as established by 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
                1400
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provide a list of all members of the legal entity and embedded
            entities along with members&apos; tax identification numbers and
            percentage interest in the entity. Where applicable, American
            Indians, Alaska Natives, and Pacific Islanders may use another
            unique identification number for each individual eligible for
            payment; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Comply with applicable registration and reporting requirements of
            the Federal Funding Accountability and Transparency Act of 2006 (
            <aref target='_blank' title='Pub. L. 109-282' alt='Pub. L. 109-282' href='http://www.gpo.gov/fdsys/pkg/PLAW-109publ282/html/PLAW-109publ282.htm'>
              Pub. L. 109-282
            </aref>
            , as amended), and 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              2 CFR parts 
              <subref title='2' part='25' tq='N'>
                25
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='2' part='170' tq='N'>
                170
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Eligible land.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A contract application must include all of the eligible land on an
            applicant&apos;s agricultural operation, except as identified in
            paragraph (b)(3) of this section. A participant may submit an
            application(s) to enter into an additional contract(s) for newly
            acquired eligible land, which would then compete with other
            applications in a subsequent ranking period. The land as described
            below is part of the agricultural operation and eligible for
            enrollment in the CSP:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Private agricultural land;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Agricultural Indian lands;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NIPF:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             By special rule in the statute, NIPF is eligible land,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No more than 10 percent of the acres enrolled nationally in any
            fiscal year may be NIPF,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The applicant will designate by submitting a separate application
            if they want to offer NIPF for funding consideration,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If designated for funding consideration, then the NIPF component of
            the operation will include all the applicant&apos;s NIPF. If not
            designated for funding consideration, then the applicant&apos;s NIPF
            will not be part of the agricultural operation; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Other private agricultural land, as determined by the Chief, on
            which resource concerns related to agricultural production could be
            addressed by enrolling the land in CSP.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Ineligible land.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The following ineligible lands are part of the agricultural
            operation, but ineligible for inclusion in the contract or for
            payment in CSP:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land enrolled in the Conservation Reserve Program (CRP), 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1410' tq='N'>
                1410
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land enrolled in the Wetlands Reserve Program (WRP), 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1467' tq='N'>
                1467
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land enrolled in the Grassland Reserve Program (GRP), 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1415' tq='N'>
                1415
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land enrolled in the Conservation Security Program, 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1469' tq='N'>
                1469
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Public land including land owned by a Federal, State, or local unit
            of government; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land used for crop production after June 18, 2008, that had not
            been planted, considered to be planted, or devoted to crop
            production for at least 4 of the 6 years preceding that date, unless
            that land:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_6_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Had previously been enrolled in CRP,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_6_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Has been maintained using long-term crop rotation practices as
            determined by the designated conservationist, or
            <PRTPAGE P='860' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_6_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is incidental land needed for efficient operation of the farm or
            ranch as determined by the designated conservationist.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 31653
          </aref>
          , June 3, 2010, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 19684
          </aref>
          , Apr. 8, 2011]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13033'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1470:A:1470.7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1470.7
      </num>
      <head>
        Enhancements and conservation practices.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1470' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              1470.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Enhancements and conservation practices.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Participant decisions describing the additional enhancements and
            conservation practices to be implemented under the conservation
            stewardship contract will be recorded in the conservation
            stewardship plan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS will make available to the public the list of enhancements and
            conservation practices available to be installed, adopted,
            maintained, and managed through the CSP.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS will make available bundled suites of conservation activities
            for participants to voluntarily select to include as part of their
            conservation stewardship plans. The bundles will be designed to
            coordinate the installation and adoption of enhancements with each
            other to address resource concerns in a more comprehensive and
            cost-effective manner.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CSP encourages the use of other NRCS programs to install
            conservation practices that are required to meet agreed-upon
            stewardship thresholds, but the practices may not be compensated
            through CSP.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13034'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1470:A:1470.8
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1470.8
      </num>
      <head>
        Technical and other assistance.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1470' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              1470.8
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Technical and other assistance.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS may provide technical assistance to an eligible applicant or
            participant either directly or through a technical service provider
            (TSP) as set forth in 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='652' tq='N'>
                652
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS retains approval authority over certification of work done by
            non-NRCS personnel for the purpose of approving CSP payments.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS will ensure that technical assistance is available and program
            specifications are appropriate so as not to limit producer
            participation because of size or type or operation or production
            system, including specialty crop and organic production. In
            providing technical assistance to specialty crop and organic
            producers, NRCS will provide appropriate training to field staff to
            enable them to work with these producers and to utilize cooperative
            agreements and contracts with nongovernmental organizations with
            expertise in delivering technical assistance to these producers.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS will assist potential applicants dealing with the requirements
            of certification under the National Organic Program and CSP
            requirements concerning how to coordinate and simultaneously meet
            eligibility standards under each program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS may utilize the services of State foresters and existing
            technical assistance programs such as the Forest Stewardship Program
            of the U.S. Forest Service, in coordinating assistance to NIPF
            owners.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13035'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1470:B:1470.20
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1470.20
      </num>
      <head>
        Application for contracts and selecting offers from applicants.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1470' sect='20' psec='' tq='N'>
              1470.20
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Application for contracts and selecting offers from applicants.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Submission of contract applications.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Applicants may submit an application to enroll all of their
            eligible land into CSP on a continuous basis.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Stewardship threshold requirement.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be eligible to participate in CSP, an applicant must submit to
            the designated conservationist for approval, a contract application
            that:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Indicates the applicant&apos;s conservation activities, at the time
            of application, are meeting the stewardship threshold for at least
            one resource concern;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Would, at a minimum, meet or exceed the stewardship threshold for
            at least one priority resource concern in addition to the resource
            concern described in paragraph (b)(1) of this section by the end of
            the conservation stewardship contract by:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Installing and adopting additional conservation activities, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Improving, maintaining, and managing conservation activities
            present on the agricultural operation at the time the contract
            application is accepted by NRCS;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provides a map, aerial photograph, or overlay that:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Identifies the applicant&apos;s agricultural operation and NIPF
            component of the operation, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Delineates eligible land with associated acreage amounts; and
            <PRTPAGE P='861' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the applicant is applying for on-farm research and demonstration
            activities or for pilot testing, describes the nature of the
            research, demonstration, or pilot testing in a manner consistent
            with design protocols and application procedures established by
            NRCS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Evaluation of contract applications.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS will conduct one or more ranking periods each fiscal year.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To the extent practicable, one ranking period will occur in the
            first quarter of the fiscal year;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In evaluating CSP applications, the State Conservationist or
            designated conservationist will rank applications based on the
            following factors, using the CMT, to the maximum extent practicable:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Level of conservation treatment on all applicable priority resource
            concerns at the time of application,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Degree to which the proposed conservation treatment on applicable
            priority resource concerns effectively increases conservation
            performance,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Number of applicable priority resource concerns proposed to be
            treated to meet or exceed the stewardship threshold by the end of
            the contract, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Extent to which other resource concerns, in addition to priority
            resource concerns, will be addressed to meet or exceed the
            stewardship threshold by the end of the contract period;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the event that application ranking scores from (2) above are
            similar, the application that represents the least cost to the
            program will be given higher priority; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State Conservationist or designated conservationist may not
            assign a higher priority to any application because the applicant is
            willing to accept a lower payment than the applicant would otherwise
            be eligible to receive.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Weighting of ranking factors.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To the extent the CSP objective of additional conservation is not
            being achieved, as determined by the Chief, NRCS will adjust the
            weighting of ranking factors in order to place emphasis on
            increasing net conservation benefits.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              State and local priorities.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Chief may develop and use additional criteria for evaluating
            applications that are determined necessary to ensure that national,
            State, and local conservation priorities are effectively addressed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Ranking pools.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Ranking pools will be established in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1470' sect='2' psec='#e_1_i' tq='N'>
                1470.2(e)(1)(i)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NIPF will compete in ranking pools separate from agricultural land.
            An applicant with both NIPF and agricultural land will have the
            options to submit:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             One application for NIPF;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             One application for agricultural land; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Two applications, one for each land type.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An applicant with an agricultural operation or NIPF component of
            the operation that crosses ranking pool boundaries will make
            application and be ranked in the ranking pool where the largest
            acreage portion of their operation occurs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Within each State or established ranking pool, the State
            Conservationist will address conservation access for certain farmers
            or ranchers, including:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Socially disadvantaged farmers or ranchers; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Beginning farmers or ranchers.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Application pre-approval.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State Conservationist or designated conservationist will make
            application pre-approval determinations during established ranking
            periods based on eligibility and ranking score.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Field verification.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS will conduct onsite field verification prior to obligation of
            contract funding to substantiate the accuracy of the information
            provided by pre-approved applicants during the application process.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13036'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1470:B:1470.21
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1470.21
      </num>
      <head>
        Contract requirements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1470' sect='21' psec='' tq='N'>
              1470.21
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Contract requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             After a determination that the application will be approved and a
            conservation stewardship plan will be developed in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1470' sect='22' psec='' tq='N'>
                1470.22
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , the State Conservationist or designee will enter into a
            conservation stewardship contract with the participant to enroll all
            of the eligible land on a participant&apos;s agricultural operation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The conservation stewardship contract will:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provide for payments over a period of 5 years;
            <PRTPAGE P='862' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Incorporate by reference the conservation stewardship plan;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State the payment amount NRCS agrees to make to the participant
            annually, subject to the availability of funds;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Incorporate all provisions as required by law or statute, including
            requirements that the participant will:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_4_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Implement the conservation stewardship plan approved by NRCS during
            the term of the contract,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_4_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Operate and maintain conservation activities on the agricultural
            operation consistent with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1470' sect='23' psec='' tq='N'>
                1470.23
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_4_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Comply with the terms of the contract or documents incorporated by
            reference into the contract,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_4_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Refund as determined by NRCS, any program payments received with
            interest, and forfeit any future payments under the program, upon
            the violation of a term or condition of the contract, consistent
            with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1470' sect='27' psec='' tq='N'>
                1470.27
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_4_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Refund as determined by NRCS, all program payments received with
            interest, upon the transfer of the right and interest of the
            participant, in land subject to the contract, unless the transferee
            of the right and interest agrees to assume all obligations of the
            contract, consistent with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1470' sect='25' psec='' tq='N'>
                1470.25
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_4_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Maintain and make available to NRCS upon request, appropriate
            records documenting applied conservation activity and production
            system information, and provide evidence of the effective and timely
            implementation of the conservation stewardship plan and contract,
            and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_4_vii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Not engage in any action during the term of the conservation
            stewardship contract on the eligible land covered by the contract
            that would interfere with the purposes of the conservation
            stewardship contract;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Permit all economic uses of the land that:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_5_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Maintain the agricultural or forestry nature of the land, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_5_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Are consistent with the conservation purposes of the contract;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Include a provision to ensure that a participant will not be
            considered in violation of the contract for failure to comply with
            the contract due to circumstances beyond the control of the
            participant, including a disaster or related condition, as
            determined by the State Conservationist; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Include such other provisions as NRCS determines necessary to
            ensure the purposes of the program are achieved.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13037'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1470:B:1470.22
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1470.22
      </num>
      <head>
        Conservation stewardship plan.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1470' sect='22' psec='' tq='N'>
              1470.22
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Conservation stewardship plan.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS will use the conservation planning process as outlined in the
            NPPH to encourage participants to address resource concerns in a
            comprehensive manner.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The conservation stewardship plan will contain a record of the
            participant&apos;s decisions that describes the schedule of
            conservation activities to be implemented, managed, or improved
            under the conservation stewardship contract.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Associated supporting information maintained with the
            participant&apos;s plan will include:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CMT documentation that will be the basis for:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Identifying and inventorying resource concerns,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Establishing benchmark data on the condition of existing
            conservation activities, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Documenting the participant&apos;s conservation objectives to reach
            and exceed stewardship thresholds;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A plan map delineating enrolled land with associated acreage
            amounts;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the case where a participant wishes to initiate or retain
            organic certification, documentation that will support the
            participant&apos;s transition to or participation in the National
            Organic Program;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the case where a participant is approved for the on-farm
            research and demonstration or pilot testing option, a research,
            demonstration, or pilot testing plan consistent with design
            protocols and application procedures established by NRCS; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Other information as determined appropriate by NRCS.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13038'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1470:B:1470.23
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1470.23
      </num>
      <head>
        Conservation activity operation and maintenance.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1470' sect='23' psec='' tq='N'>
              1470.23
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Conservation activity operation and maintenance.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The participant will maintain and manage existing conservation
          activities on the agricultural operation to at 
          <PRTPAGE P='863' />
          least the level of conservation performance identified at the time the
          application is obligated into a contract for the conservation
          stewardship contract period, and additional activities installed and
          adopted over the term of the conservation stewardship contract.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13039'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1470:B:1470.24
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1470.24
      </num>
      <head>
        Payments.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1470' sect='24' psec='' tq='N'>
              1470.24
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Payments.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Annual payments.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subject to the availability of funds, NRCS will provide, as
            appropriate, annual payments under the program to compensate a
            participant for installing and adopting additional conservation
            activities, and improving, maintaining, and managing existing
            conservation activities. A split-rate annual payment structure will
            be used to provide separate payments for additional and existing
            conservation activities in order to place emphasis on implementing
            additional conservation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To receive annual payments, a participant must:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Install and adopt additional conservation activities as scheduled
            in the conservation stewardship plan. At least one additional
            enhancement must be scheduled, installed, and adopted in the first
            fiscal year of the contract. All enhancements must be scheduled,
            installed, and adopted by the end of the third fiscal year of the
            contract, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             As a minimum, maintain existing activities to the level of existing
            conservation performance identified at the time the application is
            obligated into a contract for the conservation stewardship contract
            period;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To earn annual payments for an eligible land use, a participant
            must schedule, install, and adopt at least one additional
            conservation activity on that land-use type. Eligible land-use types
            that fail to have at least one additional conservation activity
            scheduled, installed, and adopted will not receive annual payments;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A participant&apos;s annual payments will be determined using the
            conservation performance estimated by the CMT and computed by
            land-use type for eligible land earning payments. Conservation
            performance is prorated over the contract term so as to accommodate,
            to the extent practicable, participants earning equal annual
            payments in each fiscal year;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The annual payment rates will be based to the maximum extent
            practicable, on the following factors:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_4_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Costs incurred by the participant associated with planning, design,
            materials, installation, labor, management, maintenance, or
            training,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_4_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Income foregone by the participant, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_4_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Expected environmental benefits, determined by estimating
            conservation performance improvement using the CMT;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The annual payment method will accommodate some participant
            operational adjustments without the need for contract modification.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_5_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Enhancements may be replaced with similar enhancements without
            adjustment of annual payment as long as the conservation performance
            is determined by NRCS to be equal to or better than the conservation
            performance of the additional enhancements offered at enrollment. An
            enhancement replacement that results in a decline below that
            conservation performance level will not be allowed, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_5_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Adjustments to existing activities may occur consistent with
            conservation performance requirements from 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1470' sect='23' psec='' tq='N'>
                1470.23
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Enhancements may be applied on other land included in an
            agricultural operation, as determined by NRCS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Supplemental payments.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subject to the availability of funds, NRCS will provide a
            supplemental payment to a participant receiving annual payments, who
            also agrees to adopt a resource-conserving crop rotation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State Conservationist will determine whether a
            resource-conserving crop rotation is eligible for supplemental
            payments based on whether the resource-conserving crop rotation is
            designed to provide natural resource conservation and production
            benefits;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A participant must agree to adopt and maintain a beneficial
            resource-conserving crop rotation for the term of the contract to be
            eligible to receive a supplemental payment. A resource-conserving
            crop rotation is considered adopted when the resource-conserving
            crop is planted on at least one-third of the rotation acres. The
            resource-conserving crop must be adopted by the third fiscal year of
            the contract and 
            <PRTPAGE P='864' />
            planted on all rotation acres by the fifth fiscal year of the
            contract; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The supplemental payment is set at a rate needed to encourage a
            producer to adopt a resource-conserving crop rotation and will be
            based, to the maximum extent practicable, on costs incurred and
            income foregone by the participant and expected environmental
            benefits, determined by estimating conservation performance
            improvement using the CMT.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              On-farm research and demonstration or pilot testing.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A participant may be compensated through their annual payment for:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             On-farm research and demonstration activities; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Pilot testing of new technologies or innovative conservation
            activities.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Minimum contract payment.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS will make a minimum contract payment to participants who are
            socially disadvantaged farmers or ranchers, beginning farmers or
            ranchers, or limited resource farmers or ranchers, at a rate
            determined by the Chief in any fiscal year that a contract&apos;s
            payment amount total is less than $1,000. Definitions of socially
            disadvantaged farmers or ranchers, beginning farmers or ranchers,
            and limited resource farmers or ranchers are contained in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1470' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
                1470.3
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Timing of payments.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS will make payments as soon as practicable after October 1 of
            each fiscal year for activities carried out in the previous fiscal
            year. For newly enrolled contracts, payments will be made as soon as
            practicable after October 1 following the fiscal year of enrollment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Non-compensatory matters.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A CSP payment to a participant will not be provided for:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             New conservation practices or enhancements applied with financial
            assistance through other USDA conservation programs;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The design, construction, or maintenance of animal waste storage or
            treatment facilities, or associated waste transport or transfer
            devices for animal feeding operations; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Conservation activities for which there is no cost incurred or
            income foregone by the participant.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Payment limits.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A person or legal entity may not receive, directly or indirectly,
            payments that, in the aggregate, exceed $40,000 during any fiscal
            year for all CSP contracts entered into, and $200,000 for all CSP
            contracts entered into during any 5-year period, excluding funding
            arrangements with federally recognized Indian tribes or Alaska
            Native corporations, regardless of the number of contracts entered
            into under the CSP by the person or legal entity.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Contract limits.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payments under a conservation stewardship contract with joint
            operations will be limited to $80,000 per fiscal year and $400,000
            over the term of the initial contract period, excluding funding
            arrangements with federally recognized Indian tribes or Alaska
            Native corporations. The payment limits for contracts with persons
            or legal entities are contained in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1470' sect='24' psec='#g' tq='N'>
                1470.24(g)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Payment limitation provisions for individual Indians and Indian
              tribes.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payment limitations apply to individual tribal member(s) when
            applying and subsequently being granted a contract as an
            individual(s). Contracts with Indian tribes or Alaska Native
            corporations are not subject to payment or contract limitations.
            Indian tribes and BIA will certify in writing that no one
            individual, directly or indirectly, will receive more than the
            payment limitation. Certification provided at the time of contract
            obligation will cover the entire contract period. The tribal entity
            must also provide, upon request from NRCS, a listing of individuals
            and payment made, by Social Security number or other unique
            identification number, during the previous year for calculation of
            overall payment limitations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Tax Identification Number.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be eligible to receive a CSP payment, all legal entities or
            persons applying, either alone or as part of a joint operation, must
            provide a tax identification number and percentage interest in the
            legal entity. In accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
                1400
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , an applicant applying as a joint operation or legal entity must
            provide a list of all members of the legal entity and joint
            operation and associated embedded entities, along with the
            members&apos; Social Security numbers and percentage of interest in
            the joint operation or legal entity. Payments 
            <PRTPAGE P='865' />
            will be directly attributed to legal entity members for the purpose
            of complying with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1470' sect='24' psec='#g' tq='N'>
                1470.24(g)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Unique tax identification numbers.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Where applicable, American Indians, Alaska Natives, and Pacific
            Islanders may use another unique identification number for each
            individual eligible for payment. Any participant that utilizes a
            unique identification number as an alternative to a tax
            identification number will utilize only that identifier for any and
            all other CSP contracts to which the participant is a party.
            Violators will be considered to have provided fraudulent
            representation and be subject to full penalties of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1470' sect='36' psec='' tq='N'>
                1470.36
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='l'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (l)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Payment data.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS will maintain detailed and segmented data on CSP contracts and
            payments to allow for quantification of the amount of payments made
            for:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='l_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Installing and adopting additional activities;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='l_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Improving, maintaining, and managing existing activities;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='l_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Participation in research and demonstration or pilot projects; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='l_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Development and periodic assessment and evaluation of conservation
            stewardship plans developed under this rule.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13040'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1470:B:1470.25
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1470.25
      </num>
      <head>
        Contract modifications and transfers of land.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1470' sect='25' psec='' tq='N'>
              1470.25
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Contract modifications and transfers of land.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS may allow a participant to modify a conservation stewardship
            contract if NRCS determines that the modification is consistent with
            achieving the purposes of the program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS will allow modification to a conservation stewardship contract
            to remove contract acres enrolled in the CRP, WRP, or GRP or other
            Federal or State programs that offer greater natural resource
            protection. Such modifications are consistent with the purposes of
            CSP. Participants will not be subject to liquidated damages or
            refund of payments received for enrolling land in these programs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS will not allow a participant to modify a conservation
            stewardship contract to increase the contract obligation beyond the
            amount of the initial contract, with exception for contracts
            approved by NRCS for renewal or other exceptional cases as
            determined by the Chief.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land under contract will be considered transferred if the
            participant loses control of the acreage for any reason.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The participant is responsible to notify NRCS prior to any
            voluntary or involuntary transfer of land under contract;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If all or part of the land under contract is transferred, the
            contract terminates with respect to the transferred land unless:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The transferee of the land provides written notice within 60 days
            to NRCS that all duties and rights under the contract have been
            transferred to, and assumed by, the transferee, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The transferee meets the eligibility requirements of the program;
            and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Contract payment adjustments due to modifications will be reflected
            in the fiscal year following the modification.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13041'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1470:B:1470.26
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1470.26
      </num>
      <head>
        Contract renewal.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1470' sect='26' psec='' tq='N'>
              1470.26
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Contract renewal.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             At the end of an initial conservation stewardship contract, NRCS
            may allow a participant to renew the contract to receive payments
            for one additional 5-year period, subject to the availability of
            funds, if they meet criteria from paragraph (b) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be considered for contract renewal, the participant must:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be in compliance with the terms of their initial contract as
            determined by NRCS;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Add any newly acquired eligible land that is part of the
            agricultural operation and meets minimum treatment criteria as
            established and determined by NRCS;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             At a minimum, meet stewardship thresholds for at least two priority
            resource concerns; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Agree to adopt additional conservation activities to address at
            least one additional priority resource concern during the term of
            the renewed conservation stewardship contract.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13042'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1470:B:1470.27
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1470.27
      </num>
      <head>
        Contract violations and termination.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1470' sect='27' psec='' tq='N'>
              1470.27
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Contract violations and termination.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State Conservationist may terminate, or by mutual consent with
            the participants, terminate a contract where:
            <PRTPAGE P='866' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The participants are unable to comply with the terms of the
            contract as the result of conditions beyond their control; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             As determined by the State Conservationist, it is in the public
            interest.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a contract is terminated in accordance with the provisions of
            paragraph (a) of this section, the State Conservationist may allow
            the participant to retain a portion of any payments received
            appropriate to the effort the participant has made to comply with
            the contract, or in cases of hardship, where forces beyond the
            participant&apos;s control prevented compliance with the contract.
            If a participant claims hardship, such claims must be clearly
            documented and cannot have existed when the applicant applied for
            participation in the program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If NRCS determines that a participant is in violation of the
            contract terms or documents incorporated therein, NRCS will give the
            participant a period of time, as determined by NRCS, to correct the
            violation and comply with the contract terms and attachments
            thereto. If a participant continues in violation, NRCS may terminate
            the CSP contract in accordance with paragraph (e) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph (c) of this section, a
            contract termination will be effective immediately upon a
            determination by NRCS that the participant:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Has submitted false information or filed a false claim;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Engaged in any act, scheme, or device for which a finding of
            ineligibility for payments is permitted under the provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1470' sect='36' psec='' tq='N'>
                1470.36
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Engaged in actions that are deemed to be sufficiently purposeful or
            negligent to warrant a termination without delay.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If NRCS terminates a contract, the participant will forfeit all
            rights to future payments under the contract, pay liquidated
            damages, and refund all or part of the payments received, plus
            interest. Participants violating CSP contracts may be determined
            ineligible for future NRCS-administered conservation program
            funding.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS may require a participant to provide only a partial refund of
            the payments received if a previously installed conservation
            activity has achieved the expected conservation performance
            improvement, is not adversely affected by the violation or the
            absence of other conservation activities that would have been
            installed under the contract, and has met the associated operation
            and maintenance requirement of the activity; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS will have the option to reduce or waive the liquidated
            damages, depending upon the circumstances of the case—
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When terminating a contract, NRCS may reduce the amount of money
            owed by the participant by a proportion that reflects the good faith
            effort of the participant to comply with the contract or the
            existence of hardships beyond the participant&apos;s control that
            have prevented compliance with the contract. If a participant claims
            hardship, that claim must be well documented and cannot have existed
            when the applicant applied for participation in the program, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In carrying out its role in this section, NRCS may consult with the
            local conservation district.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13043'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1470:C:1470.30
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1470.30
      </num>
      <head>
        Fair treatment of tenants and sharecroppers.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1470' sect='30' psec='' tq='N'>
              1470.30
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Fair treatment of tenants and sharecroppers.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Payments received under this part must be divided in the manner
          specified in the applicable contract. NRCS will ensure that tenants
          and sharecroppers who would have an interest in acreage being offered
          receive treatment which NRCS deems to be equitable, as determined by
          the Chief. NRCS may refuse to enter into a contract when there is a
          disagreement among joint applicants seeking enrollment as to an
          applicant&apos;s eligibility to participate in the contract as a
          tenant.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13044'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1470:C:1470.31
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1470.31
      </num>
      <head>
        Appeals.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1470' sect='31' psec='' tq='N'>
              1470.31
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Appeals.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          A participant may obtain administrative review of an adverse decision
          under this part in accordance with 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR parts 
            <subref title='7' part='11' tq='N'>
              11
            </subref>
             and 
            <subref title='7' part='614' tq='N'>
              614
            </subref>
          </aref>
          . Determinations in matters of general applicability, such as payment
          rates, payment limits, the designation of identified priority 
          <PRTPAGE P='867' />
          resource concerns, and eligible conservation activities are not
          subject to appeal.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13045'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1470:C:1470.32
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1470.32
      </num>
      <head>
        Compliance with regulatory measures.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1470' sect='32' psec='' tq='N'>
              1470.32
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Compliance with regulatory measures.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Participants will be responsible for obtaining the authorities,
          rights, easements, permits, or other approvals or legal compliance
          necessary for the implementation, operation, and maintenance
          associated with the conservation stewardship plan. Participants will
          be responsible for compliance with all laws and for all effects or
          actions resulting from the implementation of the contract.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13046'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1470:C:1470.33
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1470.33
      </num>
      <head>
        Access to agricultural operation.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1470' sect='33' psec='' tq='N'>
              1470.33
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Access to agricultural operation.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          NRCS, or its authorized representative, will have the right to enter
          an agricultural operation for the purpose of determining eligibility
          and for ascertaining the accuracy of any representations, including
          natural resource information provided by an applicant for the purpose
          of evaluating a contract application. Access will include the right to
          provide technical assistance, determine eligibility, assess natural
          resource conditions, inspect any work undertaken under the contract,
          and collect information necessary to evaluate the implementation of
          conservation activities in the contract. NRCS, or its authorized
          representative, will make an effort to contact the participant prior
          to the exercise of this provision.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13047'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1470:C:1470.34
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1470.34
      </num>
      <head>
        Equitable relief.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1470' sect='34' psec='' tq='N'>
              1470.34
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Equitable relief.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a participant relied upon the advice or action of NRCS and did
            not know, or have reason to know, that the action or advice was
            improper or erroneous, the participant may be eligible for equitable
            relief under 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='635' tq='N'>
                635
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . The financial or technical liability for any action by a
            participant that was taken based on the advice of a TSP will remain
            with the TSP and will not be assumed by NRCS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a participant has been found in violation of a provision of the
            conservation stewardship contract or any document incorporated by
            reference through failure to comply fully with that provision, the
            participant may be eligible for equitable relief under 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='635' tq='N'>
                635
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13048'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1470:C:1470.35
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1470.35
      </num>
      <head>
        Offsets and assignments.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1470' sect='35' psec='' tq='N'>
              1470.35
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Offsets and assignments.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any payment or portion thereof due to any participant under this
            part will be allowed without regard to any claim or lien in favor of
            any creditor, except agencies of the United States Government. The
            regulations governing offsets and withholdings found at 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1403' tq='N'>
                1403
              </subref>
            </aref>
             will be applicable to contract payments.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any participant entitled to any payment may assign such payments in
            accordance with regulations governing assignment of payment found at
            
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1404' tq='N'>
                1404
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13049'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1470:C:1470.36
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1470.36
      </num>
      <head>
        Misrepresentation and scheme or device.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1470' sect='36' psec='' tq='N'>
              1470.36
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Misrepresentation and scheme or device.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If NRCS determines that an applicant intentionally misrepresented
            any fact affecting a CSP determination, the application will be
            determined ineligible immediately.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A participant who is determined to have erroneously represented any
            fact affecting a program determination made in accordance with this
            part will not be entitled to contract payments and must refund to
            NRCS all payments, plus interest determined in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1403' tq='N'>
                1403
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A participant will refund to NRCS all payments, plus interest
            determined in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1403' tq='N'>
                1403
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , received by such participant with respect to all CSP contracts if
            they are determined to have:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Adopted any scheme or device that tends to defeat the purpose of
            the program;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Made any fraudulent representation;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Adopted any scheme or device for the purpose of depriving any
            tenant or sharecropper of the payments to which such person would
            otherwise be entitled under the program; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Misrepresented any fact affecting a program determination.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Participants determined to have committed actions identified in
            paragraph (c) of this section will:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Have their interest in all CSP contracts terminated; and
            <PRTPAGE P='868' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1470' sect='27' psec='#e' tq='N'>
                1470.27(e)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , may be determined by NRCS to be ineligible for future
            NRCS-administered conservation program funding.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13050'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1470:C:1470.37
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1470.37
      </num>
      <head>
        Environmental credits for conservation improvements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1470' sect='37' psec='' tq='N'>
              1470.37
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Environmental credits for conservation improvements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          NRCS believes that environmental benefits will be achieved by
          implementing conservation activities funded through CSP. These
          environmental benefits may result in opportunities for the program
          participant to sell environmental credits. Any requirements related to
          these environmental credits must be compatible with the purposes of
          the contract. NRCS asserts no direct or indirect interest on these
          credits. However, NRCS retains the authority to ensure that operation
          and maintenance (O&amp;M) requirements for CSP-funded improvements are
          met, consistent with 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1470' sect='21' psec='' tq='N'>
              1470.21
            </subref>
          </aref>
           and 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1470' sect='23' psec='' tq='N'>
              1470.23
            </subref>
          </aref>
          . Where actions may impact the land and conservation activities under
          a CSP contract, NRCS will at the request of the participant, assist
          with the development of an O&amp;M compatibility assessment prior to
          the participant entering into any credit agreement.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>