<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol4'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:C:285
    </extid>
    <num>
      285
    </num>
    <head>
      PROVISION OF A NUTRITION ASSISTANCE GRANT FOR THE COMMONWEALTH OF PUERTO
      RICO
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='2011-203' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/2011-203.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 2011-203
            </subref>
          </aref>
          6.
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          Amdt. 209, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            47 FR 32409
          </aref>
          , July 27, 1982, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='5042'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:C:285:-:285.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        285.1
      </num>
      <head>
        General purpose and scope.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='285' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              285.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General purpose and scope.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          This part describes the general terms and conditions under which grant
          funds shall be provided by the Food and Nutrition Service (FNS) to the
          government of the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico for the purpose of
          designing and conducting a nutrition assistance program for needy
          persons. The Commonwealth of Puerto Rico is authorized to establish
          eligibility and benefit levels for the nutrition assistance program.
          In addition, with FNS approval, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico may
          employ a small proportion of the grant funds to finance projects that
          the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico believes likely to improve or
          stimulate agriculture, food production, and food distribution.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5043'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:C:285:-:285.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        285.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Funding.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [Amdt. 209, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          47 FR 32409
        </aref>
        , July 27, 1982, as amended by Amdt. 243, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          49 FR 49585
        </aref>
        , Dec. 21, 1984; Amdt. 274, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          51 FR 18752
        </aref>
        , May 21, 1986; Amdt. 371, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          61 FR 60012
        </aref>
        , Nov. 26, 1996]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='285' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              285.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Funding.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS shall, consistent with the plan of operation required by 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='285' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
                285.3
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
            , and subject to availability of funds, provide nutrition assistance
            grant funds to the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico to cover 100 percent
            of the expenditures related to food assistance provided to needy
            persons and 50 percent of the administrative expenses related to the
            food assistance. The amount of the grant funds provided to the
            Commonwealth of Puerto Rico shall not exceed amounts appropriated
            for this purpose for each fiscal year.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS shall, subject to the provisions in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='285' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
                285.3
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='285' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
                285.5
              </subref>
            </aref>
             in this part, and limited by the provisions of paragraph (a) of
            this section, pay to the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico for the
            applicable fiscal year, the amount estimated by the Commonwealth of
            Puerto Rico pursuant to 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='285' sect='3' psec='#b_4' tq='N'>
                285.3(b)(4)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . Payments shall be made no less frequently than on a monthly basis
            prior to the beginning of each month consistent with the Treasury
            Fiscal Requirement Manual, Volume I, 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='6' tq='N'>
                6
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 2030
            </aref>
            ; these letters of credit shall be drawn on an as-needed basis. The
            amount shall be reduced or increased to the extent of any prior
            overpayment or underpayment which FNS determines has been made and
            which has not been previoulsy adjusted. The payment(s) received by
            the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico for a fiscal year shall not exceed
            the total authorized for the grant, or the total cost for the
            nutrition assistance program eligible for funding, whichever is
            less, for that fiscal year.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS may recover from the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, through
            offsets to funding during any fiscal year, funds previously paid to
            the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico and later determined by the
            Secretary to have been overpayments. Funds which may be recovered
            include, but are not limited to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Costs not included in the approved plan of operation;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Unallowable costs discovered in audit or investigation findings;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Funds allocated to the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico which exceeded
            expenditures during the fiscal year for which the funds were
            authorized; or
            <PRTPAGE P='1059' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Amounts owed to FNS as a result of the nutrition assistance grant
            which have been billed to the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico and which
            the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico has failed to pay without cause
            acceptable to FNS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Funds for payment of any prior fiscal year expenditures shall be
            claimed from the funding for that prior year. The payment of funds
            shall not exceed the authorization for that prior fiscal year.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [Amdt. 209, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            47 FR 32409
          </aref>
          , July 27, 1982, as amended by Amdt. 243, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            49 FR 49585
          </aref>
          , Dec. 21, 1984; Amdt. 274, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            51 FR 18752
          </aref>
          , May 21, 1986; Amdt. 371, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            61 FR 60012
          </aref>
          , Nov. 26, 1996]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5044'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:C:285:-:285.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        285.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Plan of operation.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [Amdt. 209, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          47 FR 32409
        </aref>
        , July 27, 1982, as amended by Amdt. 239, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          48 FR 23805
        </aref>
        , May 27, 1983; Amdt. 243, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          49 FR 49585
        </aref>
        , Dec. 21, 1984; Amdt. 274, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          51 FR 18752
        </aref>
        , May 21, 1986; Amdt. 371, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          61 FR 60012
        </aref>
        , Nov. 26, 1996]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='285' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              285.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Plan of operation.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To receive payments for any fiscal year the Commonwealth of Puerto
            Rico shall have a plan of operation for that fiscal year approved by
            FNS. Each plan of operation shall be sumitted for FNS approval by
            the July 1 preceding the fiscal year for which the plan of operation
            is to be effective.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The plan of operation shall include the following information:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Designation of the agency or agencies directly responsible for
            administration, or supervision of the administration, of the
            nutrition assistance program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A description of the needy persons residing in the Commonwealth of
            Puerto Rico and an assessment of the food and nutrition needs of
            these persons. The description and assessment shall demonstrate that
            the nutrition assistance program is directed toward the most needy
            persons in the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A description of the program for nutrition assistance including:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A general description of the nutrition assistance to be provided
            the needy persons who will receive assistance, and any agencies
            designated to provide such assistance; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To the extent grant funds are not used for direct nutrition
            assistance payments to needy persons, the plan of operation must
            demonstrate that the grants funds will provide nutrition assistance
            benefiting needy persons in the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A budget and an estimate of the monthly amounts of expenditures
            necessary for the provision of the nutrition assistance and related
            administrative expenses up to the monthly amounts provided for
            payment in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='285' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
                285.2
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Other reasonably related information which FNS may request.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An agreement signed by the governor or other appropriate official
            to conduct the nutrition assistance program in accordance with the
            FNS-approved plan of operation and in compliance with all pertinent
            Federal rules and regulations. The Commonwealth of Puerto Rico shall
            also agree to comply with any changes in Federal law and
            regulations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any amendments to those provisions of the plan of operation
            specified in paragraph (b) of this section, must be submitted to FNS
            for approval.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS shall approve or disapprove any plan of operation no later than
            August 1 of the year of its submission. FNS approval of the plan of
            operation shall be based on an assessment that the nutrition
            assistance program, as defined in the plan of operation, is:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Sufficient to permit analysis and review;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Reasonably targeted to the most needy persons as defined in the
            plan of operation;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Supported by an assessment of the food and nutrition needs of needy
            persons;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Reasonable in terms of the funds requested;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Structured to include safeguards to prevent fraud, waste, and abuse
            in the use of grant funds; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Consistent with all applicable Federal laws.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS shall approve or disapprove any amendments to those provisions
            of the plan of operation specified in paragraph (b) of this section.
            If FNS fails either to approve or deny the amendment, or to request
            additional information within 30 days, the amendment to the plan of
            operation is approved. If additional information is requested, the
            Commonwealth of Puerto Rico shall provide this as soon as possible,
            and FNS shall approve or deny the amendment to the plan of
            operation. Payment schedules and other program operations may not be
            altered until an amendment to the plan of operation is 
            <PRTPAGE P='1060' />
            approved. The Commonwealth of Puerto Rico shall, for informational
            purposes, submit to FNS any amendments to those provisions of the
            plan of operation not specified in paragraph (b) of this section.
            Such submittal shall be made at least 30 days prior to the effective
            date of the amendment. If circumstances warrant a waiver of the
            30-day requirement, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico shall submit a
            waiver request to FNS for consideration. Should FNS determine that
            such an amendment relates to the provisions of paragraph (b) of this
            section, FNS approval as established above will be necessary for the
            amendment to be implemented.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS may approve part of any plan of operation or amendment
            submitted by the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico contingent on
            appropriate action by the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico with respect
            to the problem areas in the plan of operation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If all or part of the plan of operation is disapproved, FNS shall
            notify the appropriate agency in the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico of
            the problem area(s) in the plan of operation and the actions
            necessary to secure approval.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In accordance with the provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='285' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
                285.5
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , funds may be withheld or denied when all or part of a plan of
            operation is disapproved.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [Amdt. 209, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            47 FR 32409
          </aref>
          , July 27, 1982, as amended by Amdt. 239, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            48 FR 23805
          </aref>
          , May 27, 1983; Amdt. 243, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            49 FR 49585
          </aref>
          , Dec. 21, 1984; Amdt. 274, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            51 FR 18752
          </aref>
          , May 21, 1986; Amdt. 371, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            61 FR 60012
          </aref>
          , Nov. 26, 1996]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5045'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:C:285:-:285.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        285.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Audits.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [Amdt. 209, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          47 FR 32409
        </aref>
        , July 27, 1982. Redesignated by Amdt. 371, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          61 FR 60013
        </aref>
        , Nov. 26, 1996]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='285' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              285.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Audits.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Commonwealth of Puerto Rico shall provide an audit of
            expenditures in compliance with the requirements in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='3015' tq='N'>
                3015 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
             at least once every two years. The findings of such audit shall be
            reported to FNS no later than 120 days from the end of each fiscal
            year in which the audit is made.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Within 120 days of the end of each fiscal year, the Commonwealth of
            Puerto Rico shall provide FNS with a statement of: (1) Whether the
            grant funds received for that fiscal year exceeded the valid
            obligations made that year for which payment is authorized, and if
            so, by how much, and (2) such additional related information as FNS
            may require.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [Amdt. 209, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            47 FR 32409
          </aref>
          , July 27, 1982. Redesignated by Amdt. 371, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            61 FR 60013
          </aref>
          , Nov. 26, 1996]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5046'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:C:285:-:285.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        285.5
      </num>
      <head>
        Failure to comply.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [Amdt. 209, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          47 FR 32409
        </aref>
        , July 27, 1982. Redesignated by Amdt. 371, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          61 FR 60013
        </aref>
        , Nov. 26, 1996]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='285' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              285.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Failure to comply.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Grant funds may be withheld in whole or in part, or denied if there
            is a substantial failure by the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico to
            comply with the requirements of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='285' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
                285.4
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , or to bring into compliance a plan of operation disapproved by
            FNS, or to comply with program requirements detailed in the plan of
            operation approved for that fiscal year. (For example, funds shall
            be paid to the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico to cover only the costs
            of the part or parts of the plan of operation receiving FNS
            approval. Withheld payments shall be paid when the unapproved
            part(s) of the plan are modified and approved.) FNS shall notify the
            Commonwealth of Puerto Rico that further payments shall not be made
            until FNS is satisfied that there will no longer be any such failure
            to comply.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon a finding of a substantial failure to comply with the
            requirements of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='285' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
                285.4
              </subref>
            </aref>
             or the plan of operation, FNS may, in addition to or in lieu of
            actions taken in accordance with paragraph (a) of this section,
            refer the matter to the Attorney General with a request that
            injunctive relief be sought from the appropriate district court of
            the United States to require compliance with these regulations by
            the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [Amdt. 209, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            47 FR 32409
          </aref>
          , July 27, 1982. Redesignated by Amdt. 371, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            61 FR 60013
          </aref>
          , Nov. 26, 1996]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>