<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol3'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:61
    </extid>
    <num>
      61
    </num>
    <head>
      COTTONSEED SOLD OR OFFERED FOR SALE FOR CRUSHING PURPOSES (INSPECTION,
      SAMPLING AND CERTIFICATION)
    </head>
    <text>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            22 FR 10948
          </aref>
          , Dec. 28, 1957, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='3721'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:61:A:61.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        61.1
      </num>
      <head>
        Words in singular form.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='61' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              61.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Words in singular form.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Words used in the regulations in this subpart in the singular form
          shall be deemed to import the plural, and vice-versa, as the case may
          demand.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3722'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:61:A:61.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        61.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Terms defined.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          22 FR 10948
        </aref>
        , Dec. 28, 1957, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 42413
        </aref>
        , Aug. 9, 1993]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='61' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              61.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Terms defined.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          As used throughout the regulations in this part, unless the context
          otherwise requires, the following terms shall be construed,
          respectively to mean:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              The act.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The applicable provisions of the Agricultural Marketing Act of 1946
            (
            <aref target='_blank' href='http://frwebgate.access.gpo.gov/cgi-bin/getpage.cgi?dbname=79_statutes2_at_large&amp;position=all&amp;page=1087'>
              60 Stat. 1087
            </aref>
            ; 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='1621' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1621.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 1621
              </subref>
            </aref>
            <E T='03'>
              et seq
            </E>
            .) or any other act of Congress conferring like authority.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Regulations.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Regulations mean the provisions in this subpart.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Department.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The United States Department of Agriculture.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Secretary.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Secretary of Agriculture of the United States, or any officer
            or employee of the Department to whom authority has heretofore been
            delegated, or to whom authority may hereafter be delegated, to act
            in his stead.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Service.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Agricultural Marketing Service of the United States Department
            of Agriculture.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Administrator.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Administrator of the Agricultural Marketing Service, or any
            officer or employee of the Service, to whom authority has heretofore
            been delegated, or to whom authority may hereafter be delegated, to
            act in his stead.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Division.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Cotton Division of the Agricultural Marketing Service.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Director.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Director of the Cotton Division, or any officer or employee of
            the Division to whom authority has heretofore been delegated, or to
            whom authority may hereafter be delegated, to act in his stead.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Custodian.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Person who has possession or control of cottonseed or of samples of
            cottonseed as agent, controller, broker, or factor, as the case may
            be.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Owner.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Person who through financial interest owns or controls, or has the
            disposition of either cottonseed or of samples of cottonseed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Official cottonseed standards.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The official standards of the United States for the grading,
            sampling, and analyzing of cottonseed sold or offered for sale for
            crushing purposes.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='l'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (l)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Supervisor of cottonseed inspection.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An officer of the Division designated as such by the Director.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='m'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (m)
            </enum>
            <head>
              License.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A license issued under the act by the Secretary.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='n'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (n)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Licensed cottonseed chemist.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A person licensed under the act by the Secretary to make
            quantitative and qualitative chemical analyses of samples of
            cottonseed according to the methods prescribed by the Science
            Division Director of the Agricultural Marketing Service and to
            certificate the grade according to the official cottonseed standards
            of the United States.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='o'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (o)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Licensed cottonseed sampler.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A person licensed by the Secretary to draw and to certificate the
            authenticity of samples of cottonseed in accordance with the
            regulations in this subpart.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='p'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (p)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Dispute.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A disagreement as to the true grade of a sample of cottonseed
            analyzed and graded by a licensed chemist.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='q'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (q)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Party.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A party to a dispute.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='r'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (r)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Commercial laboratory.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A chemical laboratory operated by an individual, firm, or
            corporation in which one or more persons are engaged in the chemical
            analysis of materials for the public.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='s'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (s)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Cottonseed.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The word “cottonseed” as used in this part means the seed, after
            having been put through the usual and customary process known as
            cotton ginning, of any cotton produced within the continental United
            States.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='t'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (t)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Lot.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             That parcel or quantity of cottonseed offered for sale or tendered
            for delivery or delivered on a sale or contract of sale, in freight
            cars, trucks, wagons, or otherwise in the quantities and within the
            time limits prescribed from time to time by the Director for the
            drawing and preparation of official samples by licensed cottonseed
            samplers.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='u'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (u)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Official sample.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A specimen of cottonseed drawn and prepared by a licensed
            cottonseed sampler and certified by him as representative of a
            certain identified lot, in accordance with the regulations in this
            subpart.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            22 FR 10948
          </aref>
          , Dec. 28, 1957, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 42413
          </aref>
          , Aug. 9, 1993]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3723'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:61:A:61.2a
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        61.2a
      </num>
      <head>
        Designation of official certificates, memoranda, marks, other
        identifications, and devices for purpose of the Agricultural Marketing
        Act.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='178' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='61' sect='2a' psec='' tq='N'>
              61.2a
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Designation of official certificates, memoranda, marks, other
          identifications, and devices for purpose of the Agricultural Marketing
          Act.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Sub
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 203(h) of
          </aref>
           the Agricultural Marketing Act of 1946, as amended by Pub. L. 272,
          84th Congress, provides criminal penalties for various specified
          offenses relating to official certificates, memoranda, marks, or other
          identifications, and devices for making such marks or identifications,
          issued or authorized under 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 203 of
          </aref>
           said act, and certain misrepresentations concerning the inspection or
          grading of agricultural products under said section. For the purposes
          of said subsection and the provisions in this part, the terms listed
          below shall have the respective meanings specified:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Official certificate
            </E>
             means any form of certification, either written or printed, used
            under this part to certify with respect to the inspection, sampling,
            class, grade, quality, quantity, or condition of products (including
            the compliance of products with applicable specifications).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Official memorandum
            </E>
             means any initial record of findings made by an authorized person
            in the process of grading, inspecting, or sampling, pursuant to this
            part, any processing or plant-operation report made by an authorized
            person in connection with grading, inspecting, or sampling under
            this part, and any report made by an authorized person of services
            performed pursuant to this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Official mark
            </E>
             means the grade mark, inspection mark, and any other mark, approved
            by the Administrator and authorized to be affixed to any product, or
            affixed to or printed on the packaging material of any product,
            stating that the product was graded or inspected or both, or
            indicating the appropriate U.S. grade or condition of the product,
            or for the purpose or maintaining the identity of products graded or
            inspected or both under this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Official identification
            </E>
             means any United States (U.S.) standard designation of class,
            grade, quality, quantity, or condition specified in this part, or
            any symbol, stamp, label, or seal indicating that the product has
            been officially graded or inspected and/or indicating the class,
            grade, quality, quantity, or condition of the product, approved by
            the Administrator and authorized to be affixed to any product, or
            affixed to or printed on the packaging material of any product.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Official device
            </E>
             means a stamping appliance, branding device, stencil, printed
            label, or any other mechanically or manually operated tool that is
            approved by the Administrator for the purpose of applying any
            official mark or other identification to any product or the
            packaging material thereof.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3724'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:61:A:61.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        61.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Director.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='61' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              61.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Director.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The Director shall perform for and under the supervision of the
          Secretary and the Administrator, such duties as the Secretary or the
          Administrator may require in enforcing the provisions of the act and
          the regulations.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3725'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:61:A:61.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        61.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Supervisor of cottonseed inspection.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='61' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              61.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Supervisor of cottonseed inspection.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The Director, whenever he deems necessary, may designate an officer of
          the Division as supervisor of cottonseed inspection who shall
          supervise the inspection and sampling of cottonseed and perform such
          other duties as may be required of him in administering the act and
          the regulations.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3726'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:61:A:61.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        61.5
      </num>
      <head>
        Regulations to govern.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='61' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              61.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Regulations to govern.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The inspection, sampling, analyzing, and grading of cottonseed in the
          United States pursuant to the act shall be performed as prescribed in
          methods approved from time to time by the Director.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3727'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:61:A:61.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        61.6
      </num>
      <head>
        Denial of further services.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          22 FR 10948
        </aref>
        , Dec. 28, 1957, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 42413
        </aref>
        , Aug. 9, 1993]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='61' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              61.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Denial of further services.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Any person, partnership, or corporation that shall have undertaken to
          utilize the services of licensed cottonseed samplers under these
          regulations who shall not make available for official sampling and
          analysis each lot of cottonseed purchased or sold on grade and
          received by such person or partnership or corporation, may be denied
          further 
          <PRTPAGE P='179' />
          services under the act and these regulations: 
          <E T='03'>
            Provided,
          </E>
           That in cases of persons, partnerships, or corporations operating two
          or more cottonseed crushing units under separate local managements,
          such penalty shall apply only to the offending unit, unless it shall
          be shown that the actions of such unit were at the direction or with
          the knowledge, approval, or acquiescence of the general management.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            22 FR 10948
          </aref>
          , Dec. 28, 1957, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 42413
          </aref>
          , Aug. 9, 1993]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3728'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:61:A:61.7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        61.7
      </num>
      <head>
        Misrepresentation.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='61' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              61.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Misrepresentation.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Any willful misrepresentation or any deceptive or fradulent practice
          made or committed by an applicant for a cottonseed sampler&apos;s
          certificate or for a cottonseed chemist&apos;s certificate or for an
          appeal grade certificate in connection with the sampling or grading of
          cottonseed by persons licensed under the act and the regulations or
          the issuance or use of a certificate not issued by a person licensed
          under the regulations in imitation of or that might mislead anyone to
          believe that such certificate was in fact issued by a person licensed
          under the act, or that might be otherwise false, misleading, or
          deceptive, may be deemed sufficient cause for debarring such applicant
          from any further benefits of the act.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3729'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:61:A:61.8
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        61.8
      </num>
      <head>
        Application for review.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          22 FR 10948
        </aref>
        , Dec. 28, 1957, Dec. 28, 1957, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 42413
        </aref>
        , Aug. 9, 1993]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='61' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              61.8
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Application for review.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          In case of dispute in which a review is desired of the grading of any
          official sample of cottonseed covered by a valid certificate issued by
          a licensed cottonseed chemist, application therefor shall be filed
          with or mailed to a supervisor of cottonseed inspection within ten
          days after the date of the original certificate, whereupon the
          licensed chemist issuing the certificate shall immediately surrender
          to such supervisor the retained portion of the original sample,
          together with such records as may be required, for the determination
          of the true grade. The supervisor shall assign to such retained
          portion an identification number, shall divide such retained portion
          into two parts and submit the parts to two other licensed cottonseed
          chemists for reanalysis. Should the supervisor determine that such
          reanalyses indicate a grade differing from the original by not more
          than plus or minus one full grade, the original grade shall be
          considered the true grade. Should he find that such reanalyses
          indicate a grade differing more than plus or minus one full grade from
          the original, he shall determine the true grade. In any case, the
          supervisor shall issue over his name an appeal cottonseed grade
          certificate showing the true grade as determined in accordance with
          this section, which shall supersede the licensed chemists&apos;
          certificates relating to the grade of such seed. Where due solely to
          errors in calculation or clerical error a grade certificated by a
          licensed cottonseed chemist is not the true grade, the supervisor
          shall direct the licensee to cancel the original and to issue a
          correct certificate. Should such error be found after an application
          for review has been filed, the supervisor shall nevertheless issue an
          appeal cottonseed grade certificate showing the true grade of the
          cottonseed involved.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            22 FR 10948
          </aref>
          , Dec. 28, 1957, Dec. 28, 1957, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 42413
          </aref>
          , Aug. 9, 1993]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3730'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:61:A:61.9
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        61.9
      </num>
      <head>
        Cost of review.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='61' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
              61.9
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Cost of review.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          In cases of review of the grade of any official sample of cottonseed,
          payment covering the costs of re-analysis shall accompany the
          application.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3731'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:61:A:61.25
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        61.25
      </num>
      <head>
        Application for license as sampler; form.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='61' sect='25' psec='' tq='N'>
              61.25
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Application for license as sampler; form.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Applications for licenses to sample cottonseed shall be made to the
            Director on forms furnished for the purpose by him.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each such application shall be in English, shall be signed by the
            applicant, and shall contain or be accompanied by (1) satisfactory
            evidence that he is an actual resident of the United States, (2)
            satisfactory evidence of his experience in the handling and sampling
            of cottonseed, (3) a statement by the applicant that he agrees to
            comply with and abide by the terms of the act and these regulations
            so far as they relate to him, and with instructions issued from time
            to time governing the sampling of cottonseed, and (4) such other
            information as may be required.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3732'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:61:A:61.27
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        61.27
      </num>
      <head>
        Period of license; renewals.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          59 FR 26411
        </aref>
        , May 20, 1994]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='180' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='61' sect='27' psec='' tq='N'>
              61.27
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Period of license; renewals.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The period for which a license may be issued under the regulations in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='61' sect='25' psec='' tq='N'>
              61.25
            </subref>
          </aref>
           through 61.42 shall be from the first day of August following receipt
          of the application, and shall continue for 5 years, ending on the 31st
          of July in the fifth year. Renewals shall be for 5 years also,
          beginning with the first day of August and ending on the 31st day of
          July in the fifth year: Provided, That licenses or renewals issued on
          and after June 1 of any year shall be for the period ending July 31 of
          the fifth year following.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            59 FR 26411
          </aref>
          , May 20, 1994]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3733'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:61:A:61.30
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        61.30
      </num>
      <head>
        Examination of sampler.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='61' sect='30' psec='' tq='N'>
              61.30
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Examination of sampler.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Each applicant for a license as a sampler and each licensed sampler
          whenever requested by an authorized representative of the Director,
          shall submit to an examination or test to show his ability properly to
          perform the duties for which he is applying for a license or for which
          he has been licensed, and each such applicant or licensee shall
          furnish the Division any information requested at any time in regard
          to his sampling of cottonseed.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3734'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:61:A:61.31
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        61.31
      </num>
      <head>
        License must be posted.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='61' sect='31' psec='' tq='N'>
              61.31
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          License must be posted.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Each licensed sampler shall keep his license conspicuously posted at
          the place where he functions as a sampler or in such other place as
          may be approved by the Director.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3735'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:61:A:61.32
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        61.32
      </num>
      <head>
        No discrimination in sampling.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='61' sect='32' psec='' tq='N'>
              61.32
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          No discrimination in sampling.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Each licensed sampler, when requested, shall without discrimination,
          as soon as practicable and upon reasonable terms, sample any
          cottonseed if the same be made available to him at his place of
          business, under conditions that will permit proper sampling. Each such
          licensee shall give preference to those who request his services as
          such over persons who request his services in any other capacity.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3736'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:61:A:61.33
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        61.33
      </num>
      <head>
        Equipment of sampler; contents of certificate.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='61' sect='33' psec='' tq='N'>
              61.33
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Equipment of sampler; contents of certificate.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Each licensed sampler shall have available suitable triers or sampling
          tools, sample containers, scales, seed cleaners, seed mixers, and
          air-tight containers for enclosing and forwarding the official samples
          to licensed chemist, and with tags and samplers&apos; certificates
          approved or furnished by the Director or his representative for
          identifying the samples of cottonseed and for certificating the
          condition of the cottonseed represented by such samples. There shall
          be clearly written or printed on the face of such certificate—
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A suitable caption;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The location of the cottonseed involved and its point of origin;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The identification of the lot from which the sample was drawn;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The date on which the sample was drawn;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The gross weight of the original sample, and the net weight of the
            cleaned sample;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A statement indicating that the sample was drawn in accordance with
            sampling methods prescribed by the Director of the Cotton Division;
            and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The signature of the licensed sampler as such. The use of such tags
            and certificates shall be in conformity with instructions issued
            from time to time by the Division.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3737'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:61:A:61.34
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        61.34
      </num>
      <head>
        Drawing and preparation of sample.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='61' sect='34' psec='' tq='N'>
              61.34
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Drawing and preparation of sample.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Each licensed cottonseed sampler shall draw, prepare, and identify one
          official sample of cottonseed and a duplicate thereof from each lot
          made available to him in such manner as may be required by the
          Director, and shall promptly prepare it for forwarding to a licensed
          cottonseed chemist for analysis and grading. The duplicate shall be
          sealed and retained by the sampler until the original official sample
          shall have been analyzed by a licensed chemist. If the original
          official sample shall become lost or destroyed before having been
          analyzed the duplicate shall become the official sample; otherwise the
          licensed sampler shall immediately remove the identification marks
          from the duplicate and discard it. In no case shall the duplicate be
          offered for analysis unless the original shall have been lost or
          destroyed before analysis.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3738'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:61:A:61.36
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        61.36
      </num>
      <head>
        Cause for suspension or revocation.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='181' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='61' sect='36' psec='' tq='N'>
              61.36
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Cause for suspension or revocation.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The failure or refusal of any cottonseed sampled, duly licensed as
          such under the regulations in this subpart, to draw, prepare,
          identify, and to forward an official sample of every lot of cottonseed
          made available to him for the purpose, in accordance with these
          regulations, shall be cause for the suspension or revocation of his
          license. A sampler&apos;s license may also be suspended when the
          sampler (a) has ceased to perform services as a licensed cottonseed
          sampler, (b) has knowingly or carelessly sampled cottonseed
          improperly, (c) has violated or evaded any provision of the Act, these
          regulations, or the sampling methods prescribed by the Director, (d)
          has used his license or allowed it to be used for any fraudulent or
          improper purposes, or (e) has in any manner become incompetent or
          incapacitated to perform the duties of a licensed sampler.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3739'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:61:A:61.37
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        61.37
      </num>
      <head>
        License may be suspended.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='61' sect='37' psec='' tq='N'>
              61.37
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          License may be suspended.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The Director may, without a hearing, suspend or revoke the license
          issued to a licensed sampler upon written request and a satisfactory
          statement of reasons therefor submitted by such licensed sampler.
          Pending final action by the Secretary, the Director may, whenever he
          deems such action necessary, suspend the license of any licensed
          sampler by giving notice of such suspension to the licensee,
          accompanied by a statement of the reasons therefor. Within 10 days
          after the receipt of the aforesaid notice and statement of reasons by
          such licensee, he may file an appeal, in writing, with the Secretary,
          supported by any argument or evidence that he may wish to offer as to
          why his license should not be suspended or revoked. After the
          expiration of the aforesaid 10-day period and consideration of such
          argument and evidence, the Secretary will take such action as he deems
          appropriate with respect to such suspension or revocation. When no
          appeal is filed within the prescribed 10 days, the license shall be
          automatically revoked.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3740'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:61:A:61.38
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        61.38
      </num>
      <head>
        Suspended license to be returned to Division.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='61' sect='38' psec='' tq='N'>
              61.38
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Suspended license to be returned to Division.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          In case a license issued to a sampler is suspended or revoked such
          license shall be returned to the Division. At the expiration of any
          period of suspension of such license, unless in the meantime it be
          revoked, the dates of beginning and termination of such suspension
          shall be endorsed thereon, it shall be returned to the person to whom
          it was originally issued, and its shall be posted as prescribed in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='61' sect='31' psec='' tq='N'>
              61.31
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3741'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:61:A:61.39
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        61.39
      </num>
      <head>
        Duplicate license.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='61' sect='39' psec='' tq='N'>
              61.39
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Duplicate license.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Upon satisfactory proof of the loss or destruction of a license issued
          to a sampler hereunder, a new license may be issued under the same or
          a new number.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3742'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:61:A:61.40
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        61.40
      </num>
      <head>
        Reports of licensed samplers.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='61' sect='40' psec='' tq='N'>
              61.40
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Reports of licensed samplers.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Each licensed sampler, when requested, shall make reports on forms
          furnished for the purpose by the Division bearing upon his activity as
          such licensee.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3743'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:61:A:61.41
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        61.41
      </num>
      <head>
        Unlicensed persons must not represent themselves as licensed samplers.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='61' sect='41' psec='' tq='N'>
              61.41
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Unlicensed persons must not represent themselves as licensed samplers.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          No person shall in any way represent himself to be a sampler licensed
          under the act unless he holds an unsuspended and unrevoked license
          issued thereunder.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3744'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:61:A:61.42
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        61.42
      </num>
      <head>
        Information on sampling to be kept confidential.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='61' sect='42' psec='' tq='N'>
              61.42
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Information on sampling to be kept confidential.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Every person licensed under the act as a sampler of cottonseed shall
          keep confidential all information secured by him relative to shipments
          of cottonseed sampled by him. He shall not disclose such information
          to any person except an authorized representative of the Department.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3745'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:61:B:61.101
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        61.101
      </num>
      <head>
        Determination of grade.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          22 FR 10948
        </aref>
        , Dec. 28, 1957, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          37 FR 20157
        </aref>
        , Sept. 27, 1972; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 42413
        </aref>
        , Aug. 9, 1993]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='182' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='61' sect='101' psec='' tq='N'>
              61.101
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Determination of grade.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The grade of cottonseed shall be determined from the analysis of
          samples by licensed chemists, and it shall be the result, stated in
          the nearest whole or half numbers, obtained by multiplying a quantity
          index by a quality index and dividing the result by 100. The quantity
          index and the quality index shall be determined as hereinafter
          provided.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The basis grade of cottonseed shall be grade 100.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             High grades of cottonseed shall be those grades above 100.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Low grades of cottonseed shall be those grades below 100.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Grades for American Pima cottonseed shall be suffixed by the
            designation “American Pima” or by the symbol “AP.”
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            22 FR 10948
          </aref>
          , Dec. 28, 1957, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            37 FR 20157
          </aref>
          , Sept. 27, 1972; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 42413
          </aref>
          , Aug. 9, 1993]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3746'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:61:B:61.102
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        61.102
      </num>
      <head>
        Determination of quantity index.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          37 FR 20157
        </aref>
        , Sept. 27, 1972]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='61' sect='102' psec='' tq='N'>
              61.102
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Determination of quantity index.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The quantity index of cottonseed shall be determined as follows:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For upland cottonseed the quantity index shall equal four times
            percentage of oil plus six times percentage of ammonia, plus 5.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For American Pima cottonseed the quantity index shall equal four
            times percentage of oil, plus six times percentage of ammonia, minus
            10.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            37 FR 20157
          </aref>
          , Sept. 27, 1972]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3747'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:61:B:61.103
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        61.103
      </num>
      <head>
        Determination of quality index.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='61' sect='103' psec='' tq='N'>
              61.103
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Determination of quality index.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The quality index of cottonseed shall be an index of purity and
          soundness, and shall be determined as follows:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Prime quality cottonseed.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Cottonseed that by analysis contains not more than 1.0 percent of
            foreign matter, not more than 12.0 percent of moisture, and not more
            than 1.8 percent of free fatty acids in the oil in the seed, shall
            be known as prime quality cottonseed and shall have a quality index
            of 100.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Below prime quality cottonseed.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The quality index of cottonseed that, by analysis, contain foreign
            matter, moisture, or free fatty acids in the oil in the seed, in
            excess of the percentages prescribed in paragraph (a) of this
            section shall be found by reducing the quality index of prime
            quality cottonseed as follows:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Four-tenths of a unit for each 0.1 percent of free fatty acids in
            the oil in the seed in excess of 1.8 percent.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             One-tenth of a unit for each 0.1 percent of foreign matter in
            excess of 1.0 percent.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             One-tenth of a unit for each 0.1 percent of moisture in excess of
            12.0 percent.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Off quality cottonseed.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Cottonseed that has been treated by either mechanical or chemical
            process other than the usual cleaning, drying, and ginning (except
            sterilization required by the United States Department of
            Agriculture for quarantine purposes) or that are fermented or hot,
            or that upon analysis are found to contain 12.5 percent or more of
            free fatty acids in the oil in the seed, or more than 10.0 percent
            of foreign matter, or more than 20.0 percent of moisture, or more
            than 25.0 percent of moisture and foreign matter combined, shall be
            designated as “off quality cottonseed.”
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Below grade cottonseed.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Cottonseed the grade of which when calculated according to 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='61' sect='101' psec='' tq='N'>
                61.101
              </subref>
            </aref>
             is below grade 40.0 shall be designated as “below grade
            cottonseed,” and a numerical grade shall not be indicated.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3748'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:61:B:61.104
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        61.104
      </num>
      <head>
        Sampling and certification of samples and grades.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          22 FR 10948
        </aref>
        , Dec. 28, 1957, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 42413
        </aref>
        , Aug. 9, 1993]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='61' sect='104' psec='' tq='N'>
              61.104
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Sampling and certification of samples and grades.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The drawing, preparation, and certification of samples of cottonseed,
          and certification of grades of cottonseed shall be performed in
          accordance with methods approved from time to time for the purposes by
          the Director, or his representatives.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            22 FR 10948
          </aref>
          , Dec. 28, 1957, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 42413
          </aref>
          , Aug. 9, 1993]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>