<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol10'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1429
    </extid>
    <num>
      1429
    </num>
    <head>
      ASPARAGUS REVENUE MARKET LOSS ASSISTANCE PAYMENT PROGRAM
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='15' sect='714b' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/15/714b.html'>
              15 U.S.C. 714b
            </subref>
             and 
            <subref title='15' sect='714c' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/15/714c.html'>
              714c
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , and 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            Sec. 10404
          </aref>
          , 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Pub. L. 110-246' alt='Pub. L. 110-246' href='http://www.gpo.gov/fdsys/pkg/PLAW-110publ246/html/PLAW-110publ246.htm'>
            Pub. L. 110-246
          </aref>
          , 
          <aref target='_blank' title='122 Stat. 2111' alt='122 Stat. 2111' href='http://www.gpo.gov/fdsys/pkg/STATUTE-122/html/STATUTE-122-Pg2111.htm'>
            122 Stat. 2111
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <PRTPAGE P='644' />
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 6316
          </aref>
          , Feb. 4, 2011, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='12630'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1429:-:1429.101
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1429.101
      </num>
      <head>
        Applicability.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1429' sect='101' psec='' tq='N'>
              1429.101
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Applicability.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The regulations in this part are applicable to program applicants
            who produced both 2003- and 2007-crop asparagus. Asparagus producers
            may apply to the Commodity Credit Corporation (CCC) for a payment
            based on the actual quantity of their 2003 asparagus production and
            their share of that production.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Total payments made through the Asparagus Revenue Marketing Loss
            Assistance Payment Program will not exceed $15 million, allocated as
            $7.5 million for fresh asparagus and $7.5 million for processed
            asparagus, less any reserve allocated for disputed claims.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12631'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1429:-:1429.102
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1429.102
      </num>
      <head>
        Administration.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1429' sect='102' psec='' tq='N'>
              1429.102
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Administration.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Asparagus Revenue Market Loss Assistance Payment Program will
            be administered under the general supervision of the Executive Vice
            President, CCC (Administrator, Farm Service Administration (FSA)),
            or a designee, and will be carried out in the field by FSA State and
            county committees and FSA employees.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FSA State and county committees, and representatives and employees
            of those committees, do not have the authority to modify or waive
            any of the provisions of this part, except as provided in paragraph
            (e) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The FSA State committee will take any action required by this part
            that has not been taken by the FSA county committee. The FSA State
            committee will also:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Correct or require correction of an action taken by an FSA county
            committee that is not in compliance with this part; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Require an FSA county committee to not take an action or implement
            a decision that is not in compliance with the regulations of this
            part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No delegation in this part to an FSA State or county committee will
            preclude the Executive Vice President, CCC, or a designee, from
            determining any question for the Asparagus Revenue Marketing Loss
            Assistance Payment Program, or from reversing or modifying any
            determination made by a State or county committee.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Deputy Administrator for Farm Programs, FSA, may authorize FSA
            State and county committees to waive or modify program requirements
            that are not statutory in cases where failure to meet such
            requirements does not adversely affect the operation of the
            Asparagus Revenue Market Loss Assistance Payment Program.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12632'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1429:-:1429.103
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1429.103
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1429' sect='103' psec='' tq='N'>
              1429.103
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The following definitions apply to this part. The definitions in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            parts 
            <subref title='7' part='718' tq='N'>
              718
            </subref>
             and 
            <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
              1400 of this title
            </subref>
          </aref>
           also apply, except where they conflict with the definitions in this
          section.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Application
          </E>
           means the Asparagus Revenue Market Loss Assistance Payment Program
          application form approved for use in this program by CCC and any
          required accompanying information or documentation.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Application period
          </E>
           means the 60-day period established by the Deputy Administrator for
          producers to apply for the Asparagus Revenue Marketing Loss Assistance
          Payment Program.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Asparagus producer
          </E>
           means any individual, group of individuals, partnership, corporation,
          estate, trust, association, cooperative, or other business enterprise
          or other legal entity, as defined in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1400' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              1400.3
            </subref>
             of this chapter
          </aref>
          , who is an owner, operator, landlord, tenant, or sharecropper, who
          directly or indirectly, as determined by the Secretary, shares in the
          risk of producing asparagus and who is entitled to ownership share in
          the asparagus crop available for marketing from the farm operation.
          Growers producing asparagus under contract for crop owners are not
          considered asparagus producers unless the grower can be determined to
          have an ownership share of the crop.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Base period
          </E>
           means the 2003 crop year of asparagus.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            County office
          </E>
           means the FSA office responsible for administering CCC programs
          located in a specific area in a State.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Crop year
          </E>
           means the marketing season or year as defined by the National
          Agricultural Statistics Service (NASS).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Department or USDA
          </E>
           means the U.S. Department of Agriculture.
          <PRTPAGE P='645' />
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Determined production
          </E>
           means, with respect to the base period, the total amount of fresh and
          processed asparagus specified on the application for payment verified
          by CCC as having been produced and marketed by the producer in the
          base period.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Farm Service Agency or FSA
          </E>
           means the Farm Service Agency of the U.S. Department of Agriculture.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Fresh asparagus
          </E>
           means domestically-produced asparagus that, regardless of intended
          use, was marketed as a fresh product without any processing other than
          cleaning, grading, sorting, trimming, drying, cooling, and packing.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Hundredweight or cwt.
          </E>
           means 100 pounds.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Processed asparagus
          </E>
           means domestically-produced asparagus that, regardless of intended
          use, was marketed as frozen, canned, pickled, or otherwise treated or
          handled in such fashion that the buyer would not consider the
          asparagus to be consumed as fresh, as determined by CCC.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Reliable production records
          </E>
           means evidence provided by the producer to the FSA county office that
          FSA determines is adequate to substantiate the amount of production
          reported when verifiable records are not available, including copies
          of receipts, ledgers of income, income statements, deposit slips,
          register tapes, invoices for custom harvesting, records to verify
          production costs, contemporaneous measurements, truck scale tickets,
          and contemporaneous diaries. When the term “acceptable production
          records” is used in this rule, it may be either reliable or verifiable
          production records, as defined in this section.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Reported production
          </E>
           means the total amount of fresh and processed asparagus produced and
          marketed by a producer, as specified by a producer on the application
          for payment.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            United States
          </E>
           means the 50 States of the United States, the District of Columbia,
          and Puerto Rico.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Verifiable production records
          </E>
           means evidence that is used to substantiate the amount of production
          reported and that can be verified by FSA through an independent
          source.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12633'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1429:-:1429.104
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1429.104
      </num>
      <head>
        Application requirements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1429' sect='104' psec='' tq='N'>
              1429.104
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Application requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be eligible for payment, asparagus producers must submit a
            completed application for payment and meet other eligibility
            requirements as specified in this part. Asparagus producers may
            obtain an application in person, by mail, by telephone, or by
            facsimile from any FSA county office. In addition, applicants may
            download a copy of the application from 
            <E T='03'>
              http://www.sc.egov.usda.gov.
            </E>
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An application for payment must be submitted on a completed
            application form. Applications and any other supporting
            documentation must be submitted to the FSA county office serving the
            county in which the producer produced asparagus in 2003 unless the
            producer now resides in a different county than the county in which
            asparagus was produced in the base period.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Asparagus producers who apply for payment must certify the
            information on the application before the application will be
            considered complete. Applications may be accompanied by acceptable
            production records for all fresh and processed asparagus produced
            and marketed from the farm in the 2003 crop year. Producers must
            certify they had a share interest in both 2003 and 2007 crop
            asparagus. To be eligible for payment on asparagus produced in the
            base period, the producer must have produced asparagus in 2007 for
            the commercial market in commercial quantities as determined for
            this purpose by the Deputy Administrator. At any time CCC deems
            appropriate, either before or after payment issuance, CCC may, at
            its discretion, require a producer to provide documentation to
            support:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Reported production of 2003 crop fresh or processed asparagus
            production or both entered on the application accompanied by
            acceptable production record,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Share percentage of 2003 crop production by marketing category for
            each producer in the asparagus farm operation, or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any other eligibility requirement specified in this part including
            commercial quantities of 2007 production to meet the 2007 production
            requirement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each asparagus producer who signs the application must certify the 
            <PRTPAGE P='646' />
            accuracy and truthfulness of the information in the application and
            any supporting documentation. All information provided is subject to
            verification by CCC. Refusal to allow CCC or any other agency of
            USDA to verify any information provided will result in a denial of
            eligibility. Furnishing the information is voluntary; however,
            without it program payments will not be approved. Providing a false
            certification may be punishable by imprisonment, fines, and other
            penalties or sanctions.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Data furnished by the applicants will be used to determine
            eligibility for program payments. Although participation in the
            Asparagus Revenue Market Loss Assistance Payment Program is
            voluntary, program payments will not be provided unless the
            participant furnishes a complete application by the end of the
            application period with all requested data.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Individuals or entities who submit applications after the
            application period are not entitled to any payment consideration or
            determination of eligibility. Regardless of the reason why an
            application is not submitted to or received by the FSA county
            office, any late application will be considered as not having been
            timely filed and the applicants on that application will not be
            eligible for the Asparagus Revenue Marketing Loss Assistance Payment
            Program.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12634'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1429:-:1429.105
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1429.105
      </num>
      <head>
        Producer eligibility requirements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1429' sect='105' psec='' tq='N'>
              1429.105
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Producer eligibility requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be eligible to receive the Asparagus Revenue Marketing Loss
            Assistance Payment Program payments, asparagus producers must submit
            an application during the application period and must:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Have produced and marketed asparagus in commercial quantities in
            commercial markets in the United States during both of the 2003 and
            2007 crop years;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be an asparagus producer, as defined in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1429' sect='103' psec='' tq='N'>
                1429.103
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , for the 2003 and 2007 crop years;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Certify their shares and the pounds of fresh and processed
            asparagus produced and marketed from the farm operation during the
            2003 crop year as reflected on the application;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the total value of payments claimed exceeds the available
            funding, have an average adjusted gross income (AGI) of less than
            $2.5 million for the 3 tax years of 2003 through 2005; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be in compliance with the requirements in 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='12' tq='N'>
                12
              </subref>
            </aref>
             regarding highly erodible cropland and wetlands and meet any
            general farm program eligibility requirements that apply under 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
                1400
              </subref>
            </aref>
             or other regulations as applicable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Asparagus producers must sign an application to be considered for
            payment eligibility. Asparagus producers who do not sign an
            application will not receive payment or a determination of
            eligibility, even if other producers in the asparagus farm operation
            sign an application and receive payment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each applicant determined by spot check or other information to not
            have an interest as an asparagus producer in 2003 and 2007 who meets
            the other qualifications of this part will be ineligible for payment
            and such applicant&apos;s claimed share shown on the application
            will not be paid.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12635'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1429:-:1429.106
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1429.106
      </num>
      <head>
        Proof of production.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1429' sect='106' psec='' tq='N'>
              1429.106
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Proof of production.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Producers selected for spot check by CCC must, in accordance with
            instructions issued by the Deputy Administrator or a designee,
            provide adequate proof of the fresh and processed asparagus produced
            and marketed during the 2003 and 2007 crop years.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If adequate proof of marketed production and supporting
            documentation in support of any application for payment is not
            presented to the satisfaction of CCC or the FSA county office
            requesting information, the application and the producers on that
            application will be determined ineligible for payment.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12636'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1429:-:1429.107
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1429.107
      </num>
      <head>
        Maximum and final payment rates.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1429' sect='107' psec='' tq='N'>
              1429.107
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Maximum and final payment rates.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subject to the funding limits that may apply to the program, the
            estimated maximum per pound payment rates for fresh market asparagus
            and for processed market asparagus are:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             $1.06 per pound ($106.00 per hundredweight) for 2003 crop
            quantities of asparagus marketed to fresh markets; and
            <PRTPAGE P='647' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             $1.08 per pound ($108.00 per hundredweight) for 2003 crop
            quantities of asparagus marketed for processing.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This program will be administered to assure that total payments do
            not exceed the available funding. If the total value of payments
            claimed calculated using the maximum payment rates specified in
            paragraph (a) of this section exceeds the funding available for each
            marketing category, less any reserve that may be created as
            specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1429' sect='109' psec='' tq='N'>
                1429.109
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , the payment quantities will be paid at a lower rate determined by
            dividing the funds available in each marketing category of
            asparagus, by the payment quantity from applications received by the
            end of the application period in each marketing category.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In no event will the payment rate exceed the maximum payment rate
            for each marketing category of asparagus determined in paragraph (a)
            of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12637'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1429:-:1429.108
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1429.108
      </num>
      <head>
        Calculation of individual payments.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1429' sect='108' psec='' tq='N'>
              1429.108
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Calculation of individual payments.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Producers will be eligible for payment for both fresh and processed
            asparagus. CCC will calculate the payment quantity of 2003 fresh and
            processed asparagus for an asparagus farm operation based on the
            lower of:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Reported production reflected on the application, or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If applicable, determined production.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The payment quantity will be multiplied by the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each asparagus producer&apos;s share, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The payment rate for the fresh or processed asparagus determined as
            specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1429' sect='107' psec='' tq='N'>
                1429.107
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the total value of payments claimed exceeds the available
            funding, payments to producers are subject to a $100,000 cap per
            each of the two program marketing categories (fresh and processed)
            per asparagus producer as defined in this part, not per “person” or
            “legal entity” as those terms might be defined in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
                1400 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12638'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1429:-:1429.109
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1429.109
      </num>
      <head>
        Availability of funds.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1429' sect='109' psec='' tq='N'>
              1429.109
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Availability of funds.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payments specified in this part are subject to the availability of
            funds. The total available program funds will be $15,000,000 as
            provided by 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 10404 of
            </aref>
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 110-246' alt='Public Law 110-246' href='http://www.gpo.gov/fdsys/pkg/PLAW-110publ246/html/PLAW-110publ246.htm'>
              Public Law 110-246
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Of the available funds, $7,500,000 are allocated for fresh market
            asparagus production and $7,500,000 are allocated to processed
            market asparagus.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC will prorate the available funds by a national factor to ensure
            that payments do not exceed $15,000,000. CCC will prorate the
            payments in such manner as it, in its sole discretion, finds fair
            and reasonable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A reserve will be created to handle appeals and errors. Claims will
            not be payable once the available funding is expended. Any amount of
            funds reserved for such purposes that are not disbursed for the
            purpose of correcting errors or omissions, or for the payment of
            appeals, will not otherwise be distributed to any payment applicants
            and will be refunded to the U.S. Department of Treasury.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12639'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1429:-:1429.111
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1429.111
      </num>
      <head>
        Misrepresentation and scheme or device.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1429' sect='111' psec='' tq='N'>
              1429.111
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Misrepresentation and scheme or device.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In addition to other penalties, sanctions, or remedies as may
            apply, an asparagus producer will be ineligible to receive
            assistance through the Asparagus Revenue Market Loss Assistance
            Payment Program if the asparagus producer is determined by CCC to
            have:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Adopted any scheme or device that tends to defeat the purpose of
            this program;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Made any fraudulent representation; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Misrepresented any fact affecting a program determination.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any funds disbursed pursuant to this part to any person or
            operation engaged in a misrepresentation, scheme, or device, must be
            refunded with interest together with such other sums as may become
            due and all charges including interest will run from the date of the
            disbursement of the CCC funds. Any asparagus farm operation,
            asparagus producer, or person engaged in acts prohibited by this
            section and any asparagus farm operation, asparagus producer, or
            person receiving payment as specified in this part will be jointly
            and severally liable with other persons or operations involved in
            such claim for payment for any refund due as specified in this
            section and for related 
            <PRTPAGE P='648' />
            charges. The remedies provided in this part will be in addition to
            other civil, criminal, or administrative remedies that may apply.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12640'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1429:-:1429.112
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1429.112
      </num>
      <head>
        Death, incompetence, or disappearance.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1429' sect='112' psec='' tq='N'>
              1429.112
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Death, incompetence, or disappearance.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the case of death, incompetency, disappearance, or dissolution
            of a person or an entity that is eligible to receive payment as
            specified in this part, an alternate person or persons as specified
            in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='707' tq='N'>
                707 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
             may receive such payment, as determined appropriate by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payment may be made for asparagus market losses suffered by an
            otherwise eligible asparagus producer who is now deceased or is a
            dissolved entity if a representative who currently has authority to
            enter into an application for the producer or the producer&apos;s
            estate signs the application for payment. Proof of authority to sign
            for the deceased producer&apos;s estate or a dissolved entity must
            be provided. If an asparagus producer is now a dissolved general
            partnership or joint venture, all members of the general partnership
            or joint venture at the time of dissolution or their duly-authorized
            representatives must sign the application for payment.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12641'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1429:-:1429.113
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1429.113
      </num>
      <head>
        Maintaining records.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1429' sect='113' psec='' tq='N'>
              1429.113
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Maintaining records.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Producers applying for payment through the Asparagus Revenue Market
          Loss Assistance Payment Program must maintain records and accounts to
          document all eligibility requirements specified in this part. Such
          records and accounts must be retained for 3 years after the date of
          payment.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12642'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1429:-:1429.114
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1429.114
      </num>
      <head>
        Refunds; joint and several liability.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1429' sect='114' psec='' tq='N'>
              1429.114
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Refunds; joint and several liability.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Excess payments, payments provided as the result of erroneous
            information provided by any person, or payments resulting from a
            failure to comply with any requirement or condition for payment in
            the application or this part, must be refunded to CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A refund required as specified in this section will be due with
            interest from the date of CCC disbursement and determined in
            accordance with paragraph (d) of this section and late payment
            charges as provided in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1403' tq='N'>
                1403 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Persons signing an ALAP Program application as having an interest
            in the asparagus farm operation will be jointly and severally liable
            for any refund and related charges found to be due as specified in
            this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Interest will be applicable to any refunds required as specified in
            
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              parts 
              <subref title='7' part='792' tq='N'>
                792
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='1403' tq='N'>
                1403 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . Such interest will be charged at the rate that the U.S. Department
            of the Treasury charges CCC for funds, and will accrue from the date
            CCC made the erroneous payment to the date of repayment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC may waive the accrual of interest if it determines that the
            cause of the erroneous determination was not due to any action of
            the person, or was beyond the control of the person committing the
            violation. Any waiver is at the discretion of CCC alone.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12643'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1429:-:1429.115
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1429.115
      </num>
      <head>
        Miscellaneous provisions and appeals.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1429' sect='115' psec='' tq='N'>
              1429.115
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Miscellaneous provisions and appeals.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Offset.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC may offset or withhold any amount due CCC as specified in this
            part in accordance with the provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1403' tq='N'>
                1403 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Claims.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Claims or debts will be settled in accordance with the provisions
            of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1403' tq='N'>
                1403 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Other interests.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payments or any portion thereof due under this part will be made
            without regard to questions of title under State law and without
            regard to any claim or lien against the asparagus crop, or proceeds
            thereof, in favor of the owner or any other creditor except agencies
            and instrumentalities of the U.S. Government.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Assignments.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any asparagus producer entitled to any payment as specified in this
            part may assign any payment in accordance with the provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1404' tq='N'>
                1404 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Appeals.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Appeals will be handled as specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              parts 
              <subref title='7' part='11' tq='N'>
                11
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='780' tq='N'>
                780 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>