<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol4'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:A:248
    </extid>
    <num>
      248
    </num>
    <head>
      WIC FARMERS&apos; MARKET NUTRITION PROGRAM (FMNP)
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='42' sect='1786' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/42/1786.html'>
              42 U.S.C. 1786
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            59 FR 11517
          </aref>
          , Mar. 11, 1994, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='4743'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:A:248:A:248.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        248.1
      </num>
      <head>
        General purpose and scope.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='248' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              248.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General purpose and scope.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          This part announces regulations under which the Secretary of
          Agriculture shall carry out the WIC Farmers&apos; Market Nutrition
          Program. The dual purposes of the FMNP are:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To provide resources in the form of fresh, nutritious, unprepared
            foods (fruits and vegetables) from farmers&apos; markets to women,
            infants, and children who are nutritionally at risk and who are
            participating in the Special Supplemental Nutrition Program for
            Women, Infants and Children (WIC) or are on the waiting list for the
            WIC Program; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To expand the awareness, use of and sales at farmers&apos; markets.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          This will be accomplished through payment of cash grants to approved
          State agencies which administer the FMNP and deliver benefits at no
          cost to eligible persons. The FMNP shall be supplementary to the food
          stamp program carried out under the Food Stamp Act of 1977 (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='2011' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/2011.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 2011
            </subref>
          </aref>
           et seq.) and to any other Federal or State program under which foods
          are distributed to needy families in lieu of food stamps.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4744'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:A:248:A:248.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        248.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          59 FR 11517
        </aref>
        , Mar. 11, 1994, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          60 FR 49745
        </aref>
        , Sept. 27, 1995; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          64 FR 48076
        </aref>
        , Sept. 2, 1999; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          73 FR 65249
        </aref>
        , Nov. 3, 2008]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='248' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              248.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          For the purpose of this part and all contracts, guidelines,
          instructions, forms and other documents related hereto, the term:
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Administrative costs
          </E>
           means those direct and indirect costs, exclusive of food costs, as
          defined in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='248' sect='12' psec='#b' tq='N'>
              248.12(b)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , which State agencies determine to be necessary to support FMNP
          operations. Administrative costs include, but are not limited to, the
          costs of administration, start-up, training, monitoring, auditing, the
          development of and accountability for coupon and market management,
          nutrition education, outreach, eligibility determination, and
          developing, printing, and distributing coupons.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Compliance buy
          </E>
           means a covert, on-site investigation in which a FMNP 
          <PRTPAGE P='483' />
          representative poses as a FMNP participant and transacts one or more
          FMNP food coupons.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Coupon
          </E>
           means a coupon, voucher, or other negotiable financial instrument by
          which benefits under the FMNP are transferred to recipients.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Days
          </E>
           means calendar days.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Demonstration project
          </E>
           means the Farmers&apos; Market Coupon Demonstration Project
          authorized by 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 17(m) of
          </aref>
           the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 (CNA), (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='42' sect='1786' note='' psec='#m' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/42/1786.html#m'>
              42 U.S.C. 1786(m)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ), as amended by 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 501 of
          </aref>
           the Hunger Prevention Act of 1988 (
          <aref target='_blank' title='Pub. L. 100-435' alt='Pub. L. 100-435' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d100:./list/bd/d100pl.lst:435%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Pub. L. 100-435
          </aref>
          ), enacted September 19, 1988. 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 102-314' alt='Public Law 102-314' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d102:./list/bd/d102pl.lst:314%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 102-314
          </aref>
           authorized the Secretary to competitively award, subject to the
          availability of funds, a 3-year grant (which was subsequently extended
          for an additional year by 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 102-142' alt='Public Law 102-142' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d102:./list/bd/d102pl.lst:142%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 102-142
          </aref>
          ) to up to 10 States that submitted applications that were approved
          for the establishment of demonstration projects designed to provide
          WIC participants with coupons that could be exchanged for fresh,
          nutritious, unprepared foods at farmers&apos; markets. Those States
          are: Connecticut, Iowa, Maryland, Massachusetts, Michigan, New York,
          Pennsylvania, Texas, Vermont, and Washington.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Department
          </E>
           means the U.S. Department of Agriculture.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Eligible foods
          </E>
           means fresh, nutritious, unprepared, locally grown fruits, vegetables
          and herbs for human consumption. Eligible foods may not be processed
          or prepared beyond their natural state except for usual harvesting and
          cleaning processes. Honey, maple syrup, cider, nuts, seeds, eggs,
          meat, cheese and seafood are examples of foods not eligible for
          purposes of the FMNP. State agencies shall consider locally grown to
          mean produce grown only within State borders but may also define it to
          include areas in neighboring States adjacent to its borders. Under no
          circumstances can produce grown outside of the United States and its
          territories be considered eligible foods.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Farmer
          </E>
           means an individual authorized to sell produce at participating
          farmers&apos; markets and/or roadside stands. Individuals who
          exclusively sell produce grown by someone else, such as wholesale
          distributors, cannot be authorized to participate in the FMNP. For
          purposes of this part, the term “farmer” shall mean “producer” as that
          term is used in 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 17(m)(6)(D) of
          </aref>
           the CNA (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='42' sect='1786' note='' psec='#m_6_D' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/42/1786.html#m_6_D'>
              42 U.S.C. 1786(m)(6)(D)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ). A participating State agency has the option to authorize individual
          farmers, farmers&apos; markets and/or roadside stands.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Farmers&apos; market
          </E>
           means an association of local farmers who assemble at a defined
          location for the purpose of selling their produce directly to
          consumers.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Fiscal year
          </E>
           means the period of 12 calendar months beginning October 1 of any
          calendar year and ending September 30 of the following calendar year.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            FMNP funds
          </E>
           means Federal grant funds provided for the FMNP, plus the required
          matching funds.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            FNS
          </E>
           means the Food and Nutrition Service of the U.S. Department of
          Agriculture.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Food costs
          </E>
           means the cost of eligible supplemental foods.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Household
          </E>
           has the same definition as that of “family” defined in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='246' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              246.2
            </subref>
             of this chapter
          </aref>
          . Each such family shall constitute a separate household for FMNP
          benefit issuance purposes.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            In-kind contributions
          </E>
           means property or services which benefit the FMNP and which are
          contributed by non-Federal parties without charge to the FMNP.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Local agency
          </E>
           means any nonprofit entity or local government agency which issues
          FMNP coupons, and provides nutrition education and/or information on
          operational aspects of the FMNP to FMNP recipients.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Matching requirement
          </E>
           means State, local or private funds, or program income, equal to not
          less than 30 percent of the administrative FMNP cost for the fiscal
          year. The Secretary may negotiate with an Indian State agency a lower
          percentage of matching funds, but not less than 10 percent of the
          administrative cost of the program, if the Indian State agency
          demonstrates to the Secretary financial hardship for the affected
          Indian tribe, band, group, or council. The match may be satisfied
          through expenditures for similar farmers&apos; market programs which
          operate during the same period as the FMNP. 
          <PRTPAGE P='484' />
          Similar programs include other farmers&apos; market programs which
          serve low-income women, infants and children (who may or may not be
          WIC participants or on the waiting list for WIC services), as well as
          other categories of low-income recipients, such as, but not limited
          to, low-income elderly persons.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Nonprofit agency
          </E>
           means a private agency which is exempt from income tax under the
          Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended, (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='26' sect='1' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/26/1.html'>
              26 U.S.C. 1
            </subref>
          </aref>
          <E T='03'>
            et. seq.
          </E>
          ).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Nutrition education
          </E>
           means individual or group education sessions and the provision of
          information and educational materials designed to improve health
          status, achieve positive change in dietary habits, and emphasize
          relationships between nutrition and health, all in keeping with the
          individual&apos;s personal, cultural, and socioeconomic preferences.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            OIG
          </E>
           means the Department&apos;s Office of the Inspector General.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Program or FMNP
          </E>
           means the WIC Farmers&apos; Market Nutrition Program authorized by 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 17(m) of
          </aref>
           the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 (CNA) (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='42' sect='1786' note='' psec='#m' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/42/1786.html#m'>
              42 U.S.C. 1786(m)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ), as amended. The Special Supplemental Nutrition Program for Women,
          Infants and Children (WIC) is authorized by 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 17 of
          </aref>
           the CNA, as amended. Within 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            section 17
          </aref>
          , 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            section 17(m)
          </aref>
           authorizes the FMNP.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Recipient
          </E>
           means a person chosen by the State agency to receive FMNP benefits.
          Such person must be a woman, infant over 4 months of age, or child,
          who receives benefits under the WIC Program or is on the waiting list
          to receive benefits under the WIC Program.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Roadside stand
          </E>
           means a location at which an individual farmer sells his/her produce
          directly to consumers. This is in contrast to a group or association
          of farmers selling their produce at a farmers&apos; market.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            SFPD
          </E>
           means the Supplemental Food Programs Division of the Food and
          Nutrition Service of the U.S. Department of Agriculture.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Similar programs
          </E>
           means other farmers&apos; market projects or programs which serve
          low-income women, infants and children, or other categories of
          recipients, such as, but not limited to, elderly persons.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State
          </E>
           means any of the 50 States, the District of Columbia, the
          Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa,
          and the Northern Marianas Islands.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State agency
          </E>
           means the agriculture department, the health department or any other
          agency approved by the chief executive officer of the State; an Indian
          tribe, band or group recognized by the Department of the Interior; an
          intertribal council or group which is an authorized representative of
          Indian tribes, bands or groups recognized by the Department of the
          Interior and which has an ongoing relationship with such tribes, bands
          or groups for other purposes and has contracted with them to
          administer the Program; or the appropriate area office of the Indian
          Health Service (IHS), an agency of the Department of Health and Human
          Services.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State Plan
          </E>
           means a plan of FMNP operation and administration that describes the
          manner in which the State agency intends to implement, operate and
          administer all aspects of the FMNP within its jurisdiction in
          accordance with 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='248' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              248.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Total FMNP funds
          </E>
           means the sum of the Federal funds provided to the State agency and
          non-Federal contributions provided by the State agency for FMNP
          purposes.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            WIC
          </E>
           means the Special Supplemental Nutrition Program for Women, Infants
          and Children authorized by 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 17 of
          </aref>
           the Child Nutrition Act of 1966, as amended (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='42' sect='1771' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/42/1771.html'>
              42 U.S.C. 1771
            </subref>
          </aref>
          <E T='03'>
            et. seq.
          </E>
          ).
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            59 FR 11517
          </aref>
          , Mar. 11, 1994, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            60 FR 49745
          </aref>
          , Sept. 27, 1995; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            64 FR 48076
          </aref>
          , Sept. 2, 1999; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            73 FR 65249
          </aref>
          , Nov. 3, 2008]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4745'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:A:248:A:248.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        248.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Administration.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          59 FR 11517
        </aref>
        , Mar. 11, 1994, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          76 FR 37983
        </aref>
        , June 29, 2011]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='248' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              248.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Administration.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Delegation to FNS.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Within the Department, FNS shall act on behalf of the Department in
            the administration of the FMNP. Within FNS, SFPD and the FNS
            Regional Offices are responsible for FMNP administration. FNS shall
            provide assistance to State agencies and evaluate all levels of FMNP
            operations to ensure that the goals of the FMNP are achieved in the
            most effective and efficient manner possible.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Delegation to State agency.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency is responsible for the effective and efficient
            administration of 
            <PRTPAGE P='485' />
            the FMNP in accordance with the requirements of this part; the
            requirements of the Department&apos;s regulations governing
            nondiscrimination (
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR parts 
              <subref title='7' part='15' tq='N'>
                15, 15a
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='15b' tq='N'>
                15b
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ), administration of grants (
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3016' tq='N'>
                3016
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ), nonprocurement debarment/suspension (
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3017' tq='N'>
                3017
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ), drug-free workplace (
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3017' tq='N'>
                3017
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ), and lobbying (
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3018' tq='N'>
                3018
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ); and, Office of Management and Budget Circular A-130, FNS
            guidelines, and Instructions issued under the FNS Directives
            Management System. The State agency shall provide guidance to
            cooperating WIC State and local agencies on all aspects of FMNP
            operations. Pursuant to 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 17(m)(2) of
            </aref>
             the CNA, State agencies may operate the FMNP locally through
            nonprofit organizations or local government entities and must ensure
            coordination among the appropriate agencies and organizations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Agreement and State Plan.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each State agency desiring to administer the FMNP shall annually
            submit a State Plan and enter into a written agreement with the
            Department for administration of the Program in the jurisdiction of
            the State agency in accordance with the provisions of this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The written agreement must include a statement that supports full
            use of Federal funds provided to State agencies for the
            administration of the FMNP, and excludes such funds from State
            budget restrictions or limitations, including hiring freezes, work
            furloughs, and travel restrictions.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              State agency ineligibility.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A State agency shall be ineligible to participate in the FMNP if
            State or local sales tax is collected on Program food purchases in
            the area in which it administers the Program, except that, if sales
            tax is collected on Program food purchases by sovereign Indian
            entities which are not State agencies, the State agency shall remain
            eligible so long as any farmers&apos; markets collecting such tax
            are disqualified.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Coordination with WIC agency.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Chief Executive Officer of the State shall ensure coordination
            between the designated administering State agency and the WIC State
            agency, if different, by ensuring that the two agencies enter into a
            written agreement. Such coordination between agencies is necessary
            for the successful operation of the FMNP, because WIC participants
            or persons on the waiting list for WIC services are the only persons
            eligible to receive Federal benefits under the FMNP. The written
            agreement shall delineate the responsibilities of each agency,
            describe any compensation for services, and shall be signed by the
            designated representative of each agency. This agreement shall be
            submitted each year along with the State Plan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              State staffing standards.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each State agency shall ensure that sufficient staff is available
            to efficiently and effectively administer the FMNP. This shall
            include, but not be limited to, sufficient staff to provide
            nutrition education in coordination with the WIC Program, coupon and
            market management, fiscal reporting, monitoring, and training. The
            State agency shall provide an outline of administrative staff and
            job descriptions for staff whose salaries will be paid from program
            funds in their State Plans.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            59 FR 11517
          </aref>
          , Mar. 11, 1994, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 37983
          </aref>
          , June 29, 2011]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4746'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:A:248:B:248.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        248.4
      </num>
      <head>
        State Plan.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          59 FR 11517
        </aref>
        , Mar. 11, 1994, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          60 FR 49746
        </aref>
        , Sept. 27, 1995; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          64 FR 48076
        </aref>
        , Sept. 2, 1999; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          73 FR 65249
        </aref>
        , Nov. 3, 2008]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='248' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              248.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          State Plan.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Requirements.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             By November 15 of each year, each applying or participating State
            agency shall submit to FNS for approval a State Plan for the
            following year as a prerequisite to receiving funds under this
            section. The State Plan shall be signed by the State designated
            official responsible for ensuring that the Program is operated in
            accordance with the State Plan. FNS will provide written approval or
            denial of a completed State Plan or amendment within 30 days.
            Portions of the State Plan which do not change annually need not be
            resubmitted. However, the State agency shall provide the title of
            the sections that remain unchanged, as well as the year of the last
            Plan in which the sections were submitted. At a minimum, the Plan
            must address the following areas in sufficient detail to demonstrate
            the State agency&apos;s ability to meet the requirements of the
            FMNP:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A copy of the agreement between the designated administering State
            agency and the WIC State agency, if 
            <PRTPAGE P='486' />
            different, for services such as nutrition education, and
            documentation of coordinated efforts as required in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='248' sect='3' psec='#e' tq='N'>
                248.3(e)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , as well as copies of agreements with agencies other than the WIC
            State agency.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Estimated number of recipients for the fiscal year, and proposed
            months of operation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Estimated cost of the FMNP, including a minimum amount necessary to
            operate the FMNP.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Description of how the Program will achieve its dual purposes of
            providing a nutritional benefit to WIC (or waiting list)
            participants and expanding the awareness and use of farmers&apos;
            markets.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Outline of administrative staff and job descriptions.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Detailed description of the recordkeeping system including, but not
            limited to, the system for maintaining records pertaining to
            financial operations, coupon issuance and redemption, and FMNP
            participation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Detailed description of the financial management system, including,
            but not limited to documentation of how the State will meet the
            matching requirement and procedures for obligating funds.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Detailed description of the service area including:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_8_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The number and addresses of participating markets, roadside stands
            and area WIC clinics including a map outlining the service area and
            proximity of markets/roadside stands to clinics; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_8_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Estimated number of WIC participants and persons on the WIC waiting
            list that will receive FMNP coupons.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Description of the coupon issuance system including:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_9_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             How the State agency will target areas with highest concentrations
            of eligible persons and greatest access to farmers&apos; markets
            within the broadest possible geographic area;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_9_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Annual benefit amount per recipient;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_9_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Method for instructing recipients on the proper use of FMNP coupons
            and the purpose of the FMNP; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_9_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Method for ensuring that FMNP coupons are only issued to eligible
            recipients.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Detailed description of the coupon and farmers&apos; market
            management system including:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_10_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Criteria for authorizing farmers&apos; markets and/or roadside
            stands;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_10_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Procedures for training farmers and market managers, at
            authorization, and annually thereafter;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_10_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Procedures for monitoring farmers, farmers&apos; markets and/or
            roadside stands;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_10_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Description of system for identifying high risk farmers,
            farmers&apos; markets and/or roadside stands and procedures for
            sanctioning farmers, farmers&apos; markets and/or roadside stands;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_10_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Facsimile of the FMNP coupon;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_10_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Identification of the fresh, nutritious, unprepared fruits,
            vegetables, and herbs which are eligible for purchase under the
            Program;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_10_vii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Description of FMNP coupon replacement policy;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_10_viii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (viii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Procedures for handling recipient and farmer/farmers&apos; market
            complaints.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_11'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (11)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Detailed description of the FMNP coupon redemption process
            including:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_11_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Procedures for ensuring the secure transportation and storage of
            FMNP coupons;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_11_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             System for identifying and reconciling FMNP coupons;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_11_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Timeframes for FMNP coupon redemption by recipients; submission for
            payment by markets, and payment by the State agency;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_12'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (12)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             System for ensuring that FMNP coupons are redeemed only by
            authorized farmers, farmers&apos; markets and/or roadside stands and
            only for eligible foods.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_13'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (13)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             System for identifying FMNP coupons which are redeemed or submitted
            for payment outside valid dates or by unauthorized farmers,
            farmers&apos; markets and/or roadside stands.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_14'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (14)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A copy of the written agreement to be used between the State agency
            and authorized farmers, farmers&apos; markets and/or roadside
            stands. In those States which authorize farmers&apos; markets, but
            not individual farmers, this agreement shall specify in detail the
            role of and procedures to be used by farmers&apos; markets for
            monitoring and 
            <PRTPAGE P='487' />
            sanctioning farmers, and the appropriate procedures to be used by a
            farmer to appeal a sanction or disqualification imposed by a
            farmers&apos; market.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_15'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (15)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If available, information on the change in consumption of fresh
            fruits and vegetables by recipients. This information shall be
            submitted as an addendum to the State Plan and shall be submitted at
            such a date specified by the Secretary.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_16'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (16)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If available, information on the effects of the program on
            farmers&apos; markets. This information shall be submitted as an
            addendum to the State Plan and shall be submitted at such a date
            specified by the Secretary.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_17'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (17)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A description of the procedures the State agency will use to comply
            with the civil rights requirements described in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='248' sect='7' psec='#a' tq='N'>
                248.7(a)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , including the processing of discrimination complaints.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_18'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (18)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State agencies which have not previously participated in the FMNP,
            shall provide the following additional information:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_18_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A statement assuring that if the State agency receives Federal
            funds, as specified under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='248' sect='14' psec='' tq='N'>
                248.14
              </subref>
            </aref>
             to operate the FMNP, and applies those funds to similar programs
            operated in the previous fiscal year with State or local funds, the
            amount of State and local funds that were available to similar
            programs in the fiscal year preceding the first year of operation
            shall not be reduced. The State agency shall include data in the
            State Plan showing that it did not reduce the amount of State and
            local funds available to the similar program in the preceding fiscal
            year.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_18_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A capability statement which includes a summary description of any
            prior experience with farmers&apos; market projects or programs,
            including information and data describing the attributes of such
            projects or programs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_19'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (19)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For States making expansion requests, documentation which
            demonstrates:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_19_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The need for an increase in funding;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_19_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             That the use of the increased funding will be consistent with
            serving WIC participants, or persons on a waiting list for WIC
            benefits, by expanding benefits to more persons, by enhancing
            current benefits, or a combination of both, and expanding the
            awareness and use of farmers&apos; markets;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_19_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The ability to satisfactorily operate the existing FMNP;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_19_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The management capabilities of the State agency to expand; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_19_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whether, in the case of a State agency that intends to use the
            funding to increase the value of the Federal share of the benefits
            received by a recipient, the funding provided will increase the rate
            of coupon redemption.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_20'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (20)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For those State agencies requesting the extra 2 percent
            administrative rate for market development or technical assistance
            to promote such development in disadvantaged areas or remote rural
            areas, an explanation of their justification and plans for the use
            of such funds.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Amendments.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             At any time after approval, the State agency may amend the State
            Plan to reflect changes. The State agency shall submit the
            amendments to FNS for approval. The amendments shall be signed by
            the State designated official responsible for ensuring that the FMNP
            is operated in accordance with the State Plan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Retention of copy.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A copy of the approved State Plan shall be kept on file at the
            State agency for public inspection.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            59 FR 11517
          </aref>
          , Mar. 11, 1994, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            60 FR 49746
          </aref>
          , Sept. 27, 1995; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            64 FR 48076
          </aref>
          , Sept. 2, 1999; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            73 FR 65249
          </aref>
          , Nov. 3, 2008]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4747'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:A:248:B:248.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        248.5
      </num>
      <head>
        Selection of new State agencies.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          64 FR 48076
        </aref>
        , Sept. 2, 1999]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='248' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              248.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Selection of new State agencies.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          In selecting new State agencies, the Department will use objective
          criteria to rank and approve State plans submitted in accordance with 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='248' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              248.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
          . In making this ranking, the Department will consider the amount of
          funds necessary to successfully operate the FMNP in the State compared
          with other States and with the total amount of funds available to the
          FMNP. Approval of a State Plan does not equate to an obligation on the
          part of the Department to fund the FMNP within that State agency.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            64 FR 48076
          </aref>
          , Sept. 2, 1999]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4748'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:A:248:C:248.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        248.6
      </num>
      <head>
        Recipient eligibility.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='248' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              248.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Recipient eligibility.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Eligibility for certification.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Individuals who are eligible to receive Federal benefits under the
            FMNP are those, excluding infants 4 months of age or younger, who
            are currently receiving benefits under WIC or who are on the waiting
            list to receive benefits from WIC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Limitations on certification.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If necessary to limit the number of recipients, State agencies may
            impose additional eligibility requirements, such as limiting
            participant certification to certain geographic areas, or to high
            priority WIC participants such as pregnant and breastfeeding women.
            States may also preclude groups of low priority persons, such as
            persons on the waiting list for WIC. Each State agency must
            specifically identify these limitations on certification in its
            State Plan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Recipient or household benefit allocation.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             On a Statewide basis, State agencies shall elect to allocate and
            issue benefits either to recipients or households. A State agency
            allocating benefits on a household basis shall not issue more
            benefits to a household than it otherwise would if benefits were
            allocated to individual recipients within the household. For those
            State agencies issuing FMNP benefits on a household basis, each
            family as defined in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='246' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
                246.2
              </subref>
               of this chapter
            </aref>
             shall constitute a separate household. Foods provided, regardless
            of method of issuance, are intended for the sole benefit of FMNP
            recipients and are not intended to be shared with other
            non-participating household members. If a State agency issues
            benefits on a household basis, data concerning number and type of
            recipients must still be provided as required by 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='248' sect='23' psec='#b' tq='N'>
                248.23(b)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . Recipients shall receive FMNP benefits free of charge.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4749'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:A:248:C:248.7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        248.7
      </num>
      <head>
        Nondiscrimination.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          59 FR 11517
        </aref>
        , Mar. 11, 1994, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          73 FR 65249
        </aref>
        , Nov. 3, 2008]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='248' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              248.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Nondiscrimination.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Civil rights requirements.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall comply with the requirements of title VI of
            the Civil Rights Act of 1964, title IX of the Education Amendments
            of 1972, 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 504 of
            </aref>
             the Rehabilitation Act of 1973, the Age Discrimination Act of 1975,
            Department of Agriculture regulations on nondiscrimination (
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR parts 
              <subref title='7' part='15' tq='N'>
                15, 15a
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='15b' tq='N'>
                15b
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ), and applicable FNS Instructions to ensure that no person shall,
            on the grounds of race, color, national origin, age, sex or
            handicap, be excluded from participation, be denied benefits, or be
            otherwise subjected to discrimination, under the FMNP. Because
            racial and ethnic participation data (as required by title VI of the
            Civil Rights Act of 1964) are collected at the time women, infants,
            and children are certified for participation in the WIC Program, the
            Department has determined that the WIC data collection effort is
            sufficient to fulfill the racial/ethnic data collection requirement
            for the FMNP. Therefore, no additional data collection is required.
            Compliance with title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964, Title IX
            of the Education Amendments of 1972, 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 504 of
            </aref>
             the Rehabilitation Act of 1973, the Age Discrimination Act of 1975,
            and regulations and instructions issued thereunder shall include,
            but not be limited to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notification to the public of the nondiscrimination policy and
            complaint rights of recipients and potentially eligible persons,
            which may be satisfied through the Department&apos;s required
            nondiscrimination statement on brochures and publications;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Review and monitoring activity to ensure FMNP compliance with the
            nondiscrimination laws and regulations;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Establishment of grievance procedures for handling recipient
            complaints based on sex and handicap.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Complaints.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Persons seeking to file discrimination complaints may file them
            either with the Secretary of Agriculture, or the Director, USDA,
            Office of Adjudication and Compliance, Room 326-W, Whitten Building,
            14th and Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC 20250-9410 (or
            call (800) 795-3272 (voice) or (202) 720-6382 (TTY)), or with the
            office established by the State agency to handle discrimination
            grievances or complaints. All complaints received by State agencies
            which allege discrimination based on race, color, national origin,
            or age shall be referred to the Secretary of Agriculture or the
            Director of the Office of Equal Opportunity, USDA. A State agency
            may process complaints which allege discrimination 
            <PRTPAGE P='489' />
            based on sex or handicap if grievance procedures are in place.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            59 FR 11517
          </aref>
          , Mar. 11, 1994, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            73 FR 65249
          </aref>
          , Nov. 3, 2008]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4750'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:A:248:D:248.8
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        248.8
      </num>
      <head>
        Level of benefits and eligible foods.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          59 FR 11517
        </aref>
        , Mar. 11, 1994, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          60 FR 49746
        </aref>
        , Sept. 27, 1995; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          73 FR 65250
        </aref>
        , Nov. 3, 2008]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='248' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              248.8
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Level of benefits and eligible foods.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State agencies shall identify in the State Plan the fresh,
            nutritious, unprepared, locally grown fruits, vegetables and herbs
            which are eligible for purchase under the FMNP. Ineligible foods for
            the purpose of the FMNP include, but are not limited to: honey,
            maple syrup, cider, nuts and seeds, eggs, cheese, meat and seafood.
            Locally grown shall mean produce grown only within a State&apos;s
            borders but may be defined to include border areas in adjacent
            States. Under no circumstances can produce grown outside of the
            United States and its territories be considered eligible foods.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              The value of the Federal benefits received.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The value of the Federal FMNP benefit received by each recipient,
            or by each family within a household in those States which elect to
            issue benefits on a household basis under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='248' sect='6' psec='#c' tq='N'>
                248.6(c)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             may not be less than $10 per year nor more than $30 per year.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            59 FR 11517
          </aref>
          , Mar. 11, 1994, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            60 FR 49746
          </aref>
          , Sept. 27, 1995; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            73 FR 65250
          </aref>
          , Nov. 3, 2008]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4751'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:A:248:D:248.9
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        248.9
      </num>
      <head>
        Nutrition education.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='248' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
              248.9
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Nutrition education.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Goals.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Nutrition education shall emphasize the relationship of proper
            nutrition to the total concept of good health, including the
            importance of consuming fresh fruits and vegetables.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Requirement.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall integrate nutrition education into FMNP
            operations and may satisfy nutrition education requirements through
            coordination with other agencies within the State. Such other
            agencies may include the WIC Program which routinely offers
            nutrition education to participants and which may wish to use the
            opportunity of the FMNP to reinforce nutrition messages. State
            agencies wishing to coordinate nutrition education with WIC shall
            enter into a written cooperative agreement with WIC agencies to
            offer nutrition education relevant to the use and nutritional value
            of foods available to FMNP recipients. In cases where relevant WIC
            nutrition education sessions are used to meet this requirement,
            reimbursement to the WIC local agency shall not be permitted. In
            cases where FMNP recipients are not receiving relevant nutrition
            education from the WIC Program, the State agency shall arrange
            alternative methods for the provision of such nutrition education
            which is an allowable cost under the FMNP.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4752'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:A:248:E:248.10
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        248.10
      </num>
      <head>
        Coupon and market management.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          59 FR 11517
        </aref>
        , Mar. 11, 1994, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          60 FR 49746
        </aref>
        , Sept. 27, 1995; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          73 FR 65250
        </aref>
        , Nov. 3, 2008]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='248' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
              248.10
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Coupon and market management.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This section sets forth State agency responsibilities regarding the
            authorization of farmers, farmers&apos; markets, and roadside
            stands. The State agency is responsible for the fiscal management
            of, and accountability for, FMNP-related activities for farmers,
            farmers&apos; markets and roadside stands. Each State agency may
            decide whether to authorize farmers individually, farmers&apos;
            markets, roadside stands, or all of the above. All contracts or
            agreements entered into by the State agency for the management or
            operation of farmers, farmers&apos; markets and roadside stands
            shall conform with the requirements of 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3016' tq='N'>
                3016
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , Uniform Administrative Requirements for Grants and Cooperative
            Agreements to State and Local Governments.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Only farmers, farmers&apos; markets and roadside stands authorized
            by the State agency may redeem FMNP coupons. Only farmers authorized
            by the State agency or that have a valid agreement with an
            authorized farmers&apos; market may redeem coupons.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall establish criteria for the authorization of
            individual farmers, farmers&apos; markets and roadside stands. Any
            authorized farmer, farmers&apos; market and roadside stand must
            agree to sell recipients only those foods identified as eligible by
            the State agency, in exchange for FMNP coupons. Individuals who
            exclusively sell produce grown by someone else, such as wholesale
            distributors, cannot be 
            <PRTPAGE P='490' />
            authorized to participate in the FMNP, except individuals employed
            by a farmer otherwise qualified under these regulations, or
            individuals hired by a nonprofit organization to sell produce at
            farmers&apos; markets or roadside stands on behalf of local farmers.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall ensure that an appropriate number of
            farmers, farmers&apos; markets and/or roadside stands are authorized
            for adequate recipient access in the area(s) proposed to be served
            and for effective management of the farmers, farmers&apos; markets
            and/or roadside stands by the State agency. The State agency may
            establish criteria to limit the number of authorized farmers,
            farmers&apos; markets and/or roadside stands.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall ensure that face-to-face training is
            conducted prior to start up of the first year of FMNP participation
            of a farmers&apos; market and individual farmer. The face-to-face
            training shall include at a minimum those items listed in paragraph
            (d) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Authorized farmers shall display a sign stating that they are
            authorized to redeem FMNP coupons.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Authorized farmers, farmers&apos; markets and roadside stands shall
            comply with the requirements of Title VI of the Civil Rights Act of
            1964, title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972, 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 504 of
            </aref>
             the Rehabilitation Act of 1973, the Age Discrimination Act of 1975,
            Department of Agriculture regulations on non-discrimination (
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR parts 
              <subref title='7' part='15' tq='N'>
                15, 15a
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='15b' tq='N'>
                15b
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ), and FNS Instructions as outlined in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='248' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
                248.7
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall ensure that there is no conflict of interest
            between the State or local agency and any participating farmer,
            farmers&apos; market and roadside stand.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Farmers&apos; market agreements.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall ensure that all participating farmers&apos;
            markets enter into written agreements with the State agency. The
            agreement shall be signed by a representative who has legal
            authority to obligate the farmer, farmers&apos; market and/or
            roadside stand. The agreement shall be signed by a representative
            who has legal authority to obligate the farmers/farmers&apos;
            market. Agreements shall include a description of sanctions for
            noncompliance with FMNP requirements and shall contain at a minimum,
            the following specifications, although the State agency may
            determine the exact wording to be used:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The farmer, farmers&apos; market and roadside stand shall:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provide such information as the State agency may require for its
            periodic reports to FNS;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Assure that FMNP coupons are redeemed only for eligible foods;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provide eligible foods at the current price or less than the
            current price charged to other customers;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Accept FMNP coupons within the dates of their validity and submit
            such coupons for payment within the allowable time period
            established by the State agency;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In accordance with a procedure established by the State agency,
            mark each transacted coupon with a farmer identifier. In those cases
            where the agreement is between the State agency and the farmer, each
            transacted FMNP coupon shall contain a farmer identifier and shall
            be batched for reimbursement under that identifier. In those cases
            where the agreement is between the State agency and the
            farmers&apos; market, each transacted FMNP coupon shall contain a
            farmer identifier and be batched for reimbursement under a
            farmers&apos; market identifier.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Accept training on FMNP procedures and provide training to farmers
            and any employees with FMNP responsibilities on such procedures;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_vii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Agree to be monitored for compliance with FMNP requirements,
            including both overt and covert monitoring;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_viii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (viii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be accountable for actions of farmers or employees in the provision
            of foods and related activities;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_ix'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ix)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Pay the State agency for any coupons transacted in violation of
            this agreement;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_x'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (x)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Offer FMNP recipients the same courtesies as other customers;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_xi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (xi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Comply with the nondiscrimination provisions of USDA regulations as
            provided in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='248' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
                248.7
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_xii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (xii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notify the State agency if any farmer, farmers&apos; market and/or
            roadside stand ceases operation prior to the end of the
            authorization period.
            <PRTPAGE P='491' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The farmer, farmers&apos; market and roadside stand shall not:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Collect sales tax on FMNP coupon purchases;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Seek restitution from FMNP recipients for coupons not paid by the
            State agency;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Issue cash change for purchases that are in an amount less than the
            value of the FMNP coupon(s).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Neither the State agency nor the farmer, farmers&apos; market nor a
            roadside stand has an obligation to renew the agreement. Either the
            State agency or the farmer, farmers&apos; market or a roadside stand
            may terminate the agreement for cause after providing advance
            written notification.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency may deny payment to the farmer, farmers&apos;
            market or roadside stand for improperly redeemed FMNP coupons and
            may demand refunds for payments already made on improperly redeemed
            coupons.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency may disqualify a farmer, farmers&apos; market or
            roadside stand for FMNP abuse. The farmer, farmers&apos; market
            and/or roadside stand has the right to appeal a denial of an
            application to participate, a disqualification, or a FMNP sanction
            by the State agency. Expiration of a contract or agreement with a
            farmer, farmers&apos; market or roadside stand, and claims actions
            under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='248' sect='20' psec='' tq='N'>
                248.20
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , are not appealable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A farmer, farmers&apos; market or a roadside stand which commits
            fraud or engages in other illegal activity is liable to prosecution
            under applicable Federal, State or local laws.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Agreements may not exceed 3 years.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Farmer agreements for State agencies which do not authorize
              farmers.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Those State agencies which authorize farmers&apos; markets but not
            individual farmers shall require authorized farmers&apos; markets to
            enter into a written agreement with each farmer within the market
            that is participating in FMNP. The State agency shall set forth the
            required terms for the agreement and provide a sample agreement
            which may be used.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Annual training for farmers/farmers&apos; market managers.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State agencies shall conduct annual training for
            farmers/farmers&apos; market managers participating in the FMNP. The
            State agency shall conduct a face-to-face training for all farmers
            and farmers&apos; market managers who have never previously
            participated in the program prior to their commencing participation
            in the FMNP. After a farmer/farmers&apos; market manager&apos;s
            first year of FMNP operation, State agencies have discretion in
            determining the method used for annual training purposes. At a
            minimum, annual training shall include instruction emphasizing:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Eligible food choices;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Proper FMNP coupon redemption procedures, including deadlines for
            submission of coupons for payment;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Equitable treatment of FMNP recipients, including the availability
            of produce to FMNP recipients that is of the same quality and cost
            as that sold to other customers;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil rights compliance and guidelines;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Guidelines for storing FMNP coupons safely; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Guidelines for cancelling FMNP coupons, such as punching holes or
            rubber stamping.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Monitoring and review of farmers, farmers&apos; markets, roadside
              stands and local agencies.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall be responsible for the monitoring of
            farmers, farmers&apos; markets, roadside stands and local agencies
            within its jurisdiction. This shall include developing a system for
            identifying high risk farmers, farmers&apos; markets, and roadside
            stands and ensuring on-site monitoring, conducting further
            investigation, and sanctioning of such farmers, farmers&apos;
            markets, or roadside stands as appropriate.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Where coupon reimbursement responsibilities are delegated to
            farmers&apos; market managers, farmers&apos; market associations, or
            nonprofit organizations, the State agency may establish bonding
            requirements for these entities. Costs of such bonding are not
            reimbursable administrative expenses.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each State agency shall rank participating farmers, farmers&apos;
            markets and roadside stands by risk factors, and shall conduct
            annual, on-site monitoring of at least 10 percent of farmers, 10
            percent of farmers&apos; markets and 10 percent of roadside stands
            which shall 
            <PRTPAGE P='492' />
            include those farmers, farmers&apos; markets and roadside stands
            identified as being the highest risk.Mandatory high-risk indicators
            are a proportionately high volume of FMNP coupons redeemed by a
            farmer as compared to other farmers within the farmers&apos; market
            and within the State, recipient complaints, and farmers and
            farmers&apos; markets in their first year of FMNP operation. States
            are encouraged to formally establish other high risk indicators for
            identifying potential problems. If additional high risk indicators
            are established, they shall be set forth in the
            farmers/farmers&apos; market agreement and in the State Plan. If
            application of the high-risk indicators results in fewer than 10
            percent of farmers and farmers&apos; markets as high-risk, the State
            agency shall randomly select additional farmers and farmers&apos;
            markets to be monitored in order to meet the 10 percent minimum. The
            high-risk indicators listed above generally apply to a State agency
            already participating in the FMNP. A State agency participating in
            the FMNP for the first time shall, in lieu of applying the high-risk
            indicators, randomly select 10 percent of its participating farmers,
            10 percent of its participating farmers&apos; markets, and 10
            percent of its participating roadside stands for monitoring visits.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The following shall be documented for all on-site farmers,
            farmers&apos; markets, and roadside stands monitoring visits. At a
            minimum, documentation must include the names of the farmer,
            farmers&apos; market or roadside stand and the reviewer; date of
            review; nature of problem(s) detected or the observation that the
            farmer, farmers&apos; market or roadside stand appears to be in
            compliance with FMNP requirements; a record of interviews with
            recipients, market managers and/or farmers; and the signature of the
            reviewer. The State agency shall do so after a reasonable delay when
            necessary to protect the identity of the reviewer(s) or the
            integrity of the investigation. After the farmer/farmers&apos;
            market has been informed of any deficiencies detected by the
            monitoring visit, and instances where the farmer/farmers&apos;
            market will be permitted to continue participation, the
            farmer/farmers&apos; market shall provide plans as to how the
            deficiencies will be corrected.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             At least every 2 years, the State agency shall review all local
            agencies within its jurisdiction. WIC State agency reviews of WIC
            local agencies, which include reviews of FMNP practices, may
            contribute to meeting the requirement that all local agencies be
            reviewed once every 2 years.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Control of FMNP coupons.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall control and provide accountability for the
            receipt and issuance of FMNP coupons.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall ensure that there is secure transportation
            and storage of unissued FMNP coupons.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall design and implement a system of review of
            FMNP coupons to detect errors. At a minimum, the errors the system
            must detect are a missing recipient signature, a missing farmer
            and/or market identification, and redemption by a farmer outside of
            the valid date. The State agency shall implement procedures to
            reduce the number of errors in transactions, where possible.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Payment to farmers/farmers&apos; markets.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall ensure that farmers/ farmers&apos; markets
            are promptly paid for food costs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Reconciliation of FMNP coupons.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall identify the disposition of all FMNP coupons
            as validly redeemed, lost or stolen, expired, or not matching
            issuance records. Validly redeemed FMNP coupons are those that are
            issued to a valid recipient and redeemed by an authorized
            farmers/farmers&apos; market within valid dates. FMNP coupons that
            were redeemed but cannot be traced to a valid recipient or
            authorized farmer/farmers&apos; market shall be subject to claims
            action in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='248' sect='20' psec='' tq='N'>
                248.20
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . (1) If the State agency elects to replace lost, stolen or damaged
            FMNP coupons, it must describe its system for doing so in the State
            Plan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall use uniform FMNP coupons within its
            jurisdiction.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FMNP coupons must include, at a minimum, the following information:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The last date by which the recipient may use the coupon. This date
            shall be no later than November 30 of each year.
            <PRTPAGE P='493' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A date by which the farmer or farmers&apos; market must submit the
            coupon for payment. When establishing this date, State agencies
            shall take into consideration the date financial statements are due
            to the FNS, and allow time for the corresponding coupon
            reconciliation that must be done by the State agency prior to
            submission of financial statements. Currently, financial statements
            are due to FNS by January 30.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A unique and sequential serial number.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_3_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A denomination (dollar amount).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_3_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A farmer identifier for the redeeming farmer when agreements are
            between the State agency and the farmer.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_3_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In those instances where State agencies have agreements with
            farmers&apos; markets, there must be a farmer identifier on each
            coupon and a market identifier on the cover of coupons which are
            batched by the market manager for reimbursement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Instructions to recipients.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each recipient shall receive instructions on the proper use and
            redemption of the FMNP coupons, including, but not limited to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A list of names and addresses of authorized farmers, farmers&apos;
            markets and roadside stands at which FMNP coupons may be redeemed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A description of eligible foods and the prohibition against cash
            change.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An explanation of their right to complain about improper
            farmer/farmers&apos; market practices with regard to FMNP
            responsibilities and the process for doing so.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Recipients and farmer/farmers&apos; market complaints.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall have procedures which document the handling
            of complaints by recipients and farmers/farmers&apos; markets.
            Complaints of civil rights discrimination shall be handled in
            accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='248' sect='7' psec='#b' tq='N'>
                248.7(b)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Recipients and farmer/farmers&apos; market sanctions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall establish policies which determine the type
            and level of sanctions to be applied against recipients and
            farmers/farmers&apos; markets, based upon the severity and nature of
            the FMNP violations observed, and such other factors as the State
            agency determines appropriate, such as whether repeated offenses
            have occurred over a period of time. Farmers/farmers&apos; markets
            may be sanctioned, disqualified, or both, when appropriate.
            Sanctions may include fines for improper FMNP coupon redemption
            procedures and the penalties outlined in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='248' sect='20' psec='' tq='N'>
                248.20
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , in case of deliberate fraud. In those instances where compliance
            purchases are conducted, the results of covert compliance purchases
            can be a basis for farmer/farmers&apos; market sanctions. A
            farmer/farmers&apos; market committing fraud or other unlawful
            activities is liable to prosecution under applicable Federal, State
            or local laws. State agency policies shall ensure that a farmer that
            is disqualified from the FMNP at one market or roadside stand shall
            not participate in the FMNP at any other farmers&apos; market or
            roadside stand in the State&apos;s jurisdiction during the
            disqualification period.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            59 FR 11517
          </aref>
          , Mar. 11, 1994, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            60 FR 49746
          </aref>
          , Sept. 27, 1995; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            73 FR 65250
          </aref>
          , Nov. 3, 2008]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4753'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:A:248:E:248.11
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        248.11
      </num>
      <head>
        Financial management system.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          59 FR 11517
        </aref>
        , Mar. 11, 1994, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          60 FR 49747
        </aref>
        , Sept. 27, 1995]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='248' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
              248.11
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Financial management system.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Disclosure of expenditures.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall maintain a financial management system which
            provides accurate, current and complete disclosure of the financial
            status of the FMNP. This shall include an accounting for all
            property and other assets and all FMNP funds received and expended
            each fiscal year.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Internal controls.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall maintain effective controls over and
            accountability for all FMNP funds. The State agency must have
            effective internal controls to ensure that expenditures financed
            with FMNP funds are authorized and properly chargeable to the FMNP.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Record of expenditures.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall maintain records which adequately identify
            the source and use of funds expended for FMNP activities. These
            records shall contain, but are not limited to, information
            pertaining to authorization, receipt of funds, obligations,
            unobligated balances, assets, liabilities, outlays, and income.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Payment of costs.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall implement procedures which ensure prompt and
            accurate payment of 
            <PRTPAGE P='494' />
            allowable costs, and ensure the allowability and allocability of
            costs in accordance with the cost principles and standard provisions
            of this part, 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3016' tq='N'>
                3016
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , and FNS guidelines and Instructions.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Identification of obligated funds.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall implement procedures which accurately
            identify obligated FMNP funds at the time the obligations are made.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Resolution of audit findings.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall implement procedures which ensure timely and
            appropriate resolution of claims and other matters resulting from
            audit findings and recommendations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Reconciliation of food instruments.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall reconcile FMNP coupons in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='248' sect='10' psec='#h' tq='N'>
                248.10(h)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Transfer of cash.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall establish the timing and amounts of its cash
            draws against its Letter of Credit in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              31 CFR part 
              <subref title='31' part='205' tq='N'>
                205
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            59 FR 11517
          </aref>
          , Mar. 11, 1994, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            60 FR 49747
          </aref>
          , Sept. 27, 1995]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4754'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:A:248:E:248.12
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        248.12
      </num>
      <head>
        FMNP costs.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          59 FR 11517
        </aref>
        , Mar. 11, 1994, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          60 FR 49747
        </aref>
        , Sept. 27, 1995]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='248' sect='12' psec='' tq='N'>
              248.12
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          FMNP costs.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Composition of allowable costs.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In general, a cost item will be deemed allowable if it is
            reasonable and necessary for FMNP purposes and otherwise satisfies
            allowability criteria set forth in 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR 
              <subref title='7' part='3016' sect='22' psec='' tq='N'>
                3016.22
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and this part. FMNP purposes include the administration and
            operation of the FMNP. Program costs supported by State matching
            contributions must meet the same criteria for allowability as costs
            supported by Federal funds. Allowable FMNP costs may be classified
            as follows:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Food costs and administrative costs.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Food costs are the costs of food benefits provided to FMNP
            recipients. Administrative costs are the costs associated with
            providing FMNP benefits and services to recipients and generally
            administering the FMNP. Specific examples of allowable
            administrative costs are listed in paragraph (b) of this section.
            Except as provided in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='248' sect='14' psec='#g' tq='N'>
                248.14(g)
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
            , a State agency&apos;s administrative costs under the FMNP may not
            exceed 17 percent of its total FMNP costs. Any costs incurred for
            food and/or administration above the Federal grant level will be the
            State agency&apos;s responsibility.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Market development or technical assistance costs.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Market development or technical assistance costs are those costs
            under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='248' sect='14' psec='#h' tq='N'>
                248.14(h)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             incurred to promote the development of farmers&apos; markets in
            socially or economically disadvantaged areas, or remote rural areas,
            where individuals eligible for participation in the program have
            limited access to locally grown fruits and vegetables. Subject to a
            determination by the Secretary under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='248' sect='14' psec='#h' tq='N'>
                248.14(h)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , a State agency may, during any fiscal year, use not more than 2
            percent of total program funds for such market development or
            technical assistance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Direct and indirect costs.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Direct costs are food and administrative costs incurred
            specifically for the FMNP. Indirect costs are administrative costs
            that benefit multiple programs or activities, and cannot be
            identified to any one without effort disproportionate to the results
            achieved. In accordance with the provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3016' tq='N'>
                3016
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , a claim for reimbursement of indirect costs shall be supported by
            an approved allocation plan for the determination of such costs. An
            indirect cost rate developed through such an allocation plan may not
            be applied to a base that includes food costs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Costs allowable with prior approval.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A State or local agency must obtain prior approval in accordance
            with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR 
              <subref title='7' part='3016' sect='22' psec='' tq='N'>
                3016.22
              </subref>
            </aref>
             before charging to the FMNP any capital expenditures and other cost
            items designated by 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR 
              <subref title='7' part='3016' sect='22' psec='' tq='N'>
                3016.22
              </subref>
            </aref>
             as requiring such approval.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Unallowable costs.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Costs that are not reasonable and necessary for FMNP purposes, or
            that do not otherwise satisfy the cost principles of 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR 
              <subref title='7' part='3016' sect='22' psec='' tq='N'>
                3016.22
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , are unallowable. Notwithstanding any other provision of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='3016' tq='N'>
                3016
              </subref>
            </aref>
             or this part, the cost of constructing or operating a farmers&apos;
            market is unallowable. Unallowable costs may never be claimed for
            Federal reimbursement or counted toward the State matching
            requirement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Specified allowable administrative costs.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Allowable administrative costs include the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The costs associated with the provision of nutrition education
            which 
            <PRTPAGE P='495' />
            meets the requirements of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='248' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
                248.9
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The costs of FMNP coupon issuance, or recipient education covering
            proper coupon redemption procedures.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The cost of outreach services.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The costs associated with the food delivery process, such as
            printing FMNP coupons, processing redeemed coupons, and training
            market managers on the food delivery system.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The cost of monitoring and reviewing Program operations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The cost of FMNP training.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The cost of required reporting and recordkeeping.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The cost of determining which local WIC sites will be utilized.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The cost of recruiting and authorizing farmers/farmers&apos;
            markets to participate in the FMNP.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The cost of preparing contracts for farmers/farmers&apos; markets
            and local WIC providers.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_11'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (11)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The cost of developing a data processing system for redemption and
            reconciliation of FMNP coupons.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_12'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (12)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The cost of designing program training and informational materials.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_13'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (13)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The cost of coordinating FMNP implementation responsibilities
            between designated administering agencies.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            59 FR 11517
          </aref>
          , Mar. 11, 1994, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            60 FR 49747
          </aref>
          , Sept. 27, 1995]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4755'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:A:248:E:248.13
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        248.13
      </num>
      <head>
        FMNP income.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='248' sect='13' psec='' tq='N'>
              248.13
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          FMNP income.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Program income means gross income the State agency earns from grant
          supported activities. It includes fees for services performed and
          receipts from the use or rental of real or personal property acquired
          with Federal grant funds, but does not include proceeds from the
          disposition of such property. The State agency shall retain Program
          income earned during the agreement period and use it for Program
          purposes in accordance with the addition method described in 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR 
            <subref title='7' part='3016' sect='25' psec='#g_2' tq='N'>
              3016.25(g)(2)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          . Fines, penalties or assessments paid by local agencies or
          farmers/farmers&apos; markets are also deemed to be FMNP income. The
          State agency shall ensure that the sources and applications of Program
          income are fully documented.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4756'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:A:248:E:248.14
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        248.14
      </num>
      <head>
        Distribution of funds.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          59 FR 11517
        </aref>
        , Mar. 11, 1994, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          60 FR 49747
        </aref>
        , Sept. 27, 1995; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          60 FR 57148
        </aref>
        , Nov. 14, 1995; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          64 FR 48076
        </aref>
        , Sept. 2, 1999; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          73 FR 65251
        </aref>
        , Nov. 3, 2008]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='248' sect='14' psec='' tq='N'>
              248.14
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Distribution of funds.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Conditions for receipt of Federal funds—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Matching of funds—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='3'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Match amount.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             As a prerequisite to the receipt of Federal funds, a State agency
            must agree to contribute State, local or private funds, or program
            income, equal to not less than 30 percent of the total
            administrative FMNP cost. The Secretary may negotiate a lower
            percentage of matching funds, but not lower than 10 percent of the
            administrative cost of the program, in the case of an Indian State
            agency that demonstrates to the Secretary financial hardship for the
            affected Indian tribe, band, group, or council. The State agency may
            contribute more than the minimum amount. State, local or private
            funds for similar programs as defined in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='248' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
                248.2
              </subref>
            </aref>
             may satisfy the State matching requirement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Sources of matching contributions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A State agency may count any form of contribution authorized by 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR 
              <subref title='7' part='3016' sect='24' psec='' tq='N'>
                3016.24
              </subref>
            </aref>
             toward the State matching requirement including in-kind
            contributions.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Failure to match.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A State agency&apos;s failure to meet the State matching
            requirement will result in the establishment of a claim for the
            amount of Federal grant funds not matched. The matching requirement
            will be considered satisfied if State or other non-Federal matching
            contributions reported on the final closeout report (required by 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='248' sect='15' psec='#a' tq='N'>
                248.15(a)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) amount to at least 30 percent of the administrative costs. This
            match amount may be lower for those Indian State agencies that have
            demonstrated to the Secretary financial hardship as set forth in
            paragraph (a)(1)(i) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              State Plan and agreement.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A State agency shall have its State Plan approved and shall execute
            an agreement with the Department in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='248' sect='3' psec='#c' tq='N'>
                248.3(c)
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Distribution of FMNP funds to previously participating State
              agencies.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provided that sufficient FMNP funds are available, each State
            agency that participated in the FMNP in any prior fiscal year, shall
            receive not less than the amount of funds the State agency received
            in the most recent fiscal year in 
            <PRTPAGE P='496' />
            which it received funding, if it otherwise complies with the
            requirements established in this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Ratable reduction.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If amounts appropriated for any fiscal year for grants under the
            FMNP are not sufficient to pay to each previously participating
            State agency at least an amount as identified in paragraph (b) of
            this section, each State agency&apos;s grant shall be ratably
            reduced, except that, to the extent permitted by available funds,
            each State agency shall receive at least $75,000 or the amount that
            the State agency received for the most recent prior fiscal year in
            which the State participated, if that amount is less than $75,000.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Expansion of participating State agencies and establishment of new
              State agencies.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any FMNP funds remaining for allocation after meeting the
            requirements of paragraph (b) of this section shall be allocated in
            the following manner:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Of the remaining funds, 75 percent shall be made available to State
            agencies already participating in the FMNP that wish to serve
            additional recipients. If this amount is greater than that necessary
            to satisfy all State plans approved for additional recipients, the
            unallocated amount shall be applied toward satisfying any unmet need
            in paragraph (d)(2) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Of the remaining funds, 25 percent shall be made available to State
            agencies that have not participated in the FMNP in any prior fiscal
            year. If this amount is greater than that necessary to satisfy the
            approved State Plans for new States, the unallocated amount shall be
            applied toward satisfying any unmet need in paragraph (d)(1) of this
            section. The Department reserves the right not to fund every State
            agency with an approved State Plan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In any fiscal year, any FMNP funds that remain unallocated after
            satisfying the requirements of paragraphs (d)(1) and (d)(2) of this
            section, shall be reallocated in accordance with paragraph (k) of
            this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Expansion for current State agencies.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In providing funds to State agencies that participated in the FMNP
            in the previous fiscal year, the Department shall consider on a
            case-by-case basis, the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whether the State agency utilized at least 80 percent of its prior
            year food grant. States that did not spend at least 80 percent of
            their prior year food grant may still be eligible for expansion
            funding if, in the judgment of the Department, good cause existed
            which was beyond the management control of the State, such as severe
            weather conditions, or unanticipated decreases in participant
            caseload in the WIC Program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Documentation supporting the funds expansion request as outlined in
            
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='248' sect='4' psec='#a_19' tq='N'>
                248.4(a)(19)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Funding of new State agencies.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Funds will be awarded to new State agencies in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='248' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
                248.5
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Administrative funding.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A State agency shall have available for administrative costs an
            amount not greater than 17 percent of total FMNP funds. The 17
            percent administrative cost limitation shall not apply to any funds
            that a State agency may contribute in excess of its minimum matching
            requirement. A State agency may use any non-Federal contributions in
            excess of the 30 percent (or the negotiated percentage for those
            Indian State agencies that received a lower amount) matching
            requirement for food and/or administrative costs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Market development.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A State agency shall be permitted to use not more than 2 percent of
            total program funds for market development or technical assistance
            to farmers&apos; markets if the Secretary determines that the State
            intends to promote the development of farmers&apos; markets in
            socially or economically disadvantaged areas, or remote rural areas,
            where individuals eligible for participation in the program have
            limited access to locally grown fruits and vegetables.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Transfer of funds.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A State agency may use not more than 5 percent of the Federal FMNP
            funds made available for the fiscal year to reimburse expenses
            incurred by the FMNP during a preceding fiscal year. The State
            agency shall provide such justification for its request to spend
            back funds under this paragraph as FNS may require.
            <PRTPAGE P='497' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Recovery of unused funds.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State agencies shall return to FNS any unexpended funds made
            available for a fiscal year by February 1 of the following fiscal
            year.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Reallocation of funds.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any funds recovered under paragraphs (d)(3) and (j) of this section
            will be reallocated in accordance with the appropriate method
            determined by FNS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            59 FR 11517
          </aref>
          , Mar. 11, 1994, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            60 FR 49747
          </aref>
          , Sept. 27, 1995; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            60 FR 57148
          </aref>
          , Nov. 14, 1995; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            64 FR 48076
          </aref>
          , Sept. 2, 1999; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            73 FR 65251
          </aref>
          , Nov. 3, 2008]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4757'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:A:248:E:248.15
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        248.15
      </num>
      <head>
        Closeout procedures.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='248' sect='15' psec='' tq='N'>
              248.15
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Closeout procedures.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State agencies shall submit to FNS a final closeout report for the
            fiscal year on a form prescribed by FNS on a date specified by FNS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Grant closeout procedures.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When grants to State agencies are terminated, the following
            procedures shall be performed in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3016' tq='N'>
                3016
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS may disqualify a State agency&apos;s participation under the
            FMNP, in whole or in part, or take such remedies as may be
            appropriate, whenever FNS determines that the State agency failed to
            comply with the conditions prescribed in this part, in its
            Federal-State Agreement, or in FNS guidelines and instructions. FNS
            will promptly notify the State agency in writing of the
            disqualification together with the effective date.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS may disqualify the State agency or restrict its participation
            in the FMNP when both parties agree that continuation under the FMNP
            would not produce beneficial results commensurate with the further
            expenditure of funds.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon termination of a grant, the affected agency shall not incur
            new obligations after the effective date of the disqualification,
            and shall cancel as many outstanding obligations as possible. FNS
            will allow full credit to the State agency for the Federal share of
            the noncancellable obligations properly incurred by the State agency
            prior to disqualification, and the State agency shall do the same
            for farmers/farmers&apos; markets.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A grant closeout shall not affect the retention period for, or
            Federal rights of access to, FMNP records as specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='248' sect='24' psec='#b' tq='N'>
                248.24(b) and (c)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . The closeout of a grant does not affect the responsibilities of
            the State agency regarding property or with respect to any FMNP
            income for which the State agency is still accountable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A final audit is not a required part of the grant closeout and
            should not be needed unless there are problems with the grant that
            require attention. If FNS considers a final audit to be necessary,
            it shall so inform OIG. OIG will be responsible for ensuring that
            necessary final audits are performed and for any necessary
            coordination with other Federal cognizant audit agencies or State or
            local auditors. Audits performed in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='248' sect='18' psec='' tq='N'>
                248.18
              </subref>
            </aref>
             may serve as final audits providing such audits meet the needs of
            requesting agencies. If the grant is closed out without an audit,
            FNS reserves the right to disallow and recover an appropriate amount
            after fully considering any recommended disallowances resulting from
            an audit which may be conducted later.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4758'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:A:248:E:248.16
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        248.16
      </num>
      <head>
        Administrative appeal of State agency decisions.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          59 FR 11517
        </aref>
        , Mar. 11, 1994, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          60 FR 49748
        </aref>
        , Sept. 27, 1995; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          60 FR 57148
        </aref>
        , Nov. 14, 1995]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='248' sect='16' psec='' tq='N'>
              248.16
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Administrative appeal of State agency decisions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Requirements.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall provide a hearing procedure whereby
            recipients, local agencies and farmers/farmers&apos; markets
            adversely affected by certain actions of the State agency may appeal
            those actions. A recipient may appeal disqualification/suspension of
            FMNP benefits. A local agency may appeal an action of the State
            agency disqualifying it from participating in the FMNP. A
            farmer/farmers&apos; market may appeal an action of the State agency
            denying its application to participate, imposing a sanction, or
            disqualifying it from participating in the FMNP. Expiration of a
            contract or agreement shall not be subject to appeal.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Postponement pending decision.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An adverse action may, at the State agency&apos;s option, be
            postponed until a decision in the appeal is rendered.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In a case where an adverse action affects a local agency or
            farmer/farmers&apos; market, a postponement is appropriate where the
            State agency finds 
            <PRTPAGE P='498' />
            that recipients would be unduly inconvenienced by the adverse
            action. In addition, the State agency may determine other relevant
            criteria to be considered in deciding whether or not to postpone an
            adverse action.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In a case where a recipient appeals the termination of benefits,
            that recipient shall continue to receive FMNP benefits until the
            hearing official reaches a decision or the expiration of the current
            FMNP season, whichever occurs first. Applicants who are denied
            benefits may appeal the denial, but shall not receive benefits while
            awaiting the decision.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Procedure.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency hearing procedure shall at a minimum provide the
            recipient, local agency or farmer/farmers&apos; market with the
            following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Written notification of the adverse action, the cause(s) for the
            action, and the effective date of the action, including the State
            agency&apos;s determination of whether the action shall be postponed
            under paragraph (b) of this section if it is appealed, and the
            opportunity for a hearing. Such notification shall be provided
            within a reasonable timeframe established by the State agency and in
            advance of the effective date of the action.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The opportunity to appeal the action within the time specified by
            the State agency in its notification of adverse action.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Adequate advance notice of the time and place of the hearing to
            provide all parties involved sufficient time to prepare for the
            hearing.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The opportunity to present its case and at least one opportunity to
            reschedule the hearing date upon specific request. The State agency
            may set standards on how many hearing dates can be scheduled,
            provided that a minimum of two hearing dates is allowed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The opportunity to confront and cross-examine adverse witnesses.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The opportunity to be represented by counsel, or in the case of a
            recipient appeal, by a representative designated by the recipient,
            if desired.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The opportunity to review the case record prior to the hearing.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An impartial decision maker, whose decision as to the validity of
            the State agency&apos;s action shall rest solely on the evidence
            presented at the hearing and the statutory and regulatory provisions
            governing the FMNP. The basis for the decision shall be stated in
            writing, although it need not amount to a full opinion or contain
            formal findings of fact and conclusions of law.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Written notification of the decision in the appeal, within 60 days
            from the date of receipt of the request for a hearing by the State
            agency.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Continuing responsibilities.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Appealing an adverse action does not relieve a farmer/farmers&apos;
            market or local agency permitted to continue in the FMNP while its
            appeal is pending, from responsibility for continued compliance with
            the terms of the written agreement or contract with the State
            agency.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Judicial review.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a State level decision is rendered against the recipient, local
            agency or farmer/farmers&apos; market and the appellant expresses an
            interest in pursuing a further review of the decision, the State
            agency shall explain any further State level review of the decision
            and any available State level rehearing process. If neither is
            available or both have been exhausted, the State agency shall
            explain the right to pursue judicial review of the decision.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Additional appeals procedures for State agencies which authorize
              farmers&apos; markets and not individual farmers.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A State agency which authorizes farmers&apos; markets and not
            individual farmers shall ensure that procedures are in place to be
            used when a farmer seeks to appeal an action of a farmers&apos;
            market or association denying the farmer&apos;s application to
            participate, or sanctioning or disqualifying the farmer. The
            procedures shall be set forth in the State Plan and in the
            agreements entered by the State agency and the farmers&apos; market
            and the farmers&apos; market and the farmer.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            59 FR 11517
          </aref>
          , Mar. 11, 1994, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            60 FR 49748
          </aref>
          , Sept. 27, 1995; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            60 FR 57148
          </aref>
          , Nov. 14, 1995]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4759'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:A:248:F:248.17
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        248.17
      </num>
      <head>
        Management evaluations and reviews.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          59 FR 11517
        </aref>
        , Mar. 11, 1994, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          60 FR 49748
        </aref>
        , Sept. 27, 1995; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          73 FR 65251
        </aref>
        , Nov. 3, 2008]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='248' sect='17' psec='' tq='N'>
              248.17
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Management evaluations and reviews.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS and each State agency shall establish a management evaluation
            system in order to assess the accomplishment of FMNP objectives as
            provided under these regulations, the State Plan, and the written
            agreement with the Department. FNS will provide assistance to State
            agencies in discharging this responsibility, and will establish
            standards and procedures to determine how well the objectives of
            this part are being accomplished, and implement sanction procedures
            as warranted by State FMNP performance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Responsibilities of FNS.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS shall establish evaluation procedures to determine whether
            State agencies carry out the purposes and provisions of this part,
            the State Plan, and the written agreement with the Department. As a
            part of the evaluation procedure, FNS shall review audits to ensure
            that the FMNP has been included in audit examinations at a
            reasonable frequency. These evaluations shall also include reviews
            of selected local agencies, and on-site reviews of selected farmers,
            farmers&apos; markets and roadside stands. These evaluations will
            measure the State agency&apos;s progress toward meeting the
            objectives outlined in its State Plan and the State agency&apos;s
            compliance with these regulations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If FNS determines that the State agency has failed, without good
            cause, to demonstrate efficient and effective administration of its
            FMNP or has failed to comply with the requirements contained in this
            section or the State Plan, FNS may withhold an amount up to 100
            percent of the State agency&apos;s administrative grant.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Sanctions imposed upon a State agency by FNS in accordance with
            this section (but not claims for repayment assessed against a State
            agency) may be appealed in accordance with the procedures
            established in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='248' sect='20' psec='' tq='N'>
                248.20
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . Before carrying out any sanction against a State agency, the
            following procedures will be followed:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS will notify the chief departmental officer of the administering
            agency in writing of the deficiencies found and of FNS&apos;
            intention to withhold administrative funds unless an acceptable
            corrective action plan is submitted by the State agency to FNS
            within 45 days after mailing of notification.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall develop a corrective action plan, including
            timeframes for implementation to address the deficiencies and
            prevent their future recurrence.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the corrective action plan is acceptable, FNS will notify the
            chief departmental officer of the administering agency in writing
            within 30 days of receipt of the plan. The letter will advise the
            State agency of the sanctions to be imposed if the corrective action
            plan is not implemented according to the schedule set forth in the
            approved plan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon notification from the State agency that corrective action has
            been taken, FNS will assess such action, and if necessary, perform a
            follow-up review to determine if the noted deficiencies have been
            corrected. FNS will then advise the State agency of whether the
            actions taken are in compliance with the corrective action plan, and
            whether the deficiency is resolved or further corrective action is
            needed. Compliance buys can be required if, during FNS management
            evaluations by regional offices, a State agency is found to be out
            of compliance with its responsibility to monitor and review farmers,
            farmers&apos; markets and roadside stands.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If an acceptable corrective action plan is not submitted within 45
            days, or if corrective action is not completed according to the
            schedule established in the corrective action plan, FNS may withhold
            the award of FMNP administrative funds. If the 45-day warning period
            ends in the fourth quarter of a fiscal year, FNS may elect not to
            withhold funds until the next fiscal year. FNS will notify the chief
            departmental officer of the administering State agency.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If compliance is achieved before the end of the fiscal year in
            which the FMNP administrative funds are withheld, the funds withheld
            may be restored to the State agency. FNS is not 
            <PRTPAGE P='500' />
            required to restore funds withheld beyond the end of the fiscal year
            for which the funds were initially awarded.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Responsibilities of State agencies.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency is responsible for meeting the following
            requirements:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall establish evaluation and review procedures
            and document the results of such procedures. The procedures shall
            include, but are not limited to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Annual monitoring reviews of participating farmers, farmers&apos;
            markets and roadside stands, including on-site reviews of a minimum
            of 10 percent of farmers, 10 percent of farmers&apos; markets, and
            10 percent of roadside stands, which includes those farmers,
            farmers&apos; markets, and roadside stands identified as being the
            highest risk. First year of operation in the FMNP shall be
            considered a high-risk indicator. More frequent reviews may be
            performed as the State agency deems necessary.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Conducting monitoring reviews of all local agencies within the
            State agency&apos;s jurisdiction at least once every 2 years.
            Monitoring of local agencies shall encompass, but not be limited to,
            evaluation of management, accountability, certification, nutrition
            education, financial management systems, and coupon management
            systems. WIC State agency reviews of local agencies conducted for
            the WIC Program may contribute to meeting the FMNP requirement that
            all local agencies be reviewed once every two years if the reviews
            include reviews of FMNP practices. When the WIC State agency
            conducts a review of the local agency outside of the FMNP season, a
            review of documents and procedural plans of the FMNP, rather than
            actual FMNP activities, is acceptable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Instituting the necessary follow-up procedures to correct
            identified problem areas.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             On its own initiative or when required by FNS, the State agency
            shall provide special reports on FMNP activities, and take positive
            action to correct deficiencies in FMNP operations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            59 FR 11517
          </aref>
          , Mar. 11, 1994, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            60 FR 49748
          </aref>
          , Sept. 27, 1995; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            73 FR 65251
          </aref>
          , Nov. 3, 2008]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4760'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:A:248:F:248.18
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        248.18
      </num>
      <head>
        Audits.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='248' sect='18' psec='' tq='N'>
              248.18
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Audits.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Federal access to information.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Secretary, the Comptroller General of the United States, or any
            of their duly authorized representatives, or duly authorized State
            auditors shall have access to any books, documents, papers, and
            records of the State agency and their contractors, for the purpose
            of making surveys, audits, examinations, excerpts, and transcripts.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              State agency response.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency may take exception to particular audit findings
            and recommendations. The State agency shall submit a response or
            statement to FNS as to the action taken or planned regarding the
            findings. A proposed corrective action plan developed and submitted
            by the State agency shall include specific time frames for its
            implementation and for completion of the correction of deficiencies
            and problems leading to the deficiencies.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Corrective action.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS shall determine whether FMNP deficiencies identified in an
            audit have been adequately corrected. If additional corrective
            action is necessary, FNS shall schedule a follow-up review, allowing
            a reasonable time for such corrective action to be taken.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              State sponsored audits.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State and local agencies shall conduct independent audits in
            accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3015' tq='N'>
                3015
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='3016' sect='26' psec='' tq='N'>
                3016.26
              </subref>
            </aref>
             or 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='3051' tq='N'>
                3051
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , as applicable. A State or local agency may elect to obtain either
            an organization-wide audit or an audit of the Program if it
            qualifies to make such an election under applicable regulations.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4761'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:A:248:F:248.19
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        248.19
      </num>
      <head>
        Investigations.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='248' sect='19' psec='' tq='N'>
              248.19
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Investigations.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Authority.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Department may make an investigation of any allegation of
            noncompliance with this part and FNS guidelines and instructions.
            The investigation may include, where appropriate, a review of
            pertinent practices and policies of any State and local agency, the
            circumstances under which the possible noncompliance with this part
            occurred, and other factors relevant to a determination as to
            whether the State and local agency has failed to comply with the
            requirements of this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Confidentiality.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No State or local agency, recipient, or other person shall 
            <PRTPAGE P='501' />
            intimidate, threaten, coerce, or discriminate against any individual
            for the purpose of interfering with any right or privilege under
            this part because that person has made a complaint or formal
            allegation, or has testified, assisted, or participated in any
            manner in an investigation, proceeding, or hearing under this part.
            The identity of every complainant shall be kept confidential except
            to the extent necessary to carry out the purposes of this part,
            including the conducting of any investigation, hearing, or judicial
            proceeding.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4762'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:A:248:G:248.20
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        248.20
      </num>
      <head>
        Claims and penalties.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='248' sect='20' psec='' tq='N'>
              248.20
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Claims and penalties.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Claims against State agencies.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If FNS determines through a review of the State agency&apos;s
            reports, program or financial analysis, monitoring, audit, or
            otherwise, that any FMNP funds provided to a State agency for food
            or administrative purposes were, through State agency negligence or
            fraud, misused or otherwise diverted from FMNP purposes, a formal
            claim will be assessed by FNS against the State agency. The State
            agency shall pay promptly to FNS a sum equal to the amount of the
            administrative funds or the value of coupons so misused or diverted.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If FNS determines that any part of the FMNP funds received by a
            State agency; or coupons, were lost as a result of theft,
            embezzlement, or unexplained causes, the State agency shall, on
            demand by FNS, pay to FNS a sum equal to the amount of the money or
            the value of the FMNP coupons so lost.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall have full opportunity to submit evidence,
            explanation or information concerning alleged instances of
            noncompliance or diversion before a final determination is made in
            such cases.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS is authorized to establish claims against a State agency for
            unreconciled FMNP coupons. When a State agency can demonstrate that
            all reasonable management efforts have been devoted to
            reconciliation and 99 percent or more of the FMNP coupons issued
            have been accounted for by the reconciliation process, FNS may
            determine that the reconciliation process has been completed to
            satisfaction.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Interest charge on claims against State agencies.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If an agreement cannot be reached with the State agency for payment
            of its debts or for offset of debts on its current Letter of Credit
            within 30 days from the date of the first demand letter from FNS,
            FNS will assess an interest (late) charge against the State agency.
            Interest accrual shall begin on the 31st day after the date of the
            first demand letter, bill or claim, and shall be computed monthly on
            any unpaid balance as long as the debt exists. From a source other
            than the FMNP, the State agency shall provide the funds necessary to
            maintain FMNP operations at the grant level authorized by FNS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Penalties.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In accordance with 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 12(g) of
            </aref>
             the National School Lunch Act, whoever embezzles, willfully
            misapplies, steals or obtains by fraud any funds, assets or property
            provided under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 17 of
            </aref>
             the Child Nutrition Act of 1966, as amended, whether received
            directly or indirectly from USDA, or whoever receives, conceals or
            retains such funds, assets or property for his or her own interest,
            knowing such funds, assets or property have been embezzled,
            willfully misapplied, stolen, or obtained by fraud shall, if such
            funds, assets or property are of the value of $100 or more, be fined
            not more than $10,000 or imprisoned not more than five years, or
            both, or if such funds, assets or property are of a value of less
            than $100, shall be fined not more than $1,000 or imprisoned for not
            more than one year, or both.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4763'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:A:248:G:248.21
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        248.21
      </num>
      <head>
        Procurement and property management.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='248' sect='21' psec='' tq='N'>
              248.21
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Procurement and property management.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Requirements.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State agencies shall comply with the requirements of 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3016' tq='N'>
                3016
              </subref>
            </aref>
             for procurement of supplies, equipment and other services with FMNP
            funds. These requirements are adopted by FNS to ensure that such
            materials and services are obtained for the FMNP in an effective
            manner and in compliance with the provisions of applicable law and
            executive orders.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Contractual responsibilities.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The standards contained in 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3016' tq='N'>
                3016
              </subref>
            </aref>
             do not relieve the State agency of the 
            <PRTPAGE P='502' />
            responsibilities arising under its contracts. The State agency is
            the responsible authority, without recourse to FNS, regarding the
            settlement and satisfaction of all contractual and administrative
            issues arising out of procurements entered into in connection with
            the FMNP. This includes, but is not limited to, disputes, claims,
            protests of award, source evaluation, or other matters of a
            contractual nature. Matters concerning violation of law are to be
            referred to such local, State or Federal authority as may have
            proper jurisdiction.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              State regulations.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency may use its own procurement regulations which
            reflect applicable State and local regulations, provided that
            procurements made with FMNP funds adhere to the standards set forth
            in 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3016' tq='N'>
                3016
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Property acquired with program funds.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State and local agencies shall observe the standards prescribed in 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3016' tq='N'>
                3016
              </subref>
            </aref>
             in their utilization and disposition of real property and equipment
            acquired in whole or in part with FMNP funds.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4764'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:A:248:G:248.22
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        248.22
      </num>
      <head>
        Nonprocurement debarment/suspension, drug-free workplace, and lobbying
        restrictions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='248' sect='22' psec='' tq='N'>
              248.22
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Nonprocurement debarment/suspension, drug-free workplace, and lobbying
          restrictions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The State agency shall ensure compliance with the requirements of the
          Department&apos;s regulations governing nonprocurement
          debarment/suspension (
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR part 
            <subref title='7' part='3017' tq='N'>
              3017
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ), drug-free workplace (
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR part 
            <subref title='7' part='3017' tq='N'>
              3017
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ), and the Department&apos;s regulations governing restrictions on
          lobbying (
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR part 
            <subref title='7' part='3018' tq='N'>
              3018
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ), where applicable.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4765'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:A:248:G:248.23
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        248.23
      </num>
      <head>
        Records and reports.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='248' sect='23' psec='' tq='N'>
              248.23
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Records and reports.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Recordkeeping requirements.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each State agency shall maintain full and complete records
            concerning FMNP operations. Such records shall comply with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3016' tq='N'>
                3016
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and the following requirements:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Records shall include, but not be limited to, information
            pertaining to financial operations, FMNP coupon issuance and
            redemption, equipment purchases and inventory, nutrition education,
            and civil rights procedures.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All records shall be retained for a minimum of 3 years following
            the date of submission of the final expenditure report for the
            period to which the report pertains. If any litigation, claim,
            negotiation, audit or other action involving the records has been
            started before the end of the 3-year period, the records shall be
            kept until all issues are resolved, or until the end of the regular
            3-year period, whichever is later. If FNS deems any of the FMNP
            records to be of historical interest, it may require the State
            agency to forward such records to FNS whenever the State agency is
            disposing of them.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Records for nonexpendable property acquired in whole or in part
            with FMNP funds shall be retained for three years after its final
            disposition.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All records shall be available during normal business hours for
            representatives of the Department of the Comptroller General of the
            United States to inspect, audit, and copy. Any reports resulting
            from such examinations shall not divulge names of individuals.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Financial and recipient reports.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State agencies shall submit financial and FMNP performance data on
            a yearly basis as specified by FNS and required by 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 17(m)(8) of
            </aref>
             the CNA. Such information shall include, but shall not be limited
            to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Number and type of recipients (Federal and non-Federal).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Value of coupons issued.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Value of coupons redeemed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Source documentation.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be acceptable for audit purposes, all financial and FMNP
            performance reports shall be traceable to source documentation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Certification of reports.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Financial and FMNP reports shall be certified as to their
            completeness and accuracy by the person given that responsibility by
            the State agency.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Use of reports.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS will use State agency reports to measure progress in achieving
            objectives set forth in the State Plan, and this part, or other
            State agency performance plans. If it is determined, through review
            of State agency reports, FMNP or financial analysis, or an audit,
            that a State agency is not meeting the objectives set forth in its
            State Plan, FNS may request additional information including, but
            not limited to, reasons for failure to achieve these objectives.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4766'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:A:248:G:248.24
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        248.24
      </num>
      <head>
        Other provisions.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          59 FR 11517
        </aref>
        , Mar. 11, 1994, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          76 FR 37983
        </aref>
        , June 29, 2011]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='503' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='248' sect='24' psec='' tq='N'>
              248.24
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Other provisions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              No aid reduction.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The value of benefits or assistance available under the FMNP shall
            not be considered as income or resources of recipients or their
            families for any purpose under Federal, State, or local laws,
            including, but not limited to, laws relating to taxation, welfare
            and public assistance programs. 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              Section 17(m)(7)(B) of
            </aref>
             the CNA provides that any programs for which a grant is received
            under this subsection shall be supplementary to the food stamp
            program carried out under the Food Stamp Act of 1977 as amended (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='2011' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/2011.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 2011
              </subref>
            </aref>
             et seq.) and to any other Federal or State program under which
            foods are distributed to needy families in lieu of food stamps.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Statistical information.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS reserves the right to use information obtained under the FMNP
            in a summary, statistical or other form which does not identify
            particular individuals.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Confidentiality.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall restrict the use or disclosure of
            information obtained from FMNP applicants and recipients to persons
            directly connected with the administration or enforcement of the WIC
            Program or the FMNP, including persons investigating or prosecuting
            violations in the WIC Program or FMNP under Federal, State or local
            authority.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Program evaluations.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State and local FMNP agencies and contractors must cooperate in
            studies and evaluations conducted by or on behalf of the Department,
            related to programs authorized under the Richard B. Russell National
            School Lunch Act and the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='42' sect='1786' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/42/1786.html'>
                42 U.S.C. 1786
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            59 FR 11517
          </aref>
          , Mar. 11, 1994, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 37983
          </aref>
          , June 29, 2011]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4767'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:A:248:G:248.25
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        248.25
      </num>
      <head>
        FMNP information.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          59 FR 11517
        </aref>
        , Mar. 11, 1994, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          60 FR 49748
        </aref>
        , Sept. 27, 1995; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          60 FR 57148
        </aref>
        , Nov. 14, 1995; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          73 FR 65251
        </aref>
        , Nov. 3, 2008]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='248' sect='25' psec='' tq='N'>
              248.25
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          FMNP information.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Any person who wishes information, assistance, records or other public
          material shall request such information from the State agency, or from
          the FNS Regional Office serving the appropriate State as listed below:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Connecticut, Maine, Massachusetts, New Hampshire, New York, Rhode
            Island, Vermont: U.S. Department of Agriculture, FNS, Northeast
            Region, 10 Causeway Street, Room 501, Boston, Massachusetts
            02222-1066.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Delaware, District of Columbia, Maryland, New Jersey, Pennsylvania,
            Puerto Rico, Virginia, Virgin Islands, West Virginia: U.S.
            Department of Agriculture, FNS, Mid-Atlantic Region, Mercer
            Corporate Park, 300 Corporate Boulevard, Robbinsville, New Jersey,
            08691-1598.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Alabama, Florida, Georgia, Kentucky, Mississippi, North Carolina,
            South Carolina, Tennessee: U.S. Department of Agriculture, FNS,
            Southeast Region, 61 Forsyth Street, SW., Room 8T36, Atlanta,
            Georgia 30303.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Illinois, Indiana, Michigan, Minnesota, Ohio, Wisconsin: U.S.
            Department of Agriculture, FNS, Midwest Region, 77 West Jackson
            Boulevard—20th floor, Chicago, Illinois 60604-3507.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Arkansas, Louisiana, New Mexico, Oklahoma, Texas: U.S. Department
            of Agriculture, FNS, Southwest Region, 1100 Commerce Street, room
            5-C-30, Dallas, Texas 75242.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Colorado, Iowa, Kansas, Missouri, Montana, Nebraska, North Dakota,
            South Dakota, Utah, Wyoming: U.S. Department of Agriculture, FNS,
            Mountain Plains Region, 1244 Speer Boulevard, suite 903, Denver,
            Colorado 80204.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Alaska, American Samoa, Arizona, California, Guam, Hawaii, Idaho,
            Nevada, Oregon, Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, the Northern
            Mariana Islands, Washington: U.S. Department of Agriculture, FNS,
            Western Region, 90 Seventh Street, Suite #10-100, San Francisco,
            California 94103.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            59 FR 11517
          </aref>
          , Mar. 11, 1994, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            60 FR 49748
          </aref>
          , Sept. 27, 1995; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            60 FR 57148
          </aref>
          , Nov. 14, 1995; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            73 FR 65251
          </aref>
          , Nov. 3, 2008]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4768'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:A:248:G:248.26
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        248.26
      </num>
      <head>
        OMB control number.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          60 FR 49748
        </aref>
        , Sept. 27, 1995]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='248' sect='26' psec='' tq='N'>
              248.26
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          OMB control number.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The collecting of information requirements for 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='248' tq='N'>
              248
            </subref>
          </aref>
           have been approved by the Office of Management and Budget and
          assigned OMB control number 0584-0477.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            60 FR 49748
          </aref>
          , Sept. 27, 1995]
          <PRTPAGE P='504' />
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>