<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol4'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:C:282
    </extid>
    <num>
      282
    </num>
    <head>
      DEMONSTRATION, RESEARCH, AND EVALUATION PROJECTS
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='2011-203' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/2011-203.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 2011-203
            </subref>
          </aref>
          6.
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          Amdt. 134, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            43 FR 54215
          </aref>
          , Nov. 21, 1978, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='5008'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:C:282:-:282.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        282.1
      </num>
      <head>
        Legislative authority and notice requirements.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [Amdt. 371, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          61 FR 60012
        </aref>
        , Nov. 26, 1996]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='282' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              282.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Legislative authority and notice requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Legislative authority.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              Section 17 of
            </aref>
             the Act authorizes the Secretary to conduct demonstration,
            research, and evaluation projects. In conducting such projects, the
            Secretary may waive all or part of the requirements of the Act and
            implementing regulations necessary to conduct such projects, except
            that no project, other than a project involving the payment of the
            average value of allotments by household size in the form of cash to
            eligible households or a project conducted to test improved
            consistency or coordination between the food stamp employment and
            training program and the Job Opportunities and Basic Skills program
            under Title IV of the Social Security Act, may be undertaken which
            would lower or further restrict the established income and resource
            standards or benefit levels.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Notices.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             At least 30 days prior to the initiation of a demonstration
            project, FNS shall publish a General Notice in the 
            <E T='04'>
              Federal Register
            </E>
             if the demonstration project will likely have a significant impact
            on the public. The notice shall set forth the specific operational
            procedures and shall explain the basis and purpose of the
            demonstration project. If significant comments are received in
            response to this General Notice, the Department will take such
            action as may be appropriate prior to implementing the project. If
            the operational procedures contained in the General Notice described
            above are significantly changed because of comments, an amended
            General Notice will be published in the 
            <E T='04'>
              Federal Register
            </E>
             at least 30 days prior to the initiation of the demonstration
            project, except where good cause exists supporting a shorter
            effective date. The explanation for the determination of good cause
            will be published with the amended General Notice. The amended
            General Notice will also explain the basis and purpose of the
            change.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [Amdt. 371, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            61 FR 60012
          </aref>
          , Nov. 26, 1996]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5009'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:C:282:-:282.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        282.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Funding.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [Amdt. 371, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          61 FR 60012
        </aref>
        , Nov. 26, 1996]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='282' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              282.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Funding.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Federal financial participation may be made available to
          demonstration, research, and evaluation projects awarded by FNS
          through grants and contracts. Funds may not be transferred from one
          project to another. FNS will pay all costs incurred during the
          project, up to the level established in the grant, or in the terms and
          conditions of the contract. FNS may grant time extensions of the
          project upon approval. Funding for additional costs is subject to
          existing Federal grant and contract procedures.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [Amdt. 371, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            61 FR 60012
          </aref>
          , Nov. 26, 1996]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>