<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol7'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:B:714
    </extid>
    <num>
      714
    </num>
    <head>
      REFUNDS OF PENALTIES ERRONEOUSLY, ILLEGALLY, OR WRONGFULLY COLLECTED
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            Secs. 372, 375, 52
          </aref>
           Stat. 65, as amended, 66, as amended; 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='1372' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1372.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 1372
            </subref>
            , 
            <subref title='7' sect='1375' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1375.html'>
              1375
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            35 FR 12098
          </aref>
          , July 29, 1970, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='6556'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:B:714:-:714.35
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        714.35
      </num>
      <head>
        Basis, purpose, and applicability.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='714' sect='35' psec='' tq='N'>
              714.35
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Basis, purpose, and applicability.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Basis and purpose.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The regulations set forth in this part are issued pursuant to the
            Agricultural Adjustment Act of 1938, as amended, for the purpose of
            prescribing the provisions governing refunds of marketing quota
            penalties erroneously, illegally, or wrongfully collected with
            respect to all commodities subject to marketing quotas under the
            Act.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Applicability.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This part shall apply to claims submitted for refunds of marketing
            quota penalties erroneously, illegally, or wrongfully collected on
            all commodities subject to marketing quotas under the Act. It shall
            not apply to the refund of penalties which are deposited in a
            special deposit account pursuant to 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              sections 314(b), 346(b), 356(b), or 359 of
            </aref>
             the Agricultural Adjustment Act of 1938, as amended, or paragraph
            (3) of Pub. L. 74, 77th Congress, available for the refund of
            penalties initially collected which are subsequently adjusted
            downward by action of the county committee, review committee, or
            appropriate court, until such penalties have been deposited in the
            general fund of the Treasury of the United States after
            determination that no downward adjustment in the amount of penalty
            is warranted. All prior regulations dealing with refunds of
            penalties which were contained in this part are superseded upon the
            effective date of the regulations in this part.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6557'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:B:714:-:714.36
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        714.36
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='714' sect='36' psec='' tq='N'>
              714.36
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General terms.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In determining the meaning of the provisions of this part, unless
            the context indicates otherwise, words imparting the singular
            include and apply to several persons or things, words imparting the
            plural include the singular, words imparting the masculine gender
            include the feminine as well, and words used in the present tense
            include the future as well as the present. The definitions in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='719' tq='N'>
                719 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
             shall apply to this part. The provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='720' tq='N'>
                720 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
             concerning the expiration of time limitations shall apply to this
            part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Other terms applicable to this part.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The following terms shall have the following meanings:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             “Act” means the Agricultural Adjustment Act of 1938, and any
            amendments or supplements thereto.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             “Claim” means a written request for refund of penalty.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             “Claimant” means a person who makes a claim for refund of penalty
            as provided in this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             “County Office” means the office of the Agricultural Stabilization
            and Conservation County Committee.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             “Penalty” means an amount of money collected, including setoff,
            from or on account of any person with respect to any commodity to
            which this part is applicable, which has been covered into the
            general fund of the Treasury of the United States, as provided in 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 372(b) of
            </aref>
             the Act.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             “State office” means the office of the Agricultural Stabilization
            and Conservation State Committee.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6558'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:B:714:-:714.37
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        714.37
      </num>
      <head>
        Instructions and forms.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='714' sect='37' psec='' tq='N'>
              714.37
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Instructions and forms.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The Deputy Administrator shall cause to be prepared and issued such 
          <PRTPAGE P='25' />
          instructions and forms as are necessary for carrying out the
          regulations in the part.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6559'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:B:714:-:714.38
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        714.38
      </num>
      <head>
        Who may claim refund.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='714' sect='38' psec='' tq='N'>
              714.38
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Who may claim refund.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Claim for refund may be made by:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any person who was entitled to share in the price or consideration
            received by the producer with respect to the marketing of a
            commodity from which a deduction was made for the penalty and bore
            the burden of such deduction in whole or in part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any person who was entitled to share in the commodity or the
            proceeds thereof, paid the penalty thereon in whole or in part and
            has not been reimbursed therefor.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any person who was entitled to share in the commodity or the
            proceeds thereof and bore the burden of the penalty because he has
            reimbursed the person who paid such penalty.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any person who, as buyer, paid the penalty in whole or in part in
            connection with the purchase of a commodity, was not required to
            collect or pay such penalty, did not deduct the amount of such
            penalty from the price paid the producer, and has not been
            reimbursed therefor.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any person who paid the penalty in whole or in part as a surety on
            a bond given to secure the payment of penalties and has not been
            reimbursed therefor.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any person who paid the whole or any part of the sum paid as a
            penalty with respect to a commodity included in a transaction which
            in fact was not a marketing of such commodity and has not been
            reimbursed therefor.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6560'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:B:714:-:714.39
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        714.39
      </num>
      <head>
        Manner of filing.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='714' sect='39' psec='' tq='N'>
              714.39
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Manner of filing.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Claim for refund shall be filed in the county office on a form
          prescribed by the Deputy Administrator. If more than one person is
          entitled to file a claim, a joint claim may be filed by all such
          persons. If a separate claim is filed by a person who is a party to a
          joint claim, such separate claim shall not be approved until the
          interest of each person involved in the joint claim has been
          determined.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6561'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:B:714:-:714.40
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        714.40
      </num>
      <head>
        Time of filing.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='714' sect='40' psec='' tq='N'>
              714.40
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Time of filing.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Claim shall be filed within 2 years after the date payment was made to
          the Secretary. The date payment was made shall be deemed to be the
          date such payment was deposited in the general fund of the Treasury as
          shown on the certificate of deposit on which such payment was
          scheduled.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6562'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:B:714:-:714.41
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        714.41
      </num>
      <head>
        Statement of claim.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='714' sect='41' psec='' tq='N'>
              714.41
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Statement of claim.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The claim shall show fully the facts constituting the basis of the
          claim; the name and address of and the amount claimed by every person
          who bore or bears any part or all of the burden of such penalty; and
          the reasons why such penalty is claimed to have been erroneously,
          illegally, or wrongfully collected. It shall be the responsibility of
          the county committee to determine that any person who executes a claim
          as agent or fiduciary is properly authorized to act in such capacity.
          There should be attached to the claim all pertinent documents with
          respect to the claim or duly authenticated copies thereof.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6563'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:B:714:-:714.42
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        714.42
      </num>
      <head>
        Designation of trustee.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='714' sect='42' psec='' tq='N'>
              714.42
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Designation of trustee.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Where there is more than one claimant and all the claimants desire to
          appoint a trustee to receive and disburse any payment to be made to
          them with respect to the claim, they shall be permitted to appoint a
          trustee. The person designated as trustee shall execute the
          declaration of trust.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6564'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:B:714:-:714.43
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        714.43
      </num>
      <head>
        Recommendation by county committee.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='714' sect='43' psec='' tq='N'>
              714.43
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Recommendation by county committee.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Immediately upon receipt of a claim, the date of receipt shall be
          recorded on the face thereof. The county committee shall determine, on
          the basis of all available information, if the data and
          representations on the claim are correct. The county committee shall
          recommend approval or disapproval of the claim, and attach a statement
          to the claim, signed by a member of the committee, giving the reasons
          for their action. After the recommendation of approval or disapproval
          is made by the county committee, the claim shall be promptly sent to
          the State committee.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6565'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:B:714:-:714.44
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        714.44
      </num>
      <head>
        Recommendation by State committee.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='714' sect='44' psec='' tq='N'>
              714.44
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Recommendation by State committee.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          A representative of the State committee shall review each claim
          referred by the county committee. If a claim is 
          <PRTPAGE P='26' />
          sent initially to the State committee, it shall be referred to the
          appropriate county committee for recommendation as provided in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='714' sect='43' psec='' tq='N'>
              714.43
            </subref>
          </aref>
           prior to action being taken by the State committee. Any necessary
          investigation shall be made. The State committee shall recommend
          approval or disapproval of the claim, attaching a statement giving the
          reasons for their action, which shall be signed by a representative of
          the State committee. After recommending approval or disapproval, the
          claim shall be promptly sent to the Deputy Administrator.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6566'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:B:714:-:714.45
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        714.45
      </num>
      <head>
        Approval by Deputy Administrator.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='714' sect='45' psec='' tq='N'>
              714.45
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Approval by Deputy Administrator.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The Deputy Administrator shall review each claim forwarded to him by
          the State committee to determine whether, (a) the penalty was
          erroneously, illegally, or wrongfully collected, (b) the claimant bore
          the burden of the payment of the penalty, (c) the claim was timely
          filed, and (d) under the applicable law and regulations the claimant
          is entitled to a refund. If a claim is filed initially with the Deputy
          Administrator, he shall obtain the recommendations of the county
          committee and the State committee if he deems such action necessary in
          arriving at a proper determination of the claim. The claimant shall be
          advised in writing of the action taken by the Deputy Administrator. If
          disapproved, the claimant shall be notified with an explanation of the
          reasons for such disapproval.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6567'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:B:714:-:714.46
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        714.46
      </num>
      <head>
        Certification for payment.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='714' sect='46' psec='' tq='N'>
              714.46
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Certification for payment.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          An officer or employee of the Department of Agriculture authorized to
          certify public vouchers for payment shall, for and on behalf of the
          Secretary of Agriculture, certify to the Secretary of the Treasury of
          the United States for payment all claims for refund which have been
          approved.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>