<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol4'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:C:278
    </extid>
    <num>
      278
    </num>
    <head>
      PARTICIPATION OF RETAIL FOOD STORES, WHOLESALE FOOD CONCERNS AND INSURED
      FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='2011-203' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/2011-203.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 2011-203
            </subref>
          </aref>
          6.
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <EDNOTE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Editorial Note:
        </HD>
        <P>
          OMB control numbers relating to this 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='278' tq='N'>
              278
            </subref>
          </aref>
           are contained in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='271' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              271.8
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </EDNOTE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='4979'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:C:278:-:278.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        278.1
      </num>
      <head>
        Approval of retail food stores and wholesale food concerns.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [Amdt. 136, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          43 FR 43274
        </aref>
        , Sept. 22, 1978]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='278' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              278.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Approval of retail food stores and wholesale food concerns.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Application.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any firm desiring to participate or continue to be authorized in
            the program shall file an application as prescribed by FNS. Such an
            application shall contain information which will permit a
            determination to be made as to whether such an applicant qualifies,
            or continues to qualify, for authorization under the provisions of
            the program. FNS may require that a retail food store or wholesale
            food concern be visited to confirm eligibility for program
            participation prior to such store or concern being authorized or
            reauthorized in the program. Required visits shall be conducted by
            an authorized employee of the Department, a designee of the
            Secretary, or an official of the State or local government
            designated by the Secretary. FNS shall approve or deny the
            application within 45 days of receipt of a completed application. A
            completed application means that all information (other than an
            on-site visit) that FNS deems necessary in order to make a
            determination on the firm&apos;s application has been received. This
            information includes, but is not limited to, a completed application
            form, all information and documentation from the applicant, as well
            as any needed third-party verification and documentation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Determination of authorization.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An applicant shall provide sufficient data and information on the
            nature and scope of the firm&apos;s business for FNS to determine
            whether the applicant&apos;s participation will further the purposes
            of the program. Upon request, an applicant shall provide
            documentation to FNS to verify information on the application. Such
            information may include, but is not limited to, State and local
            business licenses, Social Security cards, drivers&apos; licenses,
            photographic identification cards, bills of sale, deeds, leases,
            sales contracts, State certificates of incorporation, sales records,
            invoice records and business-related tax records. Retail food stores
            and wholesale food concerns and other entities eligible for
            authorization also shall be required to sign a release form which
            will authorize FNS to verify all relevant business related tax
            filings with appropriate agencies. In addition, they must obtain
            corroborating documentation from other sources as deemed necessary
            to ensure the legitimacy of applicant firms, as well as the accuracy
            of information provided by the stores and concerns. Failure to
            comply with any request for information or failure to sign a written
            release form shall result in denial of the application for
            authorization or withdrawal of a firm or concern from the program.
            In determining whether a firm qualifies for authorization, FNS shall
            consider all of the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              The nature and extent of the food business conducted by the
              applicant—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Retail food store.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_1_i_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='3'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An establishment 
            <PRTPAGE P='1003' />
            or house-to-house trade route shall normally be considered to have
            food business of a nature and extent that will effectuate the
            purposes of the program if it sells food for home preparation and
            consumption and meets one of the following criteria: Offer for sale,
            on a continuous basis, a variety of qualifying foods in each of the
            four categories of staple foods as defined in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='271' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
                271.2
              </subref>
               of this chapter
            </aref>
            , including perishable foods in at least two of the categories
            (Criterion A); or have more than 50 percent of the total gross
            retail sales of the establishment or route in staple foods
            (Criterion B).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_1_i_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A retail food store must meet eligibility determination factors
            which may be based on, but not limited to, visual inspection, sales
            records, purchase records, counting of stockkeeping units, or other
            inventory or accounting recordkeeping methods that are customary or
            reasonable in the retail food industry. In determining eligibility,
            such information may be requested for verification purposes, and
            failure to provide such documentation may result in denial or
            withdrawal from the program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Application of Criterion A.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In order to qualify under this criterion, firms shall:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_1_ii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Offer for sale and normally display in a public area, qualifying
            staple food items on a continuous basis, evidenced by having, on any
            given day of operation, no fewer than three different varieties of
            food items in each of the four staple food categories. Documentation
            to determine if a firm stocks a sufficient amount of required staple
            foods to offer them for sale on a continuous basis may be required
            in cases where it is not clear that the requirement has been met.
            Such documentation can be achieved through store visits and/or
            verifying information when requested. Failure to provide verifying
            information when requested or to cooperate with store visits shall
            result in the denial or withdrawal of authorization.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_1_ii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Offer for sale perishable staple food items in at least two staple
            food categories. Perishable foods are items which are either frozen
            staple food items or fresh, unrefrigerated or refrigerated staple
            food items that will spoil or suffer significant deterioration in
            quality within 2-3 weeks; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_1_ii_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Offer a variety of staple foods which means different types of
            foods, such as apples, cabbage, tomatoes, and squash in the fruit or
            vegetable staple food category, or milk, cheese, butter and yogurt
            in the dairy category. Variety of foods is not to be interpreted as
            different brands, different nutrient values, different varieties of
            packaging, or different package sizes. Similar processed food items
            with varying ingredients such as, but not limited to, sausages,
            breakfast cereals, milk, sliced breads, and cheeses, and similar
            unprocessed food items, such as, but not limited to, different
            varieties of apples, cabbage, tomatoes, or squash shall not each be
            considered as more than one staple food variety for the purpose of
            determining variety. Multiple ingredient food items intended for
            home preparation and consumption, such as, but not limited to, cold
            pizza, macaroni and cheese, soup, or frozen dinners, shall only be
            counted as one staple food variety each and will normally be
            included in the staple food category of the main ingredient as
            determined by the FNS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Application of Criterion B.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In order to qualify under this criterion, firms must have more than
            50 percent of their total gross retail sales in staple food sales.
            Total gross retail sales must include all retail sales of a firm,
            including food and non-food merchandise, as well as services, such
            as rental fees, professional fees, and entertainment/sports/games
            income. However, a fee directly connected to the processing of
            staple foods, such as raw meat, poultry, or fish by the service
            provider, may be calculated as staple food sales under Criterion B.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Ineligible firms.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Firms that do not meet the eligibility requirements in this section
            or that do not effectuate the purpose of the Food Stamp Program
            shall not be eligible for program participation. New applicant firms
            that are found to be ineligible will be denied authorization to
            participate in the program, and authorized retail food stores found
            to be ineligible will be withdrawn from program participation.
            Ineligible firms under this paragraph include, but are not limited
            to, stores 
            <PRTPAGE P='1004' />
            selling only accessory foods, including spices, candy, soft drinks,
            tea, or coffee; ice cream vendors selling solely ice cream; and
            specialty doughnut shops or bakeries not selling bread. In addition,
            firms that are considered to be restaurants, that is, firms that
            have more than 50 percent of their total gross retail sales in hot
            and/or cold prepared foods not intended for home preparation and
            consumption, shall not qualify for participation as retail food
            stores under Criterion A or B. This includes firms that primarily
            sell prepared foods that are consumed on the premises or sold for
            carryout. Such firms may qualify, however, under the special
            restaurant programs that serve the elderly, disabled, and homeless
            populations, as set forth in paragraph (d) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_1_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Wholesale food concerns.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Wholesale food concerns, the primary business of which is the sale
            of eligible food at wholesale, and which meet the staple food
            requirements in paragraph (b) of this section, shall normally be
            considered to have adequate food business for the purposes of the
            program, provided such concerns meet the criteria specified in
            paragraph (c) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_1_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Co-located wholesale food concerns.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No co-located wholesale/retail food concern with 50 percent or less
            of its total sales in retail food sales may be authorized to redeem
            food stamps unless it meets the criteria applicable to all retail
            firms and:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_1_vi_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             It is a legitimate retail food outlet. Indicators which may
            establish to FNS that a firm is a legitimate retail food outlet
            include, but are not limited to, the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          (
          <E T='03'>
            1
          </E>
          ) The firm&apos;s marketing structure; as may be determined by factors
          such as, but not limited to:
        </P>
        <P>
          (
          <E T='03'>
            i
          </E>
          ) A retail business license;
        </P>
        <P>
          (
          <E T='03'>
            ii
          </E>
          ) The existence of sales tax records documenting retail food sales;
          and/or separate bookkeeping records; and
        </P>
        <P>
          (
          <E T='03'>
            2
          </E>
          ) The way the firm holds itself out to the public as evidenced by
          factors such as, but not limited to:
        </P>
        <P>
          (
          <E T='03'>
            i
          </E>
          ) The layout of the retail sales space;
        </P>
        <P>
          (
          <E T='03'>
            ii
          </E>
          ) The use of retail advertisements;
        </P>
        <P>
          (
          <E T='03'>
            iii
          </E>
          ) The posting of retail prices;
        </P>
        <P>
          (
          <E T='03'>
            iv
          </E>
          ) Offering specials to attract retail customers;
        </P>
        <P>
          (
          <E T='03'>
            v
          </E>
          ) Hours of operation for retail business;
        </P>
        <P>
          (
          <E T='03'>
            vi
          </E>
          ) Parking area for retail customers; and
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_1_vi_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             It has total annual retail food sales of at least $250,000; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_1_vi_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             It is a legitimate retail outlet but fails to meet the requirements
            in paragraph (b)(1)(iv)(B) of this section, and not authorizing such
            a firm would cause hardship to food stamp households. Hardship would
            occur in any one of the following circumstances:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          (
          <E T='03'>
            1
          </E>
          ) Program recipients would have difficulty in finding authorized firms
          to accept their coupons for eligible food;
        </P>
        <P>
          (
          <E T='03'>
            2
          </E>
          ) Special ethnic foods would not otherwise be available to recipients;
          or
        </P>
        <P>
          (
          <E T='03'>
            3
          </E>
          ) Recipients would be deprived of an opportunity to take advantage of
          unusually low prices offered by the firm if no other authorized firm
          in the area offers the same types of food items at comparable prices.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              The volume of coupon business which FNS may reasonably expect the
              firm to do.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The FNS officer in charge may consider such factors as the location
            of a store and previous food sales volumes in evaluating the ability
            of an applicant firm to attract food stamp business.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              The business integrity and reputation of the applicant.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS shall deny the authorization of any firm from participation in
            the program for a period of time as specified in paragraph (k) of
            this section based on consideration of information regarding the
            business integrity and reputation of the firm as follows:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Conviction of or civil judgment against the owners, officers or
            managers of the firm for:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_3_vi_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Commission of fraud or a criminal offense in connection with
            obtaining, attempting to obtain, or performing a public or private
            agreement or transaction;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_3_vi_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Commission of embezzlement, theft, forgery, bribery, falsification
            or destruction of records, making false statements, receiving stolen
            property, making false claims, or obstruction of justice; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_3_vi_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Violation of Federal, State and/or local consumer protection laws
            or other laws relating to alcohol, tobacco, 
            <PRTPAGE P='1005' />
            firearms, controlled substances, and/or gaming licenses;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Administrative findings by Federal, State or local officials that
            do not give rise to a conviction or civil judgment but for which a
            firm is removed from such a program, or the firm is not removed from
            the program but FNS determines a pattern exists (3 or more
            instances) evidencing a lack of business integrity on the part of
            the owners, officers or managers of the firm;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Evidence of an attempt by the firm to circumvent a period of
            disqualification, a civil money penalty or fine imposed for
            violations of the Food Stamp Act and program regulations;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_3_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Previous Food Stamp Program violations administratively and/or
            judicially established as having been committed by owners, officers,
            or managers of the firm for which a sanction had not been previously
            imposed and satisfied;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_3_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Evidence of prior Food Stamp Program violations personally
            committed by the owner(s) or the officer(s) of the firm at one or
            more units of a multi-unit firm, or evidence of prior Food Stamp
            Program violations committed by management at other units of
            multi-unit firms which would indicate a lack of business integrity
            on the part of ownership and for which sanctions had not been
            previously imposed and satisfied; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_3_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Commission of any other offense indicating a lack of business
            integrity or business honesty of owners, officers or managers of the
            firm that seriously and directly affects the present responsibility
            of a person.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
            <head>
              The submission of collateral bonds or irrevocable letters of
              credit for firms with previous sanctions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the applicant firm has been sanctioned for violations of this
            part, by withdrawal, or disqualification for a period of more than
            six months, or by a civil money penalty in lieu of a
            disqualification period of more than six months, or if the applicant
            firm has been previously sanctioned for violations and incurs a
            subsequent sanction, regardless of the disqualification period, FNS
            shall, as a condition of future authorization, require the applicant
            to present a collateral bond or irrevocable letter of credit that
            meets the following conditions:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_4_vi_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The collateral bond must be issued by a bonding agent/company
            recognized under the law of the State in which the applicant is
            conducting business and which is represented by a negotiable
            certificate only. The irrevocable letter of credit must be issued by
            a commercial bank;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_4_vi_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The collateral bond or irrevocable letter of credit must be made
            payable to the Food and Nutrition Service, U.S. Department of
            Agriculture;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_4_vi_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The collateral bond cannot be canceled by the bonding agent/company
            for non-payment of the premium by the applicant. The irrevocable
            letter of credit cannot be canceled by the commercial bank for
            non-payment by the applicant;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_4_vi_D'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (D)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The collateral bond or irrevocable letter of credit must have a
            face value of $1,000 or an amount equal to ten percent of the
            average monthly food stamp benefit redemption volume of the
            applicant for the immediate twelve months prior to the effective
            date of the most recent sanction which necessitated the collateral
            bond or irrevocable letter of credit, whichever amount is greater;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_4_vi_E'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (E)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The applicant is required to submit a collateral bond or
            irrevocable letter of credit that is valid for a period of five
            years when re-entering the program; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_4_vi_F'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (F)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The collateral bond or irrevocable letter of credit shall remain in
            the custody of FNS unless released to the applicant as a result of
            the withdrawal of the applicant&apos;s authorization, without a
            fiscal claim established against the applicant by FNS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_4_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Furnishing a collateral bond or irrevocable letter of credit shall
            not eliminate or reduce a firm&apos;s obligation to pay in full any
            civil money penalty or previously determined fiscal claim which may
            have been assessed against the firm by FNS prior to the time the
            bond or letter of credit was required by FNS, and furnished by the
            firm. A firm which has been assessed a civil money penalty shall pay
            FNS as required, any subsequent fiscal claim asserted by FNS. In
            such cases a collateral bond or irrevocable letter of credit shall
            be furnished to FNS with the payment, or a schedule of intended
            payments, of the 
            <PRTPAGE P='1006' />
            civil money penalty. A buyer or transferee shall not, as result of
            the transfer or purchase of a disqualified firm, be required to
            furnish a bond or letter of credit prior to authorization.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Taxpayer identification numbers.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             At the time of an initial request for authorization as well as
            reauthorization, an applicant firm must provide its employer
            identification number and social security numbers as described
            below:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_5_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Employer Identification Number.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The firm must provide its employer identification number (EIN) if
            one has been assigned to the firm by the Internal Revenue Service.
            The authority to request EINs and the guidelines for requesting EINs
            are set forth in 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 6109(f) of
            </aref>
             the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and Treas. Reg. 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='301' sect='6109-2' psec='' tq='N'>
                301.6109-2
              </subref>
            </aref>
             (
            <aref type='CFR'>
              26 CFR 
              <subref title='26' part='301' sect='6109-2' psec='' tq='N'>
                301.6109-2
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_5_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Social Security Number.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In addition to the EIN, the firm must provide the social security
            numbers (SSNs) of the following individuals:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_5_ii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The SSN of an owner of a sole proprietorship.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_5_ii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The SSNs of general partners of firms which are partnerships.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_5_ii_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The SSNs of up to five of the largest shareholders (owners) of
            privately owned corporations. (For purposes of this section, a
            privately owned corporation is one which has shares or stock that
            are not traded on a stock exchange or available for purchase by the
            general public.)
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Other factors.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any other factors which the FNS officer in charge considers
            pertinent to the application under consideration.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Wholesalers.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A wholesale food concern may be authorized to accept coupons only
            from a specified customer or customers if it meets the requirements
            of paragraphs (a) and (b) of this section, and FNS determines it is
            required as a redemption outlet:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For one or more specified authorized drug addict or alcoholic
            treatment programs,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For one or more specified authorized group living arrangements,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For one or more specified authorized shelters for battered women
            and children,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For one or more specified authorized nonprofit cooperative
            food-purchasing ventures,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For one or more specified authorized public or private nonprofit
            homeless meal providers, or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For one or more specified authorized retail food stores which are
            without access to an insured financial institution which will redeem
            their coupons.
          </text>
        </P>
        <FP>
          No firm may be authorized to accept and redeem coupons concurrently as
          both a retail food store and a wholesale food concern. Authorizations
          of wholesale food concerns granted prior to January 28, 1982 shall
          expire on May 31, 1982. Wholesale food concerns desiring to
          participate in the program after that date must reapply for
          authorization in accordance with the provisions of this paragraph.
        </FP>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Meal services.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A meal delivery service or communal dining facility desiring to
            prepare and serve meals to households eligible to use coupons for
            those meals in addition to meeting the requirements of paragraphs
            (a) and (b) of this section, must establish that:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             It is recognized as a tax exempt organization by the Internal
            Revenue Service; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             It is a senior citizens&apos; center or apartment building occupied
            primarily by elderly persons and SSI recipients, and their spouses;
            or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             It is a restaurant operating under a contract with a State or local
            agency to prepare and serve (or deliver) low-cost meals to homeless
            persons, elderly persons and SSI recipients (and in the case of meal
            delivery services, to elderly persons or handicapped persons) and
            their spouses. Such a facility must have more than 50 percent of its
            total sales in food. The contracts of restaurants must specify the
            approximate prices which will be charged.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Treatment programs.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Drug addict or alcoholic treatment and rehabilitation programs
            wishing to redeem benefits shall in addition to meeting the
            requirements of paragraphs (a), (b) and (d)(1) of this section, be
            under Part B of Title XIX of the Public Health Service Act (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='42' sect='300x' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/42/300x.html'>
                42 U.S.C. 300x
              </subref>
            </aref>
             et seq.). Approval to participate is automatically withdrawn once
            the treatment and rehabilitation program no longer meets the
            criteria which would make it eligible for funding under part B of
            Title XIX (in accordance with the definition in 
            <E T='03'>
              Drug 
              <PRTPAGE P='1007' />
              addiction or alcoholic treatment and rehabilitation program
            </E>
             in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='271' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
                271.2
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Group living arrangements.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS shall authorize as retail food stores those group living
            arrangements wishing to redeem benefits. The group living
            arrangement must, in addition to meeting requirements of paragraphs
            (a), (b), and (d)(1) of this section, be certified by the
            appropriate agency or agencies of the State under regulations issued
            under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 1616(e) of
            </aref>
             the Social Security Act or under standards determined by the
            Secretary to be comparable to standards implemented by appropriate
            State agencies under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 1616(e) of
            </aref>
             the Social Security Act. Approval to participate is automatically
            cancelled at any time that a program loses its certification from
            the State agency or agencies.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Shelters for battered women and children.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS shall authorize as retail food stores those shelters for
            battered women and children wishing to redeem benefits. The shelter
            must be public or private nonprofit, as defined in paragraph (d)(1)
            of this section, and meet the requirements of paragraphs (a) and (b)
            of this section. Shelters which also serve other groups of
            individuals must have a portion of the facility set aside on a
            long-term basis to shelter battered women and children. Also
            required is that the shelter be a residence which serves meals or
            provides food to its residents.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
            <head>
              House-to-house trade routes.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS shall, in consultation with the Department&apos;s Office of
            Inspector General, determine those locations where the operation of
            trade routes damages the program&apos;s integrity. FNS may limit the
            authorization of house-to-house trade routes to those trade routes
            whose services are required by participating households in such
            areas in order to obtain food. The FNS Officer in Charge, in
            deciding whether households in such areas require a trade
            route&apos;s services, shall consider the volume of food business
            the trade route does and the availability of alternate sources of
            comparable food. An FNS official shall inspect any applicant trade
            route&apos;s vehicle to ensure that the trade route is a retail food
            store before authorizing it to accept coupons. An FNS official may
            require, as a condition of continuing authorization, that the trade
            route vehicle be reinspected semiannually to ensure that it
            continues to be a retail food store.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Private homeless meal providers.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS may authorize as retail food stores those restaurants which
            contract with the appropriate State agency to serve meals to
            homeless persons at “concessional” (low or reduced) prices.
            Restaurants shall be responsible for obtaining contracts with the
            appropriate State agency as defined in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='272' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
                272.9
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and for providing a copy of the contract to FNS at the time it
            applies for authorization to accept food stamp benefits. Contracts
            must specify the approximate prices which will be charged. Examples
            of reduced prices include, but are not limited to, a percentage
            reduction, a set dollar amount reduction, a daily special meal, or
            an offer of a free food item or beverage (excluding alcoholic
            beverages).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Authorization.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon approval, FNS shall issue a nontransferable authorization card
            to the firm. The authorization card shall be valid only for the time
            period for which the firm is authorized to accept and redeem food
            stamp benefits. The authorization card shall be retained by the firm
            until such time as the authorization period has ended, authorization
            in the program is superseded, or the card is surrendered or revoked
            as provided in this part. All firms will be authorized in the
            program for a period of 5 years. The specification of an
            authorization period in no way precludes FNS from periodically
            requesting information from a firm for purposes of reauthorization
            in the program or from withdrawing or terminating the authorization
            of a firm in accordance with this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Denying authorization.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS shall deny the application of any firm if it determines that:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='k_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The firm does not qualify for participation in the program as
            specified in paragraph (b), (c), (d), (e), (f), (g), (h) or (i) of
            this section; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='k_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The firm has failed to meet the eligibility requirements for
            authorization under Criterion A or Criterion B, as specified in
            paragraph (b)(1)(i) of this section; or, for co-located
            wholesale/retail firms, the firm fails to meet the requirements of
            paragraph (b)(1)(vi) 
            <PRTPAGE P='1008' />
            of this section. Any firm that has been denied authorization on
            these bases shall not be eligible to submit a new application for
            authorization in the program for a minimum period of six months from
            the effective date of the denial;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='k_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The firm has been found to lack the necessary business integrity
            and reputation to further the purposes of the program. Such firms
            shall be denied authorization in the program for the following
            period of time:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='k_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Firms for which records of criminal conviction or civil judgment
            exist that reflect on the business integrity of owners, officers, or
            managers as stipulated in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='1' psec='#b_3_i' tq='N'>
                278.1(b)(3)(i)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             shall be denied authorization permanently;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='k_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Firms which have been officially removed from other Federal, State
            or local government programs through administrative action shall be
            denied for a period equivalent to the period of removal from any
            such programs; or, if the firm is not removed from the program, but
            FNS determines a pattern (3 or more instances) exists evidencing a
            lack of business integrity on the part of the owners, officers or
            managers of the firm, such firm shall be denied for a one year
            period effective from the date of denial;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='k_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Firms for which evidence exists of an attempt to circumvent a
            period of disqualification, a civil money penalty, or fine imposed
            for violations of the Food Stamp Act of 1977, as amended, and
            program regulations shall be denied for a period of three years from
            the effective date of denial;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='k_3_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Firms for which evidence exists of prior Food Stamp Program
            violations by owners, officers, or managers of the firm for which a
            sanction had not been previously imposed and satisfied shall be
            denied for a period of time equivalent to the appropriate
            disqualification period for such previous violations, effective from
            the date of denial;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='k_3_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Firms for which evidence exists of prior Food Stamp Program
            violations at other units of multi-unit firms as specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='1' psec='#b_3_v' tq='N'>
                278.1(b)(3)(v)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             for which a sanction had not been previously imposed and satisfied
            shall be denied for a period of time equivalent to the appropriate
            disqualification period for such previous violations, effective from
            the date of denial;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='k_3_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Firms for which any other evidence exists which reflects negatively
            on the business integrity or business honesty of the owners,
            officers or managers of the firm as specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='1' psec='#b_3_vi' tq='N'>
                278.1(b)(3)(vi)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             shall be denied for a period of one year from the effective date of
            denial;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='k_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The firm has filed an application that contains false or misleading
            information about a substantive matter, as specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='6' psec='#e' tq='N'>
                278.6(e)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . Such firms shall be denied authorization for the periods specified
            in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='6' psec='#e_1' tq='N'>
                278.6(e)(1)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             or 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='6' psec='#e_3' tq='N'>
                278.6(e)(3)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='k_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The firm&apos;s participation in the program will not further the
            purposes of the program;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='k_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The firm has been found to be circumventing a period of
            disqualification or a civil money penalty through a purported
            transfer of ownership;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='k_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The firm has failed to pay in full any fiscal claim assessed
            against the firm under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
                278.7
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , any fines assessed under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='6' psec='#l' tq='N'>
                278.6(l)
              </subref>
               or 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='6' psec='#m' tq='N'>
                278.6(m)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , or a transfer of ownership civil money penalty assessed under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='6' psec='#f' tq='N'>
                278.6(f)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . The FNS officer in charge shall issue a notice to the firm (using
            any delivery method that provides evidence of delivery) to inform
            the firm of any authorization denial and advise the firm that it may
            request review of that determination.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='l'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (l)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Withdrawing authorization.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='l_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS shall withdraw the authorization of any firm authorized to
            participate in the program for any of the following reasons.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='l_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The firm&apos;s continued participation in the program will not
            further the purposes of the program;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='l_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The firm fails to meet the specifications of paragraph (b), (c),
            (d), (e), (f), (g), (h), or (i) of this section;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='l_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The firm fails to meet the requirements for eligibility under
            Criterion A or B, as specified in paragraph (b)(1)(i) of this
            section; or, for co-located wholesale/retail firms, the firm fails
            to meet the requirements of paragraph (b)(1)(vi) of this section,
            for the time period specified in paragraph (k)(2) of this section;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='l_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The firm fails to maintain the necessary business integrity to
            further the purposes of the program, as specified in paragraph
            (b)(3) of this section. 
            <PRTPAGE P='1009' />
            Such firms shall be withdrawn for lack of business integrity for
            periods of time in accordance with those stipulated in paragraph
            (k)(3) of this section for specific business integrity findings;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='l_1_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The firm has failed to pay in full any fiscal claim assessed
            against the firm under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
                278.7
              </subref>
            </aref>
             or any fines assessed under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='6' psec='#l' tq='N'>
                278.6(l)
              </subref>
               or 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='6' psec='#m' tq='N'>
                278.6(m)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             or a transfer of ownership civil money penalty assessed under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='6' psec='#f' tq='N'>
                278.6(f)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='l_1_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The firm has failed to pay fines assessed under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='6' psec='#l' tq='N'>
                278.6(l)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             or 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='6' psec='#m' tq='N'>
                278.6(m)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='l_1_vii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The firm is required under State and/or local law to charge tax on
            eligible food purchased with coupons or to sequence or allocate
            purchases of eligible foods made with coupons and cash in a manner
            inconsistent with 272.1 of these regulations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='l_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The FNS officer in charge shall issue a notice to the firm by using
            any delivery method as long as the method provides evidence of
            delivery to inform the firm of the determination and of the review
            procedure. FNS shall remove the firm from the program if the firm
            does not request review within the period specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='279' tq='N'>
                279
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='m'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (m)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Refusal to accept correspondence or to respond to inquiries.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS may withdraw or deny the authorization of any firm which:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='m_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Refuses to accept correspondence from FNS;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='m_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Fails to respond to inquiries from FNS within a reasonable time; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='m_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Cannot be located by FNS with reasonable effort.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='n'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (n)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Periodic reauthorization.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             At the request of FNS a retail food store or wholesale food concern
            will be required to undergo a periodic reauthorization determination
            by updating any or all of the information on the firm&apos;s
            application form. Failure to cooperate in the reauthorization
            process will result in withdrawal of the firm&apos;s approval to
            participate in the program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='o'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (o)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Applications containing false information.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The filing of any application containing false or misleading
            information may result in the denial of approval for participation
            in the program, as specified in paragraph (k) of this section, or
            disqualification of a firm from participation in the program, as
            specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
                278.6
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , and may subject the firm and persons responsible to civil or
            criminal action.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='p'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (p)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Administrative review.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any withdrawal or denial of authorization to participate in the
            program shall be subject to administrative review under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='279' tq='N'>
                279
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='q'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (q)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Use and disclosure of information provided by firms.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             With the exception of EINs and SSNs, any information collected from
            retail food stores and wholesale food concerns, such as ownership
            information and sales and redemption data, may be disclosed for
            purposes directly connected with the administration and enforcement
            of the Food Stamp Act and these regulations, and can be disclosed to
            and used by State agencies that administer the Special Supplemental
            Nutrition Program for Women, Infants and Children (WIC). Such
            information may also be disclosed to and used by Federal and State
            law enforcement and investigative agencies for the purpose of
            administering or enforcing other Federal or State law, and the
            regulations issued under such other law. Such disclosure and use
            shall also include companies or individuals under contract for the
            operation by, or on behalf of FNS to accomplish an FNS function.
            Such purposes include the audit and examination of such information
            by the Comptroller General of the United States authorized by any
            other provision of law. Any person who publishes, divulges,
            discloses, or makes known in any manner or to any extent not
            authorized by Federal law or regulations any information obtained
            under this paragraph shall be fined not more than $1,000 or
            imprisoned not more than 1 year, or both. Safeguards with respect to
            employee identification numbers (EINs) are contained in paragraph
            (q)(2) of this section. Safeguards with respect to Social Security
            numbers (SSNs) are contained in paragraph (q)(3) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='q_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Criteria for requesting information.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS shall determine what information can be disclosed and which
            government agencies have access to that information based on the
            following criteria:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='q_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Federal and State law enforcement or investigative agencies or
            instrumentalities administering or enforcing specified Federal and
            State 
            <PRTPAGE P='1010' />
            laws, or regulations issued under those laws, have access to certain
            information maintained by FNS. Such agencies or instrumentalities
            must have among their responsibilities the enforcement of law or the
            investigation of suspected violations of law. However, only certain
            Federal entities have access to information involving SSNs and EINs
            in accordance with paragraph (q)(1)(ii) of this section;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='q_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except for SSNs and EINs, information provided to FNS by applicants
            and authorized firms participating in the FSP may be disclosed and
            used by qualifying Federal and State entities in accordance with
            paragraph (q)(1)(i) of this section. The disclosure of SSNs and EINs
            is limited only to qualifying Federal agencies or instrumentalities
            which otherwise have access to SSNs and EINs based on law and
            routine use. Release of information under this paragraph shall be
            limited to information relevant to the administration or enforcement
            of the specified laws and regulations, as determined by FNS;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='q_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Requests for information must be submitted in writing, including
            electronic communication, and must clearly indicate the specific
            provision of law or regulations which would be administered or
            enforced by access to requested information, and the relevance of
            the information to those purposes. If a formal agreement exists
            between FNS and another agency or instrumentality, individual
            written requests may be unnecessary. FNS may request additional
            information if needed to clarify a request;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='q_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Disclosure by FNS is limited to: Information about applicant stores
            and concerns with applications on file; information about authorized
            stores participating in the FSP; and information about unauthorized
            entities or individuals illegally accepting or redeeming food
            stamps;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='q_1_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Requests for information disclosure by FNS may involve a specific
            store or concern, or some or all stores and concerns covered by
            paragraph (q)(1)(iv) of this section. In addition, FNS may sign
            agreements allowing certain government entities direct access to
            appropriate FNS data, with access to EINs and SSNs limited only to
            other Federal agencies and instrumentalities that otherwise have
            access to such numbers.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='q_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Employer identification numbers.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='q_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Department may have access to the EINs obtained pursuant to
            paragraph (b)(5) of this section for the purpose of establishing and
            maintaining a list of the names and EINs of the stores and concerns
            for use in determining those applicants who previously have been
            sanctioned or convicted under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              sections 12 and 15 of
            </aref>
             the Food Stamp Act of 1977, as amended, (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='2021' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/2021.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 2021
              </subref>
               or 
              <subref title='7' sect='2024' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/2024.html'>
                2024
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ). The Department also may share EINs with other Federal agencies
            and instrumentalities that otherwise have access to EINs if the
            Department determines that such sharing would assist in verifying
            and matching such information against information maintained by such
            other agency or instrumentality. Any such information shared
            pursuant to this paragraph may be used by the Department or such
            other agency or instrumentality for the purpose of effective
            administration and enforcement of the Food Stamp Act of 1977, as
            amended, or for the purpose of investigating violations of other
            Federal laws or enforcing such laws. See Treas. Reg. 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='301' sect='6109-2' psec='#b' tq='N'>
                301.6109-2 (b) and (c)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             (
            <aref type='CFR'>
              26 CFR 
              <subref title='26' part='301' sect='6109-2' psec='#b' tq='N'>
                301.6109-2 (b) and (c)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='q_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The only persons permitted access to EINs obtained pursuant to
            paragraph (b) of this section are officers and employees of the
            United States, who otherwise have access and whose duties or
            responsibilities require access to the EINs for the administration
            or enforcement of the Food Stamp Act of 1977, as amended, or for the
            purpose of investigating violations of other Federal laws or
            enforcing such laws. See Treas. Reg. 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='301' sect='6109-2' psec='#d_1' tq='N'>
                301.6109-2(d)(1)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             (
            <aref type='CFR'>
              26 CFR 
              <subref title='26' part='301' sect='6109-2' psec='#d_1' tq='N'>
                301.6109-2(d)(1)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='q_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Department or any agency or instrumentality of the United
            States shall provide for any additional safeguards that the
            Secretary of the Treasury determines to be necessary or appropriate
            to protect the confidentiality of the EINs. The Department may also
            provide for any additional safeguards to protect the confidentiality
            of EINs so long as these safeguards are consistent with any
            safeguards determined by the Secretary of 
            <PRTPAGE P='1011' />
            the Treasury to be necessary or appropriate. See Treas. Reg. 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='301' sect='6109-2' psec='#d_2' tq='N'>
                301.6109-2(d)(2)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             (
            <aref type='CFR'>
              26 CFR 
              <subref title='26' part='301' sect='6109-2' psec='#d_2' tq='N'>
                301.6109-2(d)(2)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='q_2_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             EINs maintained by the Department or maintained by any agency or
            instrumentality of the United States pursuant to 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='1' psec='#b_5' tq='N'>
                278.1(b)(5)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             are confidential. Except as provided in paragraph (q)(2)(ii) of
            this section above, no officer or employee of the United States who
            has or had access to any such EIN may disclose that number in any
            manner. For purposes of paragraph (q)(2)(iv) of this section the
            term 
            <E T='03'>
              officer or employee
            </E>
             includes a former officer or employee. See Treas. Reg. 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='301' sect='6109-2' psec='#e' tq='N'>
                301.6109-2(e)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             (
            <aref type='CFR'>
              26 CFR 
              <subref title='26' part='301' sect='6109' psec='#e' tq='N'>
                301.6109(e)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='q_2_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              Sections 7213(a) (1), (2) and (3) of
            </aref>
             the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 apply with respect to the
            unauthorized, willful disclosure to any person of EINs obtained by
            the Department pursuant to 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='1' psec='#b_5' tq='N'>
                278.1(b)(5)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             in the same manner and to the same extent as 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              sections 7213(a) (1), (2) and (3)
            </aref>
             apply with respect to unauthorized disclosure of returns and return
            information described in those sections. 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              Section 7213(a)(4) of
            </aref>
             the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 applies with respect to the
            willful offer of any item of material value in exchange for any EIN
            obtained by the Department pursuant to 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='1' psec='#b_5' tq='N'>
                278.1(b)(5)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             in the same manner and to the same extent as 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 7213(a)(4)
            </aref>
             applies with respect to offers (in exchange for any return or
            return information) described in that section. See Treas. Reg. 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='301' sect='6109-2' psec='#f' tq='N'>
                301.6109-2(f)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             (
            <aref type='CFR'>
              26 CFR 
              <subref title='26' part='301' sect='6109-2' psec='#f' tq='N'>
                301.6109-2(f)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='q_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Social Security numbers.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='q_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Department may have access to SSNs obtained pursuant to
            paragraph (b)(5) of this section for the purpose of establishing and
            maintaining a list of names and SSNs of stores and concerns for use
            in determining those applicants who previously have been sanctioned
            or convicted under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 12 or 15 of
            </aref>
             the Food Stamp Act of 1977, as amended, (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='2021' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/2021.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 2021
              </subref>
               or 
              <subref title='7' sect='2024' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/2024.html'>
                2024
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ). The Department may use this determination of sanctions and
            convictions in administering 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              sections 12 and 15 of
            </aref>
             the Food Stamp Act of 1977, as amended, (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='2018' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/2018.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 2018
              </subref>
              , 
              <subref title='7' sect='2021' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/2021.html'>
                2021
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ). The Department also may share SSNs with other Federal agencies
            and instrumentalities if the Department determines that such sharing
            would assist in verifying and matching such information against
            information maintained by the Department or such other agency or
            instrumentality. Any such information shared pursuant to this
            paragraph shall be used for the purpose of effective administration
            and enforcement of the Food Stamp Act of 1977, as amended, or for
            the purpose of investigating violations of other Federal laws or
            enforcing such laws.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='q_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The only persons permitted access to SSNs obtained pursuant to
            paragraph (b) of this section are officers and employees of the
            United States, who otherwise have access, and whose duties or
            responsibilities require access to the SSNs for the administration
            or enforcement of the Food Stamp Act of 1977, as amended, or for the
            purpose of investigating violations of other Federal laws or
            enforcing such laws. Such access shall also include companies or
            individuals under contract for the operation by, or on behalf of FNS
            to accomplish an FNS function.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='q_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Department shall provide for all additional safeguards that the
            Commissioner of the Social Security Administration determines to be
            necessary or appropriate to protect the confidentiality of the SSNs.
            The Department may also provide for any additional safeguards to
            protect the confidentiality of SSNs so long as these safeguards are
            consistent with any safeguards determined by the Commissioner of the
            Social Security Administration to be necessary or appropriate.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='q_3_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The SSNs and related records that are obtained or maintained by
            authorized persons are confidential, and no officer or employee
            shall disclose any such SSN or related record except as authorized.
            The term “related record” means any record, list, or compilation
            that indicates, directly or indirectly, the identity of any
            individual with respect to whom a request for a SSN is maintained.
            For purposes of paragraph (r)(3)(iv) of this section the term
            “officer or employee” includes a former officer or employee.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='q_3_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The sanctions under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              sections 7213(a) (1), (2) and (3) of
            </aref>
             the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 will apply with respect to the
            unauthorized, willful disclosure to any person of SSNs and related
            records obtained or maintained in 
            <PRTPAGE P='1012' />
            the same manner and to the same extent as 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              sections 7213(a) (1), (2) and (3)
            </aref>
             apply with respect to unauthorized disclosures of returns and
            return information described in those sections. The sanction under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 7213(a)(4) of
            </aref>
             the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 will apply with respect to the
            willful offer of any item of material value in exchange for any SSN
            or related record in the same manner and to the same extent as 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 7213(a)(4)
            </aref>
             applies with respect to offers (in exchange for any return or
            return information) described in that section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='q_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
            <head>
              FNS initiated matches.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Under the restrictions noted in paragraph (r) of this section, FNS
            will periodically initiate cross matches of retailer data with other
            Federal and State agencies&apos; files for the purpose of verifying
            information provided by applicant and participating firms, and for
            the purposes of administering and enforcing other Federal or State
            laws. Such matches could involve all firms participating after
            implementation for the purpose of verifying information such as, but
            not limited to, SSNs and retail sales data.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='r'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (r)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Public and Private Nonprofit Homeless Meal Providers.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS shall authorize as retail food stores, those public and private
            nonprofit homeless meal providers which apply and qualify for
            authorization to accept food stamps from homless food stamp
            recipients. Such meal providers must be public or private nonprofit
            organizations as defined by the Internal Revenue Service (I.R.C.
            501(c)(3)), must serve meals that include food purchased by the
            provider, must meet the requirements of paragraphs (a) and (b) of
            this section, and must be approved by an appropriate State or local
            agency, pursuant to 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='272' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
                272.9
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . Public and private nonprofit homeless meal providers shall be
            responsible for obtaining approval from an appropriate State or
            local agency and shall provide written documentation of such
            approval to FNS prior to approval of the meal provider&apos;s
            application for authorization. (If such approval is subsequently
            withdrawn, FNS authorization shall be withdrawn). Public and private
            nonprofit homeless meal providers serving meals which consist wholly
            of donated foods shall not be eligible for authorization. In an area
            in which FNS, in consultation with the Department&apos;s Office of
            Inspector General, finds evidence that the authorization of a public
            and private nonprofit homeless meal provider would damage the Food
            Stamp Program&apos;s integrity, FNS shall limit the participation of
            that public and private nonprofit homeless meal provider, unless FNS
            determines that the establishment or shelter is the only one of its
            kind serving the area.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='s'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (s)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each authorized retail food store shall post in a suitable and
            conspicuous location in the store a sign designed and provided by
            FNS which provides information on how persons may report abuses they
            have observed in the operation of the program. Refusal or repeated
            failure to display such a sign by an authorized retail food store
            may result in the withdrawal of the firm&apos;s approval to
            participate in the program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='t'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (t)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Periodic notification.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The FNS will issue periodic notification to participating retail
            stores and wholesale food concerns to clarify program eligibility
            criteria, including the definitions of “Retail food store”, “Staple
            foods”, “Eligible foods”, and “Perishable foods”. At a minimum, such
            information will be provided to stores at the time of authorization,
            reauthorization and upon request.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [Amdt. 136, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            43 FR 43274
          </aref>
          , Sept. 22, 1978]
        </CITA>
        <EDNOTE>
          <HD SOURCE='HED'>
            Editorial Note:
          </HD>
          <P>
            For 
            <E T='04'>
              Federal Register
            </E>
             citations affecting 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
                278.1
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , see the List of CFR Sections Affected, which appears in the
            Finding Aids section of the printed volume and at 
            <E T='03'>
              www.fdsys.gov
            </E>
            .
          </P>
        </EDNOTE>
        <EFFDNOT>
          <HD SOURCE='HED'>
            Effective Date Note:
          </HD>
          <P>
            At 
            <aref type='FREGIST'>
              61 FR 53600
            </aref>
            , Oct. 15, 1996, in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
                278.1
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , paragraph (i) was redesignated as paragraph (j) and a new
            paragraph (i) was added. This paragraph contains information
            collection and recordkeeping requirements and will not become
            effective until approval has been given by the Office of Management
            and Budget.
          </P>
        </EFFDNOT>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4980'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:C:278:-:278.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        278.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Participation of retail food stores.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [Amdt. 136, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          43 FR 43274
        </aref>
        , Sept. 22, 1978, as amended at Amdt. 191, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          46 FR 50277
        </aref>
        , Oct. 9, 1981; Amdt. 205, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          46 FR 60167
        </aref>
        , Dec. 8, 1981; Amdt. 257, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          49 FR 32538
        </aref>
        , Aug. 15, 1984; Amdt. 286, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          52 FR 7557
        </aref>
        , Mar. 11, 1987; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          53 FR 31649
        </aref>
        , Aug. 19, 1988; Amdt. 344, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          56 FR 54778
        </aref>
        , Oct. 23, 1991; Amdt. 356, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          59 FR 29714
        </aref>
        , June 9, 1994; Amdt. 343, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          61 FR 53601
        </aref>
        , Oct. 15, 1996; Amdt. 397, 70 72354, Dec. 5, 2005; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          73 FR 79595
        </aref>
        , Dec. 30, 2008]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='278' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              278.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Participation of retail food stores.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Use of coupons.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Coupons may be accepted by an authorized retail food store only
            from eligible households or the households&apos; authorized
            representative, and only in exchange for eligible food. Coupons may
            not be accepted in exchange for cash, except when cash is 
            <PRTPAGE P='1013' />
            returned as change in a transaction in which coupons were accepted
            in payment for eligible food under pargraph (d) of this section.
            Coupons may not be accepted in payment of interest on loans or for
            any other nonfood use. An authorized retail food store may not
            accept coupons from another retail food store, except that public or
            private nonprofit homeless meal providers may redeem coupons for
            eligible food through authorized retail food stores.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Equal treatment for coupon customers.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Coupons shall be accepted for eligible foods at the same prices and
            on the same terms and conditions applicable to cash purchases of the
            same foods at the same store except that tax shall not be charged on
            eligible foods purchased with coupons. However, nothing in this part
            may be construed as authorizing FNS to specify the prices at which
            retail food stores may sell food. However, public or private
            nonprofit homeless meal providers may only request 
            <E T='03'>
              voluntary
            </E>
             use of food stamps from homeless food stamp recipients and may not
            request such household using food stamps to pay more than the
            average cost of the food 
            <E T='03'>
              purchased
            </E>
             by the public or private nonprofit homeless meal provider contained
            in a meal served to the patrons of the meal service. For purposes of
            this section, “average cost” is determined by averaging food costs
            over a period of up to one calendar month. Voluntary payments by
            food stamp recipients in excess of such costs may be accepted by the
            meal providers. The value of donated foods from any source shall not
            be considered in determining the amount to be requested from food
            stamp recipients. All indirect costs, such as those incurred in the
            acquisition, storage, or preparation of the foods used in meals
            shall also be excluded. In addition, if others have the option of
            eating free or making a monetary donation, food stamp recipients
            must be provided the same option of eating free or making a donation
            in money or food stamps. No retail food store may single out coupon
            users for special treatment in any way.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Accepting coupons.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No authorized retail food store may accept coupons marked “paid,”
            “canceled,” or “specimen.” Nor may a retail food store accept
            coupons bearing any cancellation or endorsement, or coupons of other
            than the 1-dollar denomination which have been detached from the
            coupon books prior to the time of purchase or delivery of eligible
            food unless the detached coupons are accompanied by the coupon books
            which bear the same serial numbers that appear on the detached
            coupons. However, in the case of public or private nonprofit
            homeless meal providers, retail food stores may accept detached
            coupons which have been accepted by the homeless meal provider. It
            is the right of the household member or the authorized
            representative to detach the coupons from the book.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Making change.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An authorized retail food store shall use, for the purpose of
            making change, uncanceled and unmarked 1-dollar coupons which were
            previously accepted for eligible foods. If change in an amount of
            less than 1-dollar is required, the eligible household shall receive
            the change in cash. However, in the case of public or private
            nonprofit homeless meal providers, neither cash change nor credit
            slips shall be provided under any circumstances when food stamps are
            used to purchase meals. At no time may cash change in excess of 99
            cents be returned in a coupon transaction. An authorized retail food
            store may not engage in a series of coupon transactions the purpose
            of which is to provide the same food stamp customer an amount of
            cash change greater than the maximum 99 cents cash change allowed in
            one transaction.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Accepting coupons before delivery.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Food retailers may not accept coupons before delivering the food,
            retain custody of any unspent coupons, or in any way prevent an
            eligible household from using coupons in making purchases from other
            authorized firms. However, a nonprofit cooperative food purchasing
            venture may accept coupons from a member of the cooperative at the
            time the member places a food order. The food ordered must be made
            available to the member within 14 days from the day the cooperative
            receives the member&apos;s coupons.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Paying credit accounts.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Food stamp benefits shall not be accepted by an authorized retail
            food store in payment for items sold to a household on credit. 
            <PRTPAGE P='1014' />
            A firm that commits such violations shall be disqualified from
            participation in the Food Stamp Program for a period of one year.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Redeeming coupons.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Authorized retail food stores may exchange coupons accepted in
            accordance with this part for face value upon presentation through
            the banking system or through a wholesale food concern authorized to
            accept coupons from that retailer. Authorized drug addict or
            alcoholic treatment and rehabilitation programs, group living
            arrangements, and shelters for battered women and children may
            present coupons for redemption through authorized wholesale food
            concerns. A drug addict or alcoholic treatment center, group living
            arrangement, or shelter for battered women and children may purchase
            food in authorized retail food stores as the authorized
            representative of its participating households. Public or private
            nonprofit homeless meal providers may purchase food in authorized
            retail food stores and through authorized wholesale food concerns.
            Authorized drug addict and alcoholic treatment and rehabilitation
            programs, group living arrangements, shelters for battered women and
            children, and public or private nonprofit homeless meal providers
            for homeless food stamp households shall not present coupons
            directly to an insured financial institution for redemption.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notwithstanding paragraph (g)(1) of this section, authorized drug
            addict and alcoholic treatment and rehabilitation programs, group
            living arrangements, shelters for battered women and children, and
            public or private nonprofit homeless meal providers for homeless
            food stamp households may be authorized to redeem EBT benefits
            directly through an insured financial institution in areas where an
            Electronic Benefit Transfer (EBT) system has been implemented.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Identifying coupon users.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Coupons may not knowingly be accepted from persons who have no
            right to possession of coupons. If a food retailer has any cause to
            believe that a person presenting coupons has no right to use the
            coupons, the food retailer should request the person to show the ID
            card of the household to establish the right of that person to use
            the coupons. Where photo ID cards are in use, the person presenting
            the ID card need not be pictured on the card. Public or private
            nonprofit homeless meal providers redeeming detached coupons through
            retail food stores shall present their retailer authorization card
            as proof of their eligibility to redeem coupons through retail food
            stores.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Checking meal delivery service recipients.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A nonprofit meal delivery service shall require the recipient of a
            delivered meal to show the marked ID card establishing the
            recipient&apos;s right to use coupons for that service the first
            time that the recipient offers coupons in payment for the service,
            and shall request the marked ID card at any time the nonprofit meal
            delivery service has cause to question the continued eligibility of
            the recipient to use coupons for delivered meals.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Checking hunting and fishing equipment users.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Authorized Alaskan retailers shall require coupon customers wanting
            to purchase hunting and fishing equipment with coupons to show their
            ID cards to determine that they live in an area designated by FNS as
            one in which persons are dependent upon hunting and fishing for
            subsistence.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Checking participants in restaurants.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A restaurant operating under a State contract shall require a
            household purchasing meals to show the marked ID card establishing
            the household&apos;s right to purchase meals with coupons unless the
            personnel of the restaurant know that the program participant
            tendering coupons is eligible to use coupons to purchase meals.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='l'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (l)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Checking public or private nonprofit homeless meal provider
              recipients.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Public or private nonprofit homeless meal providers shall establish
            a food stamp patron&apos;s right to purchase meals with coupons.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [Amdt. 136, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            43 FR 43274
          </aref>
          , Sept. 22, 1978, as amended at Amdt. 191, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            46 FR 50277
          </aref>
          , Oct. 9, 1981; Amdt. 205, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            46 FR 60167
          </aref>
          , Dec. 8, 1981; Amdt. 257, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            49 FR 32538
          </aref>
          , Aug. 15, 1984; Amdt. 286, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            52 FR 7557
          </aref>
          , Mar. 11, 1987; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            53 FR 31649
          </aref>
          , Aug. 19, 1988; Amdt. 344, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            56 FR 54778
          </aref>
          , Oct. 23, 1991; Amdt. 356, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            59 FR 29714
          </aref>
          , June 9, 1994; Amdt. 343, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            61 FR 53601
          </aref>
          , Oct. 15, 1996; Amdt. 397, 70 72354, Dec. 5, 2005; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            73 FR 79595
          </aref>
          , Dec. 30, 2008]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4981'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:C:278:-:278.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        278.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Participation of wholesale food concerns.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [Amdt. 136, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          43 FR 43274
        </aref>
        , Sept. 22, 1978, as amended by Amdt. 173, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          46 FR 62810
        </aref>
        , Dec. 29, 1981; Amdt. 286, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          52 FR 7558
        </aref>
        , Mar. 11, 1987; Amdt. 344, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          56 FR 54778
        </aref>
        , Oct. 23, 1991; Amdt. 343, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          61 FR 53601
        </aref>
        , Oct. 15, 1996]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='1015' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='278' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              278.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Participation of wholesale food concerns.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Accepting coupons.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An authorized wholesale food concern may accept endorsed coupons
            from one or more specified authorized retail food stores, from one
            or more specified authorized nonprofit cooperative food-purchasing
            ventures, from one or more specified authorized group living
            arrangements, from one or more specified authorized drug addict or
            alcoholic treatment programs, from one or more specified authorized
            shelters for battered women and children, or, from one or more
            specified public or private nonprofit homeless meal providers if the
            coupons are accompanied by a properly filled-out and signed
            redemption certificate, and are not marked “paid,” “canceled,” or
            “specimen.” A wholesaler authorized to accept coupons from an
            authorized drug addict or alcoholic treatment program, or from an
            authorized group living arrangement, or from an authorized shelter
            for battered women and children, or from one or more public or
            private nonprofit homeless meal providers may accept coupons from
            that treatment program, or group living arrangement, or shelter for
            battered women and children, or from one or more public or private
            nonprofit homeless meal providers, only in exchange for food.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Accepting legally obtained coupons.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No authorized wholesale food concern may accept coupons if the
            wholesaler knows or has reasonable cause to believe that the coupons
            were not legally obtained for eligible food.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Redeeming coupons.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An authorized wholesale food concern may redeem coupons, properly
            accepted from retailers, through the banking system, upon
            presentation of the coupons with:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The authorized retail food store&apos;s properly filled-out and
            signed redemption certificate for the coupons; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The authorized wholesale food concern&apos;s properly filled-out
            and signed redemption certificate.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Handling retailer redemption certificates.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No authorized wholesale food concern may alter, prepare, or
            complete an authorized retail food store&apos;s redemption
            certificate.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [Amdt. 136, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            43 FR 43274
          </aref>
          , Sept. 22, 1978, as amended by Amdt. 173, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            46 FR 62810
          </aref>
          , Dec. 29, 1981; Amdt. 286, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            52 FR 7558
          </aref>
          , Mar. 11, 1987; Amdt. 344, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            56 FR 54778
          </aref>
          , Oct. 23, 1991; Amdt. 343, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            61 FR 53601
          </aref>
          , Oct. 15, 1996]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4982'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:C:278:-:278.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        278.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Procedure for redeeming coupons.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [Amdt. 136, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          43 FR 43274
        </aref>
        , Sept. 22, 1978, as amended by Amdt. 286, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          52 FR 7558
        </aref>
        , Mar. 11, 1987; Amdt. 344, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          56 FR 54778
        </aref>
        , Oct. 23, 1991; Amdt. 343, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          61 FR 53601
        </aref>
        , Oct. 15, 1996]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='278' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              278.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Procedure for redeeming coupons.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Coupons accepted without authorization.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Coupons accepted by a retail food store or a wholesale food concern
            before the receipt by the firm of an authorization card from FNS may
            not be presented for redemption unless the FNS officer in charge has
            approved the redemption under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='7' psec='#b' tq='N'>
                278.7(b)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . Burned or mutilated coupons shall be presented for redemption to
            the FNS officer in charge as provided in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='7' psec='#c' tq='N'>
                278.7(c)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Endorsing coupons.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each authorized retail food store or authorized wholesale food
            concern shall mark its authorization number or name on each coupon
            before it presents the coupons for redemption.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Using redemption certificates.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS will provide all authorized firms with redemption certificates.
            Wholesale food concerns and retail food stores, except for drug
            addict and alcoholic treatment and rehabilitation programs and
            public or private nonprofit homeless meal providers, shall use the
            redemption certificates to present coupons to insured financial
            institutions for credit or for cash. All retail food stores which
            wish to redeem coupons at wholesale food concerns shall use the
            redemption certificates for that purpose. An authorized retail firm
            using redemption certificates to redeem coupons shall fill out the
            redemption certificate to show the value of the coupons redeemed,
            the name of the insured financial institution or wholesaler, the
            date, and the signature and title of the official of the firm
            redeeming coupons.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [Amdt. 136, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            43 FR 43274
          </aref>
          , Sept. 22, 1978, as amended by Amdt. 286, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            52 FR 7558
          </aref>
          , Mar. 11, 1987; Amdt. 344, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            56 FR 54778
          </aref>
          , Oct. 23, 1991; Amdt. 343, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            61 FR 53601
          </aref>
          , Oct. 15, 1996]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4983'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:C:278:-:278.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        278.5
      </num>
      <head>
        Participation of insured financial institutions.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [Amdt. 136, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          43 FR 43274
        </aref>
        , Sept. 22, 1978, as amended by Amdt. 257, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          49 FR 32538
        </aref>
        , Aug. 15, 1984; Amdt. 267, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          51 FR 6514
        </aref>
        , Feb. 25, 1986; Amdt. 272, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          51 FR 12498
        </aref>
        , Apr. 11, 1986; Amdt. 288, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          52 FR 11815
        </aref>
        , Apr. 13, 1987; Amdt. 272, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          52 FR 18198
        </aref>
        , May 14, 1987; Amdt. 356, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          59 FR 29714
        </aref>
        , June 9, 1994; Amdt. 331, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          59 FR 60062
        </aref>
        , Nov. 22, 1994]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='278' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              278.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Participation of insured financial institutions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Accepting coupons.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Financial institutions that are insured by the Federal Deposit
            Insurance Corporation 
            <PRTPAGE P='1016' />
            (FDIC) or financial institutions which are insured under the Federal
            Credit Union Act and which have retail food stores or wholesale food
            concerns in their field of membership may redeem coupons only from
            authorized retail food stores, meal services, and wholesale food
            concerns in accordance with the rules contained in this part and
            instructions of the Federal Reserve Banks. No financial institution
            may impose on or collect from a retail food store a fee or other
            charge for redemption of coupons that are submitted to the financial
            institution in a manner consistent with the requirements, except for
            coupon cancellation, for the presentation of coupons by the
            financial institution to the Federal Reserve banks. Coupons
            submitted to insured financial institutions for credit or cash must
            be properly endorsed in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
                278.4
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
             and shall be accompanied by a properly completed and signed
            redemption certificate. All verified and encoded redemption
            certificates accepted by insured financial institutions shall be
            forwarded with the corresponding coupon deposits to the Federal
            Reserve Bank along with the accompanying Food Coupon Deposit
            Document (Form FNS-521). In accordance with Federal Reserve
            requirements, the coupon deposit value entered on the Food Coupon
            Deposit Document must be equal to the actual value of coupons being
            deposited and to the total value of verified amounts encoded on the
            corresponding redemption certificates.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An insured financial institution shall verify the amount of the
            coupons being redeemed and record the amount in the designated space
            on the redemption certificate. In order to conform with Federal
            Reserve requirements, the verified amount shall be recorded in the
            appropriate field on the redemption certificate using Magnetic Ink
            Character Recognition (MICR) encoding. Redemption certificates
            accepted by insured financial institutions shall be forwarded with
            the corresponding coupon deposits to the Federal Reserve Bank along
            with the Food Coupon Deposit Document (Form FNS-521).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Redeemed coupons must be indelibly cancelled on the face of the
            coupon by the first insured financial institution receiving them. If
            the cancellation on the coupon face does not show the depositing
            institution&apos;s name or its routing symbol transit number, this
            identifying information must appear on the straps affixed to each
            bundle of coupons of like denomination. Deposits not meeting these
            cancellation requirements may be returned to the depositing
            institution for reprocessing. Retail food stores may not be required
            to cancel the coupons by the insured financial institution nor may
            the insured financial institution charge the retail food stores a
            fee or other charge for cancellation of coupons. A portion of a
            coupon consisting of less than three-fifths of a whole coupon may
            not be redeemed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Insured financial institutions which are members of the Federal
            Reserve System, insured nonmember clearing institutions, and insured
            nonmember institutions which have arranged with a Federal Reserve
            Bank to deposit coupons for credit to the account of a member
            institution on the books of a Federal Reserve Bank may forward
            coupons directly to the Federal Reserve Bank. Other insured
            financial institutions may forward cancelled coupons through
            ordinary collection channels.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Role of Federal Reserve Banks.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Federal Reserve Banks, acting as fiscal agents of the United
            States, will receive canceled coupons for collection as cash items
            from armed forces installations, member insured financial
            institutions of the Federal Reserve System, nonmember clearing
            insured financial institutions, and nonmember insured financial
            institutions which have arranged with a Federal Reserve Bank to
            deposit coupons for credit to the account of a member insured
            financial institution on the books of the Federal Reserve Bank, and
            will charge those items to the general account of the Treasurer of
            the United States.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              FNS liability for losses.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS shall not be liable for the value of any coupons lost, stolen,
            or destroyed while in the custody of an insured financial
            institution or for the value of coupons lost, stolen, or destroyed
            while in transit from an insured financial institution to a Federal
            Reserve Bank.
            <PRTPAGE P='1017' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              FNS use of coupons to detect violations.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Regardless of any other provision in these regulations, coupons may
            be issued to, purchased by, or redeemed by persons authorized by FNS
            to use those coupons in examining and inspecting program operations,
            and for other purposes determined by FNS to be required for proper
            administration of the program. Coupons which have been so issued and
            used, as well as any coupons which have been issued under paragraph
            (g) of this section, or which FNS believes may have been issued,
            transferred, negotiated, used, or received in violation of this
            subchapter or of any applicable statute, shall at the request of FNS
            and on issuance of a receipt for them be turned over to FNS by the
            insured financial institution receiving the coupons, or by any other
            person to whom the request is addressed, together with any
            certificate(s) of redemption accompanying the coupons. Any coupons
            so requested shall not be eligible for redemption through Federal
            Reserve Banks or other collection channels. However, FNS may redeem
            coupons from any insured financial institution or person by payment
            of the face amount of the coupons upon determination by FNS that
            this direct redemption of coupons is warranted. FNS shall determine
            the proper disposition of any coupons held by FNS on completion of
            the examination or inspection in which the coupons were used. Claims
            or demands for unredeemed coupons surrendered to FNS may be mailed
            to the local FNS field office for the project area involved.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Selling coupons to stores for internal checks.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS may sell coupons at face value to any authorized retail food
            store which wishes to use coupons to conduct internal checks of
            coupon transactions. The retail food store must submit a written
            request to FNS which shall include a certification that the store
            recognizes that its use of coupons will not affect FNS action to
            enforce program regulations and that the requested coupons will be
            used only for internal checks of the store&apos;s employees and only
            to uncover sales of items other than eligible foods. The request
            shall also include the name of the city or county in which the
            stores to be checked through the use of the requested coupons are
            located and the name and address of any outside agency with which
            the retail food store has or will have a contract to conduct checks
            of the store&apos;s employees using coupons. The request shall be
            directed to the Benefit Redemption Division, FSP, FNS, U.S.
            Department of Agriculture, 3101 Park Center Drive, Alexandria, VA
            22302, and shall be accompanied by a check or money order made
            payable to the Food and Nutrition Service to cover the face value
            cost of the coupons requested. Coupons bought by retail food stores
            for use in internal checks may be later redeemed for full value in
            accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
                278.4
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , and in redeeming those coupons, retail food stores are authorized
            to make the certification required for redemption.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Continued participation of households under investigation.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon the written request of Federal, State, or local government
            agencies which have authority to investigate, and are investigating,
            suspected violations of Federal or State statutes concerning the
            enforcement of the Food Stamp Act or the regulations, the State
            agency may allow ineligible households to continue program
            participation. The State agency may allow the households to continue
            participation in the program until the earlier of (1) expiration of
            the period of 90 days after the request is received or any longer
            period which FNS, upon request of the State agency, may approve in a
            particular case, or (2) receipt of notification from the
            investigative agency that participation may be terminated or that
            the investigation has been completed. Regardless of any other
            provision of these regulations, FNS may not hold the State agency
            liable for the value of any coupons issued to households under this
            paragraph.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [Amdt. 136, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            43 FR 43274
          </aref>
          , Sept. 22, 1978, as amended by Amdt. 257, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            49 FR 32538
          </aref>
          , Aug. 15, 1984; Amdt. 267, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            51 FR 6514
          </aref>
          , Feb. 25, 1986; Amdt. 272, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            51 FR 12498
          </aref>
          , Apr. 11, 1986; Amdt. 288, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            52 FR 11815
          </aref>
          , Apr. 13, 1987; Amdt. 272, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            52 FR 18198
          </aref>
          , May 14, 1987; Amdt. 356, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            59 FR 29714
          </aref>
          , June 9, 1994; Amdt. 331, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            59 FR 60062
          </aref>
          , Nov. 22, 1994]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4984'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:C:278:-:278.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        278.6
      </num>
      <head>
        Disqualification of retail food stores and wholesale food concerns, and
        imposition of civil money penalties in lieu of disqualifications.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [Amdt. 136, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          43 FR 43274
        </aref>
        , Sept. 22, 1978]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='1018' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='278' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              278.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Disqualification of retail food stores and wholesale food concerns,
          and imposition of civil money penalties in lieu of disqualifications.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Authority to disqualify or subject to a civil money penalty.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS may disqualify any authorized retail food store or authorized
            wholesale food concern from further participation in the program if
            the firm fails to comply with the Food Stamp Act of 1977, as
            amended, or this part. Such disqualification shall result from a
            finding of a violation on the basis of evidence that may include
            facts established through on-site investigations, inconsistent
            redemption data, evidence obtained through a transaction report
            under an electronic benefit transfer system, or the disqualification
            of a firm from the Special Supplemental Nutrition Program for Women,
            Infants and Children (WIC), as specified in paragraph (e)(8) of this
            section. Disqualification shall be for a period of 6 months to 5
            years for the firm&apos;s first sanction; for period of 12 months to
            10 years for a firm&apos;s second sanction; and disqualification
            shall be permanent for a disqualification based on paragraph (e)(1)
            of this section. Any firm which has been disqualified and which
            wishes to be reinstated at the end of the period of
            disqualification, or at any later time, shall file a new application
            under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
                278.1
              </subref>
            </aref>
             so that FNS may determine whether reauthorization is appropriate.
            The application may be filed no earlier than 10 days before the end
            of the period of disqualification. FNS may, in lieu of a
            disqualification, subject a firm to a civil money penalty of up to
            an amount specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='3' sect='91' psec='#b_3_i' tq='N'>
                3.91(b)(3)(i)
              </subref>
               of this title
            </aref>
             for each violation if FNS determines that a disqualification would
            cause hardship to participating households. FNS may impose a civil
            money penalty of up to an amount specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='3' sect='91' psec='#b_3_ii' tq='N'>
                3.91(b)(3)(ii)
              </subref>
               of this title
            </aref>
             for each violation in lieu of a permanent disqualification for
            trafficking, as defined in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='271' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
                271.2
              </subref>
               of this chapter
            </aref>
            , in accordance with the provisions of paragraphs (i) and (j) of
            this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Charge letter—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General provisions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any firm considered for disqualification or imposition of a civil
            money penalty under paragraph (a) of this section or a fine as
            specified under paragraph (l) or (m) of this section shall have full
            opportunity to submit to FNS information, explanation, or evidence
            concerning any instances of noncompliance before FNS makes a final
            administrative determination. The FNS regional office shall send the
            firm a letter of charges before making such determination. The
            letter shall specify the violations or actions which FNS believes
            constitute a basis for disqualification or imposition of a civil
            money penalty or fine. The letter shall specify the violations or
            actions which FNS believes constitute a basis for disqualification
            or imposition of a civil money penalty. The letter shall inform the
            firm that it may respond either orally or in writing to the charges
            contained in the letter within 10 days of receiving the letter. The
            firm&apos;s response shall set forth a statement of evidence,
            information, or explanation concerning the specified violations or
            acts. The firm shall make its response, if any, to the officer in
            charge of the FNS field office which has responsibility for the
            project area in which the firm is located. In the case of a firm for
            which action is taken in accordance with paragraph (e)(8) of this
            section, the charge letter shall inform such firm that the
            disqualification action is not subject to administrative or judicial
            review, as specified in paragraph (e)(8) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Charge letter for trafficking.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The charge letter shall advise a firm being considered for
            permanent disqualification based on evidence of trafficking as
            defined in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='271' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
                271.2
              </subref>
            </aref>
             that the firm must notify FNS if the firm desires FNS to consider
            the sanction of a civil money penalty in lieu of permanent
            disqualification. The charge letter shall also advise the firm that
            the permanent disqualification shall be effective immediately upon
            the date of receipt of the notice of determination, regardless of
            whether a request for review is filed in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='279' tq='N'>
                279 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . If the disqualification is reversed through administrative or
            judicial review, the Secretary shall not be liable for the value of
            any sales lost during the disqualification period. Firms that
            request and are determined eligible for a civil money penalty in
            lieu of permanent disqualification for trafficking 
            <PRTPAGE P='1019' />
            may continue to participate in the program pending review and shall
            not be required to pay the civil money penalty pending appeal of the
            trafficking determination action.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Firms that request consideration of a civil money penalty in lieu
            of a permanent disqualification for trafficking shall have the
            opportunity to submit to FNS information and evidence as specified
            in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='6' psec='#i' tq='N'>
                278.6(i)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , that establishes the firm&apos;s eligibility for a civil money
            penalty in lieu of a permanent disqualification in accordance with
            the criteria included in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='6' psec='#i' tq='N'>
                278.6(i)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . This information and evidence shall be submitted within 10 days,
            as specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='6' psec='#b_1' tq='N'>
                278.6(b)(1)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a firm fails to request consideration for a civil money penalty
            in lieu of a permanent disqualification for trafficking and submit
            documentation and evidence of its eligibility within the 10 days
            specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='6' psec='#b_1' tq='N'>
                278.6(b)(1)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , the firm shall not be eligible for such a penalty.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Review of evidence.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The letter of charges, the response, and any other information
            available to FNS shall be reviewed and considered by the appropriate
            FNS regional office, which shall then issue the determination. In
            the case of a firm subject to permanent disqualification under
            paragraph (e)(1) of this section, the determination shall inform
            such a firm that action to permanently disqualify the firm shall be
            effective immediately upon the date of receipt of the notice of
            determination from FNS, regardless of whether a request for review
            is filed in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='279' tq='N'>
                279 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . If the disqualification is reversed through administrative or
            judicial review, the Secretary shall not be liable for the value of
            any sales lost during the disqualification period. Firms that
            request and are determined eligible to a civil money penalty in lieu
            of permanent disqualification for trafficking may continue to
            participate in the program pending review and shall not be required
            to pay the civil money penalty pending appeal of the trafficking
            determination action. In the case of a firm for which action is
            taken in accordance with paragraph (e)(8) of this section, the
            determination notice shall inform such firm that the
            disqualification action is not subject to administrative or judicial
            review, as specified in paragraph (e)(8) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Basis for determination.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The FNS regional office making a disqualification or penalty
            determination shall consider:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The nature and scope of the violations committed by personnel of
            the firm,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any prior action taken by FNS to warn the firm about the
            possibility that violations are occurring, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any other evidence that shows the firm&apos;s intent to violate the
            regulations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Penalties.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS shall take action as follows against any firm determined to
            have violated the Act or regulations. For the purposes of assigning
            a period of disqualification, a warning letter shall not be
            considered to be a sanction. A civil money penalty and a
            disqualification shall be considered sanctions for such purposes.
            The FNS regional office shall:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Disqualify a firm permanently if:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Personnel of the firm have trafficked as defined in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='271' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
                271.2
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Violations such as, but not limited to, the sale of ineligible
            items occurred and the firm had twice before been sanctioned.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             It is determined that personnel of the firm knowingly submitted
            information on the application that contains false information of a
            substantive nature that could affect the eligibility of the firm for
            authorization in the program, such as, but not limited to,
            information related to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='e_1_iii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Eligibility requirements under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='1' psec='#b' tq='N'>
                278.1(b), (c), (d), (e), (f), (g) and (h)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='e_1_iii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Staple food stock;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='e_1_iii_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Annual gross sales for firms seeking to qualify for authorization
            under Criterion B as specified in the Food Stamp Act of 1977, as
            amended;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='e_1_iii_D'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (D)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Annual staple food sales;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='e_1_iii_E'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (E)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Total annual gross retail food sales for firms seeking
            authorization as co-located wholesale/retail firms;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='e_1_iii_F'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (F)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Ownership of the firm;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='e_1_iii_G'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (G)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Employer Identification Numbers and Social Security Numbers;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='e_1_iii_H'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (H)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Food Stamp Program history, business practices, business ethics,
            WIC disqualification or authorization status, when the store did (or
            will) open 
            <PRTPAGE P='1020' />
            for business under the current ownership, business, health or other
            licenses, and whether or not the firm is a retail and wholesale firm
            operating at the same location; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='e_1_iii_I'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (I)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any other information of a substantive nature that could affect the
            eligibility of a firm.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Disqualify the firm for 5 years if it is to be the firm&apos;s
            first sanction, the firm had been previously advised of the
            possibility that violations were occurring and of possible
            consequences of violating the regulations, and the evidence shows
            that:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             It is the firm&apos;s practice to sell expensive or conspicuous
            nonfood items, cartons of cigarettes, or alcoholic beverages in
            exchange for food coupons; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The firm&apos;s coupon redemptions for a specified period of time
            exceed its food sales for the same period of time; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A wholesale food concern&apos;s redemptions of coupons for a
            specified period of time exceed the redemptions of all the specified
            authorized retail food stores, nonprofit cooperative food-purchasing
            ventures, group living arrangements, drug addict and alcoholic
            treatment programs, homeless meal providers, and shelters for
            battered women and children which the wholesale food concern was
            authorized to serve during that time; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_2_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A wholesale food concern&apos;s stated redemptions of coupons for a
            particular retail food store, nonprofit cooperative food-purchasing
            venture, group living arrangement, drug addict and alcoholic
            treatment program, homeless meal providers, or shelters for battered
            women and children exceeded the actual amount of coupons which that
            firm or organization redeemed through the wholesaler; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_2_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Personnel of the firm knowingly accepted coupons from an
            unauthorized firm or an individual known not to be legally entitled
            to possess coupons.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Disqualify the firm for 3 years if it is to be the first sanction
            for the firm and the evidence shows that:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             It is the firm&apos;s practice to commit violations such as the
            sale of common nonfood items in amounts normally found in a shopping
            basket and the firm was previously advised of the possibility that
            violations were occurring and of the possible consequences of
            violating the regulations; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any of the situations described in paragraph (e)(2) of this section
            occurred and FNS had not previously advised the firm of the
            possibility that violations were occurring and of the possible
            consequences of violating the regulations; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The firm is an authorized communal dining facility, drug addiction
            or alcoholic treatment and rehabilitation program, group living
            arrangement, homeless meal provider, meal delivery service, or
            shelter for battered women and children and it is the firm&apos;s
            practice to sell meals in exchange for food coupons to persons not
            eligible to purchase meals with food coupons and the firm has been
            previously advised of the possibility that violations were occurring
            and of the possible consequences of violating the regulations; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_3_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A wholesale food concern accepted coupons from an authorized firm
            which it was not authorized to serve and the wholesale food concern
            had been previously advised of the possibility that violations were
            occurring and of possible consequences of violating the regulations;
            or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_3_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The firm is an authorized retail food store and personnel of the
            firm have engaged in food coupon transactions with other authorized
            retail stores, not including treatment programs, group living
            arrangements, homeless meal providers, or shelters for battered
            women and children, and the firm had been previously advised of the
            possibility that violations were occurring and of the possible
            consequences of violating the regulations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_3_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Personnel of the firm knowingly submitted information on the
            application that contained false information of a substantive nature
            related to the ability of FNS to monitor compliance of the firm with
            FSP requirements, such as, but not limited to, information related
            to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='e_3_vi_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Annual eligible retail food sales;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='e_3_vi_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Store location and store address and mailing address;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='e_3_vi_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Financial institution information; or
            <PRTPAGE P='1021' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='e_3_vi_D'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (D)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Store name, type of ownership, number of cash registers, and
            non-food inventory and services.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Disqualify the firm for 1 year if:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_4_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             It is to be the first sanction for the firm and the ownership or
            management personnel of the firm have committed violations such as
            the sale of common nonfood items in amounts normally found in a
            shopping basket, and FNS had not previously advised the firm of the
            possibility that violations were occurring and of the possible
            consequences of violating the regulations; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_4_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The firm has accepted food stamp benefits in payment for items sold
            to a household on credit.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Disqualify the firm for 6 months if it is to be the first sanction
            for the firm and the evidence shows that personnel of the firm have
            committed violations such as but not limited to the sale of common
            nonfood items due to carelessness or poor supervision by the
            firm&apos;s ownership or management.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Double the appropriate period of disqualification prescribed in
            paragraphs (e) (2) through (5) of this section as warranted by the
            evidence of violations if the same firm has once before been
            assigned a sanction.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Send the firm a warning letter if violations are too limited to
            warrant a disqualification.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS shall disqualify from the Food Stamp Program any firm which is
            disqualified from the WIC Program:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Based in whole or in part on any act which constitutes a violation
            of that program&apos;s regulation and which is shown to constitute a
            misdemeanor or felony violation of law, or for any of the following
            specific program violations:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_8_ii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A pattern of claiming reimbursement for the sale of an amount of a
            specific food item which exceeds the store&apos;s documented
            inventory of that food item for a specified period of time;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_8_ii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Exchanging WIC food instruments for cash, credit or consideration
            other than eligible food; or the exchange of firearms, ammunition,
            explosives or controlled substances, as defined in 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 802 of
            </aref>
             title 21 of the United States Code, for food instruments;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_8_ii_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A pattern of receiving, transacting and/or redeeming WIC food
            instruments outside of authorized channels;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_8_ii_D'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (D)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A pattern of exchanging non-food items for a WIC food instrument;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_8_ii_E'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (E)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A pattern of charging WIC customers more for food than non-WIC
            customers or charging WIC customers more than the current shelf
            price; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_8_ii_F'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (F)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A pattern of charging for food items not received by the WIC
            customer or for foods provided in excess of those listed on the food
            instrument.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_8_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS shall not disqualify a firm from the Food Stamp Program on the
            basis of a WIC disqualification unless:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_8_ii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Prior to the time prescribed for securing administrative review of
            the WIC disqualification action, the firm was provided individual
            and specific notice that it could be disqualified from the Food
            Stamp Program based on the WIC violations committed by the firm;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_8_ii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A signed and dated copy of such notice is provided to FNS by the
            WIC administering agency; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_8_ii_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A determination is made in accordance with paragraph (a) of this
            section that such action will not cause a hardship for participating
            Food Stamp households.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_8_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Such a Food Stamp disqualification:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_8_iii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Shall be for the same length of time as the WIC disqualification;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_8_iii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             May begin at a later date than the WIC disqualification; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_8_iii_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Shall not be subject to administrative or judicial review under the
            Food Stamp Program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Criteria for civil money penalties for hardship and transfer of
              ownership.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS may impose a civil money penalty as a sanction in lieu of
            disqualification when the firm subject to a disqualification is
            selling a substantial variety of staple food items, and the
            firm&apos;s disqualification would cause hardship to food stamp
            households because there is no other authorized retail food store in
            the area selling as large a variety of staple food items at
            comparable prices. FNS may disqualify a store which meets the
            criteria for a civil money penalty if the store had previously been
            assigned a sanction. A civil money penalty for hardship to food
            stamp households may not be imposed in lieu of a permanent
            disqualification.
            <PRTPAGE P='1022' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the event any retail food store or wholesale food concern which
            has been disqualified is sold or the ownership thereof is otherwise
            transferred to a purchaser or transferee, the person or other legal
            entity who sells or otherwise transfers ownership of the retail food
            store or wholesale food concern shall be subjected to and liable for
            a civil money penalty in an amount to reflect that portion of the
            disqualification period that has not expired, to be calculated using
            the method found at 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='6' psec='#g' tq='N'>
                278.6(g)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . If the retail food store or wholesale food concern has been
            permanently disqualified, the civil money penalty shall be double
            the penalty for a ten year disqualification period. The
            disqualification shall continue in effect at the disqualified
            location for the person or other legal entity who transfers
            ownership of the retail food store or wholesale food concern
            notwithstanding the imposition of a civil money penalty under this
            paragraph.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             At any time after a civil money penalty imposed under paragraph (f)
            (2) of this section has become final under the provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='279' tq='N'>
                279
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , the Food and Consumer Service may request the Attorney General
            institute a civil action to collect the penalty from the person or
            persons subject to the penalty in a district court of the United
            States for any district in which such person or persons are found,
            reside, or transact business.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A bona fide transferee of a retail food store shall not be required
            to pay a civil money penalty imposed on the firm prior to its
            transfer. A buyer or transferee (other than a bona fide buyer or
            transferee) may not be authorized to accept or redeem coupons and
            may not accept or redeem coupons until the Secretary receives full
            payment of any penalty imposed on such store or concern.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Amount of civil money penalties for hardship and transfer of
              ownership.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS shall determine the amount of the civil money penalty as
            follows:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Determine the firm&apos;s average monthly redemptions of coupons
            for the 12-month period ending with the month immediately preceding
            that month during which the firm was charged with violations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Multiply the average monthly redemption figure by 10 percent.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Multiply the product arrived at in paragraph (g)(2) by the number
            of months for which the firm would have been disqualified under
            paragraph (e) of this section. The civil money penalty may not
            exceed an amount specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='3' sect='91' psec='#b_3_i' tq='N'>
                3.91(b)(3)(i)
              </subref>
               of this title
            </aref>
             for each violation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Notifying the firm of civil money penalties for hardship and
              transfer of ownership.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A firm has 15 days from the date the FNS regional office notifies
            the firm in writing in which to pay the civil money penalty, or to
            notify the regional office in writing of its intent to pay in
            installments as specified by the regional office. The firm must
            present to FNS a collateral bond as specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='1' psec='#b_4' tq='N'>
                278.1(b)(4)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , within the same 15-day period. The civil money penalty must be
            paid in full by the end of the period for which the firm would have
            been disqualified. FNS shall:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Disqualify the firm for the period determined to be appropriate
            under paragraph (e) of this section if the firm refuses to pay any
            of the civil money penalty;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Disqualify the firm for a period corresponding to the unpaid part
            of the civil money penalty if the firm does not pay the civil money
            penalty in full or in installments as specified by the FNS regional
            office; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Disqualify the firm for the prescribed period if the firm does not
            present a collateral bond or irrevocable letter of credit within the
            required 15 days. Any payment on a civil money penalty which have
            been received by FNS shall be returned to the firm. If the firm
            presents the required bond or irrevocable letter of credit during
            the disqualification period, the civil money penalty may be
            reinstated for the duration of the disqualification period.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Criteria for eligibility for a civil money penalty in lieu of
              permanent disqualification for trafficking.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS may impose a civil money penalty in lieu of a permanent
            disqualification for trafficking as defined in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='271' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
                271.2
              </subref>
            </aref>
             if the firm timely submits to FNS substantial evidence which
            demonstrates that the firm had established and implemented 
            <PRTPAGE P='1023' />
            an effective compliance policy and program to prevent violations of
            the Program. Firms assessed a CMP under this paragraph shall be
            subject to the applicable penalties included in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='6' psec='#e' tq='N'>
                278.6(e) (2)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             through (6) for the sale of ineligible items. Only those firms for
            which a permanent disqualification for trafficking took effect on or
            after October 1, 1988, are eligible for a civil money penalty in
            lieu of permanent disqualification for trafficking, except that
            firms that have been disqualified but are awaiting a judicial review
            decision are eligible for a civil money penalty in lieu of a
            permanent disqualification. In determining the minimum standards of
            eligibility of a firm for a civil money penalty in lieu of a
            permanent disqualification for trafficking, the firm shall, at a
            minimum, establish by substantial evidence its fulfillment of each
            of the following criteria: 
          </text>
        </P>
        <EXTRACT>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Criterion 1.
            </E>
             The firm shall have developed an effective compliance policy as
            specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='6' psec='#i_1' tq='N'>
                278.6(i)(1)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ; and
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Criterion 2.
            </E>
             The firm shall establish that both its compliance policy and
            program were in operation at the location where the violation(s)
            occurred 
            <E T='03'>
              prior
            </E>
             to the occurrence of violations cited in the charge letter sent to
            the firm; and
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Criterion 3.
            </E>
             The firm had developed and instituted an effective personnel
            training program as specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='6' psec='#i_2' tq='N'>
                278.6(i)(2)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ; and
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Criterion 4.
            </E>
             Firm ownership was not aware of, did not approve, did not benefit
            from, or was not in any way involved in the conduct or approval of
            trafficking violations; or it is only the first occasion in which a
            member of firm management was aware of, approved, benefited from, or
            was involved in the conduct of any trafficking violations by the
            firm. Upon the second occasion of trafficking involvement by any
            member of firm management uncovered during a subsequent
            investigation, a firm shall not be eligible for a civil money
            penalty in lieu of permanent disqualification. Notwithstanding the
            above provision, if trafficking violations consisted of the sale of
            firearms, ammunition, explosives or controlled substances, as
            defined in 21 U.S.C. 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 802
            </aref>
            , and such trafficking was conducted by the ownership or management
            of the firm, the firm shall not be eligible for a civil money
            penalty in lieu of permanent disqualification. For purposes of this
            section, a person is considered to be part of firm management if
            that individual has substantial supervisory responsibilities with
            regard to directing the activities and work assignments of store
            employees. Such supervisory responsibilities shall include the
            authority to hire employees for the store or to terminate the
            employment of individuals working for the store.
          </P>
        </EXTRACT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Compliance policy standards.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             As specified in Criterion 1 above, in determining whether a firm
            has established an effective policy to prevent violations, FNS shall
            consider written and dated statements of firm policy which reflect a
            commitment to ensure that the firm is operated in a manner
            consistent with this 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              part 278 of
            </aref>
             current FSP regulations and current FSP policy on the proper
            acceptance and handling of food coupons. As required by Criterion 2,
            such policy statements shall be considered only if documentation is
            supplied which establishes that the policy statements were provided
            to the violating employee(s) prior to the commission of the
            violation. In addition, in evaluating the effectiveness of the
            firm&apos;s policy and program to ensure FSP compliance and to
            prevent FSP violations, FNS may consider the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Documentation reflecting the development and/or operation of a
            policy to terminate the employment of any firm employee found
            violating FSP regulations;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Documentation of the development and/or continued operation of firm
            policy and procedures resulting in appropriate corrective action
            following complaints of FSP violations or irregularities committed
            by firm personnel;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Documentation of the development and/or continued operation of
            procedures for internal review of firm employees&apos; compliance
            with FSP regulations;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The nature and scope of the violations charged against the firm;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_1_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any record of previous firm violations under the same ownership;
            and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_1_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any other information the firm may present to FNS for
            consideration.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Compliance training program standards.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             As prescribed in Criterion 3 above, the firm shall have developed
            and implemented an effective training program for all managers and
            employees on the acceptance and handling of food coupons in
            accordance with this 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='278' tq='N'>
                278
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . A firm which seeks a civil money penalty in lieu of a permanent
            disqualification shall document its training activity by submitting
            to FNS its 
            <PRTPAGE P='1024' />
            dated training curricula and records of dates training sessions were
            conducted; a record of dates of employment of firm personnel; and
            contemporaneous documentation of the participation of the violating
            employee(s) in initial and any follow-up training held prior to the
            violation(s). FNS shall consider a training program effective if it
            meets or is otherwise equivalent to the following standards:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Training for all managers and employees whose work brings them into
            contact with food stamps or who are assigned to a location where
            food stamps are accepted, handled or processed shall be conducted
            within one month of the institution of the compliance policy under
            Criterion 1 above. Employees hired subsequent to the institution of
            the compliance policy shall be trained within one month of
            employment. All employees shall be trained periodically thereafter;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Training shall be designed to establish a level of competence that
            assures compliance with Program requirements as included in this 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='278' tq='N'>
                278
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Written materials, which may include FNS publications and program
            regulations that are available to all authorized firms, are used in
            the training program. Training materials shall clearly state that
            the following acts are prohibited and are in violation of the Food
            Stamp Act and regulations: the exchange of food coupons, ATP cards
            or other program access devices for cash; and, in exchange for
            coupons, the sale of firearms, ammunition, explosives or controlled
            substances, as the term is defined in 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 802 of
            </aref>
             title 21, United States Code.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Amount of civil money penalty in lieu of permanent
              disqualification for trafficking.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A civil money penalty assessed in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='6' psec='#i' tq='N'>
                278.6(i)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             shall not exceed the amount specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='3' sect='91' psec='#b_3_ii' tq='N'>
                3.91(b)(3)(ii)
              </subref>
               of this title
            </aref>
             for each violation and shall not exceed the amount specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='3' sect='91' psec='#b_3_ii' tq='N'>
                3.91(b)(3)(ii)
              </subref>
               of this title
            </aref>
             for all violations occurring during a single investigation. FNS
            shall determine the amount of the civil money penalty as follows:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Determine the firm&apos;s average monthly redemptions for the
            12-month period ending with the month immediately preceding the
            month during which the firm was charged with violations;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Multiply the average monthly redemption figure by 10 percent;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For the first trafficking offense by a firm, multiply the product
            obtained in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='6' psec='#j_2' tq='N'>
                278.6(j)(2)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             by 60 if the largest amount of food coupons, ATP cards, or other
            benefit instruments involved in a single trafficking transaction had
            a face value of $99 or less. If the face value of coupons, ATP cards
            or other benefit instruments involved in the largest single
            trafficking transaction was $100 or more, the amount of the product
            obtained in this paragraph shall be doubled;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For a second trafficking offense by a firm, multiply the product
            obtained in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='6' psec='#j_2' tq='N'>
                278.6(j)(2)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             by 120 if the largest amount of food coupons, ATP cards, or other
            benefit instruments involved in a single trafficking transaction had
            a face value of $99 or less and the same firm has once before been
            sanctioned for trafficking in food coupons, ATP cards, or other
            benefit instruments. If the face value of food coupons, ATP cards,
            or other benefit instruments involved in the largest single
            trafficking transaction was $100 or more, the amount of the product
            obtained in this paragraph shall be doubled; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a third trafficking offense is committed by the firm, the firm
            shall not be eligible for a civil money penalty in lieu of
            disqualification.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Payment of civil money penalty in lieu of a permanent
              disqualification for trafficking.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payment of the full amount of the civil money penalty in lieu of
            permanent disqualification for trafficking shall be made within 30
            days of the date the final determination was received by the firm.
            If payment is not made within the prescribed period, the right to
            the civil money penalty in lieu of a permanent disqualification is
            forfeited and disqualification shall become effective immediately.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='l'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (l)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Fines for the acceptance of loose coupons.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS may impose a fine against any retail food store or wholesale
            food concern that accepts coupons that are not accompanied by the
            corresponding book cover, other than the denomination of coupons
            used for making change as specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='2' psec='#d' tq='N'>
                278.2(d)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             or coupons accepted from homeless meal 
            <PRTPAGE P='1025' />
            providers as specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='2' psec='#c' tq='N'>
                278.2(c)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . The fine to be assessed against a firm found to be accepting loose
            coupons shall be $500 per investigation 
            <E T='03'>
              plus
            </E>
             an amount equal to double the face value of each loose coupon
            accepted, and may be assessed and collected in addition to any
            fiscal claim established by FNS. The fine shall be paid in full
            within 30 days of the firm&apos;s receipt of FNS&apos; notification
            to pay the fine. The Attorney General of the United States may
            institute judicial action in any court of competent jurisdiction
            against the store or concern to collect the fine. FNS may withdraw
            the authorization of the store, as well as other authorized
            locations of a multi-unit firm which are under the same ownership,
            for failure to pay such a fine as specified under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='1' psec='#k' tq='N'>
                278.1(k)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . FNS may deny the authorization of any firm that has failed to pay
            such fines as specified under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='1' psec='#j' tq='N'>
                278.1(j)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='m'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (m)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Fines for unauthorized third parties that accept food stamps.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS may impose a fine against any individual, sole proprietorship,
            partnership, corporation or other legal entity not approved by FNS
            to accept and redeem food coupons for any violation of the
            provisions of the Food Stamp Act or the program regulations,
            including violations involving the acceptance of coupons. The fine
            shall be $1,000 for each violation 
            <E T='03'>
              plus
            </E>
             an amount equal to three times the face value of the illegally
            accepted food coupons. The fine shall be paid in full within 30 days
            of the individual&apos;s or legal entity&apos;s receipt of FNS&apos;
            notification to pay the fine. The Attorney General of the United
            States may institute judicial action in any court of competent
            jurisdiction against the person to collect the fine. FNS may
            withdraw the authorization of any firm that is under the same
            ownership as an unauthorized firm that has failed to pay such a
            fine, as specified under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='1' psec='#k' tq='N'>
                278.1(k)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . FNS may deny authorization to any firm that has failed to pay such
            a fine, as specified under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='1' psec='#j' tq='N'>
                278.1(j)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='n'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (n)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Review of determination.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The determination of FNS shall be final and not subject to further
            administrative or judicial review unless a written request for
            review is filed within the period stated in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='279' tq='N'>
                279 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          Notwithstanding the above, any FNS determination made on the basis of
          paragraph (e)(8) of this section shall not be subject to further
          administrative or judicial review.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='o'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (o)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Delivery of notice.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The delivery by any method that provides evidence of delivery of
            any notice required of FNS by this part will constitute notice to
            the addressee of its contents.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [Amdt. 136, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            43 FR 43274
          </aref>
          , Sept. 22, 1978]
        </CITA>
        <EDNOTE>
          <HD SOURCE='HED'>
            Editorial Note:
          </HD>
          <P>
            For 
            <E T='04'>
              Federal Register
            </E>
             citations affecting 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
                278.6
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , see the List of CFR Sections Affected, which appears in the
            Finding Aids section of the printed volume and at 
            <E T='03'>
              www.fdsys.gov
            </E>
            .
          </P>
        </EDNOTE>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4985'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:C:278:-:278.7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        278.7
      </num>
      <head>
        Determination and disposition of claims—retail food stores and wholesale
        food concerns.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [Amdt. 136, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          43 FR 43274
        </aref>
        , Sept. 22, 1978, as amended by Amdt. 258, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          49 FR 28393
        </aref>
        , July 12, 1984; Amdt. 257, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          49 FR 32538
        </aref>
        , Aug. 15, 1984; Amdt. 262, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          49 FR 50598
        </aref>
        , Dec. 31, 1984; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          68 FR 41052
        </aref>
        , July 10, 2003; Amdt. 397, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          70 FR 72354
        </aref>
        , Dec. 5, 2005; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          73 FR 79595
        </aref>
        , Dec. 30, 2008]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='278' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              278.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Determination and disposition of claims—retail food stores and
          wholesale food concerns.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Claims against violators.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS may establish and pursue claims against firms or other entities
            which have accepted or redeemed coupons in violation of the Food
            Stamp Act or this part regardless of whether the firms or entities
            are authorized to accept food stamps. If a firm fails to pay a
            claim, FNS may collect the claim by offsetting against amounts due
            the firm on redemption of other coupons or by deducting the amounts
            due from bonds posted by firms in compliance with the provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='1' psec='#b_4' tq='N'>
                278.1(b)(4)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . FNS shall deny an application for authorization or reauthorization
            by a firm which has failed to pay a claim.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Forfeiture of a collateral bond or draw down on an irrevocable
              letter of credit.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If FNS establishes a claim against an authorized firm which has
            previously been sanctioned, collection of the claim may be through
            total or partial forfeiture of the collateral bond or draw down of
            the irrevocable letter of credit. If FNS determines that forfeiture
            or a draw down is required for collection of the claim, FNS shall
            take one or more of the following actions, as appropriate.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Determine the amount of the bond to be forfeited or irrevocable
            letter of credit drawn down on the basis of the loss to the
            Government through violations of the Act, and this Part, as detailed
            in a letter of charges to the firm;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Send written notification by method of proof of delivery to the
            firm and the bonding agent or commercial bank of FNS&apos;
            determination regarding 
            <PRTPAGE P='1026' />
            forfeiture or draw down of all or specified part of the collateral
            bond or irrevocable letter of credit and the reasons for the
            forfeiture or draw down action;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Advise the firm and the bonding agent or commercial bank of the
            firm&apos;s right to administrative review of the claim
            determination;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Advise the firm and the bonding agent or commercial bank that if
            payment of the current claim is not received directly from the firm,
            FNS shall obtain full payment through forfeiture of the bond or draw
            down of the irrevocable letter of credit;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Proceed with collection of the bond or irrevocable letter of credit
            in the amount forfeited or drawn down if a request for review is not
            filed by the firm within the period established in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='279' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
                279.5
              </subref>
               of this chapter
            </aref>
            , or if such review is unsuccessful; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon the expiration of time permitted for the filing of a request
            for administrative and/or judicial review, deposit the bond or
            irrevocable letter of credit in a Federal Reserve Bank account or in
            the Treasury Account, General. If FNS requires only a portion of the
            face value of the bond or irrevocable letter of credit to satisfy a
            claim, the entire bond or irrevocable letter of credit will be
            negotiated, and the remaining amount returned to the firm.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Coupons accepted without authorization.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The FNS officer in charge may approve the redemption under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              § 278.4 of
            </aref>
             coupons accepted by firms before the receipt of an authorization
            card from FNS if the following conditions exist:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The coupons were received in accordance with the requirements of
            this part governing acceptance of coupons except the requirement
            that the firm be authorized before acceptance;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The coupons were accepted by the firm in good faith, and without
            intent to circumvent this part; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The firm receives authorization to participate in the program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Firms seeking approval to redeem coupons accepted without
            authorization shall present a written application for approval to
            the local FNS field office. This application shall be accompanied by
            a written statement signed by the firm of all the facts about the
            acceptance of the coupons. The statement shall also include a
            certification that the coupons were accepted in good faith, and
            without any intent to circumvent this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Burned or mutilated coupons.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS may redeem burned or mutilated coupons only to the extent that
            the Bureau of Engraving and Printing of the United States Treasury
            Department can determine the value of the coupons. The firm
            presenting burned or mutilated coupons for redemption shall submit
            the coupons to the local FNS field office with a properly filled-out
            redemption certificate. In the section of the redemption certificate
            for entering the amount of coupons to be redeemed, an estimate of
            the value of the burned or mutilated coupons submitted for
            redemption shall be entered if the exact value of the coupons is
            unknown. The phrase “Deputy Administrator for Fiscal Management,
            FNS, USDA,” should be entered in the section of the redemption
            certificate for entering the name and address of the insured
            financial institution or wholesaler.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Old series coupons.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS may redeem the old series food coupons issued in 50-cent,
            2-dollar, and 5-dollar denominations when they are presented for
            redemption. Firms presenting the coupons for redemption shall submit
            the coupons to the local FNS field office with a properly completed
            redemption certificate and a written statement, signed by a
            representative of the firm, detailing the circumstances of the
            acceptance of the coupons.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Denials of claims brought by authorized firms against FNS.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a claim brought by a firm against FNS under this section is
            denied in whole or in part, notification of this action shall be
            sent to the firm by using any delivery method as long as the method
            provides evidence of delivery. If the firm is aggrieved by this
            action, it may seek administrative review as provided in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='279' tq='N'>
                279
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Lost or stolen coupons.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS may not be held liable for claims from retail food stores, meal
            services, or wholesale 
            <PRTPAGE P='1027' />
            food concerns for lost or stolen coupons.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [Amdt. 136, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            43 FR 43274
          </aref>
          , Sept. 22, 1978, as amended by Amdt. 258, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            49 FR 28393
          </aref>
          , July 12, 1984; Amdt. 257, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            49 FR 32538
          </aref>
          , Aug. 15, 1984; Amdt. 262, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            49 FR 50598
          </aref>
          , Dec. 31, 1984; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            68 FR 41052
          </aref>
          , July 10, 2003; Amdt. 397, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            70 FR 72354
          </aref>
          , Dec. 5, 2005; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            73 FR 79595
          </aref>
          , Dec. 30, 2008]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4986'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:C:278:-:278.8
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        278.8
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='278' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              278.8
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4987'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:C:278:-:278.9
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        278.9
      </num>
      <head>
        Implementation of amendments relating to the participation of retail
        food stores, wholesale food concerns and insured financial institutions.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [Amdt. 136, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          43 FR 43274
        </aref>
        , Sept. 22, 1978]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='278' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
              278.9
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Implementation of amendments relating to the participation of retail
          food stores, wholesale food concerns and insured financial
          institutions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Amendment 224.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Retail food stores shall have signs posted as required by this
            amendment no later than 30 days after distribution of the signs by
            FNS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Amendment 257.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             With the exception of the provisions in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
                278.5
              </subref>
            </aref>
             requiring redeeming financial institutions to verify that coupons
            are supported by redemption certificates, the revisions to 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='278' tq='N'>
                278
              </subref>
            </aref>
             shall be effective September 14, 1984. Redeeming financial
            institutions shall begin verifying coupon deposits as required by 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
                278.5
              </subref>
            </aref>
             in accordance with the schedule determined by the Federal Reserve
            Board. Insured financial institutions shall adhere to preexisting
            requirements for handling redemption certificates (at 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='5' psec='#a' tq='N'>
                278.5(a)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) until their Federal Reserve District implements the procedures
            contained in this final rule. FNS shall not be liable for any losses
            of coupons in transit to Federal Reserve Banks or as a result of a
            burglary or robbery of an insured financial institution which occur
            after September 14, 1984.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Amendment 267.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The federally insured credit unions authorized to redeem food
            stamps under this amendment may begin accepting food stamps for
            redemption not later than March 27, 1986.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The program changes of 
            <E T='03'>
              Amendment 272
            </E>
             at 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='5' psec='#a' tq='N'>
                278.5(a) (1) and (3)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             are effective upon publication of the amendment. Financial
            institutions must implement the provisions no later than April 21,
            1986.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Amendment No. 286.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The provisions for 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              part 278 of
            </aref>
            <E T='03'>
              Amendment No. 286
            </E>
             were effective March 11, 1987 for purposes of submitting
            applications for authorization to accept food stamps. For all other
            purposes, the effective date was April 1, 1987.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Amendment No. 280.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The provisions for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='271' tq='N'>
                271
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='1' psec='#r' tq='N'>
                278.1(r)
              </subref>
               and 278.6(f) of
            </aref>
             No. 280 are effective retroactively to April 1, 1987. The provision
            for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='1' psec='#o' tq='N'>
                278.1(o)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             is effective May 22, 1987.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Amendment No. 304.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The technical amendment for 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              part 278 of
            </aref>
            <E T='03'>
              Amendment No. 304
            </E>
             was effective August 1, 1988.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Amendment No. 323.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The program changes made to 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
                278.6
              </subref>
            </aref>
             by this amendment are retroactively effective October 1, 1988.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Amendment No. 334.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The program changes made to 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
                278.1
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
                278.6
              </subref>
            </aref>
             by this amendment are effective February 1, 1992. The program
            changes made to 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='271' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
                271.2
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='271' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
                271.5
              </subref>
            </aref>
             by this amendment are retroactively effective to November 28, 1990,
            as specified in Pub. L. No. 101-624.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Amendment No. 354.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The program changes made to 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='271' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
                271.2
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
                278.6
              </subref>
            </aref>
             by this amendment are effective October 1, 1993.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Amendment No. 331.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The program changes made to 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='271' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
                271.2
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
                278.5
              </subref>
            </aref>
             by this amendment are effective December 22, 1994.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='l'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (l)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Amendment No. 335.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Expanded authority to use and disclose information about firms
            participating in the FSP under CFR 278.1(r) for currently authorized
            firms is effective and will be implemented beginning February 25,
            1997 but not before 60-days after the date of notices to such firms,
            notifying them of the changes. The only exception to the above is
            that such disclosure of information shall not apply to firms that
            are withdrawn or are disqualified from FSP participation prior to
            implementation, unless such firms participate in the FSP at a future
            date subsequent to the implementation date.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='m'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (m)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Amendment No. 383.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The program changes made to 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
                278.1
              </subref>
            </aref>
             by this amendment are effective September 29, 2000.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [Amdt. 136, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            43 FR 43274
          </aref>
          , Sept. 22, 1978]
        </CITA>
        <EDNOTE>
          <HD SOURCE='HED'>
            Editorial Note:
          </HD>
          <P>
            For 
            <E T='04'>
              Federal Register
            </E>
             citations affecting 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='278' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
                278.9
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , see the List of CFR Sections Affected, which appears in the
            Finding Aids section of the printed volume and at 
            <E T='03'>
              www.fdsys.gov
            </E>
            .
          </P>
        </EDNOTE>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4988'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:C:278:-:278.10
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        278.10
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='1028' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='278' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
              278.10
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>