<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol5'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:III:-:351
    </extid>
    <num>
      351
    </num>
    <head>
      IMPORTATION OF PLANTS OR PLANT PRODUCTS BY MAIL
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='7711-771' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/7711-771.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 7711-771
            </subref>
          </aref>
          4, 7721, 7754, and 7755; 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR 
            <subref title='7' part='2' sect='22' psec='' tq='N'>
              2.22
            </subref>
            , 
            <subref title='7' part='2' sect='80' psec='' tq='N'>
              2.80
            </subref>
            , and 
            <subref title='7' part='371' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              371.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <CROSSREF>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Cross Reference:
        </HD>
        <P>
          For customs regulations governing importation of plants and plant
          products, see 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            19 CFR part 
            <subref title='19' part='12' tq='N'>
              12
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </CROSSREF>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='7701-777' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/7701-777.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 7701-777
            </subref>
          </aref>
          2 and 7781-7786; 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR 
            <subref title='7' part='2' sect='22' psec='' tq='N'>
              2.22
            </subref>
            , 
            <subref title='7' part='2' sect='80' psec='' tq='N'>
              2.80
            </subref>
            , and 
            <subref title='7' part='371' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              371.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </AUTH>
    </text>
    <section orderid='5603'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:III:-:351:-:351.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        351.1
      </num>
      <head>
        Joint treatment generally.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          66 FR 21059
        </aref>
        , Apr. 27, 2001]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='351' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              351.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Joint treatment generally.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The entry into the United States of certain plants, plant products,
          and soil is prohibited or restricted through various orders,
          quarantines, and regulations promulgated by the Administrator of the
          Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service (APHIS) under the authority
          of the Plant Protection Act (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='7701-777' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/7701-777.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 7701-777
            </subref>
          </aref>
          2). To assist in enforcing the aforementioned orders, quarantines, and
          regulations, the Plant Protection and Quarantine Programs of APHIS
          have made provisions with the U.S. Postal and Customs Services to
          ensure closer inspection of prohibited or restricted imported
          articles.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            66 FR 21059
          </aref>
          , Apr. 27, 2001]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5604'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:III:-:351:-:351.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        351.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Location of inspectors.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          28 FR 5203
        </aref>
        , May 24, 1963, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          36 FR 24917
        </aref>
        , Dec. 24, 1971]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='351' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              351.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Location of inspectors.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Inspectors of the Plant Protection and Quarantine Programs and customs
          officers are stationed at the following locations: 
        </P>
        <EXTRACT>
          <P>
            Anchorage, Alaska, Arlington, Va., Atlanta, Ga., Baltimore, Md.,
            Baton Rouge, La., Blaine, Wash., Boston, Mass., Brownsville, Tex.,
            Buffalo, N.Y., Calexico, Calif., Chantilly, Va., Charleston, S.C.,
            Charlotte Amalie, St. Thomas, V.I., Chicago, Ill., Christiansted,
            St. Croix, V.I., Cleveland, Ohio., Corpus Christi, Tex., Dallas,
            Tex., Del Rio, Tex., Detroit, Mich., Douglas, Ariz., Dover, Del.,
            Duluth, Minn., Eagle Pass, Tex., El Paso, Tex., Galveston, Tex.,
            Hidalgo, Tex., Hilo, Hawaii, Hoboken, N.J., Honolulu, Hawaii,
            Houston, Tex., Jacksonville, Fla., Jamaica, L.I., N.Y., Key West,
            Fla., Laredo, Tex., McGuire AFB, N.J., Memphis, Tenn., Miami, Fla.,
            Milwaukee, Wis., Mobile, Ala., New Orleans, La., New York, N.Y.,
            Newport News, Va., Nogales, Ariz., Norfolk, Va., Pensacola, Fla.,
            Philadelphia, Pa., Port Arthur, Tex., Port Canaveral, Fla., Port
            Everglades, Fla., Portland, Oreg., Presidio, Tex., Progreso, Tex.,
            Ramey AFB, P.R., Roma, Tex., Rouses Point, N.Y., St. Paul, Minn.,
            San Antonio, Tex., San Diego, Calif., San Francisco, Calif., San
            Juan, P.R., San Luis, Ariz., San Pedro, Calif., San Ysidro, Calif.,
            Savannah, Ga., Seattle, Wash., Tampa, Fla., 
            <PRTPAGE P='443' />
            Toledo, Ohio, Washington, DC, West Palm Beach, Fla., Wilmington,
            N.C.
          </P>
        </EXTRACT>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            28 FR 5203
          </aref>
          , May 24, 1963, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            36 FR 24917
          </aref>
          , Dec. 24, 1971]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5605'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:III:-:351:-:351.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        351.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Procedure on arrival.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          24 FR 9923
        </aref>
        , Dec. 9, 1959, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          28 FR 5204
        </aref>
        , May 24, 1963, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          36 FR 24917
        </aref>
        , Dec. 24, 1971]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='351' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              351.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Procedure on arrival.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          All parcel post or other mail packages from foreign countries which,
          either from examination or external evidence, are found or are
          believed to contain plants or plant products, shall be dispatched for
          submission, or actually submitted, to the plant quarantine inspector
          at the most accessible location listed in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='351' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              351.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
          . The inspector shall pass upon the contents under the Plant
          Quarantine Act and Federal Plant Pest Act and with the cooperation of
          the customs and postal officers either
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Release the package from further plant quarantine examination and
            endorse his decision thereon; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Divert it to the Plant Quarantine Station at Washington, DC,
            Brownsville, Tex., Hoboken, N.J., Honolulu, Hawaii, Jamaica, L.I.,
            N.Y., Laredo, Tex., Miami, Fla., New Orleans, La., San Francisco,
            Calif., San Juan, P.R., San Pedro, Calif., or Seattle, Wash., for
            whatever disposition is deemed warranted. If so diverted, the plant
            quarantine inspector shall attach to the package the yellow and
            green special mailing tag addressed to the proper quarantine
            station. A package so diverted shall be accompanied by customs card
            Form 3511 and transmitted to the appropriate Customs office for
            referral to the Plant Quarantine Station. Envelopes containing
            customs card Form 3511 addressed to the collector of customs, New
            York, N.Y., shall contain a notation that the material is to be
            referred to the Plant Protection and Quarantine Programs, Hoboken,
            N.J.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            24 FR 9923
          </aref>
          , Dec. 9, 1959, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            28 FR 5204
          </aref>
          , May 24, 1963, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            36 FR 24917
          </aref>
          , Dec. 24, 1971]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5606'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:III:-:351:-:351.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        351.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Records.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          28 FR 5204
        </aref>
        , May 24, 1963]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='351' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              351.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Records.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The customs officers at Washington, DC, Brownsville, Tex., Hoboken,
          N.J., Honolulu, Hawaii, Jamaica, L.I., N.Y., Laredo, Tex., Miami,
          Fla., New Orleans, La., San Francisco, Calif., San Juan, P.R., San
          Pedro, Calif., or Seattle, Wash., shall keep a record of such packages
          as may be delivered to representatives of the Department of
          Agriculture, and upon the return thereof shall prepare a mail entry to
          accompany the dutiable package and deliver it to the postmaster for
          delivery or onward dispatch or in appropriate cases subject the
          shipment to formal customs entry procedure.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            28 FR 5204
          </aref>
          , May 24, 1963]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5607'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:III:-:351:-:351.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        351.5
      </num>
      <head>
        Return or destruction.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          24 FR 9923
        </aref>
        , Dec. 9, 1959, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          36 FR 24917
        </aref>
        , Dec. 24, 1971]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='351' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              351.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Return or destruction.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Where the plant quarantine inspector requires the entire shipment to
          be returned to the country of origin as a prohibited importation (in
          which event he shall endorse his action thereon) and delivers the
          shipment to the collector of customs, the collector shall in turn
          deliver it to the postmaster for dispatch to the country of origin.
          If, upon examination, the plant material is deemed dangerous to plant
          life, the collector of customs shall permit the plant quarantine
          inspector to destroy immediately both the container and its contents.
          In either case the plant quarantine inspector shall notify the
          addressee of the action taken and the reason therefor. If the
          objectionable plant material forms only a portion of the contents of
          the mail package and in the judgment of the inspector the package can
          safely be delivered to the addressee, after removing and destroying
          the objectionable material, such procedure is authorized. In the
          latter case the inspector shall place in the package a memorandum
          (Form AQI-387) informing the addressee of the action taken by the
          inspector and describing the matter which has been seized and
          destroyed and the reasons therefor.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            24 FR 9923
          </aref>
          , Dec. 9, 1959, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            36 FR 24917
          </aref>
          , Dec. 24, 1971]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5608'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:III:-:351:-:351.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        351.6
      </num>
      <head>
        Packages in closed mail dispatches.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          24 FR 9923
        </aref>
        , Dec. 9, 1959, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          36 FR 24917
        </aref>
        , Dec. 24, 1971]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='351' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              351.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Packages in closed mail dispatches.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The foregoing instructions shall be followed in the treatment of
          packages containing plants or plant products received in closed mail
          dispatches made up for transmission directly to a post office located
          at a customs port at which no plant quarantine inspector is stationed.
          Such packages (accompanied by customs card Form 3511) shall be
          forwarded by the collector of customs 
          <PRTPAGE P='444' />
          through the postmaster to the most accessible location listed in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='351' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              351.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
           for appropriate treatment in the manner hereinbefore provided. This
          procedure shall also be followed in respect to such packages which are
          forwarded to unlisted post offices from the post office of original
          receipt, without having received plant quarantine examination.
          Packages discovered at post offices where no customs officer is
          located shall be forwarded by the postmaster under his official
          penalty envelope addressed to the collector of customs at the most
          accessible location listed for appropriate treatment as prescribed
          herein.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            24 FR 9923
          </aref>
          , Dec. 9, 1959, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            36 FR 24917
          </aref>
          , Dec. 24, 1971]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5609'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:III:-:351:-:351.7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        351.7
      </num>
      <head>
        Regulations governing importation by mail of plant material for
        immediate export.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          24 FR 9923
        </aref>
        , Dec. 9, 1959, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          28 FR 5204
        </aref>
        , May 24, 1963]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='351' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              351.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Regulations governing importation by mail of plant material for
          immediate export.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          To collectors of customs and others concerned:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Shipments of plant material may be imported by mail free of duty
            for immediate exportation by mail subject to the following
            regulations, which have been approved by the Department of
            Agriculture and the Post Office Department:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each shipment shall be dispatched in the mails from abroad,
            accompanied by a yellow and green special mail tag bearing the
            serial number of the permit for entry for immediate exportation or
            immediate transportation and exportation, issued by the U.S.
            Department of Agriculture, and also the postal form of customs
            declaration.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon arrival, the shipment shall be detained by, or redispatched
            to, the postmaster at Washington, DC, Brownsville, Tex., Hoboken,
            N.J., Honolulu, Hawaii, Jamaica, L.I., N.Y., Laredo, Tex., Miami,
            Fla., New Orleans, La., San Francisco, Calif., San Juan, P.R., San
            Pedro, Calif., or Seattle, Wash., as may be appropriate, according
            to the address on the yellow and green tag, and there submitted to
            the customs officer and the Federal quarantine inspector. The
            merchandise shall under no circumstances be permitted to enter the
            commerce of the United States.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             After inspection by the customs and quarantine officers, and with
            their approval, the addressee, or his authorized agent, shall repack
            and readdress the mail parcel under customs supervision; affix to
            the parcel the necessary postage, and comply with other mailing
            requirements, after which the parcel shall be delivered to the
            postmaster for exportation by mail pursuant to 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              19 CFR 
              <subref title='19' part='9' sect='11' psec='#a' tq='N'>
                9.11(a)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . The contents of the original parcel may be subdivided and exported
            in separate parcels in like manner.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             It will not be necessary to issue a customs mail entry nor to
            require formal entry of the shipments.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The mail shipments referred to shall be accorded special handling
            only at the points specified in paragraph (a)(2) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The foregoing procedure shall not affect the movement of plant
            material in the international mails in transit through the United
            States.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            24 FR 9923
          </aref>
          , Dec. 9, 1959, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            28 FR 5204
          </aref>
          , May 24, 1963]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>