<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol7'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:707
    </extid>
    <num>
      707
    </num>
    <head>
      PAYMENTS DUE PERSONS WHO HAVE DIED, DISAPPEARED, OR HAVE BEEN DECLARED
      INCOMPETENT
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='1385' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1385.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 1385
            </subref>
             and 
            <subref title='7' sect='8786' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/8786.html'>
              8786
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            30 FR 6246
          </aref>
          , May 5, 1965, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='6548'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:707:-:707.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        707.1
      </num>
      <head>
        Applicability.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='707' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              707.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Applicability.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          This part applies to all programs in title 7 of the Code of Federal
          Regulations which are administered by the Farm Service Agency under
          which payments are made to eligible program participants. This part
          also applies to all other programs to which this part is 
          <PRTPAGE P='20' />
          applicable by the individual program regulations.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6549'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:707:-:707.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        707.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='707' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              707.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          “Person” when relating to one who dies, disappears, or becomes
          incompetent, prior to receiving payment, means a person who has earned
          a payment in whole or in part pursuant to any of the programs to which
          this part is applicable. “Children” shall include legally adopted
          children who shall be entitled to share in any payment in the same
          manner and to the same extent as legitimate children of natural
          parents. “Brother” or “sister”, when relating to one who, pursuant to
          the regulations in this part, is eligible to apply for the payment
          which is due a person who dies, disappears, or becomes incompetent
          prior to the receipt of such payment, shall include brothers and
          sisters of the half blood who shall be considered the same as brothers
          and sisters of the whole blood. “Payment” means a payment by draft,
          check or certificate pursuant to any of the Programs to which this
          part is applicable. Payments shall not be considered received for the
          purposes of this part until such draft, check or certificate has been
          negotiated or used.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6550'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:707:-:707.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        707.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Death.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          30 FR 6246
        </aref>
        , May 5, 1965, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 81835
        </aref>
        , Dec. 29, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='707' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              707.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Death.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Where any person who would otherwise be eligible to receive a
            payment dies before the payment is received, payment may be released
            in accordance with this section so long as, and only if, a timely
            program application has been filed by the deceased before the death
            or filed in a timely way before or after the death by a person
            legally authorized to act for the deceased. Timeliness will be
            determined under the relevant program regulations. All program
            conditions for payment under the relevant program regulations must
            have been met for the deceased to be considered otherwise eligible
            for the payment. However, the payment will not be made under this
            section unless, in addition, a separate release application is filed
            in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='707' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
                707.7
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . If these conditions are met, payment may be released without
            regard to the claims of creditors other than the United States, in
            accordance with the following order of precedence:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To the administrator or executor of the deceased person&apos;s
            estate.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To the surviving spouse, if there is no administrator or executor
            and none is expected to be appointed, or if an administrator or
            executor was appointed but the administration of the estate is
            closed (i) prior to application by the administrator or executor for
            such payment or (ii) prior to the time when a check, draft, or
            certificate issued for such payment to the administrator or executor
            is negotiated or used.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If there is no surviving spouse, to the sons and daughters in equal
            shares. Children of a deceased son or daughter of a deceased person
            shall be entitled to their parent&apos;s share of the payment, share
            and share alike. If there are no surviving direct descendants of a
            deceased son or daughter of such deceased person, the share of the
            payment which otherwise would have been made to such son or daughter
            shall be divided equally among the surviving sons and daughters of
            such deceased person and the estates of any deceased sons or
            daughters where there are surviving direct descendants.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If there is no surviving spouse and no direct descendant, payment
            shall be made to the father and mother of the deceased person in
            equal shares, or the whole thereof to the surviving father or
            mother.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If there is no surviving spouse, no direct descendant, and no
            surviving parent, payment shall be made to the brothers and sisters
            of the deceased person in equal shares. Children of a deceased
            brother or sister shall be entitled to their parent&apos;s share of
            the payment, share and share alike. If there are no surviving direct
            descendants of the deceased brother or sister of such deceased
            person, the share of the payment which otherwise would have been
            made to such brother or sister shall be divided equally among the
            surviving brothers and sisters of such deceased person and the
            estates of any deceased brothers or sisters where there are
            surviving direct descendants.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If there is no surviving spouse, direct descendant, parent, or
            brothers or sisters or their descendants, the payment shall be made
            to the heirs-at-law in accordance with the law of the State of
            domicile of the deceased person.
            <PRTPAGE P='21' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If any person who is entitled to payment under the above order of
            precedence is a minor, payment of his share shall be made to his
            legal guardian, but if no legal guardian has been appointed payment
            shall be made to his natural guardian or custodian for his benefit,
            unless the minor&apos;s share of the payment exceeds $1,000, in
            which event payment shall be made only to his legal guardian.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any payment which the deceased person could have received may be
            made jointly to the persons found to be entitled to such payment or
            shares thereof under this section or, pursuant to instructions
            issued by the Farm Service Agency, a separate payment may be issued
            to each person entitled to share in such payment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            30 FR 6246
          </aref>
          , May 5, 1965, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 81835
          </aref>
          , Dec. 29, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6551'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:707:-:707.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        707.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Disappearance.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          30 FR 6246
        </aref>
        , May 5, 1965, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 81835
        </aref>
        , Dec. 29, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='707' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              707.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Disappearance.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Where any person who would otherwise be eligible to receive a
            payment disappears before the payment is received, payment may be
            released in accordance with this section so long as, and only if, a
            timely program application has been filed by that person before the
            disappearance or filed timely before or after the disappearance by
            someone legally authorized to act for the person involved.
            Timeliness will be determined under the relevant program
            regulations. All program conditions for payment under the relevant
            program regulations must have been met for the person involved to be
            considered otherwise eligible for the payment. However, the payment
            will not be made unless, in addition, a separate release application
            is filed in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='707' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
                707.7
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . If these conditions are met, payment may be released without
            regard to the claims of creditors other than the United States, in
            accordance with the following order of precedence:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The conservator or liquidator of his estate, if one be duly
            appointed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The spouse.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An adult son or daughter or grandchild for the benefit of his
            estate.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The mother or father for the benefit of his estate.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An adult brother or sister for the benefit of his estate.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Such person as may be authorized under State law to receive payment
            for the benefit of his estate.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A person shall be deemed to have disappeared if (1) he has been
            missing for a period of more than 3 months, (2) a diligent search
            has failed to reveal his whereabouts, and (3) such person has not
            communicated during such period with other persons who would be
            expected to have heard from him. Evidence of such disappearance must
            be presented to the county committee in the form of a statement
            executed by the person making the application for payment, setting
            forth the above facts, and must be substantiated by a statement from
            a disinterested person who was well acquainted with the person who
            has disappeared.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            30 FR 6246
          </aref>
          , May 5, 1965, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 81835
          </aref>
          , Dec. 29, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6552'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:707:-:707.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        707.5
      </num>
      <head>
        Incompetency.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 81836
        </aref>
        , Dec. 30, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='707' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              707.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Incompetency.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Where any person who would otherwise be eligible to receive a
            payment is adjudged incompetent by a court of competent jurisdiction
            before the payment is received, payment may be released in
            accordance with this section so long as, and only if, a timely and
            binding program application has been filed by the person involved
            while capable or by someone legally authorized to file an
            application for the person involved. Timeliness is determined under
            the relevant program regulations. In all cases, the payment
            application must have been timely under the relevant program
            regulations and all program conditions for payment must have been
            met by or on behalf of the person involved. However, the payment
            will not be made unless, in addition, a separate release application
            is filed in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='707' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
                707.7
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . If these conditions are met, payment may be released without
            regard to the claims of creditors other than the United States, to
            the guardian or committee legally appointed for the person involved.
            In case no guardian or committee had been appointed, payment, if for
            not more than $1,000, may be released without regard to claims of
            creditors other than the United States, to one of the following in
            the following order for the benefit of the person who was the
            subject of the adjudication:
            <PRTPAGE P='22' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The spouse.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An adult son, daughter, or grandchild.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The mother or father.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An adult brother or sister.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Such person as may be authorized under State law to receive payment
            for the person (see standard procedure prescribed for the respective
            region).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In case payment is more than $1,000, payment may be released only
            to such person as may be authorized under State law to receive
            payment for the incompetent, so long as all conditions for other
            payments specified in paragraph (a) of this section and elsewhere in
            the applicable regulations have been met. Those requirements include
            the filing of a proper and timely and legally authorized program
            application by or for the person adjudged incompetent. The release
            of funds under this paragraph will be made without regard to claims
            of creditors other than the United States unless the agency
            determines otherwise.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 81836
          </aref>
          , Dec. 30, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6553'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:707:-:707.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        707.6
      </num>
      <head>
        Death, disappearance, or incompetency of one eligible to apply for
        payment pursuant to the regulations in this part.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          30 FR 6246
        </aref>
        , May 5, 1965, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 81836
        </aref>
        , Dec. 29, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='707' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              707.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Death, disappearance, or incompetency of one eligible to apply for
          payment pursuant to the regulations in this part.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          In case any person entitled to apply for a release of a payment
          pursuant to the provisions of 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='707' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              707.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='707' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              707.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='707' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              707.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , or this section, dies, disappears, or is adjudged incompetent, as
          the case may be, after he has applied for such payment but before the
          payment is received, payment may be made upon proper application
          therefor, without regard to claims of creditors other than the United
          States, to the person next entitled thereto in accordance with the
          order of precedence set forth in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='707' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              707.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='707' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              707.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , or 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='707' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              707.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , as the case may be.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            30 FR 6246
          </aref>
          , May 5, 1965, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 81836
          </aref>
          , Dec. 29, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6554'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:A:707:-:707.7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        707.7
      </num>
      <head>
        Release application.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          30 FR 6246
        </aref>
        , May 5, 1965, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 81836
        </aref>
        , Dec. 29, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='707' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              707.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Release application.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          No payment may be made under this part unless a proper program
          application was filed in accordance with the rules for the program
          that generated the payment. That application must have been timely and
          filed by someone legally authorized to act for the deceased,
          disappeared, or declared-incompetent person. The filer can be the
          party that earned the payment themselves—such as the case of a person
          who filed a program application before they died—or someone legally
          authorized to act for the party that earned the payment. All program
          conditions for payment must have been met before the death,
          disappearance, or incompetency except for the timely filing of the
          application for payment by the person legally authorized to act for
          the party earning the payment. But, further, for the payment to be
          released under the rules of this part, a second application must be
          filed. That second application is a release application filed under
          this section. In particular, as to the latter, where all other
          conditions have been met, persons desiring to claim payment for
          themselves or an estate in accordance with this 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='707' tq='N'>
              707
            </subref>
          </aref>
           must do so by filing a release application on Form FSA-325,
          “Application for Payment of Amounts Due Persons Who Have Died,
          Disappeared or Have Been Declared Incompetent.If the person who died,
          disappeared, or was declared incompetent did not apply for payment by
          filing the applicable program application for payment form, such
          program application for payment must also be filed in accordance with
          applicable regulations. If the payment is made under the Naval Stores
          Conservation Program, Part II of the Form FSA-325 shall be executed by
          the local District Supervisor of the U.S. Forest Service. In
          connection with applications for payment under all other programs
          itemized in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='707' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              707.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , Form FSA-325, and program applications for payments where required,
          shall be filed with the FSA county office where the person who earned
          the payment would have been required to file his application.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            30 FR 6246
          </aref>
          , May 5, 1965, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 81836
          </aref>
          , Dec. 29, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>