<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol1'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:16
    </extid>
    <num>
      16
    </num>
    <head>
      EQUAL OPPORTUNITY FOR RELIGIOUS ORGANIZATIONS
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='5' sect='301' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/5/301.html'>
              5 U.S.C. 301
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; E.O. 13279, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            67 FR 77141, 3
          </aref>
           CFR, 2002 Comp., p. 258; E.O. 13280, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            67 FR 77145, 3
          </aref>
           CFR, 2002 Comp., p. 262.
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            69 FR 41382
          </aref>
          , July 9, 2004, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='732'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:16:-:16.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        16.1
      </num>
      <head>
        Purpose and applicability.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='16' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              16.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Purpose and applicability.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The purpose of this part is to set forth USDA policy regarding
            equal opportunity for religious organizations to participate in USDA
            assistance programs for which other private organizations are
            eligible.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as otherwise specifically provided in this part, the policy
            outlined in this part applies to all recipients and subrecipients of
            USDA assistance to which 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR parts 
              <subref title='7' part='3015' tq='N'>
                3015, 3016
              </subref>
              , or 
              <subref title='7' part='3019' tq='N'>
                3019
              </subref>
            </aref>
             apply, and to recipients and subrecipients of Commodity Credit
            Corporation assistance that is administered by agencies of USDA.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='733'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:16:-:16.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        16.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Rights of religious organizations.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='16' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              16.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Rights of religious organizations.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A religious organization is eligible, on the same basis as any
            other eligible private organization, to access and participate in
            USDA assistance programs. Neither the Federal government nor a State
            or local government receiving USDA assistance shall, in the
            selection of service providers, discriminate for or against a
            religious organization on the basis of the organization&apos;s
            religious character or affiliation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A religious organization that participates in USDA assistance
            programs will retain its independence and may continue to carry out
            its mission, including the definition, practice, and expression of
            its religious beliefs, provided that it does not use USDA direct
            assistance to support any inherently religious activities, such as
            worship, religious instruction, or proselytization. Among other
            things, a religious organization may:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Use space in its facilities to provide services and programs
            without removing religious art, icons, scriptures, or other
            religious symbols,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Retain religious terms in its organization&apos;s name,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Select its board members and otherwise govern itself on a religious
            basis, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Include religious references in its organizations&apos; mission
            statements and other governing documents.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In addition, a religious organization&apos;s exemption from the
            Federal prohibition on employment discrimination on the basis of
            religion, set forth in 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 702(a) of
            </aref>
             the Civil Rights Act of 1964, 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='42' sect='2000e-1' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/42/2000e-1.html'>
                42 U.S.C. 2000e-1
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , is not forfeited when an organization receives USDA assistance.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='734'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:16:-:16.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        16.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Responsibilities of participating organizations.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='16' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              16.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Responsibilities of participating organizations.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An organization that participates in programs and activities
            supported by direct USDA assistance programs shall not discriminate
            against a program beneficiary or prospective program beneficiary on
            the basis of religion or religious belief.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Organizations that receive direct USDA assistance under any USDA
            program may not engage in inherently religious activities, such as
            worship, religious instruction, or proselytization, as part of the
            programs or services supported with direct USDA assistance. If an
            organization conducts such activities, the activities must be
            offered separately, in time or location, from the programs or
            services supported with direct assistance from USDA, and
            participation must be voluntary for beneficiaries of the programs or
            services supported with such direct assistance. These restrictions
            on inherently religious activities do not apply where USDA funds or
            benefits are provided to religious organizations as a result of a
            genuine and independent private choice of a beneficiary or through
            other indirect funding mechanisms, provided the religious
            organizations otherwise satisfy the requirements of the program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Nothing in paragraphs (a) or (b) shall be construed to prevent
            religious organizations that receive USDA assistance under the
            Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act, 42 U.S.C. 
            <PRTPAGE P='482' />
            1751 
            <E T='03'>
              et seq.,
            </E>
             the Child Nutrition Act of 1966, 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='42' sect='1771' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/42/1771.html'>
                42 U.S.C. 1771
              </subref>
            </aref>
            <E T='03'>
              et seq.,
            </E>
             or USDA international school feeding programs from considering
            religion in their admissions practices or from imposing religious
            attendance or curricular requirements at their schools.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Direct USDA assistance may be used for the acquisition,
            construction, or rehabilitation of structures only to the extent
            that those structures are used for conducting USDA programs and
            activities and only to the extent authorized by the applicable
            program statutes and regulations. Direct USDA assistance may not be
            used for the acquisition, construction, or rehabilitation of
            structures to the extent that those structures are used by the USDA
            funding recipients for inherently religious activities. Where a
            structure is used for both eligible and inherently religious
            activities, direct USDA assistance may not exceed the cost of those
            portions of the acquisition, construction, or rehabilitation that
            are attributable to eligible activities in accordance with the cost
            accounting requirements applicable to USDA funds. Sanctuaries,
            chapels, or other rooms that an organization receiving direct
            assistance from USDA uses as its principal place of worship,
            however, are ineligible for USDA-funded improvements. Disposition of
            real property after the term of the grant or any change in use of
            the property during the term of the grant is subject to
            government-wide regulations governing real property disposition (see
            
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR parts 
              <subref title='7' part='3015' tq='N'>
                3015, 3016
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='3019' tq='N'>
                3019
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any use of direct USDA assistance funds for equipment, supplies,
            labor, indirect costs and the like shall be prorated between the
            USDA program or activity and any use for other purposes by the
            religious organization in accordance with applicable laws,
            regulations, and guidance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Nothing in this section shall be construed to prevent the residents
            of housing receiving direct USDA assistance funds from engaging in
            religious exercise within such housing.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='735'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:16:-:16.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        16.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Effect on State and local funds.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='16' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              16.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Effect on State and local funds.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          If a State or local government voluntarily contributes its own funds
          to supplement activities carried out under programs governed by this
          part, the State or local government has the option to separate out the
          direct USDA assistance funds or commingle them. If the funds are
          commingled, the provisions of this part shall apply to all of the
          commingled funds in the same manner, and to the same extent, as the
          provisions apply to the direct USDA assistance.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='736'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:16:-:16.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        16.5
      </num>
      <head>
        Compliance.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='16' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              16.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Compliance.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          USDA agencies will monitor compliance with this part in the course of
          regular oversight of USDA programs.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>