<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol15'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXX:-:3022
    </extid>
    <num>
      3022
    </num>
    <head>
      RESEARCH INSTITUTIONS CONDUCTING USDA-FUNDED EXTRAMURAL RESEARCH; RESEARCH
      MISCONDUCT
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          Office of Science and Technology Policy (
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            65 FR 76260
          </aref>
          ); USDA Secretary&apos;s Memorandum (SM) 2400-007; and USDA OIG, 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR 
            <subref title='7' part='2610' sect='1' psec='#c_4_ix' tq='N'>
              2610.1(c)(4)(ix)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 49359
          </aref>
          , Aug. 13, 2010, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='16202'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXX:-:3022:-:3022.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3022.1
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3022' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              3022.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Adjudication.
          </E>
           The stage in response to an allegation of research misconduct when
          the outcome of the investigation is reviewed, and appropriate
          corrective actions, if any, are determined. Corrective actions
          generally will be administrative in nature, such as termination 
          <PRTPAGE P='236' />
          of an award, debarment, award restrictions, recovery of funds, or
          correction of the research record. However, if there is an indication
          of violation of civil or criminal statutes, civil or criminal
          sanctions may be pursued.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Agency Research Integrity Officer (ARIO).
          </E>
           The individual appointed by a USDA agency that conducts research and
          who is responsible for:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Receiving and processing allegations of research misconduct as
            assigned by the USDA RIO;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Informing OIG and the USDA RIO and the research institution
            associated with the alleged research misconduct, of allegations of
            research misconduct in the event it is reported to the USDA agency;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Ensuring that any records, documents and other materials relating
            to a research misconduct allegation are provided to OIG when
            requested;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Coordinating actions taken to address allegations of research
            misconduct with respect to extramural research with the research
            institution(s) at which time the research misconduct is alleged to
            have occurred, and with the USDA RIO;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Overseeing proceedings to address allegations of extramurally
            funded research misconduct at intramural research institutions and
            research institutions where extramural research occurs;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Ensuring that agency action to address allegations of research
            misconduct at USDA agencies performing extramurally funded research
            is performed at an organizational level that allows an independent,
            unbiased, and equitable process;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Immediately notifying OIG, the USDA RIO, and the applicable
            research institution if:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_7_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Public health or safety is at risk;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_7_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             USDA&apos;s resources, reputation, or other interests need
            protecting;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_7_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Research activities should be suspended;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_7_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Federal action may be needed to protect the interest of a subject
            of the investigation or of others potentially affected;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_7_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A premature public disclosure of the inquiry into or investigation
            of the allegation may compromise the process;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_7_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The scientific community or the public should be informed; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_7_vii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Behavior that is or may be criminal in nature is discovered at any
            point during the inquiry, investigation, or adjudication phases of
            the research misconduct proceedings;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Documenting the dismissal of the allegation, and ensuring that the
            name of the accused individual and/or institution is cleared if an
            allegation of research misconduct is dismissed at any point during
            the inquiry or investigation phase of the proceedings;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Other duties relating to research misconduct proceedings as
            assigned.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Allegation.
          </E>
           A disclosure of possible research misconduct through any means of
          communication. The disclosure may be by written or oral statement, or
          by other means of communication to an institutional or USDA official.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Applied research.
          </E>
           Systematic study to gain knowledge or understanding necessary to
          determine the means by which a recognized and specific need may be
          met.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Assistant Inspector General for Investigations.
          </E>
           The individual in OIG who is responsible for OIG&apos;s domestic and
          foreign investigative operations through a headquarters office and the
          six regional offices.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Basic research.
          </E>
           Systematic study directed toward fuller knowledge or understanding of
          the fundamental aspects of phenomena and of observable facts without
          specific applications towards processes or products in mind.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Extramural research.
          </E>
           Research conducted by any research institution other than the Federal
          agency to which the funds supporting the research were appropriated.
          Research institutions conducting extramural research may include
          Federal research facilities.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Fabrication.
          </E>
           Making up data or results and recording or reporting them.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Falsification.
          </E>
           Manipulating research materials, equipment, or processes, or changing
          or omitting data or results such that the research is not accurately
          represented in the research record.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Finding of research misconduct.
          </E>
           The conclusion, proven by a preponderance of the evidence, that
          research misconduct occurred, that such research misconduct
          represented a significant 
          <PRTPAGE P='237' />
          departure from accepted practices of the relevant research community,
          and that such research misconduct was committed intentionally,
          knowingly, or recklessly.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Inquiry.
          </E>
           The stage in the response to an allegation of research misconduct
          when an assessment is made to determine whether the allegation has
          substance and whether an investigation is warranted.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Intramural research.
          </E>
           Research conducted by a Federal Agency, to which funds were
          appropriated for the purpose of conducting research.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Investigation.
          </E>
           The stage in the response to an allegation of research misconduct
          when the factual record is formally developed and examined to
          determine whether to dismiss the case, recommend a finding of research
          misconduct, and/or take other appropriate remedies.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Office of Inspector General (OIG).
          </E>
           The Office of Inspector General of the United States Department of
          Agriculture.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Office of Science and Technology Policy (OSTP).
          </E>
           The Office of Science and Technology Policy of the Executive Office
          of the President.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Plagiarism.
          </E>
           The appropriation of another person&apos;s ideas, processes, results,
          or words without giving appropriate credit.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Preponderance of the evidence.
          </E>
           Proof by information that, compared with that opposing it, leads to
          the conclusion that the fact at issue is more probably true than not.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Research.
          </E>
           All basic, applied, and demonstration research in all fields of
          science, engineering, and mathematics. This includes, but is not
          limited to, research in economics, education, linguistics, medicine,
          psychology, social sciences, statistics, and research involving human
          subjects or animals regardless of the funding mechanism used to
          support it.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Research institution.
          </E>
           All organizations using Federal funds for research, including, for
          example, colleges and universities, Federally funded research and
          development centers, national user facilities, industrial
          laboratories, or other research institutes.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Research misconduct.
          </E>
           Fabrication, falsification, or plagiarism in proposing, performing,
          or reviewing research, or in reporting research results. Research
          misconduct does not include honest error or differences of opinion.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Research record.
          </E>
           The record of data or results that embody the facts resulting from
          scientific inquiry, and includes, but is not limited to, research
          proposals, research records (including data, notes, journals,
          laboratory records (both physical and electronic)), progress reports,
          abstracts, theses, oral presentations, internal reports, and journal
          articles.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            United States Department of Agriculture.
          </E>
           USDA.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            USDA Research Integrity Officer (USDA RIO).
          </E>
           The individual designated by the Office of the Under Secretary for
          Research, Education, and Economics (REE) who is responsible for:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Overseeing USDA agency responses to allegations of research
            misconduct;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Ensuring that agency research misconduct procedures are consistent
            with this part;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Receiving and assigning allegations of research misconduct reported
            by the public;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Developing Memoranda of Understanding with agencies that elect not
            to develop their own research misconduct procedures;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Monitoring the progress of all research misconduct cases; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Serving as liaison with OIG to receive allegations of research
            misconduct when they are received via the OIG Hotline.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16203'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXX:-:3022:-:3022.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3022.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Procedures.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3022' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              3022.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Procedures.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Research institutions that conduct extramural research funded by USDA
          must foster an atmosphere conducive to research integrity. They must
          develop or have procedures in place to respond to allegations of
          research misconduct that ensure:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Appropriate separations of responsibility for inquiry,
            investigation, and adjudication;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Objectivity;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Due process;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whistleblower protection;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Confidentiality. To the extent possible and consistent with a fair
            and thorough investigation and as allowed by law, knowledge about
            the identity 
            <PRTPAGE P='238' />
            of subjects and informants is limited to those who need to know; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Timely resolution.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16204'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXX:-:3022:-:3022.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3022.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Inquiry, investigation, and adjudication.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3022' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              3022.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Inquiry, investigation, and adjudication.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          A research institution that conducts extramural research funded by
          USDA bears primary responsibility for prevention and detection of
          research misconduct and for the inquiry, investigation, and
          adjudication of research misconduct allegations reported directly to
          it. The research institution must perform an inquiry in response to an
          allegation, and must follow the inquiry with an investigation if the
          inquiry determines that the allegation or apparent instance of
          research misconduct has substance. The responsibilities for
          adjudication must be separate from those for inquiry and
          investigation. In most instances, USDA will rely on a research
          institution conducting extramural research to promptly:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Initiate an inquiry into any suspected or alleged research
            misconduct;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Conduct a subsequent investigation, if warranted;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Acquire, prepare, and maintain appropriate records of allegations
            of extramural research misconduct and all related inquiries,
            investigations, and findings; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Take action to ensure the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The integrity of research;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The rights and interests of the subject of the investigation and
            the public are protected;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The observance of legal requirements or responsibilities including
            cooperation with criminal investigations; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Appropriate safeguards for subjects of allegations, as well as
            informants (see 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='3022' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
                3022.6
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ). These safeguards should include timely written notification of
            subjects regarding substantive allegations made against them; a
            description of all such allegations; reasonable access to the data
            and other evidence supporting the allegations; and the opportunity
            to respond to allegations, the supporting evidence and the proposed
            findings of research misconduct, if any.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16205'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXX:-:3022:-:3022.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3022.4
      </num>
      <head>
        USDA Panel to determine appropriateness of research misconduct policy.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3022' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              3022.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          USDA Panel to determine appropriateness of research misconduct policy.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Before USDA will rely on a research institution to conduct an inquiry,
          investigation, and adjudication of an allegation in accordance with
          this part, the research institution where the research misconduct is
          alleged must provide the ARIO its policies and procedures related to
          research misconduct at the institution. The research institution has
          the option of providing either a written copy of such policies and
          procedures or a Web site address where such policies and procedures
          can be accessed. The ARIO to whom the policies and procedures were
          made available shall convene a panel comprised of the USDA RIO and
          ARIOs from the Forest Service, the Agricultural Research Service, and
          the National Institute of Food and Agriculture. The Panel will review
          the research institution&apos;s policies and procedures for compliance
          with the OSTP Policy and render a decision regarding the research
          institution&apos;s ability to adequately resolve research misconduct
          allegations. The ARIO will inform the research institution of the
          Panel&apos;s determination that its inquiry, investigation, and
          adjudication procedures are sufficient. If the Panel determines that
          the research institution does not have sufficient policies and
          procedures in place to conduct inquiry, investigation, and
          adjudication proceedings, or that the research institution is in any
          way unfit or unprepared to handle the inquiry, investigation, and
          adjudication in a prompt, unbiased, fair, and independent manner, the
          ARIO will inform the research institution in writing of the
          Panel&apos;s decision. An appropriate USDA agency, as determined by
          the Panel, will then conduct the inquiry, investigation, and
          adjudication of research misconduct in accordance with this part. If
          an allegation of research misconduct is made regarding extramural
          research conducted at a Federal research institution (whether USDA or
          not), it is presumed that the Federal research institution has
          research misconduct procedures consistent with the OSTP Policy. USDA
          reserves the right to convene the Panel to assess the sufficiency of a
          Federal agency&apos;s research 
          <PRTPAGE P='239' />
          misconduct procedures, should there be any question whether the
          agency&apos;s procedures will ensure a fair, unbiased, equitable, and
          independent inquiry, investigation, and adjudication process.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16206'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXX:-:3022:-:3022.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3022.5
      </num>
      <head>
        Reservation of right to conduct subsequent inquiry, investigation, and
        adjudication.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3022' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              3022.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Reservation of right to conduct subsequent inquiry, investigation, and
          adjudication.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             USDA reserves the right to conduct its own inquiry, investigation,
            and adjudication into allegations of research misconduct at a
            research institution conducting extramural research subsequent to
            the proceedings of the research institution related to the same
            allegation. This may be necessary if the USDA RIO or ARIO believes,
            in his or her sound discretion, that despite the Panel&apos;s
            finding that the research institution in question had appropriate
            and OSTP-compliant research misconduct procedures in place, the
            research institution conducting the extramural research at issue:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Did not adhere to its own research misconduct procedures;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Did not conduct research misconduct proceedings in a fair,
            unbiased, or independent manner; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Has not completed research misconduct inquiry, investigation, or
            adjudication in a timely manner.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Additionally, USDA reserves the right to conduct its own inquiry,
            investigation, and adjudication into allegations of research
            misconduct at a research institution conducting extramural research
            subsequent to the proceedings of the research institution related to
            the same allegation for any other reason that the USDA RIO or ARIO
            considers it appropriate to conduct research misconduct proceedings
            in lieu of the research institution&apos;s conducting the extramural
            research at issue. This right is subject to paragraph (c) of this
            section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In cases where the USDA RIO or ARIO believes it is necessary for
            USDA to conduct its own inquiry, investigation, and adjudication
            subsequent to the proceedings of the research institution related to
            the same allegation, the USDA RIO or ARIO shall reconvene the Panel,
            which will determine whether it is appropriate for the relevant USDA
            agency to conduct the research misconduct proceedings related to the
            allegation(s) of research misconduct. If the Panel determines that
            it is appropriate for a USDA agency to conduct the proceedings, the
            ARIO will immediately notify the research institution in question.
            The research institution must then promptly provide the relevant
            USDA agency with documentation of the research misconduct
            proceedings the research institution has conducted to that point,
            and the USDA agency will conduct research misconduct proceedings in
            accordance with the Agency research misconduct procedures.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16207'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXX:-:3022:-:3022.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3022.6
      </num>
      <head>
        Notification of USDA of allegations of research misconduct.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3022' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              3022.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Notification of USDA of allegations of research misconduct.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Research institutions that conduct USDA-funded extramural research
            must promptly notify OIG and the USDA RIO of all allegations of
            research misconduct involving USDA funds when the institution
            inquiry into the allegation warrants the institution moving on to an
            investigation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Individuals at research institutions who suspect research
            misconduct at the institution should report allegations in
            accordance with the institution&apos;s research misconduct policies
            and procedures. Anyone else who suspects that researchers or
            research institutions performing federally-funded research may have
            engaged in research misconduct is encouraged to make a formal
            allegation of research misconduct to OIG.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             OIG may be notified using any of the following methods:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Via the OIG Hotline: Telephone: (202) 690-1622, (800) 424-9121,
            (202) 690-1202 (TDD).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             E-mail: 
            <E T='03'>
              usda_hotline@oig.usda.gov.
            </E>
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             U.S. Mail: United States Department of Agriculture, Office of
            Inspector General, P.O. Box 23399, Washington, DC 20026-3399.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The USDA RIO may be reached at: USDA Research Integrity Officer,
            214W Whitten Building, Washington, DC 20250; telephone:
            202-720-5923; E-mail: 
            <E T='03'>
              researchintegrity@usda.gov.
            </E>
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To the extent known, the following details should be included in
            any formal allegation:
            <PRTPAGE P='240' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The name of the research projects involved, the nature of the
            alleged misconduct, and the names of the individual or individuals
            alleged to be involved in the misconduct;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The source or sources of funding for the research project or
            research projects involved in the alleged misconduct;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Important dates;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any documentation that bears upon the allegation; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any other potentially relevant information.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Safeguards for informants give individuals the confidence that they
            can bring allegations of research misconduct made in good faith to
            the attention of appropriate authorities or serve as informants to
            an inquiry or an investigation without suffering retribution.
            Safeguards include protection against retaliation for informants who
            make good faith allegations, fair and objective procedures for the
            examination and resolution of allegations of research misconduct,
            and diligence in protecting the positions and reputations of those
            persons who make allegations of research misconduct in good faith.
            The identity of informants who wish to remain anonymous will be kept
            confidential to the extent permitted by law or regulation.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16208'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXX:-:3022:-:3022.7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3022.7
      </num>
      <head>
        Notification of ARIO during an inquiry or investigation.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3022' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              3022.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Notification of ARIO during an inquiry or investigation.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Research institutions that conduct USDA-funded extramural research
            must promptly notify the ARIO should the institution become aware
            during an inquiry or investigation that:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Public health or safety is at risk;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The resources, reputation, or other interests of USDA are in need
            of protection;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Research activities should be suspended;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Federal action may be needed to protect the interest of a subject
            of the investigation or of others potentially affected;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A premature public disclosure of the inquiry into or investigation
            of the allegation may compromise the process;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The scientific community or the public should be informed; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             There is reasonable indication of possible violations of civil or
            criminal law.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If research misconduct proceedings reveal behavior that may be
            criminal in nature at any point during the proceedings, the
            institution must promptly notify the ARIO.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16209'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXX:-:3022:-:3022.8
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3022.8
      </num>
      <head>
        Communication of research misconduct policies and procedures.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3022' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              3022.8
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Communication of research misconduct policies and procedures.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Institutions that conduct USDA-funded extramural research are to
          maintain and effectively communicate to their staffs policies and
          procedures relating to research misconduct, including the guidelines
          in this part. The institution is to inform their researchers and staff
          members who conduct USDA-funded extramural research when and under
          what circumstances USDA is to be notified of allegations of research
          misconduct, and when and under what circumstances USDA is to be
          updated on research misconduct proceedings.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16210'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXX:-:3022:-:3022.9
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3022.9
      </num>
      <head>
        Documents required.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3022' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
              3022.9
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Documents required.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A research institution that conducts USDA-funded extramural
            research must maintain the following documents related to an
            allegation of research misconduct at the research institution:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A written statement describing the original allegation;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A copy of the formal notification presented to the subject of the
            allegation;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A written report describing the inquiry stage and its outcome
            including copies of all supporting documentation;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A description of the methods and procedures used to gather and
            evaluate information pertinent to the alleged misconduct during
            inquiry and investigation stages;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A written report of the investigation, including the evidentiary
            record and supporting documentation;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A written statement of the findings; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If applicable, a statement of recommended corrective actions, and
            any response to such a statement by the subject of the original
            allegation, and/or other interested parties, including any
            corrective action plan.
            <PRTPAGE P='241' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The research institution must retain the documents specified in
            paragraph (a) of this section for at least 3 years following the
            final adjudication of the alleged research misconduct.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16211'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXX:-:3022:-:3022.10
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3022.10
      </num>
      <head>
        Reporting to USDA.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3022' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
              3022.10
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Reporting to USDA.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Following completion of an investigation into allegations of research
          misconduct, the institution conducting extramural research must
          provide to the ARIO a copy of the evidentiary record, the report of
          the investigation, recommendations made to the institution&apos;s
          adjudicating official, the adjudicating official&apos;s determination,
          the institution&apos;s corrective action taken or planned, and the
          written response of the individual who is the subject of the
          allegation to any recommendations.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16212'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXX:-:3022:-:3022.11
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3022.11
      </num>
      <head>
        Research records and evidence.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3022' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
              3022.11
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Research records and evidence.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A research institution that conducts extramural research supported
            by USDA funds, as the responsible legal entity for the
            USDA-supported research, has a continuing obligation to create and
            maintain adequate records (including documents and other evidentiary
            matter) as may be required by any subsequent inquiry, investigation,
            finding, adjudication, or other proceeding.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whenever an investigation is initiated, the research institution
            must promptly take all reasonable and practical steps to obtain
            custody of all relevant research records and evidence as may be
            necessary to conduct the research misconduct proceedings. This must
            be accomplished before the research institution notifies the
            researcher/respondent of the allegation, or immediately thereafter.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The original research records and evidence taken into custody by
            the research institution shall be inventoried and stored in a secure
            place and manner. Research records involving raw data shall include
            the devices or instruments on which they reside. However, if deemed
            appropriate by the research institution or investigator, research
            data or records that reside on or in instruments or devices may be
            copied and removed from those instruments or devices as long as the
            copies are complete, accurate, and have substantially equivalent
            evidentiary value as the data or records have when the data or
            records reside on the instruments or devices. Such copies of data or
            records shall be made by a disinterested, qualified technician and
            not by the subject of the original allegation or other interested
            parties. When the relevant data or records have been removed from
            the devices or instruments, the instruments or devices need not be
            maintained as evidence.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16213'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXX:-:3022:-:3022.12
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3022.12
      </num>
      <head>
        Remedies for noncompliance.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3022' sect='12' psec='' tq='N'>
              3022.12
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Remedies for noncompliance.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          USDA agencies&apos; implementation procedures identify the
          administrative actions available to remedy a finding of research
          misconduct. Such actions may include the recovery of funds, correction
          of the research record, debarment of the researcher(s) that engaged in
          the research misconduct, proper attribution, or any other action
          deemed appropriate to remedy the instance(s) of research misconduct.
          The agency should consider the seriousness of the misconduct,
          including, but not limited to, the degree to which the misconduct was
          knowingly conducted, intentional, or reckless; was an isolated event
          or part of a pattern; or had significant impact on the research
          record, research subjects, other researchers, institutions, or the
          public welfare. In determining the appropriate administrative action,
          the appropriate agency must impose a remedy that is commensurate with
          the infraction as described in the finding of research misconduct.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16214'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXX:-:3022:-:3022.13
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3022.13
      </num>
      <head>
        Appeals.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3022' sect='13' psec='' tq='N'>
              3022.13
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Appeals.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If USDA relied on an institution to conduct an inquiry,
            investigation, and adjudication, the alleged person(s) should first
            follow the institution&apos;s appeal policy and procedures.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             USDA agencies&apos; implementation procedures identify the appeal
            process when a finding of research misconduct is elevated to the
            agency.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16215'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXX:-:3022:-:3022.14
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3022.14
      </num>
      <head>
        Relationship to other requirements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3022' sect='14' psec='' tq='N'>
              3022.14
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Relationship to other requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Some of the research covered by this part also may be subject to
          regulations of other governmental agencies (e.g., a university that
          receives funding from a USDA agency and also under a grant from
          another Federal agency). If more 
          <PRTPAGE P='242' />
          than one agency of the Federal Government has jurisdiction, USDA will
          cooperate with the other Agency(ies) in designating a lead agency.
          When USDA is not the lead agency, it will rely on the lead agency
          following its policies and procedures in determining whether there is
          a finding of research misconduct. Further, USDA may, in consultation
          with the lead agency, take action to protect the health and safety of
          the public, to promote the integrity of the USDA-supported research
          and research process, or to conserve public funds. When appropriate,
          USDA will seek to resolve allegations jointly with the other agency or
          agencies.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>