<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol10'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XV:-:1530
    </extid>
    <num>
      1530
    </num>
    <head>
      THE REFINED SUGAR RE-EXPORT PROGRAM, THE SUGAR CONTAINING PRODUCTS
      RE-EXPORT PROGRAM, AND THE POLYHYDRIC ALCOHOL PROGRAM
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          Additional U.S. note 6 to chapter 17 of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule
          of the United States (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='19' sect='1202' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/19/1202.html'>
              19 U.S.C. 1202
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ); 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='19' sect='3314' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/19/3314.html'>
              19 U.S.C. 3314
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; Proc. 6641, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 66867, 3
          </aref>
           CFR, 1994 Comp., p. 172; Proc. 6763, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            60 FR 1007, 3
          </aref>
           CFR, 1995 Comp., p. 146.
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            64 FR 7062
          </aref>
          , Feb. 12, 1999, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='13280'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XV:-:1530:-:1530.100
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1530.100
      </num>
      <head>
        General statement.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1530' sect='100' psec='' tq='N'>
              1530.100
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General statement.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          This part provides regulations for the Refined Sugar Re-Export
          Program, the Sugar Containing Products Re-Export Program, and the
          Polyhydric Alcohol Program. Under these provisions, refiners may enter
          raw sugar unrestricted by the quantitative limit established for the
          raw sugar tariff-rate quota or the requirements of certificates of
          quota eligibility provided for in 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            15 CFR part 
            <subref title='15' part='2011' tq='N'>
              2011
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , as long as licensees under the programs export an equivalent
          quantity of refined sugar, either as refined sugar or as an ingredient
          in sugar containing products, or use the refined sugar in the
          production of certain polyhydric alcohols.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13281'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XV:-:1530:-:1530.101
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1530.101
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1530' sect='101' psec='' tq='N'>
              1530.101
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Affiliated persons
          </E>
           means two or more persons where one or more of said persons directly
          or indirectly controls or has the power to control the other(s), or, a
          third person controls or has the power to control the others.
          Indications of control include, but are not limited to: interlocking
          management or ownership, identity of interests among family members,
          shared facilities and equipment, and common use of employees.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Agent
          </E>
           means a person who represents the licensee in any program
          transaction. An agent shall not, at any time, own any of the product
          produced by the program licensee. Agents may include brokers,
          shippers, freight forwarders, expediters, and co-packers.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Bond or letter of credit
          </E>
           means an insurance agreement pledging surety for the entry of foreign
          sugar without the required re-export within the program guidelines.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Certain polyhydric alcohols
          </E>
           means any polyhydric alcohol, except polyhydric alcohol produced by
          distillation or polyhydric alcohol used as a substitute for sugar as a
          sweetener in human food.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Co-packer
          </E>
           means a person who adds value to a licensed manufacturer&apos;s
          product, or produces a product for export by a licensed manufacturer.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Date of entry
          </E>
           means the date raw sugar enters the U.S. Customs Territory.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Date of export
          </E>
           means the date refined sugar or sugar containing products are
          exported from the U.S. Customs Territory, or, if exported to a
          restricted foreign trade zone, the date shown on the U.S. Customs
          Service form designating the product as restricted for export.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Date of transfer
          </E>
           means the date that ownership of program sugar is conveyed from a
          refiner to a manufacturer or producer licensee.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Day
          </E>
           means calendar day. When the day for complying with an obligation
          under this part falls on a weekend or Federal holiday, the obligation
          may be completed on the next business day.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Documentation agreement
          </E>
           means a signed and notarized letter from a licensee specifying
          certain documentation that the licensee shall obtain and maintain on
          file before said licensee requests from USDA updating of a license
          balance.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Enter or entry
          </E>
           means importation into the U.S. Customs Territory, or withdrawal from
          warehouse for consumption, as those terms are used by the U.S. Customs
          Service.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Export
          </E>
           means the conveyance (shipment) of sugar or a sugar containing
          product from a licensee under this part to a country outside the U.S.
          Customs Territory, or to a restricted foreign trade zone.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Licensing Authority
          </E>
           means a person designated by the Director, Import Policies and
          Programs Division, Foreign Agricultural Service, USDA.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Manufacturer
          </E>
           means a person who produces or causes to be produced on their behalf
          a sugar containing product for export under the provisions of this
          part.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Person
          </E>
           means any individual, partnership, corporation, association, estate,
          trust, or any other business enterprise or legal entity.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Program sugar
          </E>
           means sugar that has been charged or credited to the license 
          <PRTPAGE P='1027' />
          of a licensee in conformity with the provisions of this part.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Program transaction
          </E>
           means an appropriate entry, transfer, use, or export of program
          sugar.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Refined sugar
          </E>
           means any product that is produced by a refiner by refining raw cane
          sugar and that can be marketed as commercial, industrial or retail
          sugar.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Refiner
          </E>
           means any person in the U.S. Customs Territory that refines raw cane
          sugar through affination or defecation, clarification, and further
          purification by absorption or crystallization.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Sugar containing product
          </E>
           means any product, other than those products normally marketed by
          cane sugar refiners, that is produced from refined sugar or to which
          refined sugar has been added as an ingredient.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Transfer
          </E>
           means the transfer of legal title of program sugar from a licensed
          refiner to a licensed manufacturer of a sugar containing product or a
          licensed producer of certain polyhydric alcohols for the production of
          sugar containing products or the production of certain polyhydric
          alcohols.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Unique number
          </E>
           means a tracking number established by a licensee for a transaction
          (entry, transfer, export, or use). A unique number is established for
          a transaction to or from a specific country or licensee. The unique
          number is also assigned by the licensee to a file that contains all of
          the supporting documentation for the transaction for which it was
          established. The unique number is the means by which program
          transactions will be tracked.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13282'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XV:-:1530:-:1530.102
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1530.102
      </num>
      <head>
        Nature of the license.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1530' sect='102' psec='' tq='N'>
              1530.102
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Nature of the license.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A person who wishes to participate in the Refined Sugar Re-export
            Program, the Sugar Containing Products Re-export Program, or the
            Polyhydric Alcohol Program must first obtain a license from the
            USDA, through the Licensing Authority.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A license under the Refined Sugar Re-export Program permits a
            refiner to enter raw cane sugar under subheading 1701.11.20 of the
            HTS, and export an equivalent quantity of refined sugar onto the
            world market or transfer an equivalent quantity of refined sugar to
            licensees under the Sugar Containing Products Re-export Program or
            the Polyhydric Alcohol Program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A license under the Sugar Containing Products Re-export Program or
            Polyhydric Alcohol Program permits licensees to receive transfers
            and export an equivalent quantity of sugar as an ingredient in sugar
            containing products, or use an equivalent quantity of sugar in the
            production of certain polyhydric alcohols.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All refining, manufacturing, and production shall be accomplished
            in the U.S. Customs Territory, and within time-frames and quantity
            limitations prescribed in this part. Program sugar and non-program
            sugar are substitutable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A licensee must establish a bond or a letter of credit in favor of
            the U.S. Department of Agriculture to charge program sugar in
            anticipation of the export or transfer of refined sugar, the export
            of sugar in sugar containing products, or the production of certain
            polyhydric alcohols.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13283'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XV:-:1530:-:1530.103
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1530.103
      </num>
      <head>
        License eligibility.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1530' sect='103' psec='' tq='N'>
              1530.103
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          License eligibility.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A raw cane sugar refiner, a manufacturer of sugar containing
            products, or a producer of certain polyhydric alcohols, that owns
            and operates a facility within the U.S. Customs Territory, is
            eligible for a license to participate in the Refined Sugar Re-export
            Program, the Sugar Containing Products Re-export Program, or the
            Polyhydric Alcohol Program, respectively.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No person may apply for or hold more than one license, including a
            license held by an affiliated person.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notwithstanding paragraph (b) of this section, a person who owns
            one or more wholly-owned subsidiary corporations manufacturing sugar
            containing products or producing certain polyhydric alcohols, which
            would otherwise qualify for an individual license, is eligible for a
            consolidated license to cover the program transactions and other
            program activities of both the parent corporation and the subsidiary
            corporation(s). The program transactions and other program
            activities of the subsidiary corporation(s) covered by a
            consolidated license shall be treated as the activities of the
            corporation holding the consolidated license.
            <PRTPAGE P='1028' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notwithstanding paragraph (c) of this section, each wholly-owned
            subsidiary manufacturing sugar containing products or producing
            certain polyhydric alcohols may establish a license for program
            activities instead of the parent corporation establishing a
            consolidated license. The sum total of license limits for the parent
            corporation and its wholly-owned subsidiary corporation(s) shall not
            exceed the quantitative limits established in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1530' sect='105' psec='' tq='N'>
                1530.105
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13284'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XV:-:1530:-:1530.104
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1530.104
      </num>
      <head>
        Application for a license.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1530' sect='104' psec='' tq='N'>
              1530.104
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Application for a license.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A person seeking a license shall apply in writing to the Licensing
            Authority and shall submit the following information:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The name and address of the applicant;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The address at which the applicant will maintain the records
            required under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1530' sect='110' psec='' tq='N'>
                1530.110
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The address(es) of the applicant&apos;s processing plant(s),
            including any wholly-owned subsidiary(s) and plant(s) in the case of
            a consolidated license, and including those of any co-packer(s);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the case of a refined sugar product, the polarity of the product
            and the formula proposed by the refiner for calculating the refined
            sugar in the product;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the case of a sugar containing product, the percentage of
            refined sugar (100 degree polarity), on a dry weight basis,
            contained in such product(s);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the case of polyhydric alcohol, the quantity of refined sugar
            used producing certain polyhydric alcohols; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A certification explaining that the applicant is not affiliated
            with any other licensee, or explaining any affiliations, should they
            exist.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A documentation agreement must be concluded with the Licensing
            Authority.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If any of the information required by paragraph (a) of this section
            changes, the licensee shall promptly apply to the Licensing
            Authority to amend the application to include such changes.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13285'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XV:-:1530:-:1530.105
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1530.105
      </num>
      <head>
        Terms and conditions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1530' sect='105' psec='' tq='N'>
              1530.105
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Terms and conditions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A licensed refiner (refiner) shall, not later than 90 days after
            entering a quantity of raw cane sugar under subheading 1701.11.20 of
            the HTS, export or transfer an equivalent quantity of refined sugar
            if the entry results in a positive license balance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A licensed sugar containing products manufacturer (manufacturer) or
            a licensed polyhydric alcohol producer (producer) shall, not later
            than 18 months from the date of transfer of a quantity of refined
            sugar from a refiner, export an equivalent quantity of refined sugar
            as an ingredient in a sugar containing product if the transfer
            results in a positive license balance, or use an equivalent quantity
            of refined sugar in the production of certain polyhydric alcohols if
            the transfer results in a positive license balance, respectively.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notwithstanding paragraphs (a) and (b) of this section, licensees
            may receive credit for the exportation or transfer of refined sugar,
            the exportation of a sugar containing product, or the production of
            certain polyhydric alcohols prior to the corresponding date of entry
            of raw cane sugor the date of transfer of refined sugar.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Licensees are encouraged to submit monthly program transaction
            reports, but shall report no later than 90 days from the date of
            entry, transfer, export, or use.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A refiner may enter raw sugar, or a manufacturer or producer may
            receive a transfer of refined sugar, in anticipation of the transfer
            or export of refined sugar (refiner), the export of sugar in sugar
            containing products (manufacturer) or the production of a polyhydric
            alcohol (producer) not to exceed the value of a bond or letter of
            credit, which must be established pursuant to 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1530' sect='107' psec='' tq='N'>
                1530.107
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
            . The value of a bond or letter of credit shall not exceed the
            license limits established in this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A refiner shall not exceed a license balance of 50,000 metric tons,
            raw value for the sum of all charges and credits.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A refiner may enter raw sugar from Mexico and re-export, within 30
            days of entry, refined sugar to Mexico without a charge against the
            refiner&apos;s 
            <PRTPAGE P='1029' />
            license balance. If the refined sugar is not re-exported to Mexico
            within 30 days of entry, the license shall be charged the quantity
            that has not been re-exported.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A manufacturer or a producer shall not exceed a license balance of
            10,000 short tons, refined value for the sum of all charges and
            credits.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A manufacturer&apos;s or a producer&apos;s consolidated license
            balance, or the sum of a parent company and wholly-owned subsidiary
            license balances if held separately, shall not exceed a license
            balance of 25,000 short tons, refined value for the sum of all
            charges and credits.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For the purposes of the programs governed by this part, sugar is
            fully substitutable. The refined sugar transferred, exported, or
            used does not need to be the same sugar produced by refining raw
            sugar entered under subheading 1701.11.20 of the HTS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A licensee may use an agent to carry out the requirements of
            participation in the program. The licensee must retain ownership of
            and responsibility for the product until exported from the U.S.
            Customs Territory, to a restricted foreign trade zone, or used in
            the production of certain polyhydric alcohols, and must establish
            and maintain sufficient documentation, as agreed in the
            documentation agreement pursuant to 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1530' sect='110' psec='' tq='N'>
                1530.110
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , to substantiate export of the product or the production of certain
            polyhydric alcohols.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='l'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (l)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A license may be assigned only with the written permission of the
            Licensing Authority and subject to such terms and conditions as the
            Licensing Authority may impose.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='m'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (m)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Licensing Authority may impose such conditions, limitations or
            restrictions in connection with the use of a license at such time
            and in such manner as the Licensing Authority, at his or her
            discretion, determines to be necessary or appropriate to achieve the
            purposes of the relevant program.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13286'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XV:-:1530:-:1530.106
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1530.106
      </num>
      <head>
        License charges and credits.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1530' sect='106' psec='' tq='N'>
              1530.106
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          License charges and credits.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A license shall be charged or credited for the quantity of sugar
            entered, transferred, exported, or used, adjusted to a dry weight
            basis. Refiner quantities shall be adjusted to raw value, using the
            formulas set forth in paragraphs (a) (1), (2), and (3) of this
            section. Manufacturer and producer quantities shall be adjusted to
            100 degrees polarity on a dry weight basis.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To adjust the raw value for sugar with a polarization of less than
            92 degrees, divide the total sugar content by 0.972 (polarization ×
            outturn weight/.972).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To adjust the raw value for sugar with polarization of 92 degrees
            or above, multiply the polarization times 0.0175, subtract 0.68, and
            multiply the difference by the outturn weight (((polarization ×
            0.0175)−0.68) × outturn weight).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To determine the quantity of refined sugar that must be transferred
            or exported to equal a corresponding quantity of entered raw sugar
            charged to a license, divide the quantity of entered raw sugar by
            1.07 (raw quantity/1.07).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             [Reserved]
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13287'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XV:-:1530:-:1530.107
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1530.107
      </num>
      <head>
        Bond or letter of credit requirements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1530' sect='107' psec='' tq='N'>
              1530.107
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Bond or letter of credit requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The licensee may charge program sugar in anticipation of the
            transfer or export of refined sugar, the export of sugar in sugar
            containing products, or the production of certain polyhydric
            alcohols, if the licensee establishes a performance bond or a letter
            of credit with the U.S. Department of Agriculture, which meets the
            criteria set forth in this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The bond or letter of credit may cover entries made either during
            the period of time specified in the bond (a term bond) or for a
            specified entry (a single entry bond).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Only the licensee who will refine the sugar, manufacture the sugar
            containing product, or produce certain polyhydric alcohols may be
            the principal on the bond or letter of credit covering such sugar to
            be re-exported or used in the production of certain polyhydric
            alcohols. The surety or sureties shall be among those listed by the
            Secretary of the Treasury as acceptable on Federal bonds.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The obligation under the bond or letter of credit shall be made
            effective no later than the date of entry of the 
            <PRTPAGE P='1030' />
            sugar for refiners or the date of transfer of the corresponding
            sugar for manufacture into a sugar containing product or certain
            polyhydric alcohols.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The amount of the bond or letter of credit shall be equal to 20
            cents per pound of sugar to be entered under the license.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a licensee fails to qualify for credit to a license within the
            specified time period of the date of export or use of corresponding
            sugar in an amount sufficient to offset the charge to the license
            for that corresponding sugar, payment shall be made to the U.S.
            Treasury. The payment shall be equal to the difference between the
            Number 11 contract price and the Number 14 contract price (New York
            Coffee, Sugar and Cocoa Exchange) in effect on the last market day
            before the date of entry of the sugar or the last market day before
            the end of the period during which export or use was required,
            whichever difference is greater. The difference shall be multiplied
            by the quantity of refined sugar, converted to raw value, that
            should have been exported in compliance with this part. If there was
            not a Number 11, or a Number 14 contract price for the relevant
            market day, the Licensing Authority may estimate such price as he or
            she deems appropriate.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13288'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XV:-:1530:-:1530.108
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1530.108
      </num>
      <head>
        Revocation or surrender of licenses.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1530' sect='108' psec='' tq='N'>
              1530.108
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Revocation or surrender of licenses.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A license may be revoked upon written notice by the Licensing
            Authority.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A licensee may surrender a license when the sum of all credits is
            equal to or greater than the sum of all charges.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13289'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XV:-:1530:-:1530.109
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1530.109
      </num>
      <head>
        Reporting.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1530' sect='109' psec='' tq='N'>
              1530.109
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Reporting.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A licensee may submit as often as monthly for charges and credits
            against a license balance, but must submit at least a quarterly
            report to the Licensing Authority not later than 90 days after the
            earliest transaction in the report for which credits or charges are
            being submitted. The licensee need not report when there have not
            been transactions during the reporting period.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Reports may be submitted by e-mail, U.S. mail, private courier, or
            in person, but must be in an integrated database format acceptable
            to the Licensing Authority. A copy of this format may be obtained
            from the Licensing Authority. Applicants unable to submit a report
            in the specified electronic format may seek a temporary waiver to
            permit them to submit the report on paper.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The reports must include the following for all program
            transactions:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A unique number associated with the transaction;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The date of the entry, transfer (only a refiner shall report
            transfers to the Licensing Authority), export, or use;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The quantity of program sugar entered, transferred, exported as
            refined sugar, or used in the production of certain polyhydric
            alcohols;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The licensee&apos;s license number, or if a transfer is being
            reported, the licensee&apos;s license number as well as the transfer
            recipient&apos;s license number;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The country of origin (entry of raw sugar) or final destination
            (refined exports), using the exact country code designated in the
            HTS; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The initial and final polarization, and final weight (when
            available) for entries of raw sugar.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Licensees have an affirmative and continuing duty to maintain the
            accuracy of the information contained in previously submitted
            reports.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The licensee shall immediately notify the Licensing Authority and
            promptly request that previously claimed credits be charged back
            upon discovery that previously claimed exports of refined sugar,
            refined sugar in sugar containing products, or refined sugar used in
            the production of polyhydric alcohol were re-entered into the U.S.
            Customs Territory without substantial transformation, not used in
            the production of certain polyhydric alcohols, made under a false
            underlying proof of export, or made but previously submitted exports
            do not otherwise satisfy the requirements of regulations or the
            documentation agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Charge backs shall be as of the date of the erroneously claimed
            credit.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13290'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XV:-:1530:-:1530.110
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1530.110
      </num>
      <head>
        Records, certification, and documentation.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='1031' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1530' sect='110' psec='' tq='N'>
              1530.110
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Records, certification, and documentation.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A licensee shall establish a documentation agreement with the
            Licensing Authority before submitting for credit against a license.
            The licensee shall propose to the Licensing Authority a list of
            documents to substantiate entries, transfers, exports, or use as
            appropriate. The Licensing Authority shall consider the
            licensee&apos;s proposal to assure that it provides that a program
            transaction is fully substantiated, and shall then respond in
            writing to the licensee in a timely fashion outlining any
            deficiencies. Once agreed, the licensee shall submit a notarized
            letter specifying the documents to be maintained on file and
            certifying that the charges and credits made pursuant to 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1530' sect='106' psec='' tq='N'>
                1530.106
              </subref>
            </aref>
             will be kept on file, identifiable by a unique number, and
            available for inspection pursuant to 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1530' sect='110' psec='' tq='N'>
                1530.110
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For all transactions, the documentation shall:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Substantiate the information required in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1530' sect='109' psec='#c' tq='N'>
                1530.109 (c)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , and the completion of the reported transaction;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Establish the buyer and seller specifications for a transaction;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Include all U.S. Customs forms submitted in the entry or export
            process;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provide the correct telephone numbers and addresses of any agents,
            consignees, foreign purchasers, and non-vessel operating common
            carriers used in completing the transaction;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Indicate the port of entry or export for the program transaction;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provide the percentage of sugar in a sugar containing product or
            certain polyhydric alcohols; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provide the name of export carrier, vessel name, and container
            number.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The licensee shall maintain the documentation established in the
            documentation agreement for 5 years from the date of such program
            transaction.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon request, the licensee shall make the records, outlined by the
            documentation agreement and identified (associated) by the unique
            number assigned by the licensee to the program transaction as
            reported to the Licensing Authority for posting against a license
            balance, available for inspection and copying by the Licensing
            Authority, the Compliance Review Staff of the Foreign Agricultural
            Service, and/or the Office of the Inspector General, USDA, the U.S.
            Department of Justice, or any U.S. Government regulatory or
            investigative office.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13291'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XV:-:1530:-:1530.111
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1530.111
      </num>
      <head>
        Enforcement and penalties.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1530' sect='111' psec='' tq='N'>
              1530.111
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Enforcement and penalties.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Licensing Authority may revoke credits granted on a license if
            the credits granted do not meet the requirements set forth in the
            regulations of this part, or if the licensee does not voluntarily
            charge back credits erroneously claimed in accordance with these
            regulations. The Licensing Authority may also recommend revocation
            of a license, if the licensee has been in violation of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1530' sect='109' psec='#c' tq='N'>
                1530.109 (c)
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Administrator of the Foreign Agricultural Service, USDA, may
            suspend or revoke a license upon recommendation of the Licensing
            Authority. Suspension of a license will be governed by 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3017' tq='N'>
                3017
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , subpart D and debarment will be governed by 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3017' tq='N'>
                3017
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , subpart C.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13292'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XV:-:1530:-:1530.112
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1530.112
      </num>
      <head>
        Administrative appeals.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1530' sect='112' psec='' tq='N'>
              1530.112
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Administrative appeals.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The licensee may appeal the Licensing Authority&apos;s
            determination by filing a written notice of appeal, signed by the
            licensee or the licensee&apos;s agent, with the Director, Import
            Policies and Programs Division, Foreign Agricultural Service
            (Director), or his or her designee. The decision on such an appeal
            shall be made by the Director, and will be governed by 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='3017' sect='515' psec='' tq='N'>
                3017.515
              </subref>
               of this title
            </aref>
            . The appeal must be filed not later than 30 days after the date of
            the Licensing Authority&apos;s determination, and shall contain the
            licensee&apos;s written argument.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The licensee may request an informal hearing. The Director shall
            arrange a place and time for the hearing, except that it shall be
            held within 30 days of the filing date of the notice of appeal if
            the licensee so requests.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The licensee may be represented by counsel, and shall have full
            opportunity to present any relevant evidence, documentary or
            testimonial. The Director may permit other individuals to present
            evidence at the hearing and the licensee shall have an opportunity
            to question those witnesses.
            <PRTPAGE P='1032' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The licensee may request a verbatim transcript of the hearing, and
            shall be responsible for arranging for a professional reporter and
            shall pay all attendant expenses.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Director shall make the determination on appeal, and may
            affirm, reverse, modify or remand the Licensing Authority&apos;s
            determination. The Director shall notify the licensee in writing of
            the determination on appeal and of the basis thereof. The
            determination on appeal exhausts the licensee&apos;s administrative
            remedies.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13293'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XV:-:1530:-:1530.113
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1530.113
      </num>
      <head>
        Waivers.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1530' sect='113' psec='' tq='N'>
              1530.113
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Waivers.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Upon written application of the licensee or at the discretion of the
          Licensing Authority, and for good cause, the Licensing Authority may
          extend the period for transfer, export, or production, and/or may
          temporarily increase a maximum license limit, may extend the period
          for submitting regularly scheduled reports, or may temporarily waive
          or modify any other requirement imposed by this part if the Licensing
          Authority determines that such a waiver will not undermine the purpose
          of the relevant program or adversely affect domestic sugar policy
          objectives. The Licensing Authority may specify additional
          requirements or procedures in place of the requirements or procedures
          waived or modified.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13294'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XV:-:1530:-:1530.114
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1530.114
      </num>
      <head>
        Implementation.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1530' sect='114' psec='' tq='N'>
              1530.114
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Implementation.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Current program participants may qualify under this rule upon
          concluding a documentation agreement with the Licensing Authority, but
          must conclude a documentation agreement within 24 months of the
          effective date of this rule. Participant license balances, as of the
          effective date of this rule, shall continue under this rule.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13295'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XV:-:1530:-:1530.115
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1530.115
      </num>
      <head>
        Paperwork Reduction Act assigned number.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1530' sect='115' psec='' tq='N'>
              1530.115
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Paperwork Reduction Act assigned number.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Licensees are not required to respond to requests for information
          unless the form for collecting information displays a currently valid
          Office of Management and Budget (OMB) control number. OMB has approved
          the information collection requirements contained in this part in
          accordance with 44 U.S.C. chapter 35. OMB number 0551-0015 has been
          assigned and will expire November 30, 1999.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>