<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol11'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1728
    </extid>
    <num>
      1728
    </num>
    <head>
      ELECTRIC STANDARDS AND SPECIFICATIONS FOR MATERIALS AND CONSTRUCTION
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='901' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/901.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 901
            </subref>
          </aref>
          <E T='03'>
            et seq.,
          </E>
           1921 
          <E T='03'>
            et seq.,
          </E>
           6941 
          <E T='03'>
            et seq.
          </E>
        </P>
      </AUTH>
    </text>
    <section orderid='13851'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1728:-:1728.10
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1728.10
      </num>
      <head>
        General purpose and scope.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          50 FR 47710
        </aref>
        , Nov. 20, 1985. Redesignated at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          55 FR 39395
        </aref>
        , Sept. 27, 1990]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
              1728.10
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General purpose and scope.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The requirements of this part are based on contractual provisions
            between RUS and the organizations which receive financial assistance
            from RUS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             RUS will establish certain specifications and standards for
            materials, equipment, and construction units that will be acceptable
            for RUS financial assistance for the electric program. Materials and
            equipment purchased by the 
            <PRTPAGE P='268' />
            electric borrowers or accepted as contractor-furnished material must
            conform to RUS standards and specifications where they have been
            established and, if included in RUS Bulletin 43-5, “List of
            Materials Acceptable for Use on Systems of RUS Electrification
            Borrowers” (List of Materials), must be selected from that list or
            must have received technical acceptance from RUS. RUS, through its
            Technical Standards Committees, will evaluate certain materials,
            equipment and construction units, and will determine acceptance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            50 FR 47710
          </aref>
          , Nov. 20, 1985. Redesignated at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            55 FR 39395
          </aref>
          , Sept. 27, 1990]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13852'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1728:-:1728.20
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1728.20
      </num>
      <head>
        Establishment of standards and specifications.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          50 FR 47710
        </aref>
        , Nov. 20, 1985. Redesignated at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          55 FR 39395
        </aref>
        , Sept. 27, 1990, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          55 FR 53487
        </aref>
        , Dec. 31, 1990]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='20' psec='' tq='N'>
              1728.20
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Establishment of standards and specifications.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              National and other standards.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             RUS will utilize standards of national standardizing groups, such
            as the American National Standards Institute (ANSI), American Wood
            Preservers&apos; Association (AWPA), the various national
            engineering societies and the National Electrical Safety Code
            (NESC), to the greatest extent practical. When there are no national
            standards or when RUS determines that the existing national
            standards are not adequate for rural electric systems, RUS will
            prepare standards for material and equipment to be used on systems
            of electric borrowers. RUS standards and specifications will be
            codified or listed in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , Incorporation by Reference of Electric Standards and
            Specifications. RUS will also prepare specifications for materials
            and equipment when it determines that such specifications will
            result in reduced costs, improved materials and equipment, or in the
            more effective use of engineering services.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Deviations from Standards.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No member of the RUS staff will be permitted to authorize
            deviations from the standard specifications, or to establish or
            change the technical standards, or to authorize the use of items
            that have not received acceptance by the Technical Standards
            Committees, except as provided for under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='70' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.70
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , or by authorization and/or delegation of authority by the
            Administrator of RUS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Category of Items.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Items appearing in the List of Materials are listed by categories
            of generic items which are used in RUS construction standards
            incorporated by reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . RUS will establish and define these categories and will establish
            all criteria for acceptability within these categories.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            50 FR 47710
          </aref>
          , Nov. 20, 1985. Redesignated at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            55 FR 39395
          </aref>
          , Sept. 27, 1990, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            55 FR 53487
          </aref>
          , Dec. 31, 1990]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13853'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1728:-:1728.30
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1728.30
      </num>
      <head>
        Inclusion of an item for listing or technical acceptance.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          50 FR 47711
        </aref>
        , Nov. 20, 1985. Redesignated at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          55 FR 39395
        </aref>
        , Sept. 27, 1990]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='30' psec='' tq='N'>
              1728.30
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Inclusion of an item for listing or technical acceptance.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Scope.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             RUS, through its Technical Standards Committees “A” and “B” will
            determine the acceptability of certain standards, standard
            specifications, standard drawings, and items of materials and
            equipment to be used in transmission, distribution and general plant
            (excluding office equipment, tools, and work equipment, and
            consumer-owned electric wiring facilities).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Addresses of Committees.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The address of Technical Standards Committee “A” is: Chairman,
            Technical Standards Committee “A” (Electric), Rural Utilities
            Service, U.S. Department of Agriculture, Washington, DC 20250-1500.
            The address of Technical Standards Committee “B” is: Chairman,
            Technical Standards Committee “B” (Electric), Rural Utilities
            Service, U.S. Department of Agriculture, Washington, DC 20250-1500.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Review by Technical Standards Committee “A”.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All proposals for listing a product in the List of Materials must
            be addressed to Technical Standards Committee “A.” This committee
            will consider all proposals made by sponsors of specifications,
            drawings, materials, or equipment in categories for which RUS has
            established criteria for acceptability. A sponsor may be a
            manufacturer, supplier, contractor or any other person or
            organization which has made an application for listing or has
            requested an action by the committee. Committee “A” will consider
            all relevant information presented in determining whether an item
            should be accepted by Technical Standards Committee “A.” Formal
            rules of evidence and procedure shall not apply to proceedings
            before this committee.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Action by Technical Standards Committee “A”.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Committee “A” may take one of the following actions:
            <PRTPAGE P='269' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Accept an item for listing without conditions (domestic items
            only),
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Reject an item (domestic or nondomestic), 
            <SU>
              1
            </SU>
            <FTREF />
          </text>
        </P>
        <FTNT>
          <P>
            <SU>
              1
            </SU>
             Nondomestic items are items which do not qualify as domestic
            products pursuant to RUS “Buy American” requirement.
          </P>
        </FTNT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Accept an item for listing with conditions (domestic items only),
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Table an item for a time period sufficient to allow the sponsor to
            be notified and furnish additional information (domestic or
            nondomestic),
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Grant technical acceptance with or without conditions for a period
            of one year from the date of notification by RUS (nondomestic items
            only).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All committee decisions regarding the actions listed above must be
            unanimous. If the vote is not unanimous, the item shall be referred
            to Technical Standards Committee “B.” Written notice of Technical
            Standards Committee “A&apos;s” decision, stating the basis for the
            decision, will be provided to the sponsor.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Items accepted without conditions by the Technical Standards
            Committees will be considered to be accepted on a general basis. No
            restrictions as to quantity or application will be placed on items
            which have received general acceptance. Items accepted subject to
            certain conditions, such as limited use to gain service experience,
            or limited use appropriate to certain areas and conditions, will be
            considered to be accepted on a conditional basis. The conditions
            will be cited as a part of the listing provided for in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='60' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.60
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , or as part of the technical acceptance for nondomestic items.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Appeal to Technical Standards Committee “B”.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A sponsor may request a review of an adverse decision by Technical
            Standards Committee “A” within ten (10) days of notification of such
            decision by submitting a letter requesting such review to Technical
            Standards Committee “B” (Electric).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Action by Technical Standards Committee “B”.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Committee “B” may take any of the actions listed for Committee “A”
            in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='30' psec='#d' tq='N'>
                1728.30(d)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . However, for a Committee “B” action to be effective it must be by
            majority vote. Failure to obtain a majority on one of the proposed
            actions shall mean that the product will not be listed or accepted.
            Committee “B&apos;s” determination shall be based on the record
            developed before Committee “A” and such additional information as
            Committee “B” may request. Formal rules of procedure and evidence
            shall not apply to proceedings before Committee “B.” Written notice
            of Committee “B&apos;s” decision, stating the basis of the decision,
            will be provided to the sponsor.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Appeal to the Administrator.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the event of an adverse decision by Committee “B,” the sponsor
            may, within ten (10) days of notification of such decision, request
            a review of this decision by submitting a letter to the
            Administrator requesting such a review.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Change in Design.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             RUS acceptance of an item will be conditioned on the understanding
            that no design changes (material or dimensions) affecting the
            quality, strength, or electrical characteristics of the item shall
            be made without prior concurrence of Technical Standards Committee
            “A.”
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            50 FR 47711
          </aref>
          , Nov. 20, 1985. Redesignated at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            55 FR 39395
          </aref>
          , Sept. 27, 1990]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13854'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1728:-:1728.40
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1728.40
      </num>
      <head>
        Procedure for submission of a proposal.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          50 FR 47711
        </aref>
        , Nov. 20, 1985. Redesignated at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          55 FR 39395
        </aref>
        , Sept. 27, 1990]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='40' psec='' tq='N'>
              1728.40
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Procedure for submission of a proposal.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Written Request.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Consideration of an item of material or equipment will be obtained
            by the sponsor through the submission of a written request in an
            original and five copies addressed to the Chairman, Technical
            Standards Committee “A” (Electric). The letter must include the
            catalog number or other identifying number or code as well as a
            description of the item. In the event that an item being submitted
            is also intended for consideration by Technical Standards Committee
            “A” (Telephone), a separate request must be made to the telephone
            committee. (See 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1755' tq='N'>
                1755 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Technical and Performance Data.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Six copies of the specification of manufacture, drawings and test
            data must be submitted to the committee. Six copies of the
            performance history shall also be submitted unless RUS determines
            that such performance history is not reasonably available.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Sample.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             One sample of the item must be submitted to the Chairman, Technical
            Standards Committee “A,” unless RUS waives the requirements of 
            <PRTPAGE P='270' />
            the sample. In case of large, bulky or extremely heavy samples, the
            sponsor should contact the Chairman, Technical Standards Committee
            “A” (Electric), at the above address, before any sample is shipped.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Action on Proposal.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             RUS will inform a sponsor of the action taken on the sponsor&apos;s
            proposal.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            50 FR 47711
          </aref>
          , Nov. 20, 1985. Redesignated at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            55 FR 39395
          </aref>
          , Sept. 27, 1990]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13855'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1728:-:1728.50
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1728.50
      </num>
      <head>
        Removal of an item from listing or technical acceptance.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          50 FR 47711
        </aref>
        , Nov. 20, 1985. Redesignated at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          55 FR 39395
        </aref>
        , Sept. 27, 1990]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='50' psec='' tq='N'>
              1728.50
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Removal of an item from listing or technical acceptance.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Removal Actions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An item of material or equipment may be removed from the listing or
            technical acceptance in accordance with the following procedures
            upon determination that the item is unsatisfactory or has been
            misrepresented to the owner or RUS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Notification by the Committee.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The sponsor of an item of material or equipment will be notified in
            writing of a proposal to remove such item from the listing or
            technical acceptance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Supplemental Information.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Within ten (10) days of receipt of such notification, the sponsor
            may submit to Committee “A” a letter expressing the sponsor&apos;s
            intent to submit written supplemental technical information relevant
            to Committee “A&apos;s” determination. The sponsor must submit such
            information within twenty (20) days from the submission of its
            letter to Committee “A.” Committee “A” will have the discretion of
            making a decision following the expiration of the time periods
            provided in this paragraph.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Review by the Technical Standards Committee “A”.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Committee “A” will consider all relevant information presented in
            determining whether an item should be removed from the listing or
            technical acceptance. Formal rules of evidence and procedure shall
            not apply to proceedings before Technical Standards Committee “A.”
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Action by the Technical Standards Committee “A”.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Committee “A” may take one of the following actions:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Order the immediate removal of the item from the listing, or
            technical acceptance,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Condition the item&apos;s continued listing, or technical
            acceptance,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Recommend a basis of settlement which will adequately protect the
            interest of the Government, or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Delay the effectiveness of its decision for a time period
            sufficient to allow the sponsor to appeal to Technical Standards
            Committee “B.”
          </text>
        </P>
        <FP>
          All committee “A” decisions regarding the actions listed above must be
          by unanimous vote. If the vote is not unanimous, the item will be
          referred to Technical Standards Committee “B.”
        </FP>
        <FP>
          Written notice of Technical Standards Committee “A&apos;s” decision,
          stating the basis for the decision, will be provided to the sponsor.
        </FP>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Additional Opportunity to Present Information.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             At the request of the sponsor, RUS may afford additional
            opportunity for consideration of relevant information. Such
            additional opportunity may include, without limitation, a meeting
            between RUS and the sponsor in such a forum that RUS may determine.
            In making this decision, RUS will consider, among other things, the
            best interests of RUS, its borrowers, and the sponsor, and the best
            manner to develop sufficient information relating to the proposed
            action.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Appeal to the Technical Standards Committee “B”.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Within ten (10) days of notification of Committee “A&apos;s”
            decision, a sponsor may appeal in writing to Technical Standards
            Committee “B” to review Committee “A&apos;s” decision, specifying
            the reasons for such a request. Committee “B&apos;s” determination,
            in response to such request, shall be based on the record developed
            before Committee “A” and such additional information as Committee
            “B” may request. Formal rules of procedure and evidence shall not
            apply to proceedings before Committee “B.”
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Action by Technical Standards Committee “B”.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Committee “B,” by majority vote, may take one of the following
            actions:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Order the immediate removal of the item from listing, or technical
            acceptance,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Condition the item&apos;s continued listing, or technical
            acceptance,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Recommend a basis of settlement which adequately protects the
            interests of the Government, or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Delay the effectiveness of its decision for a time period
            sufficient to 
            <PRTPAGE P='271' />
            allow the sponsor to appeal to the Administrator of RUS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <FP>
          Failure to obtain a majority vote on any of the above actions shall
          mean that the product will continue to be listed or accepted.
        </FP>
        <FP>
          Written notice of Committee “B&apos;s” decision stating the basis of
          the decision will be provided to the sponsor.
        </FP>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Appeal to the Administrator.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Within ten (10) days of the receipt of Committee “B&apos;s”
            decision, a sponsor may appeal to the Administrator to review
            Committee “B&apos;s” decision. If an appeal is made, the sponsor
            shall submit a written request to the Administrator, Rural Utilities
            Service, Room 4053, South Building, U.S. Department of Agriculture,
            Washington, DC 20250-1500 specifying the reasons to request
            reconsideration. The Administrator will have the option to decline
            the request, in which case the decision of Committee “B” shall
            stand. If a review is granted, the determination by the
            Administrator or the Administrator&apos;s designee shall be based on
            the record developed before Committee “A” and Committee “B” and such
            additional information as the Administrator may request. Formal
            rules of procedure and evidence shall not apply to the actions of
            the Administrator.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Action by the Administrator.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Administrator may take one of the following actions:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Order the immediate removal of the item from the listing, or
            technical acceptance,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Condition its continued listing, or technical acceptance, or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Recommend a basis of settlement which adequately protects the
            interests of the Government.
          </text>
        </P>
        <FP>
          Written notice of the Administrator&apos;s determination, stating the
          basis for the decision, will be provided to the sponsor.
        </FP>
        <FP>
          The Administrator&apos;s actions are final.
        </FP>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            50 FR 47711
          </aref>
          , Nov. 20, 1985. Redesignated at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            55 FR 39395
          </aref>
          , Sept. 27, 1990]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13856'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1728:-:1728.60
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1728.60
      </num>
      <head>
        List of materials and equipment.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          50 FR 47712
        </aref>
        , Nov. 20, 1985. Redesignated at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          55 FR 39395
        </aref>
        , Sept. 27, 1990]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='60' psec='' tq='N'>
              1728.60
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          List of materials and equipment.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Those items of material or equipment accepted by Technical
            Standards Committee “A” or “B,” with the exception of technically
            accepted nondomestic items, will be listed in the List of Materials.
            Items which do not qualify as domestic products may be accepted on a
            technical basis only (technical acceptance) for a period of one year
            as provided in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='30' psec='#c_1' tq='N'>
                1728.30(c)(1)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and will not be included in the List of Materials.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Publishing and Revisions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             RUS will reissue the List of Materials every year, dated July, and
            issue supplements, if needed, dated October, January, and April of
            every year. An RUS office copy, which is the official current copy,
            of the List of Materials, will be updated every time changes are
            made by the Technical Standards Committees.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Dual Listings.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             RUS, through its Technical Standards Committees, will accept for
            listing only one item of a particular type of material or equipment
            for each manufacturer. If a manufacturer submits an item to perform
            the identical function of a listed item, RUS, through its Technical
            Standards Committees, may accept that item and remove the one
            previously listed. RUS will list only new items of material and
            equipment in the List of Materials. Used items will not be
            considered for listing.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            50 FR 47712
          </aref>
          , Nov. 20, 1985. Redesignated at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            55 FR 39395
          </aref>
          , Sept. 27, 1990]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13857'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1728:-:1728.70
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1728.70
      </num>
      <head>
        Procurement of materials.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          50 FR 47712
        </aref>
        , Nov. 20, 1985. Redesignated at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          55 FR 39395
        </aref>
        , Sept. 27, 1990]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='70' psec='' tq='N'>
              1728.70
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Procurement of materials.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              By Owner.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When purchasing the type of materials included in the List of
            Materials, RUS borrowers shall purchase only materials listed in the
            List of Materials, or materials which have a current technical
            acceptance by RUS and meet the “Buy American” requirement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              By Contractor.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When performing work for an RUS borrower, contractors shall supply
            only items from the general acceptance pages of the List of
            Materials, or obtain the borrower&apos;s concurrence prior to
            purchase and use of a technically nondomestic item or any item
            listed on a conditional basis.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Procurement of Unlisted Items.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The borrower shall request prior approval from RUS for use of an
            item that does not fall in categories established by RUS in the List
            of Materials 
            <PRTPAGE P='272' />
            for which acceptability has been established by the Technical
            Standards Committees.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             RUS will also determine, on a case-by-case basis, whether to allow
            use of an unlisted item in emergency situations and for experimental
            use or to meet a specific need. For purposes of this 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' tq='N'>
                1728
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , an emergency shall mean a situation wherein the supply of listed
            material and equipment from the industry is not readily available,
            or the standard designs are not applicable to the borrower&apos;s
            specific problem under consideration.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             RUS will make arrangements for test or experimental use of newly
            developed items requiring limited trial use. RUS, working with the
            borrower and the manufacturer, will establish test locations for the
            items to facilitate installation and observation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            50 FR 47712
          </aref>
          , Nov. 20, 1985. Redesignated at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            55 FR 39395
          </aref>
          , Sept. 27, 1990]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13858'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1728:-:1728.97
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1728.97
      </num>
      <head>
        Incorporation by reference of electric standards and specifications.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          76 FR 36963
        </aref>
        , June 24, 2011, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          77 FR 19528
        </aref>
        , Apr. 2, 2012]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
              1728.97
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Incorporation by reference of electric standards and specifications.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The materials listed below are incorporated by reference in the
          corresponding sections noted. The Director of the Federal Register
          approves the incorporations by reference in accordance with 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='5' sect='552' note='' psec='#a' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/5/552.html#a'>
              5 U.S.C. 552(a)
            </subref>
          </aref>
           and 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            1 CFR part 
            <subref title='1' part='51' tq='N'>
              51
            </subref>
          </aref>
          . A notice of any change in these materials will be published in the 
          <E T='04'>
            Federal Register.
          </E>
           Standards and specifications materials are available for purchase at
          the addresses in the corresponding sections noted below. The materials
          incorporated by reference may also be inspected at the Rural Utilities
          Service&apos;s Program Development and Regulatory Analysis, Stop 1520,
          Room 5820-S, Washington, DC 20250-1522, call (202) 720-8674. Bulletins
          are also available for inspection at the National Archives and Records
          Administration (NARA). For information on the availability of these
          materials at NARA, call (202) 741-6030, or go to: 
          <E T='03'>
            http://www.archives.gov/or
          </E>
           at the Office of the Federal Register, 800 North Capitol Street, NW.,
          suite 700, Washington, DC, or go to: 
          <E T='03'>
            http://www.archives.gov/federal_register/code_of_federal_regulations/ibr_locations.htm.
          </E>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The following RUS bulletins are available from the Rural Utilities
            Service, Room 1246-S, U.S. Department of Agriculture, Washington, DC
            20250. For information on the availability of this material, call
            (202) 720-1900. The bulletins containing construction standards
            (50-4 and 1728F-803 to 1728F-811) may be obtained from the
            Superintendent of Documents, U.S. Government Printing Office (GPO)
            for Washington, DC 20402, Phone: 1-866-512-1800 (toll-free)
            202-512-1800 (DC Area) or go to the GPO Web site at: 
            <E T='03'>
              http://www.gpoaccess.gov/about/index.html
            </E>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bulletin 50-4 (D-801), Specification and Drawings for 34.5/19.9 kV
            Distribution Line Construction (11-86), incorporation approved for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='98' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.98
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bulletin 50-15 (DT-3), RUS Specifications for Pole Top Pins with 1
            <FR>
              3/8
            </FR>
            ′ Diameter Lead Thread (1-51), incorporation approved for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='98' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.98
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bulletin 50-16 (DT-4), RUS Specifications for Angle Suspension
            Brackets (3-52), incorporation approved for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='98' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.98
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bulletin 50-19 (DT-7), RUS Specifications for Clevis Bolts (8-53),
            incorporation approved for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='98' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.98
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bulletin 50-23 (DT-18), RUS Specifications for 60″ Wood Crossarm
            Braces (2-71), incorporation approved for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='98' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.98
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bulletin 50-31 (D-3), RUS Specifications for Pole Top Pins with 1”
            Diameter Lead Threads (2-79), incorporation approved for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='98' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.98
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bulletin 50-32 (D-4), RUS Specifications for Steel Crossarm Mounted
            Pins with 1″ Diameter Lead Threads (10-50), incorporation approved
            for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='98' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.98
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bulletin 50-33 (D-5), RUS Specifications for Single and Double
            Upset Spool Bolts (2-51), incorporation approved for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='98' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.98
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bulletin 50-34 (D-6), RUS Specifications for Secondary Swinging
            Clevises (12-70), incorporation approved for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='98' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.98
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bulletin 50-35 (D-7), RUS Specifications for Service Swinging
            Clevises (9-52), incorporation approved for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='98' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.98
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_11'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (11)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bulletin 50-36 (D-8), RUS Specifications for Service Deadend
            Clevises (9-52), incorporation approved for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='98' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.98
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
            <PRTPAGE P='273' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_12'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (12)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bulletin 50-40 (D-14), RUS Specifications for Pole Top Brackets for
            Channel Type Pins (9-51), incorporation approved for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='98' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.98
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_13'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (13)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bulletin 50-41 (D-15), RUS Specifications for Service Wireholders
            (11-51), incorporation approved for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='98' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.98
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_14'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (14)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bulletin 50-55 (T-2), RUS Specifications for Overhead Ground Wire
            Support Brackets (5-53), incorporation approved for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='98' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.98
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_15'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (15)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bulletin 50-56 (T-3), RUS Specifications for Steel Plate Anchors
            for Transmission Lines (12-53), incorporation approved for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='98' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.98
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_16'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (16)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bulletin 50-60 (T-9), RUS Specification—Single Pole Steel
            Structures, Complete with Arms (12-71), incorporation approved for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='98' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.98
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_17'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (17)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bulletin 50-72 (U-4), RUS Specification for Electrical Equipment
            Enclosures (5-35 kV) (10-79), incorporation approved for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='98' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.98
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_18'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (18)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bulletin 50-73 (U-5), RUS Specifications for Pad-Mounted
            Transformers (Single and Three-Phase) (1-77), incorporation approved
            for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='98' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.98
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_19'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (19)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bulletin 50-74 (U-6), RUS Specification for Secondary Pedestals
            (600 Volts and Below) (10-79), incorporation approved for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='98' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.98
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_20'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (20)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bulletin 50-91 (S-3), RUS Specifications for Step-Down Distribution
            Substation Transformers (34.4-138 kV) (1-78), incorporation approved
            for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='98' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.98
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_21'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (21)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bulletin 1728F-700, RUS Specification for Wood Poles, Stubs and
            Anchor Logs (3-2011), incorporation approved for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='98' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.98
              </subref>
              , 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='202' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.202
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_22'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (22)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bulletin 1728F-803, Specifications and Drawings for 24.9/14.4 kV
            Line Construction (10-98), incorporation approved for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='98' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.98
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_23'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (23)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bulletin 1728F-804 (D-804), Specification and Drawings for
            12.47/7.2 kV Line Construction, October 2005, incorporation approved
            for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='98' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.98
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_24'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (24)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bulletin 1728F-806 (D-806), Specifications and Drawings for
            Underground Electric Distribution, June 2000, incorporation approved
            for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='98' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.98
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_25'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (25)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bulletin 1728F-810, Electric Transmission Specifications and
            Drawings, 34.5 kV to 69 kV (3-98), incorporation approved for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='98' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.98
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='201' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.201
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_26'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (26)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bulletin 1728F-811, Electric Transmission Specifications and
            Drawings, 115 kV to 230 kV (3-98), incorporation approved for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='98' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.98
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='201' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.201
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The following material is available for purchase from American
            Institute of Timber Construction (AITC), 7012 S. Revere Park Way,
            Englewood, Colorado 80112, telephone (303) 792-9559, web address: 
            <E T='03'>
              https://www.aitc-glulam.org/index.asp.
            </E>
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             AITC 200-2004, Manufacturing Quality Control Systems Manual For
            Structural Glued Laminated Timber, copyright 2004, (incorporation by
            reference approved for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='201' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.201
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='202' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.202
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             [Reserved]
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The following standards are available for purchase from the
            American National Standards Institute (ANSI), 25 West 43rd Street,
            New York, New York 10036, telephone (212) 642-4900, Web address: 
            <E T='03'>
              http://www.ansi.org/
            </E>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             ANSI O5.2-2006, American National Standard for Wood Products,
            Structural Glued Laminated Timber for Utility Structures, approved
            December 5, 2006, incorporation by reference approved for §§ ,
            1728.201, 1728.202.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             ANSI O5.3.2008, American National Standard for Wood Poles and Wood
            Products, Solid Sawn-Wood Crossarms &amp; Braces—Specifications
            &amp; Dimensions, approved July 15, 2008, incorporation by reference
            approved for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='201' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.201
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The American National Standards Institute/Insulated Cable Engineers
            Association, Inc. (ANSI/ICEA) makes the following material available
            for purchase from Global Engineering Documents for a fee at the
            following address: IHS Global Engineering Documents, 15 Inverness
            Way East, Englewood, CO 80112, Phone: (303) 397-7956;
            (800)-854-7179, Fax: (303) 397-2740, email: 
            <E T='03'>
              global@ihs.com,
            </E>
             Web site: 
            <E T='03'>
              http://global.ihs.com
            </E>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             ANSI/ICEA S-94-649-2004—Standard for Concentric Neutral Cables
            Rated 5 Through 46 KV (ANSI/ICEA S-94-649-2004), approved September
            20, 2005, incorporation by reference approved for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='204' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.204
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             ANSI/ICEA T-31-610-2007—Test Method for Conducting Longitudinal
            Water Penetration Resistance Tests on Blocked Conductors (ANSI/ICEA
            T-31-
            <PRTPAGE P='274' />
            610-2007), approved October 31, 2007, incorporated by reference
            approved for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='204' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.204
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Copies of American Society for Testing and Materials (ASTM)
            publications referenced in this specification can be obtained from
            ASTM for a fee at the following address: ASTM, 100 Barr Harbor
            Drive, West Conshohocken, PA 19428-2959, Telephone: (610) 832-9585,
            Web site: 
            <E T='03'>
              http://astm.org
            </E>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             ASTM B 3-01 (Reapproved 2007)—Standard Specification for Soft or
            Annealed Copper Wire, (ASTM B 3-01) approved March 15, 2007,
            incorporated by reference approved for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='204' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.204
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             ASTM B 8-04—Standard Specification for Concentric-Lay-Stranded
            Copper Conductors, Hard, Medium-Hard, or Soft (ASTM B 8-04),
            approved April 1, 2004, incorporated by reference approved for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='204' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.204
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             ASTM B 230/B 230M-07—Standard Specification for Aluminum 1350-H19
            Wire for Electrical Purposes (ASTM B 230/B 230M-07), approved March
            15, 2007, incorporated by reference approved for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='204' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.204
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             ASTM B 231/B 231M-04—Standard Specification for
            Concentric-Lay-Stranded Aluminum 1350 Conductors (ASTM B 231/B
            231M-04), approved April 1, 2004, incorporated by reference approved
            for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='204' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.204
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             ASTM B 400-08—Standard Specification for Compact Round
            Concentric-Lay-Stranded Aluminum 1350 Conductors (ASTM B 400-08),
            approved September 1, 2008, incorporated by reference approved for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='204' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.204
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             ASTM B 496-04—Standard Specification for Compact Round
            Concentric-Lay-Stranded Copper Conductors (ASTM B 496-04), approved
            April 1, 2004, incorporated by reference approved for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='204' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.204
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             ASTM B 609/B 609M-99—Standard Specification for Aluminum 1350 Round
            Wire, Annealed and Intermediate Tempers, for Electrical Purposes
            (ASTM B 609/B 609M-99), approved April 1, 2004, incorporated by
            reference approved for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='204' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.204
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             ASTM B 786-08—Standard Specification for 19 Wire Combination
            Unilay-Stranded Aluminum 1350 Conductors for Subsequent Insulation
            (ASTM B 786-08), approved September 1, 2008, incorporated by
            reference approved for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='204' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.204
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             ASTM B 787/B 787M-04—Standard Specification for 19 Wire Combination
            Unilay-Stranded Copper Conductors for Subsequent Insulation (ASTM B
            787/B 787M-04), approved September 1, 2004, incorporated by
            reference approved for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='204' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.204
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             ASTM B 835-04—Standard Specification for Compact Round Stranded
            Copper Conductors Using Single Input Wire Construction (ASTM B
            835-04), approved September 1, 2004, incorporated by reference
            approved for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='204' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.204
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_11'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (11)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             ASTM B902-04a—Standard Specification for Compressed Round Stranded
            Copper Conductors, Hard, Medium-Hard, or Soft Using Single Input
            Wire Construction (ASTM B902-04a), approved September 1, 2004,
            incorporated by reference approved for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='204' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.204
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_12'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (12)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             ASTM D 1248-05—Standard Specification for Polyethylene Plastics
            Extrusion Materials for Wire and Cable (ASTM D 1248-05), approved
            March 1, 2005, incorporated by reference approved for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='204' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.204
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_13'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (13)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             ASTM D 2275-01 (Reapproved 2008)—Standard Test Method for Voltage
            Endurance of Solid Electrical Insulating Materials Subjected to
            Partial Discharges (Corona) on the Surface (ASTM D 2275-01),
            approved May 1, 2008, incorporated by reference approved for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='204' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.204
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_14'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (14)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             ASTM E 96/E 96M-05—Standard Test Methods for Water Vapor
            Transmission of Materials (ASTM E 96/E 96M-05), approved May 1,
            2005, incorporated by reference approved for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='204' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.204
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The following standards from the American Wood Protection
            Association (AWPA), Book of Standards, 2008 edition, are available
            for purchase from AWPA, P.O. Box 361784, Birmingham, AL 35236-1784,
            telephone 205-733-4077, 
            <E T='03'>
              http://www.awpa.com/
            </E>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             AWPA A1-06, 
            <E T='03'>
              Standard Methods for Analysis of Creosote and Oil-Type
              Preservatives,
            </E>
             amended in 2006, incorporation by reference approved for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='201' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.201
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='202' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.202
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             AWPA A2-08, 
            <E T='03'>
              Standard Methods for Analysis of Waterborne Preservatives and
              Fire-Retardant Formulations,
            </E>
             2008, incorporation by reference approved for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='201' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.201
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='202' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.202
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
            <PRTPAGE P='275' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             AWPA A3-08, 
            <E T='03'>
              Standard Methods for Determining Penetration of Preservatives and
              Fire Retardants,
            </E>
             revised in 2008, incorporation by reference approved for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='201and' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.201and
              </subref>
            </aref>
             1728.202.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             AWPA A5-05, 
            <E T='03'>
              Standard Methods for Analysis of Oil-Borne Preservatives,
            </E>
             2008, incorporation by reference approved for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='201' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.201
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='202' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.202
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             AWPA A6-01, 
            <E T='03'>
              Method for the Determination of Oil-Type Preservatives and Water
              in Wood,
            </E>
             amended in 2001, incorporation by reference approved for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='202' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.202
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             AWPA A7-04, 
            <E T='03'>
              Standard for Wet Ashing Procedures for Preparing Wood for Chemical
              Analysis,
            </E>
             amended in 2004, incorporation by reference approved for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='202' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.202
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             AWPA A9-01, 
            <E T='03'>
              Standard Method for Analysis of Treated Wood and Treating
              Solutions By X-Ray Spectroscopy,
            </E>
             amended in 2001, incorporation by reference approved for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='201' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.201
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='202' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.202
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             AWPA M2-07, 
            <E T='03'>
              Standard for Inspection of Wood Products Treated with
              Preservatives,
            </E>
             reaffirmed in 2007, incorporation by reference approved for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='202' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.202
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             AWPA M3-05, 
            <E T='03'>
              Standard Quality Control Procedures for Wood Preserving Plants,
            </E>
             amended in 2005, incorporation by reference approved for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='202' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.202
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             AWPA P1/P13-06, 
            <E T='03'>
              Standard for Creosote Preservative,
            </E>
             reaffirmed in 2006, incorporation by reference approved for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='201' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.201
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='202' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.202
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_11'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (11)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             AWPA P5-08, 
            <E T='03'>
              Standard for Waterborne Preservatives,
            </E>
             revised in 2008, incorporation by reference approved for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='201and' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.201and
              </subref>
            </aref>
             1728.202.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_12'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (12)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             AWPA P8-08, 
            <E T='03'>
              Standard for Oil-Borne Preservatives,
            </E>
             revised in 2008, incorporation by reference approved for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='201and' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.201and
              </subref>
            </aref>
             1728.202.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_13'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (13)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             AWPA P9-06, 
            <E T='03'>
              Standards for Solvents and Formulations for Organic Preservative
              Systems,
            </E>
             copyright 2008, incorporation by reference approved for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='201' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.201
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='202' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.202
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The following material is available from the Insulated Cable
            Engineers Association (ICEA) and may be purchased from Global
            Engineering Documents for a fee at the following address: IHS Global
            Engineering Documents, 15 Inverness Way East, Englewood, CO 80112,
            Phone: (303) 397-7956; (800)-854-7179, Fax: (303) 397-2740, email: 
            <E T='03'>
              global@ihs.com,
            </E>
             Web site: 
            <E T='03'>
              http://global.ihs.com
            </E>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             ICEA T-32-645-93—Guide for Establishing Compatibility of Sealed
            Conductor Filler Compounds with Conducting Stress Control Materials
            (ICEA T-32-645-93), approved February 1993, incorporated by
            reference approved for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='204' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.204
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             [Reserved]
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The following material is available from Southern Pine Inspection
            Bureau Standards, 4709 Scenic Highway, Pensacola, Florida
            32504-9094, telephone (850) 434-2611. The web address for the
            Southern Pine Inspection Bureau is 
            <E T='03'>
              http://www.spib.org/.
            </E>
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Special Product Rules for Structural, Industrial, and
              Railroad-Freight Car Lumber,
            </E>
             effective October 15, 1991, incorporation by reference approved for
            
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='201' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.201
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             [Reserved]
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The following material is available for purchase from West Coast
            Lumber Inspection Bureau, P.O. Box 23145, Portland, Oregon 97281,
            telephone (503) 639-0651, fax (503) 684-8928. The web address for is
            
            <E T='03'>
              http://www.wclib.org/
            </E>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Standard No. 17, Grading Rules for West Coast Lumber,
            </E>
             Revised January 1, 2004, incorporation by reference approved for 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='201' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.201
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             [Reserved]
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 36963
          </aref>
          , June 24, 2011, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            77 FR 19528
          </aref>
          , Apr. 2, 2012]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13859'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1728:-:1728.98
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1728.98
      </num>
      <head>
        Electric standards and specifications.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          76 FR 36964
        </aref>
        , June 24, 2011]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='98' psec='' tq='N'>
              1728.98
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Electric standards and specifications.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To comply with this part, you must follow the requirements
            contained in the following REA/RUS bulletins. These bulletins are
            incorporated by reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bulletin 50-4 (D-801), Specification and Drawings for 34.5/19.9 kV
            Distribution Line Construction (11-86).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bulletin 50-15 (DT-3), RUS Specifications for Pole Top Pins with 1
            <FR>
              3/8
            </FR>
            ′ Diameter Lead Thread (1-51).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bulletin 50-16 (DT-4), RUS Specifications for Angle Suspension
            Brackets (3-52).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bulletin 50-19 (DT-7), RUS Specifications for Clevis Bolts (8-53).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bulletin 50-23 (DT-18), RUS Specifications for 60″ Wood Crossarm
            Braces (2-71).
            <PRTPAGE P='276' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bulletin 50-31 (D-3), RUS Specifications for Pole Top Pins with 1″
            Diameter Lead Threads (2-79).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bulletin 50-32 (D-4), RUS Specifications for Steel Crossarm Mounted
            Pins with 1″ Diameter Lead Threads (10-50).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bulletin 50-33 (D-5), RUS Specifications for Single and Double
            Upset Spool Bolts (2-51).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bulletin 50-34 (D-6), RUS Specifications for Secondary Swinging
            Clevises (12-70).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bulletin 50-35 (D-7), RUS Specifications for Service Swinging
            Clevises (9-52).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_11'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (11)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bulletin 50-36 (D-8), RUS Specifications for Service Deadend
            Clevises (9-52).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_12'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (12)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bulletin 50-40 (D-14), RUS Specifications for Pole Top Brackets for
            Channel Type Pins (9-51).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_13'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (13)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bulletin 50-41 (D-15), RUS Specifications for Service Wireholders
            (11-51).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_14'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (14)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bulletin 50-55 (T-2), RUS Specifications for Overhead Ground Wire
            Support Brackets (5-53).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_15'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (15)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bulletin 50-56 (T-3), RUS Specifications for Steel Plate Anchors
            for Transmission Lines (12-53).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_16'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (16)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bulletin 50-60 (T-9), RUS Specification—Single Pole Steel
            Structures, Complete with Arms (12-71).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_17'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (17)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bulletin 50-72 (U-4), RUS Specification for Electrical Equipment
            Enclosures (5-35 kV) (10-79).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_18'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (18)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bulletin 50-73 (U-5), RUS Specifications for Pad-Mounted
            Transformers (Single and Three-Phase) (1-77).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_19'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (19)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bulletin 50-74 (U-6), RUS Specification for Secondary Pedestals
            (600 Volts and Below) (10-79).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_20'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (20)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bulletin 50-91 (S-3), RUS Specifications for Step-Down Distribution
            Substation Transformers (34.4-138 kV) (1-78).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_21'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (21)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bulletin 1728F-700, RUS Specification for Wood Poles, Stubs and
            Anchor Logs (3-2011).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_22'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (22)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bulletin 1728F-803, Specifications and Drawings for 24.9/14.4 kV
            Line Construction (10-98).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_23'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (23)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bulletin 1728F-804 (D-804), Specification and Drawings for
            12.47/7.2 kV Line Construction, October 2005.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_24'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (24)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bulletin 1728F-806 (D-806), Specifications and Drawings for
            Underground Electric Distribution, June 2000.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_25'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (25)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bulletin 1728F-810, Electric Transmission Specifications and
            Drawings, 34.5 kV to 69 kV (3-98).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_26'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (26)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bulletin 1728F-811, Electric Transmission Specifications and
            Drawings, 115 kV to 230 kV (3-98).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The terms “RUS form”, “RUS standard form”, “RUS specification”, and
            “RUS bulletin” have the same meanings as the terms “REA form”, “REA
            standard form”, “REA specification”, and “REA bulletin”,
            respectively unless otherwise indicated.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 36964
          </aref>
          , June 24, 2011]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13860'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1728:-:1728.201
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1728.201
      </num>
      <head>
        Bulletin 1728H-701, Specification for Wood Crossarms (Solid and
        Laminated), Transmission Timbers and Pole Keys.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='201' psec='' tq='N'>
              1728.201
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Bulletin 1728H-701, Specification for Wood Crossarms (Solid and
          Laminated), Transmission Timbers and Pole Keys.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General Provisions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This section implements contractual provisions between Rural
            Utilities Service (RUS) and borrowers receiving financial
            assistance. The contractual agreement between RUS and its borrowers
            requires the borrower&apos;s system to be constructed in accordance
            with agency accepted plans and specifications. Each electric
            borrower must purchase only wood crossarms produced in accordance
            with the specification in this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each electric borrower shall require each contractor to agree in
            writing to furnish only materials produced in accordance with the
            specifications in this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This specification describes the minimum acceptable quality of wood
            distribution crossarms and transmission crossarms (hereinafter
            called crossarms) that are purchased by or for borrowers. Where
            there is conflict between this specification and any other
            specification referred to in this section, this specification shall
            govern.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Various requirements relating to quality control and inspection are
            contained in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='202' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.202
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
            , Specification for Quality Control and Inspection of Timber
            Products. 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              Section 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='201' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.201
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
            , ANSI O5.2, (incorporated by reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ), and ANSI O5.3, (incorporated by reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) shall be followed exactly 
            <PRTPAGE P='277' />
            and shall not be interpreted or subjected to judgment by the quality
            control person or an independent inspector.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The purchaser shall purchase from producers only material that
            meets the requirements of this specification. Each purchaser shall
            use a written purchase order to purchase material for use in
            financed systems in order to ensure compliance with the standards
            and specifications of this part. The written purchase order shall
            contain a provision that specifically requires the producer to
            comply with the provisions of this part. The purchase order shall
            contain a provision that specifically requires the producer to make
            the treating plant and storage areas available, during normal
            business hours, in order for representatives of either the purchaser
            or this agency to inspect such to determine compliance with the
            standards and specifications of this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The producer shall provide the inspectors with full information
            (drawings, etc.) relating to the requirements contained in the
            purchase order which is supplementary to this specification.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The producer shall maintain, or have access to, adequate laboratory
            facilities at or very near the treating plant, and all chemical
            tests, assays or analyses associated with the treatment shall be
            independently performed in this laboratory by both the quality
            control designee and the borrower&apos;s inspector. The producer may
            use a central laboratory as accepted on a case-by-case basis.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Inspection and treatment of all timber products produced under this
            specification shall be performed after receipt of the order from the
            purchaser, except as provided for reserve treated stock.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The testing and inspection of the lamination process shall be in
            accordance with AITC 200 (incorporated by reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             With the exception of reserve treated stock, if requested by the
            borrower invoices for treated timber products shall be accompanied,
            in duplicate, by a copy of the producer&apos;s Certificate of
            Compliance and a copy of either the Independent Inspection Report or
            a Quality Assurance Plan Certificate. For reserve treated stock,
            inspection reports shall be available from the inspection agency.
            When shipped from reserve stock, the invoice shall bear an
            endorsement and a further certification by the producer that the
            material meets the requirements of this specification and any
            supplementary requirements cited in the purchase order under which
            it is purchased.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_11'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (11)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Crossarms shall be warranted to conform to this specification. If
            any crossarm is determined to be defective or does not conform to
            this specification within 1 year after delivery to the borrower, it
            shall be replaced as promptly as possible by the producer. In the
            event of failure to do so, the purchaser may make such replacement
            and the cost of the crossarm, at destination, shall be recoverable
            from the producer.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_12'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (12)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Crossarm producers shall take out and maintain liability insurance
            for not less than $1 million. Upon request, evidence of compliance
            shall be provided. The evidence shall be in the form of a
            certificate of insurance signed by a representative of the insurance
            company and include a provision that no changes in, or cancellation
            of, will be made without the prior written notice to the Director,
            Electric Staff Division, Rural Utilities Service.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Definitions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Agency
          </E>
           refers to Rural Utilities Service (RUS), United States Department of
          Agriculture.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Arm
          </E>
           refers to structural wood member used to support electrical
          conductors and equipment. Arm is used interchangeably with crossarm.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Certificate of compliance
          </E>
           is a written certification by an authorized employee of the producer
          that the material shipped meets the requirements of this specification
          and any supplementary requirements specified in a purchase order from
          a borrower or the borrower&apos;s contractor.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Crossarm
          </E>
           refers to a structural wood member used to support electrical
          conductors and equipment and is a term used interchangeably with arm.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Independent inspection
          </E>
           relates to examination of material by an independent inspector
          employed by a commercial inspection agency.
          <PRTPAGE P='278' />
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Inspection
          </E>
           means an examination of material in sufficient detail to ensure
          conformity to all phases of the specification under which it was
          purchased.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Lot
          </E>
           is a quantity of crossarms of like size, conditioning, and
          fabrication, usually making up one treating charge.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Producer
          </E>
           is used to describe the party who manufactures and/or treats
          crossarms.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Purchaser
          </E>
           refers to either the borrower or contractors acting as the
          borrower&apos;s agent, except where a part of the specification
          specifically refers to only the borrower or the contractor.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Quality control designee
          </E>
           refers to an individual designated by the producer to oversee proper
          operation of the manufacturer&apos;s internal quality control system.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Reserve treated stock
          </E>
           consists of timber products treated in accordance with this
          specification, prior to and in anticipation of the receipt of specific
          orders, and held in storage ready for immediate shipment.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Supplier
          </E>
           is a term used interchangeably with producer, or in some cases, may
          be the distributor selling crossarms to the borrower.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Treating plant
          </E>
           is the organization that applies the preservative treatment to the
          crossarms.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Independent Inspection Plan.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This plan or a Quality Assurance Plan, as described in paragraph
            (e) of this section, is acceptable for supplying crossarms. All
            crossarms purchased under the Independent Inspection Plan, for use
            on an agency financed system shall be inspected by a qualified
            independent inspector in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='202' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.202
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The borrower has the prerogative to contract directly with the
            inspection agency for service. The borrower should, where practical,
            select the inspection agency so that continual employment is
            dependent only on performance acceptable to the borrower and in
            accordance with this specification. The selected inspection agency
            shall not be allowed to subcontract the service to any other
            inspection agency.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The producer shall not be permitted to be a party to the selection
            of the inspection agency by the borrower and shall not interfere
            with the work of the inspector, except to provide notification of
            the readiness of material for inspection. To obtain inspection
            services for reserve stock, the producer may deal directly with the
            inspection agency. The producer shall not be permitted to treat
            material before it has been properly inspected and hammered with the
            appropriate inspection/quality assurance mark.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The methods of inspection described in this section and in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='202' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.202
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
             shall be used no matter which plan crossarms are produced under,
            i.e., Independent Inspection Plan, or Quality Assurance Plans, as
            described in this section
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Quality Assurance Plans.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The producer shall furnish crossarms conforming to this
            specification as monitored by an acceptable Quality Assurance Plan.
            Borrower groups or agents for borrower groups endeavoring to operate
            Quality Assurance Plans shall submit their plan for assuring quality
            control to the Chairman, Technical Standards Committee “A”, Electric
            Staff Division, Rural Utilities Service, Stop 1569, Washington, DC
            20250-1569.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Material Requirements.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Material and Grade.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All crossarms furnished under this specification shall be free of
            brashy wood, decay, and insect holes larger than 
            <FR>
              3/32
            </FR>
             of an inch and shall meet additional requirements as shown on
            specific drawings. Crossarms shall be made of one of the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Douglas-fir which conforms to the applicable crossarm provisions of
            paragraphs 170 and 170a, or the applicable transmission arm
            provisions of paragraphs 169 and 169a of the Standard No. 17 Grading
            Rules for West Coast Lumber (incorporated by reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ). Only coastal origin Douglas-fir shall be used for Douglas-fir
            crossarms manufactured under this specification;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Southern Yellow Pine which conforms to the provisions of Dense
            Industrial Crossarm 65, as described in paragraph 31.2 in the 2001
            Southern Pine Inspection Bureau&apos;s Special Product Rules for
            Structural, Industrial, and Railroad-Freight Car Lumber,
            (incorporated by reference at 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ); or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Laminated wood crossarms shall conform to ANSI O5.2 (incorporated
            by reference at 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) and have at least the same load carrying capacity as the 
            <PRTPAGE P='279' />
            solid sawn arm it replaces. The load carrying capacity of the
            laminated arms shall be determined by one of the procedures outlined
            in ANSI O5.2.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Borrowers may use alternative crossarms that are listed in
            Informational Publication 202-1, List of Materials Acceptable for
            Use on Systems of USDA Rural Utilities Service Borrowers. For
            information on the availability of this material, call RUS at (202)
            720-1900, or go to: 
            <E T='03'>
              http://www.rurdev.usda.gov/UEP_Engineering_LOM.html
            </E>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Knots.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Sound, firm, and tight knots, if well spaced, are allowed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Slightly decayed knots are permitted, except on the top face,
            provided the decay extends no more than 
            <FR>
              3/4
            </FR>
             of an inch into the knot and provided the cavities will drain water
            when the arm is installed. For knots to be considered well spaced,
            the sum of the sizes of all knots in any 6 inches of length of a
            piece shall not exceed twice the size of the largest knot permitted.
            More than one knot of maximum permissible size shall not be in the
            same 6 inches of length. Slightly decayed, firm, or sound “pin
            knots” (
            <FR>
              3/8
            </FR>
             of an inch or less) are not considered in size, spacing, or zone
            considerations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Knots are subject to limits on size and location as detailed in
            Tables I and II.
          </text>
        </P>
        <table class='gpotable' CDEF='s100,12,12,12' COLS='4' OPTS='l2'>
          <caption>
            <div>
              <strong>
                Table I—Knot Limits for Distribution Arms (See Figure 1,
                Appendix A)
              </strong>
            </div>
            <div class='description'>
              [All dimensions in inches]
            </div>
          </caption>
          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th rowspan='2'>
                Class of knot and location
              </th>
              <th>
                Maximum
              </th>
              <th rowspan='2'>
                Knot
              </th>
              <th>
                Diameter
              </th>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <th>
                Close grain
              </th>
              <th>
                Dense grain
              </th>
            </tr>
          </thead>
          <tfoot>
            <tr>
              <td class='tnote' colspan='4'>
                * No knot shall be closer than its diameter to the pole mounting
                hole.
              </td>
            </tr>
          </tfoot>
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td I='22'>
                Round Knots
              </td>
              <td />
              <td />
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='03' O='xl'>
                Single Knot: Maximum Diameter Center Section*
              </td>
              <td />
              <td />
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='05'>
                Upper Half
              </td>
              <td>
                <sup>
                  3
                </sup>
                /
                <sub>
                  4
                </sub>
              </td>
              <td />
              <td>
                1
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='05'>
                Lower Half
              </td>
              <td>
                1
              </td>
              <td />
              <td>
                1
                <sup>
                  1
                </sup>
                /
                <sub>
                  4
                </sub>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='03'>
                Elsewhere
              </td>
              <td>
                1
                <sup>
                  1
                </sup>
                /
                <sub>
                  4
                </sub>
              </td>
              <td />
              <td>
                1
                <sup>
                  1
                </sup>
                /
                <sub>
                  2
                </sub>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22'>
                Sum of Diameters in a 6-Inch Length: Maximum:
              </td>
              <td />
              <td />
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='03' O='xl'>
                Center Section
              </td>
              <td />
              <td />
              <td />
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='05'>
                Upper Half
              </td>
              <td>
                1
                <sup>
                  1
                </sup>
                /
                <sub>
                  2
                </sub>
              </td>
              <td />
              <td>
                2
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='05'>
                Lower Half
              </td>
              <td>
                2
              </td>
              <td />
              <td>
                2
                <sup>
                  1
                </sup>
                /
                <sub>
                  2
                </sub>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='03'>
                Elsewhere
              </td>
              <td>
                2
                <sup>
                  1
                </sup>
                /
                <sub>
                  2
                </sub>
              </td>
              <td />
              <td>
                3
              </td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>
        <table class='gpotable' CDEF='s100,xs80' COLS='2' OPTS='L2'>
          <caption>
            <div>
              <strong>
                Table II—Knot Limits for Transmission Arms (See Figure 2,
                Appendix A)
              </strong>
            </div>
            <div class='description'>
              [All dimensions in inches]
            </div>
          </caption>
          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th>
                Pole mounting hole zone *
              </th>
              <th>
                Maximum diameter for Single Knot
              </th>
            </tr>
          </thead>
          <tfoot />
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                UPPER HALF (inner zone)
              </td>
              <td>
                <sup>
                  3
                </sup>
                /
                <sub>
                  4
                </sub>
                .
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                UPPER HALF (outer zone)
              </td>
              <td>
                1 for close grain.
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='22' />
              <td>
                1
                <sup>
                  1
                </sup>
                /
                <sub>
                  4
                </sub>
                 dense grain.
              </td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>
        <table class='gpotable' CDEF='s50,12,12,12' COLS='4' OPTS='L2(0,,),ns'>
          <caption />
          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th rowspan='2'>
                Other locations transmission arm size **
              </th>
              <th rowspan='2'>
                Narrow face
              </th>
              <th colspan='2'>
                Wide face (two sides)
              </th>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <th>
                Edge
              </th>
              <th>
                Along
                <LI>
                  centerline
                </LI>
              </th>
            </tr>
          </thead>
          <tfoot>
            <tr>
              <td class='tnote' colspan='4'>
                * No knot shall be closer than its diameter to the pole mounting
                hole.
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td class='tnote' colspan='4'>
                ** For cross sections not shown, refer to grading rules.
              </td>
            </tr>
          </tfoot>
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                4
                <sup>
                  5
                </sup>
                /
                <sub>
                  8
                </sub>
                 × 5
                <sup>
                  5
                </sup>
                /
                <sub>
                  8
                </sub>
                 or less
              </td>
              <td>
                1
              </td>
              <td>
                1
                <sup>
                  1
                </sup>
                /
                <sub>
                  4
                </sub>
              </td>
              <td>
                1
                <sup>
                  1
                </sup>
                /
                <sub>
                  4
                </sub>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                5
                <sup>
                  5
                </sup>
                /
                <sub>
                  8
                </sub>
                 × 7
                <sup>
                  3
                </sup>
                /
                <sub>
                  8
                </sub>
              </td>
              <td>
                1
                <sup>
                  1
                </sup>
                /
                <sub>
                  4
                </sub>
              </td>
              <td>
                1
                <sup>
                  3
                </sup>
                /
                <sub>
                  8
                </sub>
              </td>
              <td>
                1
                <sup>
                  7
                </sup>
                /
                <sub>
                  8
                </sub>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                3
                <sup>
                  5
                </sup>
                /
                <sub>
                  8
                </sub>
                 × 9
                <sup>
                  3
                </sup>
                /
                <sub>
                  8
                </sub>
              </td>
              <td>
                <sup>
                  3
                </sup>
                /
                <sub>
                  4
                </sub>
              </td>
              <td>
                1
                <sup>
                  3
                </sup>
                /
                <sub>
                  4
                </sub>
              </td>
              <td>
                2
                <sup>
                  1
                </sup>
                /
                <sub>
                  4
                </sub>
              </td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Knot clusters shall be prohibited unless the entire cluster,
            measured on the worst face, is equal to or less than the round knot
            allowed at the specific location.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_3_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Spike knots shall be prohibited in deadend arms. Any spike knot
            across the top face shall be limited to the equivalent displacement
            of a knot 
            <FR>
              3/8
            </FR>
             of an inch deep on one face and the maximum round knot for its
            particular location on the worst face, with a maximum width of 1
            inch measured at the 
            <PRTPAGE P='280' />
            midpoint of the spiked section. Elsewhere across the bottom or side
            faces, spike knots shall not exceed 
            <FR>
              1/2
            </FR>
             the equivalent displacement of a round knot permitted at that
            location, provided that the depth of the knot on the worst face
            shall not exceed the maximum round knot allowed at that location.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_3_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Loose knots and knot holes shall be such that they can drain water
            when the arm is installed in its normal position. In the center
            section, upper half, loose knots shall not be greater than 
            <FR>
              1/2
            </FR>
             the dimensions of round knots. Elsewhere, loose knots shall not be
            greater than the round knot dimension. Loose knots shall be
            prohibited in deadend arms.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_3_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All knots except those “spike” knots intersecting a corner shall be
            measured on the least diameter of the knot.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_3_vii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A knot shall be considered to occupy a specific zone or section if
            the center of the knot (i.e., pith of knot) is within the zone or on
            the zone&apos;s boundary.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_3_viii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (viii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a round or oval knot appears on two faces and is in two zones,
            each face shall be judged independently. When this does not occur,
            average the least dimension showing on both faces. Knots which occur
            on only one face of a free of heart center (FOHC) arm shall be
            permitted to be 25 percent larger than the stated size.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_3_ix'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ix)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Two or more knots opposite each other on any face shall be limited
            by a sum not to exceed the size of a maximum single knot permitted
            for the location. On all four faces, all knots shall be well spaced.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_3_x'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (x)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Knots which have a maximum of 
            <FR>
              5/8
            </FR>
             inch diameter may intersect pin holes in the center section. One
            inch diameter knots may intersect insulator pin holes elsewhere.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Miscellaneous characteristics, features, and requirements.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_4_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The top face of distribution crossarms shall not have more than
            four medium pitch and bark pockets in 8-foot arms, and not more than
            five pitch and bark pockets in 10-foot arms. Elsewhere a maximum of
            six medium pockets in 8-foot arms and eight in 10-foot arms shall be
            permitted. Equivalent smaller pockets shall be permissible. An
            occasional large pocket is permissible.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_4_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Shakes shall be prohibited.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_4_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Prior to treatment on properly seasoned arms, single face checks
            shall not exceed an average penetration of 
            <FR>
              1/4
            </FR>
             the depth from any face and shall be limited to 10 inches long on
            the top face, and 
            <FR>
              1/3
            </FR>
             the arm length on the other faces. Checks shall not be repeated in
            the same line of grain in adjacent pin holes. The sum of the average
            depths of checks occurring in the same plane on opposite faces shall
            be limited to 
            <FR>
              1/4
            </FR>
             the face depth.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_4_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Compression wood shall be prohibited on any face. Compression wood
            is permitted if wholly enclosed in the arm, more than six annual
            rings from the surface, and not over 
            <FR>
              3/8
            </FR>
             of an inch in width.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_4_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Insect holes 
            <FR>
              3/32
            </FR>
             of an inch and larger shall be prohibited. Insect pin holes (i.e.
            holes not over 
            <FR>
              1/16
            </FR>
             of an inch diameter) shall be allowed if scattered and not
            exceeding 10 percent of the arm girth.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_4_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Wane shall be allowed on one edge, limited to approximately 1 inch
            measured across the corner. Outside of the top center section, an
            aggregate length not to exceed 2 feet may have wane up to 1
            <FR>
              1/2
            </FR>
             inches on an occasional piece on one or both edges. Bark shall be
            removed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_4_vii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Prior to and after preservative treatment, crook, bow, or twist
            shall not exceed 
            <FR>
              1/2
            </FR>
             of an inch in 8 foot arms and 
            <FR>
              5/8
            </FR>
             of an inch in 10 foot arms.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Manufacturing.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All dimensions and tolerances shall conform to those shown on the
            drawings in this section or drawings supplied with the purchase
            order. Drawings supplied shall meet or exceed minimum dimensions and
            tolerances shown on the drawings in this section. Cross-sectional
            dimensions shall be measured and judged at about 
            <FR>
              1/4
            </FR>
             the arm length, except when the defects of “skip dressing” or
            “machine bite or offset” are involved.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Lamination techniques shall comply with ANSI O5.2 (incorporated by
            reference at 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Pin and bolt holes shall be smoothly bored without undue
            splintering where drill bits break through the surface. The center
            of any hole 
            <PRTPAGE P='281' />
            shall be within 
            <FR>
              1/8
            </FR>
             of an inch of the center-line locations on the face in which it
            appears. Holes shall be perpendicular to the starting and finishing
            faces.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Shape.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The shape of the arms at any cross section, except for permissible
            wane, shall be as shown on the respective drawings in this section
            or supplied with the order. The two top edges may be either
            chamfered or rounded 
            <FR>
              3/8
            </FR>
             of an inch radius. The two bottom edges shall be slightly eased 
            <FR>
              1/8
            </FR>
             of an inch radius for the entire length.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Incising.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The lengthwise surfaces of Douglas-fir crossarms shall be incised
            approximately 
            <FR>
              1/4
            </FR>
             of an inch deep. The incision shall be reasonably clean cut with a
            spacing pattern that ensures uniform penetration of preservative.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Quality of work.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All crossarms shall be of the highest quality production. Crossarms
            shall be dressed on four sides, although “hit and miss skips” may
            occur on two adjacent faces on occasional pieces.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Conditioning prior to treatment.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All solid sawn crossarms shall be made of lumber which has been
            kiln-dried. Douglas-fir arms shall have an average moisture content
            of 19 percent or less, with a maximum not to exceed 22 percent in a
            single arm. Southern Yellow Pine arms shall have an average moisture
            content of 22 percent or less, with a maximum not to exceed 30
            percent in a single arm.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Moisture content levels shall be measured at about 
            <FR>
              1/4
            </FR>
             the length and at a depth of about 
            <FR>
              1/5
            </FR>
             the crossarm&apos;s thickness. Additionally, the moisture content
            gradient between the shell (i.e. 
            <FR>
              1/4
            </FR>
             of an inch deep) and the core (i.e. about 1 inch deep) shall not
            exceed 5 percentage points.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A minimum of at least 20 solid sawn crossarms per treating charge
            shall be measured to verify moisture content and shall be duly
            recorded by the quality control designee.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The moisture content of lumber used in laminating shall, at the
            time of gluing, be within the range of 8 to 12 percent, inclusive.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Preservatives.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The preservatives shall be:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Creosote which conforms to the requirements of AWPA P1/13-06
            (incorporated by reference at 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ), when analyzed in accordance with the methods in AWPA A1-06
            (incorporated by reference at 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ), 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              sections 2, 3, 4
            </aref>
            , either 5 or 9, and 6;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Pentachlorophenol which contains not less than 95 percent
            chlorinated phenols and conforms to AWPA P8-08 (incorporated by
            reference at 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) when analyzed in accordance with AWPA A5-05 (incorporated by
            reference at 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) or AWPA A9-01 (incorporated by reference at 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ). The hydrocarbon solvents for introducing the preservative into
            the wood shall meet the requirements of AWPA P9-06 (incorporated by
            reference at 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) Type A;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Waterborne Preservatives shall be any of the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Ammoniacal Copper Arsenates (ACA) and Ammoniacal Copper Zinc
            Arsenate (ACZA) which shall meet the requirements of AWPA P5-08
            (incorporated by reference at 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ), when analyzed in accordance with methods in AWPA A2-08
            (incorporated by reference at 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) or AWPA A9-01 (incorporated by reference at 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ); and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Chromated Copper Arsenates (CCA) which shall meet the requirements
            of one of the formulations given in AWPA P5-08 (incorporated by
            reference at 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              sections 4, 5 or 6, and 10
            </aref>
            . Tests to establish conformity shall be made in accordance with
            AWPA A2-08 (incorporated by reference at 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) or A9-01 (incorporated by reference at 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='h_2_ii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The pH of treating solutions of the waterborne preservatives shown
            in AWPA P5-08 (incorporated by reference at 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 10
            </aref>
            , shall be determined in accordance with AWPA A2-08, (incorporated
            by reference at 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 8
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='h_2_ii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The oxide formulations of waterborne preservatives shall be
            supplied.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='h_2_ii_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Douglas-fir crossarms shall not be treated with CCA preservatives.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='h_2_ii_D'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (D)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Materials treated with waterborne preservatives shall be free of
            visible surface deposits.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Copper Naphthenate (CuN) concentrate used to prepare wood
            preserving solutions shall contain not less than 6 percent nor more
            than 8 percent copper in the form of CuN and shall conform to AWPA
            P8-08 (incorporated by reference at 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) when analyzed 
            <PRTPAGE P='282' />
            in accordance with AWPA A5-05 (incorporated by reference at 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ). The hydrocarbon solvents for introducing the preservative into
            the wood shall meet the requirements of AWPA P9-06 (incorporated by
            reference at 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) Type A.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Preservative treatment.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All timber products treated under this specification shall be
            treated by either a pressure or a thermal (non-pressure) process.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             These materials may be further conditioned by steaming, or by
            heating in hot oil (Douglas-fir), within the following limits:
          </text>
        </P>
        <table class='gpotable' CDEF='s100,12,xs48' COLS='3' OPTS='L2'>
          <caption />
          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th />
              <th>
                Time hours
                <LI>
                  (max.)
                </LI>
              </th>
              <th>
                Temperature
              </th>
            </tr>
          </thead>
          <tfoot />
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Steam
              </td>
              <td>
                3
              </td>
              <td>
                220 °F
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Heating in Preservation
              </td>
              <td>
                3
              </td>
              <td>
                210 °F
              </td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A final steam or hot oil bath may be used only to meet cleanliness
            requirements of paragraph (k) of this section. Total duration of the
            final steam bath shall not exceed 2 hours and the temperature shall
            not exceed 240 degrees Fahrenheit.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Results of treatments.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The quality control designee shall test or supervise the testing of
            each treated charge for penetration and retention.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Method of sampling.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When testing penetration and retention, a borer core shall be taken
            from not less than 20 crossarms in each treating charge. The borings
            shall be taken from any face except the top face at a point as close
            to the end as possible, being at least 3 inches from the end of the
            arm and no closer than 3 inches from the edge of the holes. The
            bored holes shall be plugged with preservative-treated plugs driven
            into the arm. Borings from laminated arms shall not be taken from
            the same laminate unless there is an end joint separation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             As determined in accordance with AWPA A3-08 (incorporated by
            reference at 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) all sapwood present in Douglas-fir or Southern Yellow Pine
            crossarms shall be completely penetrated with preservative. In the
            heartwood of Douglas-fir crossarms, the penetration shall be not
            less than 3 inches longitudinally from the edge of holes and ends,
            and at least 
            <FR>
              3/16
            </FR>
             inch from the surface of any face.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Retention of preservative in the outer 
            <FR>
              6/10
            </FR>
             of an inch for Douglas-fir and one inch for Southern Yellow Pine
            assay zones at the treating plant shall be not less than:
          </text>
        </P>
        <table class='gpotable' CDEF='s80,12.2,xs56' COLS='3' OPTS='L2'>
          <caption />
          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th>
                Preservation
              </th>
              <th>
                Retention
                <LI>
                  (pcf)
                </LI>
              </th>
              <th>
                AWPA analysis method **
              </th>
            </tr>
          </thead>
          <tfoot>
            <tr>
              <td class='tnote' colspan='3'>
                * The pentachlorophenol retention is for the lime ignition
                method. The copper pyridine method, retention 0.36 pcf is
                required when timbers may have been in contact with salt water,
                and for all species native to the Pacific coast region. It is
                not required when it specifically states on the rough sawn
                material invoice that this material has not been in contact with
                salt water or is shown by analysis to have no additional
                chlorides present in the wood before treating.
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td class='tnote' colspan='3'>
                ** All the AWPA Analysis Methods are incorporated by reference
                at 
                <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
                  § 
                  <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                    1728.97
                  </subref>
                </aref>
                .
              </td>
            </tr>
          </tfoot>
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Creosote
              </td>
              <td>
                8
              </td>
              <td>
                A6.
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Pentachlorophenol
              </td>
              <td>
                * 0.4
              </td>
              <td>
                A5.
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                ACA, ACZA, or CCA
              </td>
              <td>
                0.4
              </td>
              <td>
                A2, A7, or A9.
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Copper Naphthenate
              </td>
              <td>
                0.04
              </td>
              <td>
                A5, or A9.
              </td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Cleanliness of lengthwise surfaces of all crossarms shall be free
            from tarry, greasy, or sticky material, and from oil exudation and
            pentachlorophenol crystallization (blooming).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Re-treatment of materials which do not meet the penetration and
            retention requirements of this specification may be done only twice.
            Initial treatment steaming time plus re-treatment steaming time,
            combined, shall not exceed time allowed in paragraph (i) of this
            section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Marks and brands.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='k_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All crossarms shall be legibly branded (hot brand) or die-stamped
            and to a depth of approximately 
            <FR>
              1/16
            </FR>
             of an inch before treatment.
            <PRTPAGE P='283' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='k_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The letters and figures shall be not less than 
            <FR>
              1/2
            </FR>
             of an inch in height. The top of the brand shall be oriented to the
            top of the arm.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='k_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The brand or die-stamp shall include:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='k_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The manufacturer&apos;s identification symbol;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='k_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Month and year of manufacture;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='k_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Species of timber such as DF for Douglas-fir and SP for Southern
            Yellow Pine; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='k_3_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The preservative notated with a C for creosote, P for penta, S for
            waterbornes, or N for Copper Naphthenate.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='k_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An example is:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          M-6-06 Manufacturer—Month—Year
        </P>
        <P>
          DF-P Douglas-fir—penta treated
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='k_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The brand or stamp shall be placed on either of the wide surfaces
            of the arms, oriented with letters right side up towards the top of
            the arm and preferably about 1 foot from the midpoint of the arm.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='k_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each producer should mark each type of arm in approximately the
            same location on the arm.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='k_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Brands, inspection marks, or quality assurance marks shall be
            removed from arms that do not meet these specifications.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='l'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (l)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Storage.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='l_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Producers may treat crossarms for reserve stock under any of the
            agency approved plans.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='l_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Crossarms treated with oil-borne preservatives which have been held
            in storage for more than 1 year before shipment to the borrower,
            shall be re-assayed before shipment and shall be re-treated if found
            nonconforming for retention on orders placed in accordance with this
            section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='l_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Crossarms shall meet the assay after re-treatment in accordance
            with paragraph (k) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='l_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Crossarms which are held in storage after final acceptance shall be
            stacked in piles or on skids in such a manner as to assure good
            ventilation. The stacks shall be covered or stored indoors for
            protection from the sun and weather to reduce checking, bending, and
            loss of preservative.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='m'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (m)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Drawings.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='m_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The drawings of Appendix B of this section, Crossarm Drilling
            Guide, have a type number and show in detail the hole size, shape,
            and pattern desired for crossarms ordered under this specification.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='m_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Purchase orders shall indicate the type crossarm required.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='m_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Crossarms shall be furnished in accordance with the details of
            these drawings or in accordance with drawings attached to the
            purchase order.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='m_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Appropriate drawings for transmission arms are to be specified and
            included with purchase orders. Technical drawings for transmission
            crossarms are published in Bulletin 1728F-811, “Electric
            Transmission Specifications and Drawings, 115kV through 230kV”
            (incorporated by reference at 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ), and Bulletin 1728F-810, “Electric Transmission Specification and
            Drawings, 34.5kV through 69kV” (incorporated by reference at 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='n'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (n)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Destination inspection.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All crossarms shall meet or exceed their minimum dimensions for at
            least 1 year after date of delivery to the borrower.
          </text>
        </P>
        <GPH DEEP='470' SPAN='2'>
          <PRTPAGE P='284' />
          <GID>
            ER24JN11.013
          </GID>
        </GPH>
        <GPH DEEP='470' SPAN='2'>
          <PRTPAGE P='285' />
          <GID>
            ER24JN11.014
          </GID>
        </GPH>
        <table class='gpotable' CDEF='s100,r50,12' COLS='3' OPTS='L2'>
          <caption>
            <div>
              <strong>
                Appendix C to 
                <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
                  § 
                  <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='201' psec='' tq='N'>
                    1728.201
                  </subref>
                </aref>
                —Metric Conversion Factors
              </strong>
            </div>
          </caption>
          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th>
                To convert from
              </th>
              <th>
                To
              </th>
              <th>
                Multiply by
              </th>
            </tr>
          </thead>
          <tfoot />
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Foot (ft)
              </td>
              <td>
                Meter (m)
              </td>
              <td>
                0.3048
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Inch (in)
              </td>
              <td>
                Centimeter
              </td>
              <td>
                2.54
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Pound per cubic foot (pcf) (lb/ft 
                <sup>
                  3
                </sup>
                )
              </td>
              <td>
                Kilogram per cubic meter (kg/m 
                <sup>
                  3
                </sup>
                )
              </td>
              <td>
                16.01846
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Pound per square inch (psi) (lb/in 
                <sup>
                  2
                </sup>
                )
              </td>
              <td>
                Kilogram per square meter (kg/m 
                <sup>
                  2
                </sup>
                )
              </td>
              <td>
                703.0696
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Degrees Fahrenheit (°F)
              </td>
              <td>
                Degrees Celsius (°C)
              </td>
              <td>
                5/9(F°−32)
              </td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13861'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1728:-:1728.202
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1728.202
      </num>
      <head>
        Bulletin 1728H-702, Specification for Quality Control and Inspection of
        Timber Products.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          76 FR 36965
        </aref>
        , June 24, 2011, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          77 FR 29537
        </aref>
        , May 18, 2012]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='202' psec='' tq='N'>
              1728.202
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Bulletin 1728H-702, Specification for Quality Control and Inspection
          of Timber Products.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Scope.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This specification describes in more detail the responsibilities
            and procedures pertaining to quality control for crossarms, as
            specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='201' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.201
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
            , and poles, covered in Bulletin 1728F-700, “Specification for Wood
            Poles, Stubs and Anchor Logs,” incorporated by reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
             and in 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              § 1755.97 of
            </aref>
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1755' tq='N'>
                1755
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General stipulations.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Conformance of poles and crossarms to agency specifications for the
            most part is the responsibility of the producer&apos;s management.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          A member of the producer&apos;s staff shall be designated quality
          control designee and charged with the responsibility for the exercise
          of proper quality control procedures.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The requirements of AWPA M3-05 (incorporated by reference at 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ), covering records, adequate laboratory, plant gauges, and other
            plant facilities including proper storage, shall be followed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The methods of inspection described in this section shall be used
            no matter which plan timber products are purchased under, i.e.,
            Insured Warranty Plan, Independent Inspection Plan, or Quality
            Assurance Plans, as described in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='201' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.201
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
             or Bulletin 1728F-700 (incorporated by reference at 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ). The number of poles and crossarms actually inspected by monitors
            for quality control under a Quality Assurance Plan or the Insured
            Warranty Plan may vary from the number of poles and crossarms
            inspected under the Independent Inspection Plan. Under the
            Independent Inspection Plan, each pole and a sample number of
            crossarms shall be inspected.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Under the Independent Inspection Plan, the borrower should
            designate in the purchase order which inspection agency it has
            selected. Unless the borrower contracts for inspection as a separate
            transaction, the treating company shall obtain the services of the
            borrower&apos;s designated inspection agency. For reserve treated
            stock for purchase under the Independent Inspection Plan, the
            treating company shall obtain the services of an inspection agency.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Individual inspectors in the employ of Independent Inspection
            Agencies shall be experienced and competent. The inspector shall
            perform all phases of the inspection personally and in the proper
            sequence. The primary responsibility of the inspector is to
            determine, for the borrower, by careful inspection and verification,
            that the timber products, preservative, and treatment meet the
            requirements of Bulletins 1728F-700 (incorporated by reference at 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) and 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='201' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.201
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
             (Bulletin 1728H-701) and that the methods, storage facilities, and
            production equipment conform to applicable specifications. For
            details of the inspector&apos;s qualifications see Appendix A of
            this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Independent inspection agencies and inspectors shall maintain their
            impartiality. To do so, inspection agencies, inspectors, producers
            and brokers must maintain the greatest degree of separation and
            eliminate even the appearance of a conflict of interest. Inspection
            agencies shall not receive gratuities from or enter into financial
            agreements, other than for inspection services, with suppliers for
            which they perform inspection. Inspection agencies shall not provide
            gratuities or free services to suppliers. Inspection agencies shall
            not offer product warranties on inspected material.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Failure of an individual inspector to follow proper procedures or
            failure of an inspection agency to properly train and supervise
            inspectors or follow the appropriate RUS specifications 
            <PRTPAGE P='287' />
            constitutes grounds for RUS debarment of said company from future
            inspection of RUS financed material
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Inspection agencies shall have and maintain liability insurance in
            the amount of $500,000 and a surety bond or miscellaneous errors and
            omission insurance for consequential damages for not less than
            $250,000. Upon request, evidence of compliance to this requirement
            shall be forwarded to the agency. The evidence shall be in the form
            of a certificate of insurance or a Bond signed by a representative
            of the insurance or Surety Bonding company and include a provision
            that no change in, or cancellation of, will be made without the
            prior written notice to Chairman, Technical Standards Committee “A”
            (Electric).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Inspection agencies shall maintain their own laboratory that is
            properly equipped, and capable of completely analyzing the
            respective preservatives and retentions, and at a minimum able to
            run referee methods. This laboratory shall be independent from any
            treating plant laboratory. Independent Inspection Agencies may use
            one central laboratory.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Laminated materials manufactured for use on borrower systems shall
            comply with manufacturing and quality control requirements specified
            in ANSI O5.2 (incorporated by reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ). The product shall be marked and certified.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_10_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Laminated material shall be inspected in accordance with ANSI O5.2,
            (incorporated by reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_10_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Quality control of material shall be performed to determine
            conformance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='201' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.201
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
             and AITC 200, (incorporated by reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Quality control and inspection procedures for product acceptance.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             It is the responsibility of the plant quality control designee to
            perform the following procedures to ensure that a particular lot of
            material conforms to the requirements of the applicable Agency
            specification prior to treatment. After the plant quality control
            designee has performed these procedures, a particular lot of
            material shall be released to the inspector for verification of
            conformance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Poles can be purchased under any of the three purchase plans. These
            plans are Insured Warranty Plan, Independent Inspection Plan, or a
            Quality Assurance Plan. Under all of these plans, all poles in a lot
            shall be inspected by the plant quality control designee.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          Under the Insured Warranty Plan and a Quality Assurance Plan, the
          number of poles inspected by a third party inspector may be less than
          every pole, depending on the terms of the plans.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Ample space and assistance shall be provided by the treating plant
            for handling and turning to ensure that the surfaces of all items
            can be adequately inspected.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Under the Independent Inspection Plan, all poles shall be inspected
            by the Independent Inspector for conformance to the requirements of
            Bulletin 1728F-700 (incorporated by reference at 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ). If a pole is rejected and the cause of rejection is corrected,
            the rejected pole may be offered again for inspection as new
            material.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Dimensions, length, and circumference shall be measured by a
            standard steel tape to determine that they are in agreement with the
            details for class and length in the brand and butt stamp. If it is
            obvious by visual comparison with a measured pole that the brand
            information is correct, individual poles need not be measured. Pole
            circumference dimensions made prior to treatment shall govern
            acceptance. Reduction in dimension due to treatment and shipping
            shall be not more than 2 percent below the minimum for the pole
            class.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If 5 percent of the poles in a lot offered for inspection are
            defective, the inspector shall terminate the inspection.
            Re-examination of an entire lot by plant quality control shall be
            required when the number of rejected poles equals or exceeds 5
            percent of the lot inspected. All defective or nonconforming poles
            either shall be removed from the lot or have their brands marked
            out.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Poles in a lot shall be inspected for decay and all poles shall be
            of the same seasoning condition. If the plant quality control
            designee suspects that decay is present, a slice from both ends
            shall be cut for closer examination. If 3 
            <PRTPAGE P='288' />
            percent of the inspected poles in a lot show evidence of decay, the
            entire lot shall be unconditionally rejected without further
            sorting.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Moisture content, when limited by the purchaser, as stated on the
            purchaser&apos;s purchase order, shall be measured by calibrated
            electronic moisture meter. Calibration of the meter shall include
            not only the zero settings for the X and Y readings, but also two
            resistance standards for 12 and 22 percent moisture content.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_vii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Material failing to conform for moisture content may be retested
            upon request after a recalibration of the instrument. The results of
            the second test shall govern disposition of the lot.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_viii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (viii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Re-examination for any mechanical damage or deterioration and for
            original acceptance shall be conducted on timber products not
            treated within 10 days after original inspection.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Crossarms can be purchased only under either of two purchase plans.
            These plans are the Independent Inspection Plan or Quality Assurance
            Plans. Under the Independent Inspection Plan, crossarms are to be
            inspected prior to manufacture, during manufacture, and after
            treatment. Under a Quality Assurance Plan, crossarms are inspected
            according to the terms of the quality assurance program acceptable
            to Rural Utilities Service.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Inspection prior to treatment shall include:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_viii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Surface inspection of all ends of all arms. This is usually done on
            the stacks of arms prior to manufacture. Particular attention shall
            be paid to defects commonly found in the ends, such as compression
            wood, red heart and other forms of decay, shakes, splits, through
            checks, scantiness, honeycomb, and low density, determined by rings
            per inch and percent of summerwood. All non-conforming arms shall be
            rejected. Whenever the number of nonconforming arms is found to
            exceed 0.5 percent of the lot or one arm, whichever is greater, the
            entire lot shall be rejected for excess number of defective ends.
            After the producer has removed or marked out the defective material,
            the arms may be resubmitted for inspection.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_viii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Surface inspection of the lengthwise sides performed on a random
            representative sample. The sample size shall equal 20 percent of a
            lot size or 200 arms, whichever is smaller. The inspector shall
            examine side surfaces as they are slowly rotated. When necessary,
            the rotation may be stopped for closer inspection. All
            non-conforming arms shall be rejected. Whenever the number of
            nonconforming arms is found to exceed 2 percent of the sample size,
            the entire lot shall be rejected. After the producer has removed or
            marked out the defective material, the arms may be resubmitted for
            inspection.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_viii_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Check of moisture content of the random sample by a calibrated
            moisture meter.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_viii_D'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (D)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Check of crossarm dimensions of the random sample measured after
            surfacing.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Inspection during manufacture shall consist of:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_ii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Checking bolt and insulator pin holes for squareness and excessive
            splintering;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_ii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Checking brands for completeness, location, and legibility; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_ii_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Checking arms for conformance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Under the Independent Inspection Plan, there shall be a final
            inspection after treatment for preservative retention and
            penetration and for damage.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Structural glued laminated timber shall be tested and inspected in
            accordance with AITC 200 (incorporated by reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ). Grade of lumber shall be inspected by a qualified grader for
            specified quality, so marked. Adhesives used for all structural arms
            shall meet requirements of ANSI O5.2 (incorporated by reference at 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) paragraph 5.2. Melamine urea adhesives shall not be used. End
            joint spacing and limitations shall be in accordance with ANSI O5.2.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Preservatives.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Creosote shall conform to the requirements of AWPA P1/P13-06
            (incorporated by reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) when analyzed by AWPA A-06, (incorporated by reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              sections 2, 3, 4
            </aref>
            , either 5 or 9, and 6, as follows:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each occasional charge; and
            <PRTPAGE P='289' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The first charge and one of every five charges randomly selected in
            consecutive charges shall be analyzed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Solutions of waterborne preservatives shall be analyzed for
            components in accordance with AWPA A2-08 (incorporated by reference
            in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            )) or AWPA A9-01 (incorporated by reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) and shall meet the requirements of AWPA P5-08 (incorporated by
            reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) for composition. AWPA A2-08 shall be used as a referee method.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Pentachlorophenol shall contain not less than 95 percent
            chlorinated phenols and should conform to AWPA P8-08 (incorporated
            by reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='297' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.297
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ), in hydrocarbon solvent AWPA P9-06, Type A (incorporated by
            reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Copper Naphthenate in hydrocarbon solvent AWPA P9-06 Type A
            (incorporated by reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ), shall contain not less than 6 percent nor more than 8 percent
            copper in the form of Copper Naphthenate and shall conform to AWPA
            P8-08 (incorporated by reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ), when analyzed in accordance with AWPA A5-05 (incorporated by
            reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Plant facilities and inspection during treatment.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Manufacturing and treating plant facilities shall conform to
            paragraph 3, AWPA M3-05 (incorporated by reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ), Pressure plants shall be equipped with recording instruments to
            register time, pressure, temperature and vacuum during each cycle of
            treatment. Pressure plants shall also be equipped with indicating
            thermometers and pressure and vacuum gauges to check the accuracy of
            the recorders. Work tanks shall be equipped with a thermometer.
            Thermal treating vats shall be equipped with a time and temperature
            recorder and with an indicating thermometer. Temperature recording
            devices are not mandatory for plants treating exclusively with
            waterborne preservatives.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Temperature and humidity readings throughout the kiln shall be
            recorded on a recording chart and verified by observation of direct
            reading equipment. Gauges and recording equipment shall be
            calibrated annually.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Recording instruments shall be checked with calibrated indicating
            gauges and thermometers, per AWPA M3-05 (incorporated by reference
            in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ). Inaccuracies shall be referred to the treating plant for prompt
            correction. If an inaccuracy which indicates error resulting in
            non-compliance with this specification indicating possible damage to
            the material, the inspector shall reject the charge.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Results of treatment.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Poles shall be tested for retention and penetration by means of a
            calibrated increment borer 0.2 inches ±0.02 inches in diameter in
            accordance with procedures in AWPA M2-07 (incorporated by reference
            in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ). Under the Independent Inspection Plan, all treating charges shall
            be tested for retention and penetration. Plant quality control and
            independent inspection shall do their analyses separately. Under the
            Insured Warranty Plan and Quality Assurance Plans, the frequency of
            testing retention and penetration may vary according to the agency
            approved plan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Unless otherwise specified, borings shall be taken approximately 1
            foot above the face brand to 1 foot below the face brand. For
            pressure treated Western Red Cedar and all butt treated poles,
            borings shall be taken approximately 1 foot below groundline.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Penetration compliance shall be determined in accordance with AWPA
            A3-08 (incorporated by reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ). Chrome Azurol S and Penta-Check shall be used to determine
            penetration of copper containing preservatives and penta,
            respectively.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Retention sampling shall be when there are 20 or more poles in the
            treating charge, the retention sample for creosote shall consist of
            20 assay zones from southern pine and Douglas-fir poles. All poles
            in charges with fewer than 20 poles shall be bored once. Charges
            with less than 15 poles shall be bored once and bored again on a
            random basis to obtain a minimum of 15 assay zones.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Retention samples shall be taken from 20 poles in charges of 20 or
            more poles.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Retention samples for Alaska yellow, western red, and northern
            white cedars shall consist of a minimum of 30 assay zones for
            creosote and waterborne preservatives. For penta charges of fewer
            than 30 poles, the sample shall 
            <PRTPAGE P='290' />
            contain the assay zone from each pole in the lot.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Retention samples shall consist of borings, representative of pole
            volumes for each class and length in the charge. Further selection
            and marking of poles of mixed seasoning, volume, and location on the
            tram shall be made as illustrated in the following table:
          </text>
        </P>
        <table class='gpotable' CDEF='s25,12,12,12,12' COLS='5' OPTS='L2'>
          <caption />
          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th>
                Number of poles
              </th>
              <th>
                Class/length
              </th>
              <th>
                Vol. in cu. ft.
              </th>
              <th>
                % of total
                <LI>
                  volume
                </LI>
              </th>
              <th>
                Number of borings
              </th>
            </tr>
          </thead>
          <tfoot>
            <tr>
              <td class='tnote' colspan='5'>
                * If a portion of these poles were green and some partially
                seasoned, then the number of borings should reflect the
                approximate percentage of each.
              </td>
            </tr>
          </tfoot>
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                27
              </td>
              <td>
                7/30
              </td>
              <td>
                232
              </td>
              <td>
                15
              </td>
              <td>
                3
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                26
              </td>
              <td>
                4/35
              </td>
              <td>
                447
              </td>
              <td>
                29
              </td>
              <td>
                6
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                11
              </td>
              <td>
                5/35
              </td>
              <td>
                163
              </td>
              <td>
                10
              </td>
              <td>
                2
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr RUL='n,n,s,n'>
              <td I='01'>
                55 *
              </td>
              <td>
                6/35
              </td>
              <td>
                704
              </td>
              <td>
                46
              </td>
              <td>
                9
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='03'>
                Total
              </td>
              <td />
              <td>
                1,526
              </td>
              <td />
              <td />
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_2_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When material in a lot consists of fewer pieces than the designated
            minimum number of samples for assay, additional borings shall be
            taken so as to make up at least the minimum sample, and in such
            manner that the sample is representative of the lot of material with
            respect to any variations in size, seasoning condition, or other
            features that might affect the results of treatment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_2_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Analyses for preservative retention shall be performed as follows:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='f_2_v_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Creosote retention shall be analyzed by AWPA A6-01 (incorporated by
            reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            );
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='f_2_v_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Penta retention shall be analyzed by AWPA A5-05 (incorporated by
            reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) or AWPA A9-01 (incorporated by reference at 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ). Copper pyridine method is required when timber may have been in
            contact with salt water and for all species native to the Pacific
            coast region, unless the raw material invoice specifically states
            that the material either has not been in contact with salt water or
            has been shown by analysis to have contained no additional chlorides
            before treating;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='f_2_v_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Copper Naphthenate retention shall be analyzed by tests in
            accordance with AWPA A5-05 (incorporated by reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) or AWPA A9-01 (incorporated by reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            );
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='f_2_v_D'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (D)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Waterborne preservatives retention shall be analyzed by tests in
            accordance with AWPA A2-08 (incorporated by reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ), AWPA A7-04 (incorporated by reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ); or AWPA A9-01 (incorporated by reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ); and,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='f_2_v_E'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (E)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Prior to unloading a tram, the inspectors may take their own
            samples and analyze them concurrently with the quality control
            designee, but each shall work independently, and quality control
            data shall be presented before acceptance of the charge.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The penetration sampling of poles shall conform as follows:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Group A poles consist of poles with a circumference of 37.5 inches
            or less at 6 feet from butt.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_3_v_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bore 20 Group A poles or 20 percent of the poles, whichever is
            greater. Accept if 100 percent of the sample conform; otherwise,
            bore all poles.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_3_v_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Re-treat the charge if more than 15 percent of the borings are
            found to be nonconforming.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_3_v_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Re-treat all nonconforming poles if 15 percent or fewer fail the
            requirement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Group B poles consist of poles with circumference greater than 37.5
            inches at 6 feet from the butt.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_3_ii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For Group B poles 45 feet and shorter, bore each pole and re-treat
            only those found to be nonconforming, unless more than 15 percent
            fail; in that case, re-treat the entire lot.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_3_ii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For Group B 50 feet and longer, bore each pole twice at 90 degrees
            apart around the pole and accept only those poles conforming to the
            penetration requirement in both borings. All nonconforming poles may
            be re-treated only twice.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All bored holes (nominal 0.2 of an inch diam. bit) shall be
            promptly filled with treated, tight-fitting wood plugs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Under the Independent Inspection Plan, all treated charges of
            crossarms 
            <PRTPAGE P='291' />
            shall be tested for retention and penetration. Plant quality control
            inspectors and independent inspectors shall do their analyses
            independently. Under the Quality Assurance Plans, the frequency of
            testing retention and penetration may vary according to the plan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_4_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The penetration and retention sample shall consist of 20 (48 for
            creosote) outer 
            <FR>
              6/10
            </FR>
             of an inch for Douglas-fir and 1 inch for Southern Yellow Pine
            zones from borings taken from any face except the top face at a
            location as close to the end as possible being at least 3 inches
            from the end of the arm and no closer than 3 inches from the edge of
            any holes. For laminated material, borings shall be taken from
            laminates on a random basis.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_4_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Preservative penetration shall be tested by taking not less than 20
            borings from 20 crossarms in each charge, determined in accordance
            with AWPA A3-08 (incorporated by reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ). Chrome Azurol S and Penta-Check shall be used to determine
            penetration of copper containing preservatives and penta,
            respectively.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Laminated material shall be checked for any evidence of
            delamination due to treatment and for the identifying quality stamp
            of AITC or American Plywood Association (APA).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If used for analysis, x-ray fluorescence instruments (XRF) shall be
            accurate and reliable, and they shall generate reproducible results.
            Instruments shall have thorough instructions which should include
            recommendations on drying techniques, equipment, and density
            calculations. These drying recommendations shall be followed when
            using XRF instruments.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To check the precision and accuracy of the in-plant x-ray
            fluorescence units (XRF) being used by producers, at least once
            monthly the independent inspector shall take a retention sample
            previously analyzed in the producer&apos;s laboratory and rerun it
            in the inspection agency&apos;s own laboratory. This sample shall be
            run utilizing either the XRF or recognized referee method for the
            given preservative. If the analytical results are within ±5% of
            retention value that was previously obtained on the sample using the
            plant&apos;s XRF unit, the plant instrument needs no further
            calibration. All XRF units maintained by independent agencies as
            part of their required laboratories shall be calibrated at least
            quarterly either by the referee method for each preservative
            treatment being analyzed by said agency or by comparison with a set
            of graduated treated wood standards.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each independent inspector and plant quality control personnel that
            use XRF instruments, shall be properly trained in the analysis of
            treated wood and preservatives under the supervision of a competent
            instructor. Proof of training shall be kept on file.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Product acceptance.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Under the Independent Inspection Plan, the inspector shall signify
            acceptance by marking each piece of accepted material with a clear,
            legible hammer stamp in one end prior to treatment and in the other
            end after treatment. The inspector shall personally mark each piece,
            and shall not delegate this responsibility to another person.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Charge Inspection Reports.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Inspection Reports shall include the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Total pieces offered by the producer, number of pieces rejected and
            cause of rejection;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Conditioning details of the material prior to treatment;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Copy of preservative analysis by preservative supplier;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_2_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The details of treatment; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_2_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The results of treatment. Results shall include the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='g_2_v_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The depth of penetration for each sample and a summary of all poles
            rejected for insufficient penetration;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='g_2_v_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Separate worksheets for retention analyses, prepared by quality
            control designee and independent inspector.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             On each inspection report the independent inspector and the plant
            quality control designee shall certify, in writing, that the
            material listed on the report has been inspected before and after
            treatment, and that the preservative used was analyzed in accordance
            with the requirements of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each inspector or inspection agency shall permanently retain for a
            period of 1 year a copy or transcript of each report of inspection,
            together 
            <PRTPAGE P='292' />
            with laboratory worksheets covering retention by assay and
            preservative analyses for the purchaser, and on request shall
            furnish a copy or transcript of any of these reports to the
            Chairman, Technical Standards Committee “A”, Electric Staff
            Division, Rural Utilities Service, Washington, DC 20250-1569.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Charge numbers on re-treat poles.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The letter “R” shall be added to the original charge number in the
            butts of all poles that are re-treated for insufficient penetration
            or retention of preservative.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All poles that fail to meet treatment requirements after two
            re-treatments shall be permanently rejected.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Safety provisions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Poles intended for agency borrowers shall not be inspected when, in
            the opinion of the inspector, unsafe conditions are present.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 36965
          </aref>
          , June 24, 2011, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            77 FR 29537
          </aref>
          , May 18, 2012]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13862'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1728:-:1728.203
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1728.203
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='203' psec='' tq='N'>
              1728.203
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13863'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1728:-:1728.204
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1728.204
      </num>
      <head>
        Electric standards and specifications for materials and construction.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          77 FR 19529
        </aref>
        , Apr. 2, 2012]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='204' psec='' tq='N'>
              1728.204
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Electric standards and specifications for materials and construction.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General specifications.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This section details requirements for 15 and 25 kV single phase,
            V-phase, and three-phase power cables for use on 12.5/7.2 kV (15 kV
            rated) and 24.9/14.4 kV (25 kV rated) underground distribution
            systems with solidly multi-grounded neutral. Cable complying with
            this specification shall consist of solid or strand-filled
            conductors which are insulated with tree-retardant cross-linked
            polyethylene (TR-XLPE) or ethylene propylene rubber (EPR), with
            concentrically wound copper neutral conductors covered by a
            nonconducting or semiconducting jacket. 35 kV rated cables may be
            used in 24.9/14.4 kV application where additional insulation is
            desired.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The cable may be used in single-phase, two (V)-phase, or
            three-phase circuits.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Acceptable conductor sizes are: No. 2 AWG (33.6 mm
            <SU>
              2
            </SU>
            ) through 1000 kcmil (507 mm
            <SU>
              2
            </SU>
            ) for 15 kV cable, No. 1 AWG (42.4 mm
            <SU>
              2
            </SU>
            ) through 1000 kcmil (507 mm
            <SU>
              2
            </SU>
            ) for 25 kV, and 1/0 (53.5 mm
            <SU>
              2
            </SU>
            ) through 1000 kcmil (507 mm
            <SU>
              2
            </SU>
            ) for 35 kV cable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except where provisions therein conflict with the requirements of
            this specification, the cable shall meet all applicable provisions
            of ANSI/ICEA S-94-649-2004 (incorporated by reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ). Where provisions of the ANSI/ICEA specification conflict with
            this section, 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='204' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.204
              </subref>
            </aref>
             shall apply.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Definitions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             As used in this section:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Agency
          </E>
           refers to the Rural Utilities Service (RUS), an agency of the United
          States Department of Agriculture&apos;s 
          <PRTPAGE P='293' />
          (USDA), hereinafter referred to as the Agency.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            EPR Insulating Compound
          </E>
           is a mixture of ethylene propylene base resin and selected
          ingredients.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            TR-XLPE Insulating Compound
          </E>
           is a tree retardant crosslinked polyethylene (TR-XLPE) insulation
          compound containing an additive, a polymer modification filler, which
          helps to retard the growth of electrical trees in the compound.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Phase conductors.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Central phase conductors shall be copper or aluminum as specified
            by the borrower within the limit of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='204' psec='#a_2' tq='N'>
                1728.204(a)(2)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Central copper phase conductors shall be annealed copper in
            accordance with ASTM B 3-01 (incorporated by reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ). Concentric-lay-stranded phase conductors shall conform to ASTM B
            8-04 (incorporated by reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) for Class B stranding. Compact round concentric-lay-stranded phase
            conductors shall conform to ASTM B 496-04 (incorporated by reference
            in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ). Combination unilay stranded phase conductors shall conform to
            ASTM B 787/B 787M-04 (incorporated by reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ). Compact round atranded copper conductors using single input wire
            construction shall conform to ASTM B835-04 (incorporated by
            reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ). Compressed round stranded copper conductors, hard, medium-hard,
            or soft using single input wire construction shall conform to ASTM
            B902-04a (incorporated by reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ). If not specified, stranded phase conductors shall be Class B
            stranded.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Central aluminum phase conductors shall be one of the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Solid: Aluminum 1350 H12 or H22, H14 or H24, H16 or H26, in
            accordance with ASTM B 609/B 609M-99 (incorporated by reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Stranded: Aluminum 1350 H14 or H24, H142 or H242, H16, or H26, in
            accordance with ASTM B 609/B 609M-99 (incorporated by reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) or Aluminum 1350-H19 in accordance with ASTM B 230/B 230M-07
            (incorporated by reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ). Concentric-lay-stranded (includes compacted and compressed) phase
            conductors shall conform to ASTM B 231/B 231M-04 (incorporated by
            reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) for Class B stranding. Compact round concentric-lay-stranded phase
            conductors shall conform to ASTM B 400-08 (incorporated by reference
            in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ). Combination unilay stranded aluminum phase conductors shall
            conform to ASTM B 786-08 (incorporated by reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ). If not specified, stranded phase conductors shall be class B
            stranded.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The interstices between the strands of stranded conductors shall be
            filled with a material designed to fill the interstices and to
            prevent the longitudinal migration of water that might enter the
            conductor. This material shall be compatible with the conductor and
            conductor shield materials. The surfaces of the strands that form
            the outer surface of the stranded conductor shall be free of the
            strand fill material. Compatibility of the strand fill material with
            the conductor shield shall be tested and shall be in compliance with
            ICEA T-32-645-93 (incorporated by reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ). Water penetration shall be tested and shall be in compliance with
            ANSI/ICEA T-31-610-2007 (incorporated by reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The center strand of stranded conductors shall be indented with the
            manufacturer&apos;s name and year of manufacture at regular
            intervals with no more than 12 inches (0.3 m) between repetitions.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Conductor shield (stress control layer).
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A non-conducting (for discharge resistant EPR) or semi-conducting
            shield (stress control layer) meeting the applicable requirements of
            ANSI/ICEA S-94-649-2004 (incorporated by reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) shall be extruded around the central conductor. The minimum
            thickness at any point shall be in accordance with ANSI/ICEA
            S-94-649-2004. The void and protrusion limits on the conductor
            shield shall be in compliance with ANSI/ICEA S-94-649-2004. The
            shield shall have a nominal operating temperature equal to, or
            higher than, that of the insulation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Insulation.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The insulation shall conform to the requirements of ANSI/ICEA
            S-94-649-2004 (incorporated by reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) and may either be tree retardant cross-linked polyethylene
            (TR-XLPE) or ethylene propylene rubber (EPR), as specified by 
            <PRTPAGE P='294' />
            the borrower. The void and protrusion limits on the insulation shall
            be in compliance with ANSI/ICEA S-94-649-2004.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The thickness of insulation shall be as follows:
          </text>
        </P>
        <table class='gpotable' CDEF='s50,r50,r50,xs74' COLS='4' OPTS='L2'>
          <caption>
            <div>
              <strong />
            </div>
          </caption>
          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th>
                Cable rated voltage
              </th>
              <th>
                Nominal thickness
              </th>
              <th>
                Minimum thickness
              </th>
              <th>
                Maximum thickness
              </th>
            </tr>
          </thead>
          <tfoot />
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                15 kV
              </td>
              <td>
                220 mils (5.59 mm)
              </td>
              <td>
                210 mils (5.33 mm)
              </td>
              <td>
                250 mils (6.35 mm).
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                25 kV
              </td>
              <td>
                260 mils (6.60 mm)
              </td>
              <td>
                245 mils (6.22 mm)
              </td>
              <td>
                290 mils (7.37 mm).
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                35 kV
              </td>
              <td>
                345 mils (8.76 mm)
              </td>
              <td>
                330 mils (8.38 mm)
              </td>
              <td>
                375 mils (9.53 mm).
              </td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Insulation shield.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A semi-conducting thermosetting polymeric layer meeting the
            requirements of ANSI/ICEA S-94-649-2004 (incorporated by reference
            in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) shall be extruded tightly over the insulation to serve as an
            electrostatic shield and protective covering. The shield compound
            shall be compatible with, but not necessarily the same material
            composition as, that of the insulation (e.g., cross-linked
            polyethylene shield may be used with EPR insulation). The void and
            protrusion limits on the semi-conducting shields shall be in
            compliance with the ANSI/ICEA S-94-649-2004.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The thickness of the extruded insulation shield shall be in
            accordance with ANSI/ICEA S-94-649-2004 (incorporated by reference
            in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The shield shall be applied such that all conducting material can
            be easily removed without the need for externally applied heat.
            Stripping tension values shall be 3 through 18 pounds (1.36 through
            8.16 kg) for TR-XLPE and EPR discharge free cables. Discharge
            resistant cables shall have strip tension of 0 through 18 pounds (0
            through 8.16 kg).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The insulation shield shall meet all applicable tests of ANSI/ICEA
            S-94-649-2004 (incorporated by reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Concentric neutral conductor.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Concentric neutral conductor shall consist of annealed round,
            uncoated copper wires in accordance with ASTM B 3-01 (incorporated
            by reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) and shall be spirally wound over the shielding with uniform and
            equal spacing between wires. The concentric neutral wires shall
            remain in continuous intimate contact with the extruded insulation
            shield. Full neutral is required for single phase and 
            <FR>
              1/3
            </FR>
             neutral for three phase applications unless otherwise specified.
            The minimum wire size for the concentric neutral is 16 AWG (1.32 mm
            <SU>
              2
            </SU>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When a strap neutral is specified by the borrower, the neutral
            shall consist of uncoated copper straps applied concentrically over
            the insulation shield with uniform and equal spacing between straps
            and shall remain in intimate contact with the underlying extruded
            insulation shield. The straps shall not have sharp edges. The
            thickness of the flat straps shall be not less than 20 mils (0.5
            mm).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Overall outer jacket.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An electrically nonconducting (insulating) or semi-conducting outer
            jacket shall be applied directly over the concentric neutral
            conductors.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The jacket material shall fill the interstice area between
            conductors, leaving no voids. The jacket shall be free stripping.
            The jacket shall have three red stripes longitudinally extruded into
            the jacket surface 120° apart.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Nonconducting jackets shall consist of low density, linear low
            density, medium density, or high density HMW black polyethylene
            (LDPE, LLDPE, MDPE, HDPE) compound meeting the requirements of
            ANSI/ICEA S-94-649-2004 (incorporated by reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) and ASTM D 1248-05 (incorporated by reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) for Type I, Class C, Category 4 or 5, Grade J3 before application
            to the cable. Polyvinyl chloride (PVC) and chlorinated polyethylene
            (CPE) jackets are not acceptable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Semi-conducting jackets shall have a maximum radial resistivity of
            100 ohm-meter and a maximum moisture vapor transmission rate of 1.5
            g/m
            <SU>
              2
            </SU>
            /24 hours at 38 °C (100 °F) and 90 percent relative humidity in
            accordance 
            <PRTPAGE P='295' />
            with ASTM E 96/E96M-05 (incorporated by reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The minimum thickness of the jacket over metallic neutral wires or
            straps shall comply with the thickness specified in ANSI/ICEA
            S-94-649-2004 (incorporated by reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Tests.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             As part of a request for Agency consideration for acceptance and
            listing, the manufacturer shall submit certified test data results
            to the Agency that detail full compliance with ANSI/ICEA
            S-94-649-2004 (incorporated by reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) for each cable design.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Test results shall confirm compliance with each of the material
            tests, production sampling tests, tests on completed cable, and
            qualification tests included in ANSI/ICEA S-94-649-2004
            (incorporated by reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The testing procedure and frequency of each test shall be in
            accordance with ANSI/ICEA S-94-649-2004 (incorporated by reference
            in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Certified test data results shall be submitted to the Agency for
            any test, which is designated by ANSI/ICEA S-94-649-2004
            (incorporated by reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) as being “for Engineering Information Only,” or any similar
            designation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Partial discharge tests.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Manufacturers shall demonstrate that their cable is not adversely
            affected by excessive partial discharge. This demonstration shall be
            made by completing the procedures described in paragraphs (i)(2)(i)
            and (i)(2)(ii) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each shipping length of completed cable shall be tested and have
            certified test data results available indicating compliance with the
            partial discharge test requirements in ANSI/ICEA S-94-649-2004
            (incorporated by reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Manufacturers shall test production samples and have available
            certified test data results indicating compliance with ASTM D
            2275-01 (incorporated by reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) for discharge resistance as specified in the ANSI/ICEA
            S-94-649-2004 (incorporated by reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ). Samples of insulated cable shall be prepared by either removing
            the overlying extruded insulation shield material, or using
            insulated cable before the extruded insulation shield material is
            applied. The sample shall be mounted as described in ASTM D 2275-01
            and shall be subjected to a voltage stress of 250 volts per mil of
            nominal insulation thickness. The sample shall support this voltage
            stress, and not show evidence of degradation on the surface of the
            insulation for a minimum of 100 hours. The test shall be performed
            at least once on each 50,000 feet (15,240 m) of cable produced, or
            major fractions thereof, or at least once per insulation extruder
            run.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Jacket tests.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Tests described in paragraph (i)(3)(i) of this section shall be
            performed on cable jackets from the same production sample as in
            paragraphs (i)(2)(i) and (i)(2)(ii) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A Spark Test shall be performed on nonconducting jacketed cable in
            accordance with ANSI/ICEA S-94-649-2004 (incorporated by reference
            in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) on 100 percent of the completed cable prior to its being wound on
            shipping reels. The test voltage shall be 4.5 kV AC for cable
            diameters &lt;1.5 inches and 7.0 kV for cable diameters &gt;1.5
            inches, and shall be applied between an electrode at the outer
            surface of the nonconducting (insulating) jacket and the concentric
            neutral for not less than 0.15 second.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             [Reserved]
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Frequency of sample tests shall be in accordance with ANSI/ICEA
            S-94-649-2004 (incorporated by reference in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1728' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
                1728.97
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If requested by the borrower, a certified copy of the results of
            all tests performed in accordance with this section shall be
            furnished by the manufacturer on all orders.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Miscellaneous.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All cable provided under this specification shall have suitable
            markings on the outer surface of the jacket at sequential intervals
            not exceeding 2 feet (0.61 m). The label shall indicate the name of
            the manufacturer, conductor size, type and thickness of insulation,
            center conductor material, voltage rating, year of manufacture, and
            jacket type. There shall be no more than 6 inches (0.15 m) of
            unmarked spacing between texts label sequence. The jacket shall be
            marked with the symbol required by Rule 350G of the National
            Electrical 
            <PRTPAGE P='296' />
            Safety Code and the borrower shall specify any markings required by
            local safety codes. This is in addition to extruded red stripes
            required in this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Watertight seals shall be applied to all cable ends to prevent the
            entrance of moisture during transit or storage. Each end of the
            cable shall be firmly and properly secured to the reel.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Cable shall be placed on shipping reels suitable for protecting it
            from damage during shipment and handling. Reels shall be covered
            with a suitable covering to help provide physical protection to the
            cable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A durable label shall be securely attached to each reel of cable.
            The label shall indicate the purchaser&apos;s name and address,
            purchase order number, cable description, reel number, feet of cable
            on the reel, tare and gross weight of the reel, and beginning and
            ending sequential footage numbers.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            77 FR 19529
          </aref>
          , Apr. 2, 2012]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>