<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol6'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:A:600
    </extid>
    <num>
      600
    </num>
    <head>
      ORGANIZATION
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='6962' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/6962.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 6962
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            65 FR 14781
          </aref>
          , Mar. 20, 2000, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='6122'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:A:600:-:600.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        600.1
      </num>
      <head>
        General.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='600' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              600.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Natural Resources Conservation Service (NRCS) was authorized by
            the Federal Crop Insurance Reform and Department of Agriculture
            Reorganization Act of 1994 (
            <aref target='_blank' title='Pub. L. 103-354' alt='Pub. L. 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Pub. L. 103-354
            </aref>
            , 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='6901' note='notes' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/6901.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 6901 note)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and established by Secretary&apos;s Memorandum 1010-1 (2.b.6), 
            <E T='03'>
              Reorganization of the Department of Agriculture,
            </E>
             to provide national leadership in the conservation, development,
            and productive use of the Nation&apos;s natural resources. Such
            leadership encompasses the conservation of soil, water, air, plant,
            and animal resources with consideration of the many human (economic
            and sociological) interactions. NRCS is the Federal agency that
            works with landowners on private lands to help them conserve their
            natural resources. NRCS employees are highly skilled in many
            scientific and technical specialties, including soil science, soil
            conservation, agronomy, biology, agroecology, range conservation,
            forestry, engineering, geology, hydrology, wetlands science,
            cultural resources, and economics. NRCS was formerly the Soil
            Conservation Service (SCS) which was established by the Soil
            Conservation Act of 1935 (Pub. L. 74-46, 
            <aref target='_blank' href='http://frwebgate.access.gpo.gov/cgi-bin/getpage.cgi?dbname=74_statutes_at_large&amp;position=all&amp;page=163'>
              49 Stat. 163
            </aref>
             (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='16' sect='590' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/590.html'>
                16 U.S.C. 590
              </subref>
            </aref>
             (a-f))). NRCS has responsibility for three major areas:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Soil and water conservation;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Natural resource surveys including soil surveys, resources
            inventory, snow surveys, and water supply forecasting; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Community resource protection and management including watershed
            projects, river basin studies and investigations, resource
            conservation and development areas, land evaluation and site
            assessment, and emergency watershed protection. In addition, NRCS
            has leadership for the Wetlands Reserve Program, Environmental
            Quality Incentives Program, Grazing Lands Conservation Initiative,
            Farmland Protection Program, Wildlife Habitat Incentives Program,
            Forestry Incentives Program, and Conservation Farm Option. NRCS
            provides technical support for the Conservation Reserve Program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The NRCS organization consists of a National Headquarters located
            in Washington, DC; six regional offices; 50 state offices and two
            equivalent offices in the Caribbean Area and the U.S. Trust
            Territories of the Pacific Basin Area; approximately 2,500 field
            offices and 300 specialized offices; 26 plant materials centers; 17
            major land resource area soil survey offices; nine national centers;
            and seven national institutes. A Chief who reports to the USDA Under
            Secretary for Natural Resources and Environment heads NRCS.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6123'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:A:600:-:600.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        600.2
      </num>
      <head>
        National headquarters.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='600' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              600.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          National headquarters.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Chief.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Chief, with assistance of the Associate Chief, is responsible
            for administering a coordinated national program of natural resource
            conservation; planning, directing, and coordinating all program,
            technical, and administrative activities of NRCS; developing
            policies and procedures; correlating NRCS conservation programs with
            other agencies; accepting departmental leadership for programs for
            other activities assigned by the Secretary of Agriculture; and
            serving as Equal Employment Opportunity Officer for NRCS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Deputy chiefs.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Five deputy chiefs assist the Chief as follows:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Deputy Chief for Management.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Deputy Chief for Management is responsible for policies,
            guidelines, and standards for management services, 
            <PRTPAGE P='442' />
            human resources management, financial management, information
            technology, administrative support (providing a coordinated
            administrative management program for National Headquarters
            activities), NRCS outreach, training, and correspondence management.
            This deputy chief also is responsible for the activities of three
            national centers: business management, information technology, and
            employee development.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Deputy Chief for Strategic Planning and Accountability.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Deputy Chief for Strategic Planning and Accountability is
            responsible for policies, guidelines, and standards for strategic
            and performance planning, budget planning and analysis, and
            operations management and oversight.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Deputy Chief for Programs.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Deputy Chief for Programs is responsible for policies,
            guidelines, and standards for conservation operations, resource
            conservation and community development, watersheds and wetlands,
            international programs, conservation compliance activities,
            conservation programs funded by the Commodity Credit Corporation,
            and animal husbandry and clean water programs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Deputy Chief for Soil Survey and Resource Assessment.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Deputy Chief for Soil Survey and Resource Assessment is
            responsible for policies, guidelines, and standards for NRCS
            technical activities, and provides leadership for soils, resource
            inventory, and resource assessment. This deputy chief also is
            responsible for the activities of two national centers (soil survey
            and cartography and geospatial) and two national institutes (soil
            quality and natural resources inventory and analysis).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Deputy Chief for Science and Technology.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Deputy Chief for Science and Technology is responsible for
            policies, guidelines, and standards for the agency, and provides
            leadership for resource economics and social sciences, conservation
            engineering, and ecological sciences. This deputy chief also is
            responsible for the activities of four national centers (water and
            climate, water management, soil mechanics, and plant data) and five
            national institutes (grazing lands technology, social sciences,
            watershed science, wetlands science, and wildlife habitat
            management). This deputy chief, working closely with the deputy
            chiefs for Management and Soil Survey and Resource Assessment,
            provides overall direction for the National Science and Technology
            Consortium.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              National Science and Technology Consortium.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The consortium consists of three divisions, four centers, five
            technical institutes, and several cooperating scientists under the
            Deputy Chief for Science and Technology; two divisions, two centers,
            and two technical institutes under the Deputy Chief for Soil Survey
            and Resource Assessment; and one division and three centers under
            the Deputy Chief for Management.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Centers.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The nine centers provide specific products and services that
            maintain and enhance the technical quality of the agency. The
            centers are: water and climate, water management, soil mechanics,
            plant data, soil survey, cartography and geospatial, information
            technology, business management, and employee development.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Institutes.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The seven institutes are: soil quality, natural resources inventory
            and analysis, grazing lands technology, social sciences, watershed
            science, wetlands science, and wildlife habitat management. The
            institutes provide training; develop technical materials; and
            acquire, develop, and transfer needed technology in special emphasis
            areas so field employees can better serve their customers. The
            institutes often establish partnerships with other Federal agencies,
            universities, and public and private organizations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Cooperating Scientists.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Cooperating scientists work in the areas of soil erosion and
            sedimentation, air quality, and agroforestry. These scientists are
            located at various universities and research centers.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Civil Rights.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Civil Rights staffs provide coordination, assistance, and
            recommendations to the Chief on civil rights employment and program
            compliance issues.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Legislative Affairs.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Legislative Affairs Staff provides coordination and assistance
            to the Chief on legislative affairs issues and activities.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Conservation Communications.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Conservation Communications Staff is 
            <PRTPAGE P='443' />
            responsible for communications, volunteer programs, conservation
            education, and public affairs activities.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Strategic Natural Resource Issues.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Strategic Natural Resource Issues Staff is responsible for
            coordinating priority strategic issues as determined by the Chief.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6124'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:A:600:-:600.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        600.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Regional offices.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='600' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              600.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Regional offices.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Each regional office is under the direction and supervision of a
          regional conservationist. Regional offices are responsible for
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Providing agency leadership, guidance, coordination, and partnering
            for solutions to regional resource issues;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Program implementation, consistency, and accountability;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Region-wide strategic planning, performance measurement, and
            operations management;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Administrative operations and support;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Fund integrity and accountability;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Technical quality of work; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All NRCS activities in the region. Regional offices are located in
            Beltsville, Maryland; Atlanta, Georgia; Fort Worth, Texas; Madison,
            Wisconsin; Lincoln, Nebraska; and Sacramento, California.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6125'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:A:600:-:600.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        600.4
      </num>
      <head>
        State offices.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='600' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              600.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          State offices.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Each office is under the direction and supervision of a State
          conservationist. Each State conservationist is responsible for NRCS
          programs in a State. The Pacific Basin Area Office, under the
          direction and supervision of a director, serves the U.S. Trust
          Territories in that area. The Caribbean Area Office, under the
          direction and supervision of a director, serves the Commonwealth of
          Puerto Rico and the U.S. Virgin Islands. Directors of the Pacific
          Basin and Caribbean areas have the same responsibility and authority
          as a State conservationist. All references to State conservationists
          in this chapter include the directors of the Pacific Basin and
          Caribbean areas.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6126'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:A:600:-:600.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        600.5
      </num>
      <head>
        Area offices.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='600' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              600.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Area offices.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Each area office is under the direction and supervision of an area
          conservationist or assistant State conservationist for field
          operations who is responsible for NRCS activities in the geographical
          area served by the area office. Usually the geographical area includes
          multiple field offices and counties. Many area offices now consist of
          teams working on a watershed or other geopolitical basis.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6127'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:A:600:-:600.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        600.6
      </num>
      <head>
        Field offices.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='600' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              600.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Field offices.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Each field office is under the direction and supervision of a district
          conservationist who is responsible for NRCS activities in the
          geographical area served by the field office. Usually the geographical
          area of a field office includes one or more conservation districts and
          one or more counties. Field offices are generally collocated with
          other USDA agencies in USDA Service Centers.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6128'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:A:600:-:600.7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        600.7
      </num>
      <head>
        Specialized field offices.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='600' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              600.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Specialized field offices.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Other field offices serve specialized activities, such as watershed
          protection and flood reduction projects, construction projects,
          resource conservation and development areas, and soil survey
          activities. State conservationists designate direction and supervision
          of these offices.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6129'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:A:600:-:600.8
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        600.8
      </num>
      <head>
        Plant materials centers.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='600' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              600.8
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Plant materials centers.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Plant materials centers (PMC) assemble and test plant species for
          conservation uses. Usually a PMC serves two or more States, and is
          under the jurisdiction of the State conservationist where the center
          is located. Each PMC is directed and supervised by a manager who is
          responsible to a State office specialist/manager as designated by the
          State conservationist.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6130'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:A:600:-:600.9
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        600.9
      </num>
      <head>
        Major land resource area soil survey offices.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='600' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
              600.9
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Major land resource area soil survey offices.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The United States is divided into 17 major land resource areas (MLRA)
          for the purpose of soil survey production. Major land resource area
          soil survey offices (MO) provide the technical leadership,
          coordination, and quality assurance for all soil survey project
          activities within the respective MLRA. Each MO serves two or more
          States (except for the MO in Alaska), and is under the jurisdiction of
          the State conservationist where the office is located. Each MO is
          directed and supervised by 
          <PRTPAGE P='444' />
          a leader who is designated by the State conservationist.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>