<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol10'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:A:1403
    </extid>
    <num>
      1403
    </num>
    <head>
      DEBT SETTLEMENT POLICIES AND PROCEDURES
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='15' sect='714b' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/15/714b.html'>
              15 U.S.C. 714b
            </subref>
             and 
            <subref title='15' sect='714c' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/15/714c.html'>
              714c
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='1445b-2' note='' psec='#b' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1445b-2.html#b'>
              7 U.S.C. 1445b-2(b)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            54 FR 52878
          </aref>
          , Dec. 22, 1989, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='12229'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:A:1403:-:1403.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1403.1
      </num>
      <head>
        Applicability.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          54 FR 52878
        </aref>
        , Dec. 22, 1989, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          56 FR 66955
        </aref>
        , Dec. 27, 1991]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1403' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              1403.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Applicability.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Except as may otherwise be provided by statute, this part sets forth
          the manner in which the Commodity Credit Corporation (CCC) will settle
          and collect debts by and against CCC.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            54 FR 52878
          </aref>
          , Dec. 22, 1989, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            56 FR 66955
          </aref>
          , Dec. 27, 1991]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12230'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:A:1403:-:1403.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1403.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Administration.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1403' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              1403.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Administration.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The regulations in this part will be administered under the general
          supervision and direction of the Executive Vice President, CCC and the
          Administrator, Farm Service Agency (FSA).
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12231'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:A:1403:-:1403.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1403.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          54 FR 52878
        </aref>
        , Dec. 22, 1989, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          56 FR 66955
        </aref>
        , Dec. 27, 1991]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='442' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1403' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              1403.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The following definitions shall be applicable to this part:
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Administrative charges
          </E>
           means the additional costs of processing delinquent debts against the
          debtor, to the extent such costs are attributable to the delinquency.
          Such costs include, but are not limited to, costs incurred in
          obtaining a credit report, costs of employing commercial firms to
          locate debtor, costs of employing contractors for collection services,
          costs of selling collateral or property to satisfy the debt.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Administrative offset
          </E>
           means deducting money payable or held by the United States
          Government, or any agency thereof, to satisfy in whole or in part a
          debt owed the Government, or any agency thereof.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            FSA
          </E>
           means the Farm Service Agency of the United States Department of
          Agriculture (USDA).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Carrier
          </E>
           means a person or other entity, including but not limited to
          railroads, motor carriers, ocean carriers or piggyback enterprises,
          which provide transportation or other transportation-related services
          for compensation.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Certified financial statement
          </E>
           means an account of the assets, liabilities, income and expenses of a
          debtor, executed in accordance with generally accepted accounting
          principles and attested to as accurate by the preparer, under penalty
          of perjury.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            CCC
          </E>
           means the Commodity Credit Corporation.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Claim
          </E>
           means an amount of money or property which has been determined by
          CCC, after a notice of delinquency and a demand for the payment of the
          debt has been made by CCC, to be owed to CCC by any person other than
          a Federal agency.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Credit reporting agency
          </E>
           means:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A reporting agency as defined at 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              4 CFR 
              <subref title='4' part='102' sect='5' psec='#a' tq='N'>
                102.5(a)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any entity which has entered into an agreement with USDA concerning
            the referral of credit information.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Debt
          </E>
           means any amount owed to CCC or owed by CCC which has not been
          satisfied through payment or otherwise.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Debt record
          </E>
           refers to the account, register, balance sheet, file, ledger, data
          file, or similar record of debts owed to CCC, FSA, or any other
          Government Agency with respect to which collection action is being
          pursued, and which is maintained in an FSA office.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Delinquent debt
          </E>
           means:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any debt owed to CCC that has not been paid by the date specified
            in the applicable statute, regulation, contract, or agreement; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             any debt that has not been paid by the date of an initial
            notification of indebtedness mailed or hand-delivered pursuant to 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1403' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
                1403.4
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Discharged debt
          </E>
           means any debt, or part thereof, which CCC has determined is
          uncollectible.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            IRS
          </E>
           means the Internal Revenue Service.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Late payment interest rate
          </E>
           means the amount of interest charged on delinquent debts and claims.
          The late payment interest rate shall be determined as of the date a
          debt becomes delinquent and shall be equal to the rate of interest
          assessed under the Prompt Payment Act.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Person
          </E>
           means an individual, partnership, association, corporation, estate or
          trust, or other business enterprise or other legal entity and,
          whenever applicable, the Federal Government or a State government, or
          any agency thereof.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Salary offset
          </E>
           means the deduction of money from the current pay account of a
          present or former Government employee payable by the United States
          Government to, or held by the Government for, such person to satisfy a
          debt that person owes the Government.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Settlement
          </E>
           means any final disposition of a debt or claim.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Shipment
          </E>
           means a carload, truckload, containerload, or other conveyance load
          of freight shipped from one location by one shipper for delivery. Such
          shipment must move in accordance with the terms of a commercial or
          ocean bill or lading, or other similar agreement between the carrier
          and CCC. In the case of export shipments, the agreement may also be
          between the carrier and a private voluntary organization, foreign
          government, or the Agency for International Development.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            System of records
          </E>
           means a group of any records under the control of CCC or FSA from
          which information is retrieved by the name of the individual,
          organization or other entity or by 
          <PRTPAGE P='443' />
          some identifying number, symbol, or other identification assigned to
          the individual, organization or other entity.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Withholding
          </E>
           means the taking of action to temporarily prevent the payment of some
          or all amounts to a debtor under one or more contracts or programs.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            54 FR 52878
          </aref>
          , Dec. 22, 1989, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            56 FR 66955
          </aref>
          , Dec. 27, 1991]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12232'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:A:1403:-:1403.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1403.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Demand for payment of debts.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          54 FR 52878
        </aref>
        , Dec. 22, 1989, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          56 FR 66955
        </aref>
        , Dec. 27, 1991]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1403' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              1403.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Demand for payment of debts.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When a debt is due CCC, an initial written demand for payment of
            such amount shall be mailed or hand-delivered to the debtor. If the
            debt is not paid in full by the date specified in the initial demand
            letter, or if a repayment schedule acceptable to CCC has not been
            arranged with the debtor, the initial demand may be followed by two
            subsequent written demands at approximately 30-day intervals. The
            initial or subsequent demand letters shall specify the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The basis for and the amount of the debt determined to be due CCC,
            including the principal, applicable interest, costs and other
            charges;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC&apos;s intent to establish an account on a debt record 30 days
            after the date of the letter, or other applicable period of time, if
            the debt is not paid within that time;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The applicable late payment interest rate.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a late payment interest rate is specified in the contract,
            agreement or program regulation, the debtor shall be informed of
            that rate and the date from which the late payment interest has been
            accruing;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a late payment interest rate is not specified in the contract,
            agreement or program regulation, the debtor shall be informed of the
            applicable late payment interest rate set out in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1403' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
                1403.9
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC&apos;s intent, if applicable, to collect the debt 30 days from
            the date of the initial demand letter, or other applicable period of
            time, by administrative offset from any CCC or FSA payments due or
            to become due to the debtor, and that the claim may be reported to
            other agencies of the Federal government for offset from any amounts
            due or to become due to the debtor;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If not previously provided, the debtor&apos;s right to request
            administrative review by an authorized CCC official, and the proper
            procedure for making such request. If the request relates to the:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_5_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Existence or amount of the debt, it must be made within 15 days
            from the date of the letter, unless a different time period is
            specified in the contract, agreement or program regulation;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_5_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Appropriateness of reporting to a credit reporting agency, it must
            be made within 30 days from the date of the letter; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_5_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Appropriateness of referral to IRS for tax refund offset, it must
            be made within 60 days from the date of the letter.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The debtor&apos;s right to a full explanation of the debt and to
            dispute any information in the records of CCC concerning the debt;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             That CCC maintains the right to initiate legal action to collect
            the amount of the debt;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             That if any portion of the debt remains unpaid or if a repayment
            schedule satisfactory to CCC has not been arranged 90 days after the
            due date, an additional interest rate shall be assessed on the
            unpaid balance of the debt as prescribed in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1403' sect='9' psec='#e' tq='N'>
                1403.9(e)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC&apos;s intent, if applicable, under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1403' sect='16' psec='' tq='N'>
                1403.16
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , to report any delinquent debt to a credit reporting agency no
            sooner than 60 days from the date of the letter;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC&apos;s intent, if applicable, under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1403' sect='18' psec='' tq='N'>
                1403.18
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , to refer any delinquent debt to the IRS, no sooner than 60 days
            from the date of the letter, to be considered for offset against any
            tax refund due or to become due the debtor.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When CCC deems it necessary to protect the Government&apos;s
            interest, written demand may be preceded by other appropriate
            actions.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            54 FR 52878
          </aref>
          , Dec. 22, 1989, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            56 FR 66955
          </aref>
          , Dec. 27, 1991]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12233'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:A:1403:-:1403.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1403.5
      </num>
      <head>
        Collection by payment in full.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1403' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              1403.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Collection by payment in full.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Except as CCC may provide in accordance with 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1403' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              1403.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , CCC shall collect debts owed to the Government, including applicable
          interest, penalties, and administrative costs, in full, whenever
          feasible whether the debt is being collected by administrative offset
          or by 
          <PRTPAGE P='444' />
          another method, including voluntary payment. If a debt is paid in one
          lump sum after the due date, CCC will impose late payment interest, as
          provided in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1403' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
              1403.9
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , unless such interest is waived as provided in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1403' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
              1403.10
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12234'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:A:1403:-:1403.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1403.6
      </num>
      <head>
        Collection by installment payments.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1403' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              1403.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Collection by installment payments.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payments in installments may be arranged, at CCC&apos;s discretion,
            if a debtor furnishes satisfactory evidence of inability to pay a
            claim in full by the specified date. The size and frequency of
            installment payments shall:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bear a reasonable relation to the size of the debt and the
            debtor&apos;s ability to pay; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Normally be of sufficient size and frequency to liquidate the debt
            in not more than three years.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as otherwise determined by CCC, no installment arrangement
            will be considered unless the debtor submits a certified financial
            statement which reflects the debtor&apos;s assets, liabilities,
            income, and expenses. The financial statement shall not be required
            to be submitted sooner than 15 business days following its request
            by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All installment payment agreements shall be in writing and may
            require the payment of interest at the late payment interest rate in
            effect on the date such agreement is executed. The installment
            agreement shall specify all the terms of the arrangement and include
            provision for accelerating the debt in the event the debtor
            defaults. A confession of judgment provision may be included in the
            agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC may deem a repayment plan to be abrogated if the debtor fails
            to comply with its terms.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the debtor&apos;s financial statement or other information
            discloses the ownership of assets which are not encumbered, the
            debtor may be required to secure the payment of an installment note
            by executing a security agreement and financing agreement which
            provides CCC a security interest in the assets until the debt is
            paid in full.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the debtor owes more than one debt to CCC, CCC may allow the
            debtor to designate the manner in which a voluntary installment
            payment is to be applied. If the debtor does not designate the
            application of a voluntary installment or partial payment, the
            payment will be applied to such debts as determined by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12235'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:A:1403:-:1403.7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1403.7
      </num>
      <head>
        Collection by administrative offset.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          54 FR 52878
        </aref>
        , Dec. 22, 1989, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          56 FR 66955
        </aref>
        , Dec. 27, 1991; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          60 FR 43706
        </aref>
        , Aug. 23, 1995]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1403' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              1403.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Collection by administrative offset.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The provisions of this section shall apply to all debts due CCC
            except as otherwise provided in this part and 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              part 1404 of
            </aref>
             this Chapter. This section is not applicable to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC requests for administrative offset against money payable to a
            debtor from the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund and CCC
            requests for salary offset against a present or former employee of
            the Federal Government which shall be made in accordance with
            regulations at 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='3' tq='N'>
                3 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC requests for administrative offset against a Federal income tax
            refund payable to a debtor which shall be made in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1403' sect='18' psec='' tq='N'>
                1403.18
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Cases in which CCC must adjust, by increasing or decreasing, a
            payment which is to be paid under a contract in order to properly
            make other payments due by CCC;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any case in which collection of the type of debt involved by
            administrative offset is explicitly provided for or prohibited by
            statute; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             IRS Notices of Levy which shall be honored in accordance with IRS
            statutes and regulations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Debts due CCC may be collected by administrative offset from
            amounts payable by CCC when:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The debtor has been provided written notification of the basis and
            amount of the debt and has been given an opportunity to make
            payment. Such written notification and opportunity includes notice
            of the right to pursue an administrative appeal in accordance with 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              part 780 of
            </aref>
             this Title or any other applicable appeal procedures, if not
            previously provided;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The debtor has been provided an opportunity to request to inspect
            and copy the records of CCC related to the debt;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The debtor has been notified in writing that the debt may be
            collected by administrative offset if not paid; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The debt has not been delinquent for more than ten years or legal
            action 
            <PRTPAGE P='445' />
            to enforce the debt has not been barred by an applicable period of
            limitation, whichever is later.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Administrative offset shall also be effected against amounts
            payable by CCC:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When requested or approved by the Department of Justice; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When a person is indebted under a judgment in favor of CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Debts due CCC from carriers for overcharges shall be offset against
            amounts due such carriers under freight bills involving shipments
            if:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The carrier, without reasonable justification, has declined payment
            of the debt or has failed to pay the debt after being given a
            reasonable opportunity to make payment; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The period of limitation prescribed at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='49' sect='11706' note='' psec='#f' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/49/11706.html#f'>
                49 U.S.C. 11706(f)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             has not expired.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Debts due CCC from carriers for loss or damage shall be offset
            against amounts due such carriers under freight bills involving
            shipments if:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Timely demand for payment was made on the carrier;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The carrier has declined payment of the debt without reasonable
            justification or has ignored the claim; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The period of limitation prescribed at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='49' sect='11707' note='' psec='#e' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/49/11707.html#e'>
                49 U.S.C. 11707(e)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             has not expired.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any overcharge or loss or damage debt due CCC on which the
            applicable period of limitation has run may be offset against any
            amounts owing by CCC to the carrier which are subject to a defense
            of limitation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A payment due any person may be offset when there is a breach of a
            contract or a violation of CCC program requirements, and offset is
            considered necessary by CCC to protect the financial interests of
            the Government.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the case of any procurement contract with CCC which provides for
            invoicing at the time of shipment with delivery to be made at
            designated destination points when:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payment is made to the contractor prior to receipt of evidence of
            delivery, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC thereafter determines that the Contractor is indebted to CCC
            because of losses sustained from shortage, damage to or
            deterioration of the commodity while in transit and prior to
            delivery, CCC may offset such indebtedness against amounts due and
            payable to the Contractor under any other contract with CCC
            providing the Contractor has not assigned the proceeds of such
            contract in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1404' tq='N'>
                1404 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC may effect administrative offset against a payment to be made
            to a debtor prior to completion of the procedures required by
            (b)(1-3) of this section if:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Failure to take the offset would substantially prejudice CCC&apos;s
            ability to collect the debt; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The time before the payment is to be made does not reasonably
            permit the completion of those procedures.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Debts due any agency other than CCC shall be offset against amounts
            payable by CCC to a debtor when an agency of the U.S. Government has
            submitted a written request for offset which is mailed or
            hand-delivered to the appropriate FSA State office, Kansas City
            Management Office or Kansas City Commodity Office. Such written
            request must:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='j_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bear the signature of an authorized representative of the
            requesting agency;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='j_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Include a certification that all requirements of the law and the
            regulations for collection of the debt and for requesting offset
            have been complied with;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='j_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State the name, address (including county), and, where legally
            available, the social security number or employer ID number of the
            debtor and a brief description of the basis of the debt, including
            identification of the judgment, if any.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='j_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State the amount of the debt separately as to principal, interest,
            penalties, and administrative costs. Interest, if any, shall be
            computed on a daily basis to a date shown in the request. The amount
            to be offset shall not exceed the principal sum owed by the debtor,
            plus interest computed in accordance with the request, and any late
            payment interest, penalties and administrative costs that have been
            assessed;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='j_1_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Certify that the debtor has not filed for bankruptcy. If the debtor
            has filed for bankruptcy, a copy of the order of the bankruptcy
            court relieving 
            <PRTPAGE P='446' />
            the agency from the automatic stay must be included; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='j_1_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State the name, address, and telephone number of a contact person
            within the agency and the address to which payment should be sent.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Unless prohibited by law, the head of an agency, or a designee, may
            defer or subordinate in whole or in part the right of the agency to
            recover through offset all or part of any indebtedness to such
            agency, or may withdraw a request for offset. Notice of such action
            must be sent to the appropriate FSA office.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='k_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             After CCC has complied with the provisions of this part, CCC may
            request other agencies of the Government to offset amounts payable
            by them to persons indebted to CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='k_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the case of a request to IRS for a tax refund offset, the
            provisions at 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1403' sect='18' psec='' tq='N'>
                1403.18
              </subref>
            </aref>
             shall apply.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='l'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (l)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='l_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Debts shall be collected by offset in the following order of
            priority without regard to the date of the request for such
            collection:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='l_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Debts to CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='l_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Debts to other agencies of USDA as determined by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='l_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Debts to other government agencies as determined by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='l_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the case of multiple debts involving the same debtor, CCC may,
            at its discretion, deviate from the usual order of priority in
            applying recovered amounts to debts owed other agencies when
            considered to be in the Government&apos;s best interest. Such
            decision shall be made by CCC based on the facts and circumstances
            of the particular case.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='m'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (m)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='m_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No amounts payable to a debtor by CCC shall be paid to an assignee
            until there have been collected any amounts owed by the debtor
            except as provided in this subsection.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='m_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A payment which is assigned in accordance with 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              part 1404 of
            </aref>
             this Chapter by execution of Form CCC-36 shall be subject to offset
            for any debt owed to CCC or FSA without regard to the date notice of
            assignment was accepted by CCC or FSA.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='m_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A payment which is assigned in accordance with 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              part 1404 of
            </aref>
             this Chapter by execution of Form CCC-252 shall be offset:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='m_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Against any debt of the assignor entered on the debt record of the
            applicable FSA office prior to the filing of such form with CCC or
            FSA, or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='m_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             At anytime, regardless of the date of filing of such form with CCC
            or FSA, if the debt which is the basis for the offset arises under
            the same contract under which the payment is earned by the assignor.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='m_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             With respect to all other Federal agencies, offset shall be made of
            any amounts due any other Federal agency which are entered on the
            debt record of the appropriate FSA office prior to the date the
            notice of assignment was accepted by CCC or FSA.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='m_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any amount due and payable to the assignor which remains after
            deduction of amounts paid to the assignee shall be available for
            offset.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='n'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (n)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Amounts recovered by offset for CCC and FSA debts but later found
            not to be owed to the Government shall be promptly refunded.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='o'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (o)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The debtor shall be notified whenever any offset action has been
            taken.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='p'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (p)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Offsets made pursuant to this section shall not deprive a debtor of
            any right he might otherwise have to contest the debt involved in
            the offset action either by administrative appeal or by legal
            action.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='q'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (q)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any action authorized by the provisions of this section may be
            taken:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='q_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Against a debtor&apos;s pro rata share of payments due any entity
            which the debtor participates in, either directly or indirectly, as
            determined by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='q_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When CCC determines that the debtor has established an entity, or
            reorganized, transferred ownership of, or changed in some other
            manner, their operation, for the purpose of avoiding the payment of
            the claim or debt.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='r'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (r)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The amount to be offset shall not exceed the actual or estimated
            amount of the debt, including interest, administrative charges, and
            penalties, unless the Department of Justice requests that a larger
            specified amount be offset.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='s'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (s)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Offset action will not be taken against payments when:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='s_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The payment represents loan or purchase proceeds for a commodity
            which is subject to the rights of the holder of a prior valid
            enforceable lien. However, any amount that exceeds the 
            <PRTPAGE P='447' />
            amount of the prior lien shall be available for offset.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='s_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A debt has been discharged as provided in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1403' sect='15' psec='' tq='N'>
                1403.15
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='s_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The amount payable to the debtor is used to satisfy a prior lien on
            property pledged as collateral for a CCC loan or sold to CCC.
            However, any amount exceeding the amount of the prior lien shall be
            available for offset.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='s_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC determines such action will unduly interfere with the
            administration of a CCC or FSA program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='s_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The debt has been delinquent for more than ten years or legal
            action to enforce the debt due CCC is barred by an applicable period
            of limitation, whichever is later.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='t'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (t)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='t_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph (b) of this section and
            
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1403' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
                1403.4
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , with respect to debts which are based upon an unsettled CCC loan,
            offset action may be taken when the debtor has been:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='t_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provided written notification of the maturity date of the loan and
            the debtor has not repaid the loan by the maturity date or, in the
            case of a nonrecourse price support loan, has not repaid the loan or
            forfeited the loan collateral to CCC by the date specified by CCC;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='t_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notified of CCC&apos;s intent to establish an account on a debt
            record 30 days after the maturity date, or other applicable period
            of time, if the loan is not settled in accordance with the loan
            agreement;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='t_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notified of the right to pursue an administrative appeal in
            accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='780' tq='N'>
                780 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
             if such an opportunity has not been previously provided;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='t_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provided an opportunity to inspect and copy CCC records related to
            the debt; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='t_1_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notified in writing that the debt may be collected by
            administrative offset if the loan is not repaid or, with respect to
            nonrecourse loans only, settled through forfeiture of the loan
            collateral.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='t_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             After a claim has been established by CCC with respect to a loan
            which has not been settled by the date specified in the loan
            agreement:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='t_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the event CCC takes possession of the collateral which is
            security for a nonrecourse of recourse loan made in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              parts 
              <subref title='7' part='1421' tq='N'>
                1421, 1427, 1434
              </subref>
              , or 
              <subref title='7' part='1435' tq='N'>
                1435 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , the value of such loan collateral shall be determined by CCC in
            accordance with the provisions of such parts which are used to
            determine the settlement value of the collateral. The value of such
            collateral shall be applied to the claim. Any amount remaining due
            on the claim must be paid by the debtor.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='t_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the event CCC takes possession of the collateral which is the
            security for any other loan, the value of such collateral, as
            determined by CCC, less any costs incurred by CCC in taking
            possession and disposing of the collateral, shall be applied to the
            claim. Any amount remaining due on the claim must be paid by the
            debtor.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            54 FR 52878
          </aref>
          , Dec. 22, 1989, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            56 FR 66955
          </aref>
          , Dec. 27, 1991; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            60 FR 43706
          </aref>
          , Aug. 23, 1995]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12236'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:A:1403:-:1403.8
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1403.8
      </num>
      <head>
        Withholding.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          54 FR 52878
        </aref>
        , Dec. 22, 1989]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1403' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              1403.8
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Withholding.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Withholding of a payment prior to the completion of an applicable
            offset procedure may be made from amounts payable to a debtor by CCC
            to ensure that the interests of CCC and the United States will be
            protected as provided in this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A payment may be withheld to protect the interests of CCC or the
            United States only if CCC determines that:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             There has been a serious breach of contract or violation of program
            requirements and the withholding action is considered necessary to
            protect the financial interests of CCC;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             There is substantial evidence of violations of criminal or civil
            frauds statutes and criminal prosecution or civil frauds action is
            of primary importance to program operations of CCC;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Prior experience with the debtor indicates that collection will be
            difficult if amounts payable to the debtor are not withheld;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             There is doubt that the debtor will be financially able to pay a
            judgment on the claim of CCC;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The facts available to CCC are insufficient to determine the amount
            to be offset or the proper payee;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A judgment on a claim of CCC has been obtained; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Such action has been requested by the Department of Justice.
            <PRTPAGE P='448' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except for debts due CCC or FSA, withholding action by CCC on
            amounts payable to debtors of other Government agencies may not be
            made unless requested by the Department of Justice.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            54 FR 52878
          </aref>
          , Dec. 22, 1989]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12237'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:A:1403:-:1403.9
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1403.9
      </num>
      <head>
        Late payment interest and administrative charges.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          54 FR 52878
        </aref>
        , Dec. 22, 1989, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          56 FR 66955
        </aref>
        , Dec. 27, 1991; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          60 FR 43706
        </aref>
        , Aug. 23, 1995]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1403' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
              1403.9
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Late payment interest and administrative charges.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The provisions of this section are applicable to all persons whose
            debt to CCC becomes delinquent after January 1, 1990, unless the
            debtor and CCC agree otherwise.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Late payment interest provisions of this section shall not apply:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To debts owed by Federal agencies and State and local governments.
            Interest on debts owed by such entities shall be charged in
            accordance with applicable statutes or, if none are applicable, at
            the rate of interest charged by the U.S. Treasury for funds borrowed
            by CCC on the day the debt became delinquent;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If an applicable statute, regulation, agreement or contract either
            prohibits the charging of such interest or specifies the interest or
            charges applicable to the debt involved;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the late payment interest is waived by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC will assess late payment interest on the full amount of
            delinquent debts. For purposes of this section, the term “full
            amount of the delinquent debt” means the sum of the principal,
            accrued regular loan interest or accrued program interest, and any
            other charges which are otherwise due and owing to CCC on the
            delinquent debt at the time the late payment interest is assessed,
            except as provided in paragraphs (a)(2) and (d)(3) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The late payment interest shall be expressed as an annual rate of
            interest which CCC charges on delinquent debts. The late payment
            interest rate shall be equal to the higher of the Treasury
            Department&apos;s current value of funds rate or the rate of
            interest assessed under the Prompt Payment Act, determined as of the
            date specified in paragraphs (d)(1) and (d)(2) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When a debt results from a statute, regulation, contract or other
            agreement with specific provisions for late payment interest and
            payment due date, late payment interest shall accrue on the amount
            of the debt from the first day the debt became delinquent, unless
            otherwise provided by statute.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             With respect to debts not resulting from a statute, regulation,
            contract or agreement containing specific provisions for late
            payment interest and payment due date, late payment interest shall
            begin to accrue from the date on which notice of the debt is first
            mailed or hand-delivered to the debtor, except that, with respect to
            debts resulting from price support loans, late payment interest
            shall begin to accrue from the date on which a claim is established.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The rate of late payment interest initially assessed will be fixed
            for the duration of the indebtedness, except when a debtor has
            defaulted on a repayment agreement and seeks to enter into a new
            agreement. CCC may then set a new rate of interest which reflects
            the late payment interest rate in effect at the time the new
            agreement is executed. All charges which accrued, but which were not
            collected under the defaulted agreement, shall be added to the
            principal to be paid under a new repayment agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The late payment interest on delinquent debts will accrue on a
            daily basis.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as specified in paragraphs (a)(2) and (e)(2) of this
            section, an additional interest rate of three (3) percent per annum
            will be assessed on any portion of a debt which remains unpaid 90
            days after the date described in paragraph (d)(1) or (d)(2) of this
            section, if no repayment schedule satisfactory to CCC has been
            agreed upon. Such rate will be assessed retroactively from the date
            late payment interest began to accrue and apply on a daily basis.
            Such rate shall continue to accrue until the delinquent debt has
            been paid.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             With respect to debts resulting from price support loans, an
            additional interest rate of three (3) percent per annum will be
            assessed on a portion of a debt which remains unpaid 60 days after
            the date on which a claim was established. Such rate will be
            assessed 
            <PRTPAGE P='449' />
            retroactively from the date of claim establishment and apply on a
            daily basis. Such rate shall continue to accrue until the delinquent
            debt has been paid.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC shall assess as administrative charges the additional costs of
            processing delinquent debts against the debtor, to the extent such
            costs are attributable to the delinquency. Such costs include, but
            are not limited to, costs incurred in obtaining a credit report,
            costs of employing commercial firms to locate debtor, costs of
            employing contractors for collection services, costs of selling
            collateral or property to satisfy the debt.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When a debt is paid in partial or installment payments, payments
            will be applied first to administrative charges, second to
            additional interest assessed in accordance with paragraph (e) of
            this section and late payment interest, and third to outstanding
            principal.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            54 FR 52878
          </aref>
          , Dec. 22, 1989, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            56 FR 66955
          </aref>
          , Dec. 27, 1991; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            60 FR 43706
          </aref>
          , Aug. 23, 1995]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12238'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:A:1403:-:1403.10
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1403.10
      </num>
      <head>
        Waiver of late payment interest, additional interest and administrative
        charges.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          54 FR 52878
        </aref>
        , Dec. 22, 1989, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          56 FR 66956
        </aref>
        , Dec. 27, 1991]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1403' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
              1403.10
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Waiver of late payment interest, additional interest and
          administrative charges.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except for debts resulting from price support loans, CCC shall
            waive the collection of late payment interest and administrative
            charges on a debt or any portion of a debt which is paid within 30
            days after the date on which late payment interest began to accrue.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC may waive the assessment and collection of all or a portion of
            the additional interest on debts which are appealed in accordance
            with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='780' tq='N'>
                780
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , or other applicable appeal procedures, from either the date of the
            appeal or the date of delinquency, as determined by CCC, until the
            date a final administrative determination is issued. However, with
            respect to CCC programs administered by the Foreign Agricultural
            Service, CCC shall waive the assessment and collection of additional
            interest on debts which are appealed in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='780' tq='N'>
                780
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , or other applicable appeal procedures, from the date of
            delinquency until 30 days after the date of the letter informing the
            appellant of the final administrative determination. The waiver
            provisions of the paragraph shall not apply during any period of
            delay due to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The appellant&apos;s request for a postponement of the scheduled
            hearing;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The appellant&apos;s request for an additional time following the
            hearing to present additional information or a written closing
            statement; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The appellant&apos;s failure to timely present information to the
            reviewing authority.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Assessment and collection of late payment interest, additional
            interest and administrative charges under this part may be waived by
            CCC in full, or in part, if it is determined that such action is in
            the best interest of CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            54 FR 52878
          </aref>
          , Dec. 22, 1989, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            56 FR 66956
          </aref>
          , Dec. 27, 1991]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12239'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:A:1403:-:1403.11
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1403.11
      </num>
      <head>
        Administrative appeal.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          56 FR 66956
        </aref>
        , Dec. 27, 1991]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1403' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
              1403.11
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Administrative appeal.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          If the opportunity to appeal the determination has not previously been
          provided under 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='24' tq='N'>
              24
            </subref>
             or 
            <subref title='7' part='780' tq='N'>
              780 of this title
            </subref>
          </aref>
           or any other appeal procedure, a debtor may obtain an administrative
          review under 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='780' tq='N'>
              780 of this title
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , or other applicable appeal procedures, of CCC&apos;s determination
          concerning the existence or amount of a debt, if a request is filed
          with the authority who made the determination within 15 days of the
          date of CCC&apos;s initial demand letter, unless a longer period is
          specified in the initial demand letter.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            56 FR 66956
          </aref>
          , Dec. 27, 1991]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12240'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:A:1403:-:1403.12
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1403.12
      </num>
      <head>
        Additional administrative collection action.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          56 FR 66956
        </aref>
        , Dec. 27, 1991]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1403' sect='12' psec='' tq='N'>
              1403.12
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Additional administrative collection action.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Nothing contained in this part shall preclude the use of any other
          administrative or contractual remedy which may be available to CCC to
          collect debts owed to the Government.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            56 FR 66956
          </aref>
          , Dec. 27, 1991]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12241'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:A:1403:-:1403.13
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1403.13
      </num>
      <head>
        Contact with debtor&apos;s employing agency.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1403' sect='13' psec='' tq='N'>
              1403.13
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Contact with debtor&apos;s employing agency.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          When a debtor is employed by the Federal Government or is a member of
          the military establishment or the Coast Guard, and collection by
          offset cannot be accomplished in accordance with 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='5' sect='5514' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/5/5514.html'>
              5 U.S.C. 5514
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , CCC may contact the employing agency to arrange for payment of the
          debt by allotment or otherwise, in accordance with section 
          <PRTPAGE P='450' />
          206 of Executive Order No. 11222, May 8, 1965, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            30 FR 6469
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12242'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:A:1403:-:1403.14
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1403.14
      </num>
      <head>
        Prior provision of rights with respect to debt.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1403' sect='14' psec='' tq='N'>
              1403.14
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Prior provision of rights with respect to debt.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          CCC will not provide an administrative appeal with respect to issues
          which were subject to administrative review at the debtor&apos;s
          request as provided under another statute or regulation before:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Effecting administrative offset;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Referring the debt to private collection or credit reporting
            agencies;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Referring the debt to the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) for
            salary offset against the current pay of a present or former
            Government employee; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Referring the debt to IRS for tax refund offset.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12243'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:A:1403:-:1403.15
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1403.15
      </num>
      <head>
        Discharge of debts.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1403' sect='15' psec='' tq='N'>
              1403.15
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Discharge of debts.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as required by other applicable regulation or statute, a
            debt or part thereof owed CCC shall be discharged and the records
            and accounts on that debt closed in the following situations:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When an obligation or part thereof is discharged in bankruptcy;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When an obligation or part thereof is the subject of a final
            judgment entered by a court of competent jurisdiction which is
            adverse to CCC;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When a debt or part thereof is compromised and paid, the amount of
            such compromise;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When collection of a debt by administrative offset is barred in
            accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1403' sect='7' psec='#s_5' tq='N'>
                1403.7(s)(5)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A debt or part thereof owed CCC may be discharged and the records
            and accounts on that debt closed when the Controller, CCC, has
            determined that such action is in the best interest of CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A claims official or claims officer may discharge a delinquent debt
            if such debt arises under the terms of the authority delegated to
            such official or officer in the following circumstances:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The delinquent debt is owed by an entity which has been liquidated
            or dissolved and no legal remedy is feasible.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The delinquent debt is owed by an individual who:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is declared legally insane or incompetent;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Possessed of no assets or other means of payment; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Possessed of no reasonable prospects of being able to pay the debt
            in the future.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The delinquent debt was incurred by an individual who is deceased,
            and from whose estate recovery cannot be made.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Debts discharged in accordance with this section may be reported to
            the Internal Revenue Service pursuant to 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1403' sect='19' psec='' tq='N'>
                1403.19
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12244'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:A:1403:-:1403.16
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1403.16
      </num>
      <head>
        Referral of delinquent debts to credit reporting agencies.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          54 FR 52878
        </aref>
        , Dec. 22, 1989, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          56 FR 66956
        </aref>
        , Dec. 27, 1991]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1403' sect='16' psec='' tq='N'>
              1403.16
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Referral of delinquent debts to credit reporting agencies.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This section specifies the procedures that will be followed by CCC
            and the rights that will be afforded to farm producers when CCC
            reports delinquent debts to credit reporting agencies.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Before disclosing information to a credit reporting agency in
            accordance with this part, CCC shall review the claim and determine
            that it is valid and delinquent.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Before a debt may be referred to a credit reporting agency, the
            debtor must be notified, pursuant to 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              § 1403.4, of
            </aref>
             CCC&apos;s intent to make such a report. Such notification shall
            include:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC&apos;s intent to disclose to a credit reporting agency that the
            debtor is responsible for the debt, and that such disclosure will be
            made not less than 60 days after notification to such debtor.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The information intended to be disclosed to the credit reporting
            agency under paragraph (g)(1) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The debtor&apos;s right to enter a repayment agreement on the debt,
            including, at the discretion of CCC, installment payments, and that
            if such an agreement is reached, the debt will not be referred to a
            credit reporting agency.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The debtor&apos;s right to review of this action in accordance with
            paragraph (i) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The debtor shall be notified, in writing at the debtor&apos;s last
            known address, when CCC has reported any delinquent debt to a credit
            reporting agency.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC shall notify each credit reporting agency to which an original
            disclosure of delinquent debt information was made of any
            substantial 
            <PRTPAGE P='451' />
            change in the condition or amount of the claim.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC shall promptly verify or correct, as appropriate, information
            about the debt on request of a credit reporting agency. The records
            of the debtor shall reflect any correction resulting from such
            request.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Information reported to a credit reporting agency on delinquent
            debts shall be derived from the system of records maintained by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC shall limit delinquent debt information disclosed to credit
            reporting agencies to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The name, address, taxpayer identification number, and other
            information necessary to establish the identity of the debtor;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The amount, status, and history of the claim; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The program under which the claim arose.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Reasonable action shall be taken to locate a debtor for whom CCC
            does not have a current address before reporting delinquent debt
            information to a credit reporting agency.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Before disclosing delinquent debt information to a credit reporting
            agency, CCC shall, upon request of the debtor, provide for a review
            of the debt in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1403' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
                1403.11
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . This review shall only consider defenses or arguments which were
            not available or could not have been available at any previous
            appeal proceeding permitted under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1403' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
                1403.11
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon receipt of a request for review within 30 days from the date
            of notice to the debtor of intent to refer delinquent debt
            information to a credit reporting agency, CCC shall suspend its
            schedule for disclosure to a credit reporting agency until a final
            decision regarding the appropriateness of disclosure to a credit
            reporting agency is made.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon completion of the review, the reviewing official shall
            transmit to the debtor a written notification of the decision. If
            appropriate, the debtor shall be notified of the scheduled date on
            or after which the debt will be referred to the credit reporting
            agency. The debtor will also be notified of any changes from the
            initial notification in the information to be disclosed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In accordance with guidelines established by the Executive Vice
            President, CCC, the responsible claims official shall report to
            credit reporting agencies delinquent debt information specified in
            paragraph (g) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The agreements entered into by USDA and credit reporting agencies
            shall provide the necessary assurances to CCC that the credit
            reporting agencies to which information will be provided are in
            compliance with the provisions of all the laws and regulations of
            the United States relating to providing credit information.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC shall not report delinquent debt information to credit
            reporting agencies when:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='j_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The debtor has entered a repayment agreement covering the debt with
            CCC, and such agreement is still valid; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='j_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC has suspended its schedule for disclosure of delinquent debt
            information pursuant to paragraph (i)(2) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Disclosures made under this section shall be in accordance with the
            requirements of the Privacy Act, as amended (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='5' sect='552a' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/5/552a.html'>
                5 U.S.C. 552a
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='l'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (l)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraphs (a) through (k) of
            this section, all commercial debts owed by debtors other than farm
            producers may be reported to credit reporting agencies.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            54 FR 52878
          </aref>
          , Dec. 22, 1989, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            56 FR 66956
          </aref>
          , Dec. 27, 1991]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12245'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:A:1403:-:1403.17
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1403.17
      </num>
      <head>
        Referral of debts to Department of Justice.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1403' sect='17' psec='' tq='N'>
              1403.17
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Referral of debts to Department of Justice.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Debts which cannot be collected in accordance with these regulations
          may be referred to the Department of Justice for collection action.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12246'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:A:1403:-:1403.18
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1403.18
      </num>
      <head>
        Referral of delinquent debts to IRS or tax refund offset.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1403' sect='18' psec='' tq='N'>
              1403.18
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Referral of delinquent debts to IRS or tax refund offset.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          CCC may refer legally enforceable delinquent debts to IRS to be offset
          against tax refunds due to debtors under 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='26' sect='6402' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/26/6402.html'>
              26 U.S.C. 6402
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , in accordance with the provisions of 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='31' sect='3720A' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/31/3720A.html'>
              31 U.S.C. 3720A
            </subref>
          </aref>
           and Treasury Department regulations.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12247'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:A:1403:-:1403.19
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1403.19
      </num>
      <head>
        Reporting discharged debts to IRS.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='452' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1403' sect='19' psec='' tq='N'>
              1403.19
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Reporting discharged debts to IRS.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In accordance with IRS regulations, CCC may report to IRS as
            discharged debts on IRS Form 1099-G only the amounts specified in
            paragraph (b) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The following discharged debts may be reported to IRS:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The amount of a debt discharged under a compromise agreement
            between CCC and the debtor, except for compromises made due to doubt
            about the Government&apos;s ability to prove its case in court for
            the full amount of the debt.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The amount of a debt discharged by the running of the statutory
            period of limitation for collecting the debt by administrative
            offset specified in 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='31' sect='3716' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/31/3716.html'>
                31 U.S.C. 3716
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The amount of a debt discharged by CCC in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1403' sect='15' psec='#b' tq='N'>
                1403.15(b)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12248'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:A:1403:-:1403.20
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1403.20
      </num>
      <head>
        Referral of debts to private collection agencies.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1403' sect='20' psec='' tq='N'>
              1403.20
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Referral of debts to private collection agencies.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          If CCC&apos;s collection efforts have been unsuccessful after 90 days
          and the delinquent debt remains unpaid, CCC may refer the debt to a
          private collection agency for collection.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12249'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:A:1403:-:1403.21
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1403.21
      </num>
      <head>
        Collection of 1988 and 1989 advance deficiency overpayments.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          56 FR 32319
        </aref>
        , July 16, 1991]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1403' sect='21' psec='' tq='N'>
              1403.21
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Collection of 1988 and 1989 advance deficiency overpayments.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The provisions of this section set forth the policies and
            procedures for collection of 1988 and 1989 advance deficiency
            overpayments (“overpayments”).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The following definition shall be applicable to this section:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Financial hardship
          </E>
           means that condition of a producer in which payment of the debt by
          lump sum would jeopardize the producer&apos;s ability to provide food,
          shelter, and medical care to his immediate family, or to continue the
          producer&apos;s farming operation, as determined by CCC.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This section applies to collection of overpayments from those
            producers who are suffering financial hardship, as determined by
            CCC, and who also meet the following conditions, as determined by
            CCC:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Who received an advance deficiency payment for the 1988 or 1989
            crop of a commodity under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1413' tq='N'>
                1413 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Who are required to provide a refund of at least $1,500 of such
            payment, as a result of the increase in market prices of the
            commodity;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Who reside in a county, or in a county that is contiguous to a
            county where CCC has determined that farming, ranching, or
            aquaculture operations have been substantially affected as evidenced
            by a reduction in normal production for the county of at least 30
            percent during two of the three crop years 1988, 1989, and 1990 by:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A natural disaster designated by the Secretary of Agriculture;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A major disaster or emergency designated by the President under the
            Robert T. Stafford Disaster and Emergency Assistance Act (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='42' sect='5121' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/42/5121.html'>
                42 U.S.C. 5121
              </subref>
            </aref>
            <E T='03'>
              et seq.
            </E>
            );
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Where the total quantity of the 1988 or 1989 crop of the commodity
            that the producers were able to harvest is less than the result of
            multiplying 65 percent of the farm payment yield established CCC for
            the crop by the sum of the acreage planted for the harvest and the
            acreage prevented from being planted (because of the disaster or
            emergency referred to in paragraph (c)(3) of this section) for the
            crop; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Who have applied to the County Farm Service Agency Office which
            issued the advance deficiency payment, no later than May 31, 1991,
            for a determination of eligibility for the repayment provisions of
            this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC shall assess interest on delinquent debts for 1988 or 1989
            overpayments as follows:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC shall establish a regional annual interest rate for each of 12
            geographic regions, corresponding to the extent practicable, as
            determined by CCC, with the 12 geographic districts of the Farm
            Credit System.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each regional annual interest rate shall not exceed the average of
            the interest rates charged by Farm Credit System institutions within
            the region to high-risk borrowers on 1-year operating loans, as
            determined by CCC based upon information provided to CCC by the Farm
            Credit System.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Interest shall accrue at the established regional annual interest
            rate for the region in which the debt arose, beginning November 28,
            1990.
            <PRTPAGE P='453' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC shall not offset, in each of the crop years 1990, 1991, and
            1992, more than 
            <FR>
              1/3
            </FR>
             of the farm program payments otherwise due a producer, as a result
            of the producer&apos;s delinquency in repaying the overpayment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC shall permit producers to repay the overpayment in three equal
            installments during each of the crop years 1990, 1991, and 1992, if
            the producers document to CCC that they have entered into agreements
            to obtain multiperil crop insurance policies for the 1991 and 1992
            crop years.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            56 FR 32319
          </aref>
          , July 16, 1991]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>