<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol6'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:IV:-:407
    </extid>
    <num>
      407
    </num>
    <head>
      GROUP RISK PLAN OF INSURANCE REGULATIONS
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='1506' note='' psec='#l' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1506.html#l'>
              7 U.S.C. 1506(l)
            </subref>
             and 
            <subref title='7' sect='1506' psec='#o' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1506.html#o'>
              1506(o)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            64 FR 30219
          </aref>
          , June 7, 1999, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='5865'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:IV:-:407:-:407.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        407.1
      </num>
      <head>
        Applicability.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='407' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              407.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Applicability.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The provisions of this part are applicable only to those crops and
          crop years for which a Crop Provision is contained in this part.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5866'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:IV:-:407:-:407.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        407.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Availability of Federal crop insurance.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          64 FR 30219
        </aref>
        , June 7, 1999, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          69 FR 48731
        </aref>
        , Aug. 10, 2004]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='407' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              407.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Availability of Federal crop insurance.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Insurance shall be offered under the provisions of this part on the
            insured crop in counties within the limits prescribed by and in
            accordance with the provisions of the Federal Crop Insurance Act, (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='1501' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1501.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 1501
              </subref>
            </aref>
             et seq.) (the Act). The crops and counties shall be designated by
            the Manager of the Federal Crop Insurance Corporation (FCIC) from
            those approved by the Board of Directors of FCIC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The insurance will be offered through companies reinsured by FCIC
            under the same terms and conditions as the contract contained in
            this part. These contracts are clearly identified as being reinsured
            by FCIC. Additionally, the contract contained in this part may be
            offered directly to producers through agents of the United States
            Department of Agriculture. Those contracts are specifically
            identified as being offered by FCIC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No person may have in force more than one insurance policy issued
            or reinsured by FCIC on the same crop for the same crop year, in the
            same county, unless specifically approved in writing by FCIC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as specified in paragraph (c) of this section, if a person
            has more than one contract authorized under the Act that provides
            coverage for the same loss on the same crop for the same crop year
            in the same county, all such contracts shall be voided for that crop
            year and the person will be liable for the premium on all contracts,
            unless the person can show to the satisfaction of the Corporation
            that the multiple contracts of insurance were without the fault of
            the person.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the multiple contracts of insurance are shown to be without the
            fault of the person and:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             One contract is an additional coverage policy and the other
            contract is a Catastrophic Risk Protection policy, the additional
            coverage policy will apply if both policies are with the same
            insurance provider, or if not, both insurance providers agree, and
            the Catastrophic Risk Protection policy will be canceled (If the
            insurance providers do not agree, the policy with the earliest date
            of application will be in force and the other contract will be
            canceled); or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Both contracts are additional coverage policies or both are
            Catastrophic Risk Protection policies, the contract with the
            earliest signature date on the application will be valid and the
            other contract on that crop in the county for that crop year will be
            canceled, unless both policies are with the same insurance provider
            and the insurance provider agrees otherwise or both policies are
            with different insurance providers and both insurance providers
            agree otherwise.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No liability for indemnity or premium will attach to the contracts
            canceled as specified in paragraphs (d)(1)(i) and (ii) of this
            section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The person must repay all amounts received in violation of this
            section with interest at the rate contained in the contract (see 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='407' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
                407.9
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 15
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A person whose contract with FCIC or with a company reinsured by
            FCIC under the Act has been terminated because of violation of the
            terms of the contract is not eligible to obtain crop insurance under
            the Act with FCIC or with a company reinsured by FCIC unless the
            person can show that the termination was improper and should not
            result in subsequent ineligibility.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All applicants for insurance under the Act must advise the
            insurance provider, in writing at the time of application, of any
            previous applications for insurance or contracts of insurance 
            <PRTPAGE P='80' />
            under the Act within the last 5 years and the present status of any
            such applications or insurance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            64 FR 30219
          </aref>
          , June 7, 1999, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            69 FR 48731
          </aref>
          , Aug. 10, 2004]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5867'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:IV:-:407:-:407.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        407.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Premium rates, amounts of protection, and coverage levels.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='407' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              407.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Premium rates, amounts of protection, and coverage levels.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Manager of FCIC shall establish premium rates, amounts of
            protection, and coverage levels for the insured crop that will be
            included in the actuarial documents on file in the insurance
            provider&apos;s office. Premium rates, amounts of protection, and
            coverage levels may be changed from year to year.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             At the time the application for insurance is made, the person must
            elect an amount of protection and a coverage level from among those
            contained in the actuarial documents for the crop year.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5868'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:IV:-:407:-:407.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        407.4
      </num>
      <head>
        OMB control numbers.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='407' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              407.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          OMB control numbers.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The information collection activity associated with this rule has been
          previously approved by the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) under
          control number 0563-0053.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5869'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:IV:-:407:-:407.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        407.5
      </num>
      <head>
        Creditors.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='407' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              407.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Creditors.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          An interest of a person in an insured crop existing by virtue of a
          lien, mortgage, garnishment, levy, execution, bankruptcy, involuntary
          transfer or other similar interest shall not entitle the holder of the
          interest to any benefit under the contract.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5870'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:IV:-:407:-:407.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        407.6
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='407' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              407.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5871'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:IV:-:407:-:407.7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        407.7
      </num>
      <head>
        The contract.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          64 FR 30219
        </aref>
        , June 7, 1999, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          69 FR 48731
        </aref>
        , Aug. 10, 2004]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='407' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              407.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          The contract.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The insurance contract shall become effective upon the acceptance by
          FCIC or the reinsured company of a complete, duly executed application
          for insurance on a form prescribed or approved by FCIC. The contract
          shall consist of the accepted application, Group Risk Plan of
          Insurance Basic Provisions, Crop Provisions, Special Provisions,
          Actuarial Table, and any amendments, endorsements, or options thereto.
          Changes made in the contract shall not affect its continuity from year
          to year. No indemnity shall be paid unless the person complies with
          all terms and conditions of the contract. The forms required under
          this part and by the contract are available at the office of the
          insurance provider, or the local FSA office, if applicable.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            64 FR 30219
          </aref>
          , June 7, 1999, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            69 FR 48731
          </aref>
          , Aug. 10, 2004]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5872'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:IV:-:407:-:407.8
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        407.8
      </num>
      <head>
        The application and policy.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='407' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              407.8
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          The application and policy.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Application for insurance, on a form prescribed or approved by
            FCIC, must be made by any person who wishes to participate in the
            program in order to cover such person&apos;s share in the insured
            crop as landlord, owner-operator, tenant, or other crop ownership
            interest. No other person&apos;s interest in the crop may be insured
            under the application. The application must be submitted to the
            insurance provider on or before the applicable sales closing date on
            file in the insurance provider&apos;s local office.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FCIC or the reinsured company may reject or no longer accept
            applications upon the FCIC&apos;s determination that the insurance
            risk is excessive. The Manager of the Corporation is authorized in
            any crop year to extend the sales closing date for submitting
            applications for fall planted crops, unless prohibited by law, upon
            determining that the probability and severity of claims will not
            increase because of the extension, by placing the extended date on
            file in the insurance provider&apos;s office and publishing a notice
            in the 
            <E T='04'>
              Federal Register.
            </E>
             If adverse conditions should develop during the extended period,
            the Corporation will require the insurance provider to immediately
            discontinue acceptance of applications.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Since this Group Risk Plan differs significantly from traditional
            Multiple Peril Crop Insurance, persons who purchase the Group Risk
            Plan and their crop insurance agents will be required to execute an
            “Acknowledgment of Differences” that explains that the terms and
            conditions of the Group Risk Plan are different from traditional
            crop insurance in that:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Group Risk Plan indemnity payment, if any, will be made after
            the Group Risk Plan premium is received;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A person may have a low yield on his or her individual farm and not
            receive a payment under Group Risk Plan; and
            <PRTPAGE P='81' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A person may not have any loss of production and still collect
            under the policy if a loss of production is general in the area.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             By executing the “Acknowledgment of Differences,” the insured
            certifies that:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_4_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             He or she understands the terms of the Group Risk Plan;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_4_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An MPCI policy may be available in the county; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_4_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Both a Group Risk Plan and a MPCI Plan cannot be purchased on the
            same crop by the same insured in the same county.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5873'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:IV:-:407:-:407.9
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        407.9
      </num>
      <head>
        Group risk plan common policy.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          64 FR 30219
        </aref>
        , June 7, 1999, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          65 FR 40485
        </aref>
        , June 30, 2000; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          68 FR 37721
        </aref>
        , June 25, 2003; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          69 FR 48731
        </aref>
        , Aug. 10, 2004; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          73 FR 36408
        </aref>
        , June 27, 2008; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          73 FR 70864
        </aref>
        , Nov. 24, 2008; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          73 FR 76891
        </aref>
        , Dec. 18, 2008; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          74 FR 11643
        </aref>
        , Mar. 19, 2009; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          74 FR 45543
        </aref>
        , Sept. 3, 2009; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          76 FR 4804
        </aref>
        , Jan. 27, 2011]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='407' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
              407.9
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Group risk plan common policy.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          [FCIC policies]
        </P>
        <EXTRACT>
          <HD SOURCE='HD1'>
            Department of Agriculture
          </HD>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            Federal Crop Insurance Corporation
          </HD>
          <HD SOURCE='HD2'>
            Group Risk Plan Common Policy
          </HD>
          <P>
            [Reinsured policies]
          </P>
          <FP>
            (Appropriate title for insurance provider)
          </FP>
          <FP>
            (This is a continuous policy. Refer to 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              Section 18
            </aref>
            .)
          </FP>
          <P>
            [FCIC policies]
          </P>
          <P>
            This insurance policy establishes a risk management program
            developed by the Federal Crop Insurance Corporation (FCIC), an
            agency of the United States Government, under the authority of the
            Federal Crop Insurance Act (Act), as amended (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='1501' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1501.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 1501
              </subref>
            </aref>
             et seq.). All terms of the policy and rights and responsibilities
            of the parties thereto are subject to the Act and all regulations
            under the Act published in 7 CFR chapter IV. The provisions of this
            policy may not be waived or modified in any way by us, your
            insurance agent or any employee of USDA unless the policy
            specifically authorizes a waiver or modification by written
            agreement. Procedures (handbooks, manuals, memoranda, and
            bulletins), issued by us and published on the RMA Web site at 
            <E T='03'>
              http://www.rma.usda.gov/
            </E>
             or a successor Web site will be used in the administration of this
            policy. All provisions of state and local laws in conflict with the
            provisions of this policy as published at 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='407' tq='N'>
                407
              </subref>
            </aref>
             are preempted and the provisions of this policy control.
          </P>
          <P>
            Throughout this policy, “you” and “your” refer to the person shown
            on the accepted application and “we,” “us,” and “our” refer to the
            Federal Crop Insurance Corporation. Unless the context indicates
            otherwise, the use of the plural form of a word includes the
            singular use and the singular form of the word includes the plural.
          </P>
          <P>
            AGREEMENT TO INSURE: In return for the payment of the premium, and
            subject to all of the provisions of this policy, we agree with you
            to provide the insurance as stated in this policy. If there is a
            conflict between the Act, the regulations published at 7 CFR chapter
            IV, and the procedures issued by us, the order of priority is as
            follows: (1) The Act; (2) the regulations; and (3) the procedures
            issued by us, with (1) controlling (2), etc. If there is a conflict
            between the policy provisions published at 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='407' tq='N'>
                407
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and the administrative regulations published at 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='400' tq='N'>
                400
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , the policy provisions published at 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='407' tq='N'>
                407
              </subref>
            </aref>
             control. If a conflict exists among the policy provisions, the
            order of priority is: (1) The Catastrophic Risk Protection
            Endorsement, as applicable; (2) the Special Provisions; (3) the Crop
            Provisions; and (4) these Basic Provisions, with (1) controlling
            (2), etc.
          </P>
          <P>
            [Reinsured policies]
          </P>
          <P>
            This insurance policy establishes a risk management program
            developed by the Federal Crop Insurance Corporation (FCIC), an
            agency of the United States Government, under the authority of the
            Federal Crop Insurance Act (Act), as amended (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='1501' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1501.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 1501
              </subref>
            </aref>
             et seq.).
          </P>
          <P>
            This insurance policy is reinsured by FCIC under the provisions of
            the Act. All terms of the policy and rights and responsibilities of
            the parties are subject to the Act and all regulations under the Act
            published in 7 CFR chapter IV. The provisions of this policy may not
            be waived or modified in any way by us, our insurance agent or any
            other contractor or employee of ours or any employee of USDA unless
            the policy specifically authorizes a waiver or modification by
            written agreement. We will use the procedures (handbooks, manuals,
            memoranda, and bulletins), as issued by FCIC and published on the
            RMA Web site at 
            <E T='03'>
              http://www.rma.usda.gov/
            </E>
             or a successor Web site, in the administration of this policy. All
            provisions of state and local laws in conflict with the provisions
            of this policy as published at 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='407' tq='N'>
                407
              </subref>
            </aref>
             are preempted and the provisions of this policy will control. In
            the event that we cannot pay your loss because we are insolvent or
            are otherwise unable to perform our duties under our reinsurance
            agreement with FCIC, your claim will be settled in accordance with
            the provisions of this policy and FCIC will be responsible for any
            amounts owed. No state guarantee fund will be liable for your loss.
          </P>
          <P>
            Throughout this policy, “you” and “your” refer to the person shown
            on the accepted application and “we,” “us,” and “our” refer to the
            reinsured company issuing this policy. Unless the context indicates
            otherwise, the use of the plural form of a word includes the
            singular use and the singular form of the word includes the plural.
          </P>
          <P>
            AGREEMENT TO INSURE: In return for the payment of premium and
            subject to all of the provisions of this policy, we agree with you
            to provide risk protection as stated in 
            <PRTPAGE P='82' />
            this policy. If there is a conflict between the Act, the regulations
            published at 7 CFR chapter IV, and the procedures as issued by FCIC,
            the order of priority is as follows: (1) The Act; (2) the
            regulations; and (3) the procedures as issued by FCIC, with (1)
            controlling (2), etc. If there is a conflict between the policy
            provisions published at 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='407' tq='N'>
                407
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and the administrative regulations published at 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='400' tq='N'>
                400
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , the policy provisions published at 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='407' tq='N'>
                407
              </subref>
            </aref>
             control. If a conflict exists among the policy provisions, the
            order of priority is: (1) the Catastrophic Risk Protection
            Endorsement, as applicable; (2) the Special Provisions; (3) the Crop
            Provisions; and (4) these Basic Provisions, with (1) controlling
            (2), etc.
          </P>
          <P>
            [Both policies]
          </P>
          <P>
            The Group Risk Plan of Insurance (GRP) is designed as a risk
            management tool to insure against widespread loss of production of
            the insured crop in a county. It is primarily intended for use by
            those producers whose farm yields tend to follow the average county
            yield. It is possible for you to have a low yield on the acreage
            that you insure and still not receive a payment under this plan.
          </P>
          <P>
            For additional coverage you may select any percent coverage level
            shown on the actuarial documents. Multiplying your coverage level
            percent by the expected county yield shown on the actuarial
            documents gives your trigger yield. If the payment yield that FCIC
            publishes for the insured crop year falls below your trigger yield,
            you will receive a payment.
          </P>
          <P>
            On or before the sales closing date, you may select any dollar
            amount of protection between 60 and 100 percent (except for
            Catastrophic Risk Protection (CAT) which is 45 percent) of the
            maximum protection per acre shown on the actuarial documents. This
            protection will be provided for each acre of the crop planted by the
            acreage reporting date and shown on your acreage report (unless
            otherwise provided in the crop provisions) in which you have a
            share.
          </P>
          <P>
            In accordance with the Act, FCIC will pay a portion of your premium,
            as published in the actuarial documents. The premium rates,
            practices, types, maximum protection per acre, and maximum subsidy
            per acre are also shown on the actuarial documents.
          </P>
          <P>
            FCIC will issue the payment yield in the calendar year following the
            crop year insured. This yield will be the official estimated yield
            published by the National Agricultural Statistics Service (NASS).
            You will be paid if the payment yield falls below your trigger
            yield. The amount of your payment per net insured acre will be
            calculated by subtracting the payment yield from the trigger yield,
            dividing that quantity by the trigger yield, and multiplying that
            result by your protection per acre for each net acre that you have
            insured.
          </P>
          <P>
            To be eligible to participate in the Group Risk Plan of Insurance
            for any crop in any county, and to receive an indemnity thereunder,
            you must have an insurable interest in an insured crop that is
            planted in the county shown on the approved application. The crop
            must be planted for harvest and be reported to us by the acreage
            reporting date. You may only purchase coverage under the Group Risk
            Plan of Insurance on your net acres of the insured crop.
          </P>
          <P>
            The insurance contract shall become effective upon the acceptance by
            us of a duly executed application for insurance on our form. The
            policy will consist of the accepted application, these Basic
            Provisions, the Crop Provisions, the Special Provisions, other
            applicable amendments, endorsements or options, the actuarial
            documents for the insured agricultural commodity, the Catastrophic
            Risk Protection Endorsement, if applicable, and the applicable
            regulations published in 7 CFR chapter IV. Insurance for each
            agricultural commodity in each county will constitute a separate
            policy.
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD2'>
            Terms and Conditions
          </HD>
          <HD SOURCE='HD2'>
            Group Risk Plan of Insurance Basic Provisions
          </HD>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            1. Definitions
          </HD>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Acreage report.
            </E>
             A report required by 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 7 of
            </aref>
             these Basic Provisions that contains, in addition to other
            information, your report of your share of all acreage of an insured
            crop in the county, whether insurable or not insurable.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Acreage reporting date.
            </E>
             The date contained in the Special Provisions by which you must
            submit your acreage report in order to be eligible for Group Risk
            Insurance.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Act.
            </E>
             Federal Crop Insurance Act, (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='1501' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1501.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 1501
              </subref>
            </aref>
             et seq.).
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Actuarial documents.
            </E>
             The material for the crop year which is available for public
            inspection in your agent&apos;s office and published on RMA&apos;s
            Web site at 
            <E T='03'>
              http://www.rma.usda.gov/
            </E>
             or a successor Web site, and which shows the maximum protection per
            acre, expected county yield, coverage levels, information needed to
            determine the premium rates, practices, program dates, and other
            related information regarding crop insurance in the county.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Additional coverage.
            </E>
             For GRP, an amount of protection greater than catastrophic risk
            protection. The protection is on a per acre basis as specified in
            the actuarial documents for the crop, practice, and type.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Agricultural commodity.
            </E>
             Any crop or other commodity produced, regardless of whether or not
            it is insurable.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Agricultural experts.
            </E>
             Persons who are employed by the National Institute of Food and
            Agriculture or the agricultural departments of universities, or
            other persons approved by 
            <PRTPAGE P='83' />
            FCIC, whose research or occupation is related to the specific crop
            or practice for which such expertise is sought.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Area.
            </E>
             Land surrounding the insured acreage with geographic
            characteristics, topography, soil types and climatic conditions
            similar to the insured acreage.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Billing date.
            </E>
             The date, contained in the actuarial documents, by which we will
            bill you for the premium and administrative fee on the insured crop.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Cancellation date.
            </E>
             The calendar date specified in the Crop Provisions on which
            insurance for the next crop year will automatically renew unless the
            policy is canceled in writing by either you or us or terminated in
            accordance with policy terms.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Catastrophic risk protection.
            </E>
             The minimum level of coverage offered by FCIC. For GRP, an amount
            of protection equal to 65 percent of the expected county yield
            indemnified at 45 percent of the maximum protection per acre
            specified in the actuarial documents for the crop, practice, and
            type.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              County.
            </E>
             Any county, parish, or other political subdivision of a state shown
            on your accepted application.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Certifying agent.
            </E>
             A private or governmental entity accredited by the USDA Secretary
            of Agriculture for the purpose of certifying a production,
            processing or handling operation as organic.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Code of Federal Regulations (CFR).
            </E>
             The codification of general and permanent rules published in the 
            <E T='04'>
              Federal Register
            </E>
             by the Executive departments and agencies of the Federal
            Government. Rules published in the 
            <E T='04'>
              Federal Register
            </E>
             by FCIC are contained in 7 CFR chapter IV. The full text of the CFR
            is available in electronic format at 
            <E T='03'>
              http://www.access.gpo.gov/
            </E>
             or a successor Web site.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Contract change date.
            </E>
             The calendar date by which changes to the policy, if any, will be
            made available in accordance with 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 19 of
            </aref>
             these Basic Provisions.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Conventional farming practice.
            </E>
             A system or process for producing an agricultural commodity,
            excluding organic farming practices, that is necessary to produce
            the crop that may be, but is not required to be, generally
            recognized by agricultural experts for the area to conserve or
            enhance natural resources and the environment.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Cover crop.
            </E>
             A crop generally recognized by agricultural experts as
            agronomically sound for the area for erosion control or other
            reasons related to conservation or soil improvement. A cover crop
            may be considered to be a second crop (see the definition of “second
            crop”).
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Crop practice.
            </E>
             The combination of inputs such as fertilizer, herbicide, and
            pesticide, and operations such as planting, cultivation, and
            irrigation, used to produce the insured crop. The insurable
            practices are contained in the actuarial documents.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Crop Provisions.
            </E>
             The part of the policy that contains the specific provisions of
            insurance for each insured crop.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Crop year.
            </E>
             The period of time within which the insured crop is normally grown
            and designated by the calendar year in which the crop is normally
            harvested.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Delinquent debt.
            </E>
             Any administrative fees or premiums for insurance issued under the
            authority of the Act, and the interest on those amounts, if
            applicable, that are not postmarked or received by us or our agent
            on or before the termination date unless you have entered into an
            agreement acceptable to us to pay such amounts or have filed for
            bankruptcy on or before the termination date; any other amounts due
            us for insurance issued under the authority of the Act (including,
            but not limited to, indemnities found not to have been earned or
            that were overpaid), and the interest on such amounts, if
            applicable, which are not postmarked or received by us or our agent
            by the due date specified in the notice to you of the amount due; or
            any amounts due under an agreement with you to pay the debt, which
            are not postmarked or received by us or our agent by the due dates
            specified in such agreement.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Dollar amount of protection per acre.
            </E>
             The percentage of coverage selected by you multiplied by the
            maximum protection per acre specified in the actuarial documents for
            the crop, practice, and type. The dollar amount of protection per
            acre is shown on your Summary of Protection.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Double crop.
            </E>
             Producing two or more crops for harvest on the same acreage in the
            same crop year.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Expected county yield.
            </E>
             The yield contained in the actuarial documents, on which your
            coverage for the crop year is based. This yield is determined using
            historical NASS county average yields, as adjusted by FCIC.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              FCIC.
            </E>
             The Federal Crop Insurance Corporation, a wholly owned corporation
            within USDA.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              First insured crop.
            </E>
             With respect to a single crop year and any specific crop acreage,
            the first instance that an agricultural commodity is planted for
            harvest or prevented from being planted and is insured under the
            authority of the Act. For example, if winter wheat that is not
            insured is planted on acreage that is later planted to soybeans that
            are insured, the first insured crop would be soybeans. If the winter
            wheat was insured, it would be the first insured crop.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              FSA.
            </E>
             The Farm Service Agency, an agency of the United States Department
            of Agriculture, or a successor agency.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Generally recognized.
            </E>
             When agricultural experts or the organic agricultural industry, as
            applicable, are aware of the production method or practice and there
            is no genuine dispute regarding whether the production method or
            practice allows the crop to make normal progress toward maturity.
            <PRTPAGE P='84' />
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Good farming practices.
            </E>
             The production methods utilized to produce the insured crop and
            allow it to make normal progress toward maturity, which are: (1) For
            conventional or sustainable farming practices, those generally
            recognized by agricultural experts for the area; or (2) for organic
            farming practices, those generally recognized by the organic
            agricultural industry for the area or contained in the organic plan
            that is in accordance with the National Organic Program published in
            
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='205' tq='N'>
                205
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . We may, or you may request us to, contact FCIC to determine
            whether or not production methods will be considered to be “good
            farming practices.”
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              GRP.
            </E>
             Group Risk Plan of Insurance.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Household.
            </E>
             A domestic establishment including the members of a family
            (parents, brothers, sisters, children, spouse, grandchildren, aunts,
            uncles, nieces, nephews, first cousins, or grandparents, related by
            blood, adoption or marriage, are considered to be family members)
            and others who live under the same roof.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Insurable loss.
            </E>
             Damage for which coverage is provided under the terms of your
            policy, and for which you accept an indemnity payment.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Insurance provider.
            </E>
             The FSA or a private insurance company approved by FCIC which
            provides crop insurance coverage to producers participating in any
            Federal crop insurance program administered under the Act.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Limited resource farmer.
            </E>
             A person with:
          </P>
          <P>
            (1) Direct or indirect gross farm sales not more than $100,000.00 in
            each of the previous two years (to be increased starting in fiscal
            year 2004 to adjust for inflation using Prices Paid by Farmer Index
            as compiled by NASS); and
          </P>
          <P>
            (2) A total household income at or below the national poverty level
            for a family of four, or less than 50 percent of county median
            household income in each of the previous two years (to be determined
            annually using Commerce Department Data).
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Maximum protection per acre.
            </E>
             The highest amount of protection specified in the actuarial
            documents.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              MPCI.
            </E>
             Multiple peril crop insurance, an insurance product based on an
            individual yield or amount of insurance.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              NASS.
            </E>
             National Agricultural Statistics Service, an agency within USDA, or
            its successor, that publishes the official United States Government
            yield estimates.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Native sod.
            </E>
             Acreage that has no record of being tilled (determined in
            accordance with FSA or other verifiable records acceptable to us)
            for the production of an annual crop on or before May 22, 2008, and
            on which the plant cover is composed principally of native grasses,
            grass-like plants, forbs, or shrubs suitable for grazing and
            browsing.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Net acres.
            </E>
             The planted acreage of the insured crop multiplied by your share.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Offset.
            </E>
             The act of deducting one amount from another amount.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Organic agricultural industry.
            </E>
             Persons who are employed by the following organizations:
            Appropriate Technology Transfer for Rural Areas, Sustainable
            Agriculture Research and Education or the Cooperative Extension
            System, the agricultural departments of universities, or other
            persons approved by FCIC, whose research or occupation is related to
            the specific organic crop or practice for which such expertise is
            sought.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Organic crop.
            </E>
             An agricultural commodity that is organically produced consistent
            with 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 2103 of
            </aref>
             the Organic Foods Production Act of 1990 (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='6502' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/6502.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 6502
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Organic farming practice.
            </E>
             A system of plant production practices used to produce an organic
            crop that is approved by a certifying agent in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='205' tq='N'>
                205
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Payment yield.
            </E>
             The yield determined by FCIC based on NASS yields for each
            insurable crop&apos;s type and practice, as adjusted by FCIC, and
            used to determine whether an indemnity will be due.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Person.
            </E>
             An individual, partnership, association, corporation, estate,
            trust, or other legal entity, and wherever applicable, a state or a
            political subdivision or agency of a state.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Prairie Pothole National Priority Area.
            </E>
             Consists of specific counties within the States of Iowa, Minnesota,
            Montana, North Dakota or South Dakota as specified on the RMA Web
            site at 
            <E T='03'>
              http://www.rma.usda.gov/
            </E>
            , or a successor Web site, or the Farm Service Agency, Agricultural
            Resource Conservation Program 2-CRP (Revision 4), dated April 28,
            2008, or a subsequent publication.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Replanted crop.
            </E>
             The same agricultural commodity replanted on the same acreage as
            the first insured crop for harvest in the same crop year if the
            replanting is specifically made optional by the policy and you elect
            to replant the crop and insure it under the policy covering the
            first insured crop, or replanting is required by the policy.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Sales closing date.
            </E>
             The date contained in the Special Provisions by which an
            application must be filed. The last date by which you may change
            your crop insurance coverage for a crop year.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Second crop.
            </E>
             With respect to a single crop year, the next occurrence of planting
            any agricultural commodity for harvest following a first insured
            crop on the same acreage. The second crop may be the same or a
            different agricultural commodity as the first insured crop, except
            the term does not include a replanted crop. A cover crop, planted
            after a first insured crop and planted for the purpose of haying,
            grazing or otherwise harvesting in any manner or that is hayed or
            grazed during the crop year, or that is otherwise harvested is
            considered to be a second crop. A cover crop that is covered by
            FSA&apos;s noninsured crop disaster assistance program (NAP) or 
            <PRTPAGE P='85' />
            receives other USDA benefits associated with forage crops will be
            considered as planted for the purpose of haying, grazing or
            otherwise harvesting. A crop meeting the conditions stated herein
            will be considered to be a second crop regardless of whether or not
            it is insured.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Share.
            </E>
             Your percentage of interest in the insured crop, as an owner,
            operator, or tenant at the time insurance attaches. Premium will be
            determined on your share as of the acreage reporting date. However,
            only for the purpose of determining the amount of indemnity, your
            share will not exceed your share at the acreage reporting date or on
            the date of harvest, whichever is less.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Special provisions.
            </E>
             The part of the policy that contains specific provisions of
            insurance for each crop that may vary by geographic area.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Subsidy.
            </E>
             The portion of your premium, shown on the actuarial documents, that
            FCIC will pay in accordance with the Act.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Substantial beneficial interest.
            </E>
             An interest held by any person of at least 10 percent in you. The
            spouse of any individual applicant or individual insured will be
            considered to have a substantial beneficial interest in the
            applicant or insured unless the spouses can prove they are legally
            separated or otherwise legally separate under state law. Any child
            of an individual applicant or individual insured will not be
            considered to have a substantial beneficial interest in the
            applicant or insured unless the child has a separate legal interest
            in such person. For example, there are two partnerships that each
            have a 50 percent interest in you and each partnership is made up of
            two individuals, each with a 50 percent share in the partnership. In
            this case, each individual would be considered to have a 25 percent
            interest in you, and both the partnerships and the individuals would
            have a substantial beneficial interest in you (The spouses of the
            individuals would not be considered to have a substantial beneficial
            interest unless the spouse was one of the individuals that made up
            the partnership). However, if each partnership is made up of six
            individuals with equal interests, then each would only have an 8.33
            percent interest in you and although the partnership would still
            have a substantial beneficial interest in you, the individuals would
            not for the purposes of reporting in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 18
            </aref>
            .
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Summary of protection.
            </E>
             Our statement to you of the crop insured, dollar amount of
            protection per acre, premiums, and other information obtained from
            your accepted application, acreage report, and the actuarial
            documents.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Sustainable farming practice.
            </E>
             A system or process for producing an agricultural commodity,
            excluding organic farming practices, that is necessary to produce
            the crop and is generally recognized by agricultural experts for the
            area to conserve or enhance natural resources and the environment.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Termination date.
            </E>
             The calendar date contained in the Crop Provisions upon which
            insurance ceases to be in effect because of nonpayment of any amount
            due us under the policy, including premium and administrative fees.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Tilled.
            </E>
             The termination of existing plants by plowing, disking, burning,
            application of chemicals, or by other means to prepare acreage for
            the production of an annual crop.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Trigger yield.
            </E>
             The result of multiplying the expected county yield by the coverage
            level percentage chosen by you. When the payment yield falls below
            the trigger yield, an indemnity is due.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Type.
            </E>
             Plants of the insured crop having common traits or characteristics
            that distinguish them as a group or class, and which are designated
            in the actuarial documents.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              USDA.
            </E>
             United States Department of Agriculture.
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            2. Insured Crop
          </HD>
          <P>
            The insured crop will be the crop shown on your accepted
            application, as specified in the applicable Crop Provisions, and
            must be grown on insurable acres.
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            3. Insured and Insurable Acreage
          </HD>
          <P>
            (a) The insurable acreage is all of the acreage of the insured crop
            for which premium rates are provided by the actuarial documents and
            in which you have a share and which is in the county listed in your
            accepted application. The dollar amount of protection per acre,
            amount of premium, and indemnity will be calculated separately for
            each county, type, and practice.
          </P>
          <P>
            (b) Only the acreage seeded to the insured crop on or before the
            acreage reporting date (unless otherwise provided in the Crop
            Provisions) and physically located in the county listed on your
            accepted application will be insured. Crops grown on acreage
            physically located in another county must be reported and insured
            separately.
          </P>
          <P>
            (c) We will not insure any acreage:
          </P>
          <P>
            (1) Where the crop was destroyed or put to another use during the
            crop year for the purpose of conforming with, or obtaining a payment
            under, any other program administered by the USDA;
          </P>
          <P>
            (2) Where you have failed to follow good farming practices for the
            insured crop; or
          </P>
          <P>
            (i) Planted to a type, class or variety not generally recognized for
            the area; or
          </P>
          <P>
            (ii) Where the conditions under which the crop is planted are not
            generally recognized for the area (For example, where agricultural
            experts determine that planting a non-irrigated corn crop after a
            failed small grain crop on the same acreage in the same crop year is
            not appropriate for the area);
            <PRTPAGE P='86' />
          </P>
          <P>
            (3) Of a second crop, if you elect not to insure such acreage when
            an indemnity for a first insured crop may be subject to reduction in
            accordance with the provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 21
            </aref>
             and you intend to collect an indemnity payment that is equal to 100
            percent of the insurable loss for the first insured crop acreage.
            This election must be made for all first insured crop acreage that
            may be subject to an indemnity reduction if the first insured crop
            is insured under this policy, or on a first insured crop unit basis
            if the first insured crop is not insured under this policy. For
            example, if the first insured crop under this policy consists of 40
            acres, or the first insured crop unit insured under another policy
            contains 40 planted acres, then no second crop can be insured on any
            of the 40 acres. In this case:
          </P>
          <P>
            (i) If the first insured crop is insured under this policy, you must
            provide written notice to us of your election not to insure acreage
            of a second crop by the acreage reporting date for the second crop
            if it is insured under this policy, or before planting the second
            crop if it is insured under any other policy, or, if the first
            insured crop is not insured under this policy, at the time the first
            insured crop acreage is released by us (if no acreage in the first
            insured crop unit is released, this election must be made by the
            earlier of the acreage reporting date for the second crop or when
            you sign the claim for the first insured crop), and if you fail to
            provide such notice, the second crop acreage will be insured in
            accordance with applicable policy provisions and you must repay any
            overpaid indemnity for the first insured crop;
          </P>
          <P>
            (ii) In the event a second crop is planted and insured with a
            different insurance provider, or planted and insured by a different
            person, you must provide written notice to each insurance provider
            that a second crop was planted on acreage on which you had a first
            insured crop; and
          </P>
          <P>
            (iii) You must report the crop acreage that will not be insured on
            the applicable acreage report; or
          </P>
          <P>
            (4) Of a crop planted following a second crop or following an
            insured crop that is prevented from being planted after a first
            insured crop, unless it is a practice that is generally recognized
            by agricultural experts or the organic agricultural industry for the
            area to plant three or more crops for harvest on the same acreage in
            the same crop year, and additional coverage insurance provided under
            the authority of the Act is offered for the third or subsequent crop
            in the same crop year. Insurance will only be provided for a third
            or subsequent crop as follows:
          </P>
          <P>
            (i) You must provide records acceptable to us that show:
          </P>
          <P>
            (A) You have produced and harvested the insured crop following two
            other crops harvested on the same acreage in the same crop year in
            at least two of the last four years in which you produced the
            insured crop; or
          </P>
          <P>
            (B) The applicable acreage has had three or more crops produced and
            harvested on it in at least two of the last four years in which the
            insured crop was grown on it; and
          </P>
          <P>
            (ii) The amount of insurable acreage will not exceed 100 percent of
            the greatest number of acres for which you provide the records
            required in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 3(c)(4)(i)(A) or (B)
            </aref>
            .
          </P>
          <P>
            (d) If the Governor of a State designated within the Prairie Pothole
            National Priority Area elects to make 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 508(o) of
            </aref>
             the Act effective for the State, any native sod acreage greater
            than five acres located in a county contained within the Prairie
            Pothole National Priority Area that has been tilled after May 22,
            2008, is not insurable for the first five crop years of planting
            following the date the native sod acreage is tilled.
          </P>
          <P>
            (1) If the Governor makes this election after you have received an
            indemnity or other payment for native sod acreage, you will be
            required to repay the amount received and any premium for such
            acreage will be refunded to you.
          </P>
          <P>
            (2) If we determine you have tilled less than five acres of native
            sod a year for more than one crop year, we will add all the native
            sod acreage tilled after May 22, 2008, and all such acreage will be
            ineligible for insurance for the first five crop years of planting
            following the date the cumulative native sod acreage tilled exceeds
            five acres.
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            4. Policy Protection
          </HD>
          <P>
            (a) For catastrophic risk protection GRP policies, the dollar amount
            of protection per acre will be 45 percent of the maximum protection
            per acre specified on the actuarial documents for each insured crop,
            practice, and type. For additional coverage GRP policies, you may
            select any dollar amount of protection from 60 percent through 100
            percent of the maximum protection per acre shown on the actuarial
            documents for the crop, practice, and type.
          </P>
          <P>
            (b) The dollar amount of protection per acre, multiplied by your net
            insured acreage, is your policy protection for each insured crop,
            practice, and type specified in the actuarial documents.
          </P>
          <P>
            (c) All yields are based on NASS determinations, and such
            determinations for the county will be conclusively presumed to be
            accurate.
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            5. Coverage Levels
          </HD>
          <P>
            (a) For catastrophic risk protection GRP policies, the coverage
            level is shown on the actuarial documents for each insured crop,
            practice, and type. For additional coverage GRP policies, you may
            select any percentage of coverage shown on the actuarial documents
            for the crop, practice, and type.
            <PRTPAGE P='87' />
          </P>
          <P>
            (b) Your coverage level multiplied by the expected county yield
            shown on the actuarial documents is your trigger yield. If the
            payment yield published by FCIC for the insured crop, practice, and
            type for the insured crop year falls below your trigger yield, you
            will receive an indemnity payment.
          </P>
          <P>
            (c) You may change the coverage level or amount of protection for
            each insured crop on or before the sales closing date. Changes must
            be in writing and received by us by the sales closing date.
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            6. Payment Calculation Factor
          </HD>
          <P>
            Your payment calculation factor will be ((your trigger yield−payment
            yield) ÷ your trigger yield) for the purposes of calculating an
            indemnity payment.
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            7. Report of Acreage and Share
          </HD>
          <P>
            (a) You must report on our form all acreage for each insured crop in
            which you have a share (insurable and not insured) by practice and
            type specified in the actuarial documents in each county listed on
            your accepted application. This report must be submitted each year
            on or before the acreage reporting date for the insured crop
            contained in the actuarial documents. If you do not submit an
            acreage report by the acreage reporting date, we will determine your
            acreage and share or deny liability on the policy.
          </P>
          <P>
            (b) We will not insure any acreage of the insured crop planted after
            the acreage reporting date, unless otherwise provided in the Crop
            Provisions.
          </P>
          <P>
            (c) The premium amount and payment of an indemnity will be based on
            your insurable acreage on the acreage reporting date subject to 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 7(d)
            </aref>
            .
          </P>
          <P>
            (d) You must provide all required reports and you are responsible
            for the accuracy of all information contained in those reports. You
            should verify the information on all such reports prior to
            submitting them to us.
          </P>
          <P>
            (1) If you submit information on any report that is different than
            what is determined to be correct and such information results in:
          </P>
          <P>
            (i) A lower amount of policy protection than the correct amount, the
            amount of policy protection will be reduced to an amount consistent
            with the reported information; or
          </P>
          <P>
            (ii) A higher amount of policy protection than the correct amount,
            the information contained in the acreage report will be revised to
            be consistent with the correct information.
          </P>
          <P>
            (2) In addition to the other adjustments specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 7(d)(1)
            </aref>
            , if you misreport any information that results in an amount of
            policy protection greater than 110.0 percent or lower than 90.0
            percent of the correct amount of policy protection, any indemnity
            will be based on the amount of policy protection determined in
            accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 7(d)(1)(i) or (ii)
            </aref>
             and will be reduced in an amount proportionate with the amount of
            policy protection that is misreported in excess of the tolerances
            stated in this paragraph (For example, if the correct amount of
            policy protection is determined to be $100.00, but you reported a
            policy protection amount of $120.00, any indemnity will be reduced
            by 10.0 percent ($120.00 / $100.00 = 1.20, and 1.20 −1.10 = 0.10)).
          </P>
          <P>
            (e) If you request an acreage measurement prior to the acreage
            reporting date and submit documentation of such request and an
            acreage report with estimated acreage by the acreage reporting date,
            you must provide the measurement to us, we will revise your acreage
            report if there is a discrepancy, and no indemnity will be paid
            until the acreage measurement has been received by us (Failure to
            provide the measurement to us will result in the application of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 7(d)
            </aref>
             if the estimated acreage is not correct, and estimated acreage
            under this paragraph will no longer be accepted for any subsequent
            acreage report).
          </P>
          <P>
            (f) If there is an irreconcilable difference between:
          </P>
          <P>
            (1) The acreage measured by FSA or a measuring service and our
            on-farm measurement, our on-farm measurement will be used; or
          </P>
          <P>
            (2) The acreage measured by a measuring service, other than our
            on-farm measurement, and FSA, the FSA measurement will be used.
          </P>
          <P>
            (g) Information on the initial acreage report will not be considered
            misreported for the purposes of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 7(d)
            </aref>
             if the acreage report is revised:
          </P>
          <P>
            (1) In accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 7(e) or (f)
            </aref>
            ;
          </P>
          <P>
            (2) Because information is clearly transposed;
          </P>
          <P>
            (3) When you provide adequate evidence that we or someone from USDA
            have committed an error regarding the information; or
          </P>
          <P>
            (4) As expressly permitted by the policy.
          </P>
          <P>
            (h) If we discover you have incorrectly reported any information on
            the acreage report for any crop year, you may be required to provide
            documentation in subsequent crop years substantiating your report of
            acreage for those crop years, including, but not limited to, an
            acreage measurement service at your own expense. If the correction
            of any misreported information would affect an indemnity that was
            paid in a prior crop year, such claim will be adjusted and you will
            be required to repay any overpaid amounts.
          </P>
          <P>
            (i) You may insure only your share of the crop, which includes any
            share of your spouse and dependent children unless it is
            demonstrated to our satisfaction, prior to the sales closing date,
            that you and your spouse maintain completely separate farming
            operations and that each spouse is the operator of his or her own
            separate operation. Any commingling of any part of the 
            <PRTPAGE P='88' />
            operations will cause shares of you and your spouse to be combined.
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            8. Administrative Fees and Annual Premium
          </HD>
          <P>
            (a) If you obtain a catastrophic risk protection GRP policy, you
            will pay an administrative fee, unless otherwise authorized in the
            Act:
          </P>
          <P>
            (1) Of $300 per crop per county unless otherwise specified in the
            Special Provisions;
          </P>
          <P>
            (2) Payable to the insurance provider on the billing date for the
            crop.
          </P>
          <P>
            (b) If you obtain an additional coverage GRP policy, you will pay an
            administrative fee:
          </P>
          <P>
            (1) Of $30 per crop per county;
          </P>
          <P>
            (2) Payable to the insurance provider on the billing date for the
            crop.
          </P>
          <P>
            (c) The administrative fee will be waived if you request it and:
          </P>
          <P>
            (1) You qualify as a limited resource farmer; or
          </P>
          <P>
            (2) You were insured prior to the 2005 crop year or for the 2005
            crop year and your administrative fee was waived for one or more of
            those crop years because you qualified as a limited resource farmer
            under a policy definition previously in effect, and you remain
            qualified as a limited resource farmer under the definition that was
            in effect at the time the administrative fee was waived.
          </P>
          <P>
            (d) For additional coverage GRP policies, your premium is determined
            by multiplying your policy protection by the premium rate per
            hundred dollars of protection for your coverage level contained in
            the actuarial documents, by 0.01, and subtracting the applicable
            subsidy.
          </P>
          <P>
            (e) For catastrophic risk protection and additional coverage GRP
            policies, payment of an administrative fee will not be required if
            you file a bona fide zero acreage report on or before the acreage
            reporting date for the crop (if you falsely file a zero acreage
            report you may be subject to criminal and administrative sanctions).
          </P>
          <P>
            (f) The annual premium is earned and payable at the time the insured
            crop is planted. For each insured crop, you will be billed for
            premium and the administrative fee not earlier than the billing date
            specified in the Special Provisions. Premium, administrative fee,
            and any other amount owed us is due on the billing date and interest
            will accrue if the premium, administrative fee, or any other amount
            owed is not received by us before the first day of the month
            following the premium billing date.
          </P>
          <P>
            (g) If the amount of premium (gross premium less premium subsidy
            paid on your behalf by FCIC) and administrative fee you are required
            to pay for any acreage exceeds the amount of protection for the
            acreage, coverage for those acres will not be provided (no premium
            or administrative fee will be due and no indemnity will be paid for
            such acreage).
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            9. Written Agreements
          </HD>
          <P>
            Terms of this policy which are specifically designated for the use
            of written agreements may be altered by written agreement in
            accordance with the following:
          </P>
          <P>
            (a) You must apply in writing for each written agreement or for
            renewal of any written agreement no later than the sales closing
            date, unless you demonstrate your physical inability to submit the
            request prior to the sales closing date (For example, you have been
            hospitalized or a blizzard has made it impossible to submit the
            written agreement request in person or by mail);
          </P>
          <P>
            (b) The application for written agreement must contain all variable
            terms of the contract between you and us that will be in effect if
            the written agreement is not approved;
          </P>
          <P>
            (c) If approved by FCIC, the written agreement will include all
            variable terms of the contract, including, but not limited to, crop
            practice, and type or variety;
          </P>
          <P>
            (d) Each written agreement will only be valid for the number of crop
            years specified in the written agreement and a multi-year written
            agreement:
          </P>
          <P>
            (1) Will only apply for any particular crop year designated in the
            written agreement if all terms and conditions in the written
            agreement are still applicable for the crop year and the conditions
            under which the written agreement has been provided have not changed
            prior to the beginning of the crop year (If conditions change during
            or prior to a crop year, the written agreement will not be effective
            for that crop year but may still be effective for a subsequent crop
            year if conditions under which the written agreement has been
            provided exist for such year);
          </P>
          <P>
            (2) May be canceled in writing by:
          </P>
          <P>
            (i) FCIC not less than 30 days before the cancellation date if it
            discovers that any term or condition of the written agreement,
            including the premium rate, is not appropriate for the crop; or
          </P>
          <P>
            (ii) You or us on or before the cancellation date;
          </P>
          <P>
            (3) That is not renewed in writing after it expires, is not
            applicable for a crop year, or is canceled, then insurance coverage
            will be in accordance with the terms and conditions stated in this
            policy, without regard to the written agreement; and
          </P>
          <P>
            (4) Will be automatically cancelled if you transfer your policy to
            another insurance provider (No notice will be provided to you and
            for any subsequent crop year, for a written agreement to be
            effective, you must timely request renewal of the written agreement
            in accordance with this section);
          </P>
          <P>
            (e) A request for any written agreement must contain:
          </P>
          <P>
            (1) A completed “Request for Actuarial Change” form;
            <PRTPAGE P='89' />
          </P>
          <P>
            (2) Evidence from agricultural experts or the organic agricultural
            industry, as applicable, that the crop can be produced in the area
            if the request is to provide insurance for practices, types, or
            varieties that are not insurable, unless we are notified in writing
            by FCIC that such evidence is not required;
          </P>
          <P>
            (3) The legal description of the land (in areas where legal
            descriptions are available), FSA Farm Serial Number including tract
            number, and a FSA aerial photograph, acceptable Geographic
            Information System or Global Positioning System maps, or other
            legible maps delineating field boundaries where you intend to plant
            the crop for which insurance is requested; and
          </P>
          <P>
            (4) Such other information as specified in the Special Provisions or
            required by FCIC;
          </P>
          <P>
            (f) A request for written agreement will not be accepted if:
          </P>
          <P>
            (1) The request is submitted to us after the deadline contained in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 9(a)
            </aref>
            ;
          </P>
          <P>
            (2) All the information required in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 9(e)
            </aref>
             is not submitted to us with the request for a written agreement
            (The request for a written agreement may be accepted if any missing
            information is available from other acceptable sources); or
          </P>
          <P>
            (3) The request is to add land or crops to an existing written
            agreement or to add land or crops to a request for a written
            agreement and the request is not submitted by the deadlines
            specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 9(a)
            </aref>
            ;
          </P>
          <P>
            (g) A request for a written agreement will be denied if:
          </P>
          <P>
            (1) FCIC determines the risk is excessive;
          </P>
          <P>
            (2) There is not adequate information available to establish an
            actuarially sound premium rate and insurance coverage for the crop
            and acreage; or
          </P>
          <P>
            (3) Agricultural experts or the organic agricultural industry
            determines the crop practices, types, or varieties are not generally
            recognized for the county;
          </P>
          <P>
            (h) A written agreement will be denied unless FCIC approves the
            written agreement and the original written agreement is signed by
            you and sent to us not later than the expiration date;
          </P>
          <P>
            (i) With respect to your and our ability to reject an offer for a
            written agreement:
          </P>
          <P>
            (1) When a single Request for Actuarial Change form is submitted,
            regardless of how many requests for changes are contained on the
            form, you and we can only accept or reject the written agreement in
            its entirety (you cannot reject specific terms of the written
            agreement and accept others);
          </P>
          <P>
            (2) When multiple Request for Actuarial Change forms are submitted,
            regardless of when the forms are submitted, for the same condition,
            all these forms may be treated as one request and you and we will
            only have the option of accepting or rejecting the written agreement
            in its entirety (you cannot reject specific terms of the written
            agreement and accept others);
          </P>
          <P>
            (3) When multiple Request for Actuarial Change forms are submitted,
            regardless of when the forms are submitted, for the different
            conditions or for different crops, separate agreements may be issued
            and you and we will have the option to accept or reject each written
            agreement; and
          </P>
          <P>
            (4) If we reject an offer for a written agreement approved by FCIC,
            you may seek arbitration or mediation of our decision to reject the
            offer in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 16
            </aref>
            ;
          </P>
          <P>
            (j) Any information that is submitted by you after the applicable
            deadlines in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 9(a)
            </aref>
             will not be considered, unless such information is specifically
            requested in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 9(e)(4)
            </aref>
            ;
          </P>
          <P>
            (k) If the written agreement or the policy is canceled for any
            reason, or the period for which an existing written agreement is in
            effect ends, a request for renewal of the written agreement must
            contain all the information required by this section and be
            submitted in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 9(a)
            </aref>
            , unless otherwise specified by FCIC; and
          </P>
          <P>
            (l) If a request for a written agreement is not approved by FCIC, a
            request for a written agreement for any subsequent crop year that
            fails to address the stated basis for the denial will not be
            accepted (If the request for a written agreement contains the same
            information that was previously rejected or denied, you will not
            have any right to arbitrate, mediate or appeal the non-acceptance of
            your request).
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            10. Access to Insured Crop and Record Retention
          </HD>
          <P>
            (a) We, and any employee of USDA authorized to investigate or review
            any matter relating to crop insurance, have the right to examine the
            insured crop, any records relating to the crop and this insurance,
            and any records regarding mediation, arbitration or litigation
            involving the insured crop, at any location where such crop or
            records may be found or maintained, as often as reasonably required
            during the record retention period.
          </P>
          <P>
            (b) You must retain, and provide upon our request, or the request of
            any employee of USDA authorized to investigate or review any matter
            relating to crop insurance, complete records pertaining to the
            planting of the insured crop and your net acres for a period of
            three years after the end of the crop year or three years after the
            date of final payment of the indemnity, whichever is later. This
            requirement also applies to all such records for acreage that is not
            insured.
          </P>
          <P>
            (c) We, or any employee of USDA authorized to investigate or review
            any matter relating to crop insurance, may extend the record
            retention period beyond three years by notifying you of such
            extension in writing.
            <PRTPAGE P='90' />
          </P>
          <P>
            (d) By signing the application for insurance authorized under the
            Act or by continuing insurance for which you have previously
            applied, you authorize us or USDA, or any person acting for us or
            USDA authorized to investigate or review any matter relating to crop
            insurance, to obtain records relating to the planting, replanting,
            inputs, production, harvesting, and disposition of the insured crop
            from any person who may have custody of such records, including but
            not limited to, FSA offices, banks, warehouses, gins, cooperatives,
            marketing associations, and accountants. You must assist in
            obtaining all records we or any employee of USDA authorized to
            investigate or review any matter relating to crop insurance request
            from third parties.
          </P>
          <P>
            (e) Failure to provide access to the insured crop or the farm,
            maintain or provide any required records, authorize access to the
            records maintained by third parties, or assist in obtaining all such
            records will result in a determination that no indemnity is due for
            the crop year in which such failure occurred.
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            11. Transfer of Coverage and Right to Indemnity
          </HD>
          <P>
            If you transfer any part of your share during the crop year, you may
            transfer your coverage rights, if the transferee is eligible for
            crop insurance. We will not be liable for any more than the
            liability determined in accordance with your policy that existed
            before the transfer occurred. The transfer of coverage rights must
            be on our form and will not be effective until approved by us in
            writing. Both you and the transferee are jointly and severally
            liable for payment of the premium. The transferee has all rights and
            responsibilities under this policy consistent with the
            transferee&apos;s interest.
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            12. Assignment of Indemnity
          </HD>
          <P>
            You may assign to another person your right to an indemnity for the
            crop year. The assignment must be on our form and will not be
            effective until approved in writing by us.
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            13. Other Insurance.
          </HD>
          <P>
            Nothing in this section prevents you from obtaining other insurance
            not authorized under the Act. However, unless specifically required
            by policy provisions, you must not obtain any other crop insurance
            authorized under the Act on your share of the insured crop. If you
            cannot demonstrate that you did not intend to have more than one
            policy in effect, you may be subject to the consequences authorized
            under this policy, the Act, or any other applicable statute. If you
            can demonstrate that you did not intend to have more than one policy
            in effect (For example, an application to transfer your policy or
            written notification to an insurance provider that states you want
            to purchase, or transfer, insurance and you want any other policies
            for the crop canceled would demonstrate you did not intend to have
            duplicate policies), and:
          </P>
          <P>
            (a) One is an additional coverage policy and the other is a
            Catastrophic Risk Protection policy:
          </P>
          <P>
            (1) The additional coverage policy will apply if both policies are
            with the same insurance provider or, if not, both insurance
            providers agree; or
          </P>
          <P>
            (2) The policy with the earliest date of application will be in
            force if both insurance providers do not agree; or
          </P>
          <P>
            (b) Both are additional coverage policies or both are Catastrophic
            Risk Protection policies, the policy with the earliest date of
            application will be in force and the other policy will be void,
            unless both policies are with:
          </P>
          <P>
            (1) The same insurance provider and the insurance provider agrees
            otherwise; or
          </P>
          <P>
            (2) Different insurance providers and both insurance providers agree
            otherwise.
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            14. [Reserved]
          </HD>
          <P>
            [FCIC policy]
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            15. Restrictions, Limitations, and Amounts Due Us
          </HD>
          <P>
            (a) We may restrict the amount of acreage we will insure to the
            amount allowed under any acreage limitation program established by
            USDA.
          </P>
          <P>
            (b) Violation of Federal statutes including, but not limited to, the
            Act; the controlled substance provisions of the Food Security Act of
            1985; the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990;
            and the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1993, and any
            regulation promulgated thereunder, will result in cancellation,
            termination, or voidance of your crop insurance contract. We will
            recover any and all monies paid to you or received by you during
            your period of ineligibility, and your premium will be refunded,
            less an amount for expenses and handling not to exceed 20 percent of
            the premium paid or to be paid by you.
          </P>
          <P>
            (c) Our maximum liability under this policy will be limited to the
            policy protection specified in 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 4 of
            </aref>
             this policy.
          </P>
          <P>
            (d) We will pay simple interest computed on the net indemnity
            ultimately found to be due by us or determined by a final judgment
            of a court of competent jurisdiction or a final administrative
            determination from, and including, the 61st day after the date we
            receive the NASS county yield estimates for the insured crop year.
            Interest will be paid only if the reason for our failure to timely
            pay is not due to your failure to provide information or other
            material necessary for the computation or payment of the indemnity.
            The interest rate will be that established by the Secretary of the
            Treasury 
            <PRTPAGE P='91' />
            under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 12 of
            </aref>
             the Contract Disputes Act of 1978 (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='41' sect='611' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/41/611.html'>
                41 U.S.C. 611
              </subref>
            </aref>
             et seq.), and published in the 
            <E T='04'>
              Federal Register
            </E>
            .
          </P>
          <P>
            (e) Any amount illegally or erroneously paid to you or that is owed
            to us but is delinquent may be recovered by us through offset by
            deducting it from any loan or payment due you under any Act of
            Congress or program administered by any United States Government
            Agency, or by other collection action.
          </P>
          <P>
            (f) Interest will accrue at the rate not to exceed 1.25 percent
            simple interest per calendar month, or any part thereof, on any
            unpaid premium or administrative fee balance. For the purpose of
            premium and administrative fee amounts due us, interest will begin
            to accrue on the first day of the month following the premium
            billing date specified in the Special Provisions.
          </P>
          <P>
            (g) For the purpose of any other amounts due us, such as repayment
            of indemnities found not to have been earned:
          </P>
          <P>
            (1) Interest will start to accrue on the date that notice is issued
            to you for the collection of the unearned amount;
          </P>
          <P>
            (2) Amounts found due under this paragraph will not be charged
            interest if payment is made in full within 30 days of issuance of
            the notice by us;
          </P>
          <P>
            (3) The amount will be considered delinquent if not paid within 30
            days of the date the notice is issued by us;
          </P>
          <P>
            (4) Penalties and interest will be charged in accordance with 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='31' sect='3717' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/31/3717.html'>
                31 U.S.C. 3717
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              4 CFR part 
              <subref title='4' part='102' tq='N'>
                102
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ; and
          </P>
          <P>
            (5) The penalty for accounts more than 90 days delinquent is an
            additional 6 percent per annum.
          </P>
          <P>
            (h) Interest on any amount due us found to have been received by you
            because of fraud, misrepresentation, or presentation by you of a
            false claim will start on the date you received the amount with the
            additional 6 percent penalty beginning on the 31st day after the
            notice of amount due is issued to you. This interest is in addition
            to any other amount found to be due under any other Federal criminal
            or civil statute.
          </P>
          <P>
            (i) If we determine that it is necessary to contract with a
            collection agency, refer the debt to governmental collection
            centers, the Department of Treasury Offset Program, or to employ an
            attorney to assist in collection, you agree to pay all of the
            expenses of collection.
          </P>
          <P>
            (j) All amounts paid by you will be applied first to expenses of
            collection if any, second to reduction of any penalties which may
            have been assessed, then to reduction of accrued interest, and
            finally, to reduction of the principal balance.
          </P>
          <P>
            [Reinsured policy]
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            15. Restrictions, Limitations, and Amounts Due Us
          </HD>
          <P>
            (a) We may restrict the amount of acreage we will insure to the
            amount allowed under any acreage limitation program established by
            USDA.
          </P>
          <P>
            (b) Violation of Federal statutes including, but not limited to, the
            Act; the controlled substance provisions of the Food Security Act of
            1985; the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990;
            and the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1993, and any
            regulation promulgated thereunder, will result in cancellation,
            termination, or voidance of your crop insurance contract. We will
            recover any and all monies paid to you or received by you during
            your period of ineligibility, and your premium will be refunded,
            less a reasonable amount for expenses and handling not to exceed 20
            percent of the premium paid or to be paid by you.
          </P>
          <P>
            (c) Our maximum liability under this policy will be limited to the
            policy protection specified in 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 4 of
            </aref>
             this policy.
          </P>
          <P>
            (d) Interest will accrue at the rate not to exceed 1.25 percent
            simple interest per calendar month, or any part thereof, on any
            unpaid premium or administrative fee balance. For the purpose of
            premium and administrative fee amounts due us, interest will begin
            to accrue on the first day of the month following the premium
            billing date specified in the Special Provisions.
          </P>
          <P>
            (e) For the purpose of any amounts due us, such as repayment of
            indemnities found not to have been earned, interest will start to
            accrue on the date that notice is issued to you for the collection
            of the unearned amount. Amounts found due under this paragraph will
            not be charged interest if payment in full is made within 30 days of
            issuance of notice by us. The amount will be considered delinquent
            if not paid in full within 30 days of the date the notice is issued
            by us.
          </P>
          <P>
            (f) All amounts paid will be applied first to expenses of collection
            (see subsection (g) of this section) if any, second to reduction of
            accrued interest, and then to reduction of the principal balance.
          </P>
          <P>
            (g) If we determine that it is necessary to contract with a
            collection agency or to employ an attorney to assist in collection,
            you agree to pay all of the expenses of collection.
          </P>
          <P>
            (h) A portion of the amount paid to you to which you were not
            entitled may be collected through administrative offset from
            payments you receive from United States government agencies in
            accordance with 31 U.S.C. chapter 37.
          </P>
          <P>
            (i) We will pay simple interest computed on the net indemnity
            ultimately found to be due by us or determined by a final judgment
            of a court of competent jurisdiction or a final administrative
            determination from, and including, the 61st day after the date we
            receive the NASS county yield estimates for 
            <PRTPAGE P='92' />
            the insured crop year. Interest will be paid only if the reason for
            our failure to timely pay is not due to your failure to provide
            information or other material necessary for the computation or
            payment of the indemnity. The interest rate will be that established
            by the Secretary of the Treasury under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 12 of
            </aref>
             the Contract Disputes Act of 1978 (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='41' sect='611' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/41/611.html'>
                41 U.S.C. 611
              </subref>
            </aref>
             et seq.), and published in the 
            <E T='04'>
              Federal Register.
            </E>
          </P>
          <P>
            [FCIC policy]
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            16. Appeals, Administrative and Judicial Review
          </HD>
          <P>
            (a) All determinations required by the policy will be made by us.
          </P>
          <P>
            (b) If you disagree with our determinations, you may:
          </P>
          <P>
            (1) Except for determinations specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 16(b)(2)
            </aref>
            , obtain an administrative review in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='400' tq='N'>
                400
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , subpart J or appeal in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='11' tq='N'>
                11
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ; or
          </P>
          <P>
            (2) For determinations regarding whether you have used good farming
            practices, request reconsideration in accordance with the
            reconsideration process established for this purpose and published
            at 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='400' tq='N'>
                400
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , subpart J.
          </P>
          <P>
            (c) If you fail to exhaust your administrative remedies under 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='11' tq='N'>
                11
              </subref>
            </aref>
             or the reconsideration process for determinations of good farming
            practices described in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 16(b)(2)
            </aref>
            , as applicable, you will not be able to resolve the dispute through
            judicial review.
          </P>
          <P>
            (d) If reconsideration for good farming practices under 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='400' tq='N'>
                400
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , subpart J or appeal under 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='11' tq='N'>
                11
              </subref>
            </aref>
             has been initiated within the time frames specified in those
            sections and judicial review is sought, any suit against us must be:
          </P>
          <P>
            (1) Filed not later than one year after the date of the decision
            rendered in the reconsideration process for good farming practices
            or administrative review process under 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='11' tq='N'>
                11
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ; and
          </P>
          <P>
            (2) Brought in the United States district court for the district in
            which the insured farm involved in the decision is located.
          </P>
          <P>
            (e) You may only recover contractual damages from us. Under no
            circumstances can you recover any attorney fees or other expenses,
            or any punitive, compensatory or any other damages from us in
            administrative review, appeal or litigation.
          </P>
          <P>
            [Reinsured policy]
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            16. Mediation, Arbitration, Appeals, and Administrative and Judicial
            Review
          </HD>
          <P>
            (a) If you and we fail to agree on any determination made by us
            except those specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 16(d) or (e)
            </aref>
            , the disagreement may be resolved through mediation in accordance
            with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 16(g)
            </aref>
            . If resolution cannot be reached through mediation, or you and we
            do not agree to mediation, the disagreement must be resolved through
            arbitration in accordance with the rules of the American Arbitration
            Association (AAA), except as provided in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              sections 16(c) and (f)
            </aref>
            , and unless rules are established by FCIC for this purpose. Any
            mediator or arbitrator with a familial, financial or other business
            relationship to you or us, or our agent or loss adjuster, is
            disqualified from hearing the dispute.
          </P>
          <P>
            (1) All disputes involving determinations made by us, except those
            specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 16(d) or (e)
            </aref>
            , are subject to mediation or arbitration. However, if the dispute
            in any way involves a policy or procedure interpretation, regarding
            whether a specific policy provision or procedure is applicable to
            the situation, how it is applicable, or the meaning of any policy
            provision or procedure, either you or we must obtain an
            interpretation from FCIC in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='400' tq='N'>
                400
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , subpart X or such other procedures as established by FCIC.
          </P>
          <P>
            (i) Any interpretation by FCIC will be binding in any mediation or
            arbitration.
          </P>
          <P>
            (ii) Failure to obtain any required interpretation from FCIC will
            result in the nullification of any agreement or award.
          </P>
          <P>
            (iii) An interpretation by FCIC of a policy provision is considered
            a rule of general applicability and is not appealable. If you
            disagree with an interpretation of a policy provision by FCIC, you
            must obtain a Director&apos;s review from the National Appeals
            Division in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR 
              <subref title='7' part='11' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
                11.6
              </subref>
            </aref>
             before obtaining judicial review in accordance with subsection (e).
          </P>
          <P>
            (iv) An interpretation by FCIC of a procedure may be appealed to the
            National Appeals Division in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='11' tq='N'>
                11
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </P>
          <P>
            (2) Unless the dispute is resolved through mediation, the arbitrator
            must provide to you and us a written statement describing the issues
            in dispute, the factual findings, the determinations and the amount
            and basis for any award and breakdown by claim for any award. The
            statement must also include any amounts awarded for interest.
            Failure of the arbitrator to provide such written statement will
            result in the nullification of all determinations of the arbitrator.
            All agreements reached through settlement, including those resulting
            from mediation, must be in writing and contain at a minimum a
            statement of the issues in dispute and the amount of the settlement.
          </P>
          <P>
            (b) Regardless of whether mediation is elected:
          </P>
          <P>
            (1) The initiation of arbitration proceedings must occur within one
            year of the date we denied your claim or rendered the determination
            with which you disagree, whichever is later;
          </P>
          <P>
            (2) If you fail to initiate arbitration in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 16(b)(1)
            </aref>
             and complete 
            <PRTPAGE P='93' />
            the process, you will not be able to resolve the dispute through
            judicial review;
          </P>
          <P>
            (3) If arbitration has been initiated in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 16(b)(1)
            </aref>
             and completed, and judicial review is sought, suit must be filed
            not later than one year after the date the arbitration decision was
            rendered; and
          </P>
          <P>
            (4) In any suit, if the dispute in any way involves a policy or
            procedure interpretation, regarding whether a specific policy
            provision or procedure is applicable to the situation, how it is
            applicable, or the meaning of any policy provision or procedure, an
            interpretation must be obtained from FCIC in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='400' tq='N'>
                400
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , subpart X or such other procedures as established by FCIC. Such
            interpretation will be binding.
          </P>
          <P>
            (c) Any decision rendered in arbitration is binding on you and us
            unless judicial review is sought in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 16(b)(3)
            </aref>
            . Notwithstanding any provision in the rules of the AAA, you and we
            have the right to judicial review of any decision rendered in
            arbitration.
          </P>
          <P>
            (d) If you do not agree with any determination made by us or FCIC
            regarding whether you have used a good farming practice, you may
            request reconsideration by FCIC of this determination in accordance
            with the reconsideration process established for this purpose and
            published at 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='400' tq='N'>
                400
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , subpart J (reconsideration).
          </P>
          <P>
            (1) You must complete reconsideration before filing suit against
            FCIC and any such suit must be brought in the United States district
            court for the district in which the insured farm is located.
          </P>
          <P>
            (2) Suit must be filed not later than one year after the date of the
            decision rendered in the reconsideration.
          </P>
          <P>
            (3) You cannot sue us for determinations of whether good farming
            practices were used by you.
          </P>
          <P>
            (e) Except as provided in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 16(d)
            </aref>
            , if you disagree with any other determination made by FCIC or any
            claim where FCIC is directly involved in the claims process or
            directs us in the resolution of the claim, you may obtain an
            administrative review in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='400' tq='N'>
                400
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , subpart J (administrative review) or appeal in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='11' tq='N'>
                11
              </subref>
            </aref>
             (appeal).
          </P>
          <P>
            (1) If you elect to bring suit after completion of any appeal, such
            suit must be filed against FCIC not later than one year after the
            date of the decision rendered in such appeal.
          </P>
          <P>
            (2) Such suit must be brought in the United States district court
            for the district in which the insured acreage is located.
          </P>
          <P>
            (3) Under no circumstances can you recover any attorney fees or
            other expenses, or any punitive, compensatory or any other damages
            from FCIC.
          </P>
          <P>
            (f) In any mediation, arbitration, appeal, administrative review,
            reconsideration or judicial process, the terms of this policy, the
            Act, and the regulations published at 7 CFR chapter IV, including
            the provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='400' tq='N'>
                400
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , subpart P, are binding. Conflicts between this policy and any
            state or local laws will be resolved in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 31
            </aref>
            . If there are conflicts between any rules of the AAA and the
            provisions of your policy, the provisions of your policy will
            control.
          </P>
          <P>
            (g) To resolve any dispute through mediation, you and we must both:
          </P>
          <P>
            (1) Agree to mediate the dispute;
          </P>
          <P>
            (2) Agree on a mediator; and
          </P>
          <P>
            (3) Be present, or have a designated representative who has
            authority to settle the case present, at the mediation.
          </P>
          <P>
            (h) Except as provided in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 16(i)
            </aref>
            , no award or settlement in mediation, arbitration, appeal,
            administrative review or reconsideration process or judicial review
            can exceed the amount of liability established or which should have
            been established under the policy, except for interest awarded in
            accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 15(i)
            </aref>
            .
          </P>
          <P>
            (i) In a judicial review only, you may recover attorneys fees or
            other expenses, or any punitive, compensatory or any other damages
            from us only if you obtain a determination from FCIC that we, our
            agent or loss adjuster failed to comply with the terms of this
            policy or procedures issued by FCIC and such failure resulted in you
            receiving a payment in an amount that is less than the amount to
            which you were entitled. Requests for such a determination should be
            addressed to the following: USDA/RMA/Deputy Administrator of
            Compliance/Stop 0806, 1400 Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC
            20250-0806.
          </P>
          <P>
            (j) If FCIC elects to participate in the adjustment of your claim,
            or modifies, revises or corrects your claim, prior to payment, you
            may not bring an arbitration, mediation or litigation action against
            us. You must request administrative review or appeal in accordance
            with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 16(e)
            </aref>
            .
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            17. Holidays and Weekends
          </HD>
          <P>
            If any date specified in this program falls on Saturday, Sunday, or
            a legal Federal holiday, that date will be extended to the next
            business day.
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            18. Life of Policy, Cancellation, and Termination
          </HD>
          <P>
            (a) This is a continuous policy and will remain in effect for each
            crop year following the acceptance of the original application until
            canceled by you in accordance with the terms of the policy or
            terminated by operation of the terms of the policy or by us.
          </P>
          <P>
            (b) Your application for insurance must contain your social security
            number (SSN) if you are an individual or employer identification
            number (EIN) if you are a person other than an individual, and all
            SSNs and EINs, 
            <PRTPAGE P='94' />
            as applicable, of all persons with a substantial beneficial interest
            in you, the coverage level, price election, crop, type, variety, or
            class, plan of insurance, and any other material information
            required on the application to insure the crop. If you or someone
            with a substantial beneficial interest is not legally required to
            have a SSN or EIN, you must request and receive an identification
            number for the purposes of this policy from us or the Internal
            Revenue Service (IRS) if such identification number is available
            from the IRS. If any of the information regarding persons with a
            substantial beneficial interest changes during the crop year, you
            must revise your application by the next sales closing date
            applicable under your policy to reflect the correct information.
          </P>
          <P>
            (1) Applications that do not contain your SSN, EIN or identification
            number, or any of the other information required in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 18(b)
            </aref>
             are not acceptable and insurance will not be provided (Except if
            you fail to report the SSNs, EINs or identification numbers of
            persons with a substantial beneficial interest in you, the
            provisions in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 18(b)(2)
            </aref>
             will apply);
          </P>
          <P>
            (2) If the application does not contain the SSNs, EINs or
            identification numbers of all persons with a substantial beneficial
            interest in you, you fail to revise your application in accordance
            with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 18(b)
            </aref>
            , or the reported SSNs, EINs or identification numbers are incorrect
            and the incorrect SSN, EIN or identification number has not been
            corrected by the acreage reporting date, and:
          </P>
          <P>
            (i) Such persons are eligible for insurance, the amount of coverage
            for all crops included on this application will be reduced
            proportionately by the percentage interest in you of such persons,
            you must repay the amount of indemnity that is proportionate to the
            interest of the persons whose SSN, EIN or identification number was
            unreported or incorrect for such crops, and your premium will be
            reduced commensurately; or
          </P>
          <P>
            (ii) Such persons are not eligible for insurance, except as provided
            in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 18(b)(3)
            </aref>
            , the policy is void and no indemnity will be owed for any crop
            included on this application, and you must repay any indemnity that
            may have been paid for such crops. If previously paid, the balance
            of any premium and any administrative fees will be returned to you,
            less twenty percent of the premium that would otherwise be due from
            you for such crops. If not previously paid, no premium or
            administrative fees will be due for such crops.
          </P>
          <P>
            (3) The consequences described in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 18(b)(2)(ii)
            </aref>
             will not apply if you have included an ineligible person&apos;s
            SSN, EIN or identification number on your application and do not
            include the ineligible person&apos;s share on the acreage report.
          </P>
          <P>
            (c) After acceptance of the application, you may not cancel this
            policy for the initial crop year. Thereafter, the policy will
            continue in force for each succeeding crop year unless canceled or
            terminated as provided below.
          </P>
          <P>
            (d) Either you or we may cancel this policy after the initial crop
            year by providing written notice to the other on or before the
            cancellation date shown in the Crop Provisions.
          </P>
          <P>
            (e) Any amount due to us for any policy authorized under the Act
            will be offset from any indemnity due you for this or any other crop
            insured with us.
          </P>
          <P>
            (1) Even if your claim has not yet been paid, you must still pay the
            premium and administrative fee on or before the termination date for
            you to remain eligible for insurance.
          </P>
          <P>
            (2) If we offset any amount due us from an indemnity owed to you,
            the date of payment for the purpose of determining whether you have
            a delinquent debt will be the date FCIC publishes the payment yield
            for the applicable crop year.
          </P>
          <P>
            (f) A delinquent debt for any policy will make you ineligible to
            obtain crop insurance authorized under the Act for any subsequent
            crop year and result in termination of all policies in accordance
            with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 18(f)(2)
            </aref>
            .
          </P>
          <P>
            (1) With respect to ineligibility:
          </P>
          <P>
            (i) Ineligibility for crop insurance will be effective on:
          </P>
          <P>
            (A) The date that a policy was terminated in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 18(f)(2)
            </aref>
             for the crop for which you failed to pay premium, an administrative
            fee, or any related interest owed, as applicable;
          </P>
          <P>
            (B) The payment due date contained in any notification of
            indebtedness for any overpaid indemnity, if you fail to pay the
            amount owed, including any related interest owed, as applicable, by
            such due date;
          </P>
          <P>
            (C) The termination date for the crop year prior to the crop year in
            which a scheduled payment is due under a payment agreement if you
            fail to pay the amount owed by any payment date in any agreement to
            pay the debt; or
          </P>
          <P>
            (D) The termination date the policy was or would have been
            terminated under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              sections 18(f)(2)(i)(A), (B) or (C)
            </aref>
             if your bankruptcy petition is dismissed before discharge.
          </P>
          <P>
            (ii) If you are ineligible and a policy has been terminated in
            accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 18(f)(2)
            </aref>
            , you will not receive any indemnity, and such ineligibility and
            termination of the policy may affect your eligibility for benefits
            under other USDA programs. Any indemnity that may be owed for the
            policy before it has been terminated will remain owed to you, but
            may be offset in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 18(e)
            </aref>
            , unless your policy was terminated in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              sections 18(f)(2)(i)(D) or (E)
            </aref>
            .
          </P>
          <P>
            (2) With respect to termination:
          </P>
          <P>
            (i) Termination will be effective on:
          </P>
          <P>
            (A) For a policy with unpaid administrative fees or premiums, the
            termination date 
            <PRTPAGE P='95' />
            immediately subsequent to the billing date for the crop year;
          </P>
          <P>
            (B) For a policy with other amounts due, the termination date
            immediately following the date you have a delinquent debt;
          </P>
          <P>
            (C) For each policy for which the termination date has passed before
            you become ineligible, the termination date immediately following
            the date you become ineligible;
          </P>
          <P>
            (D) For execution of an agreement to pay any amounts owed and
            failure to make any scheduled payment, the termination date for the
            crop year prior to the crop year in which you failed to make the
            scheduled payment; or
          </P>
          <P>
            (E) For dismissal of a bankruptcy petition before discharge, the
            termination date the policy was or would have been terminated under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              sections 18(f)(2)(i)(A), (B) or (C)
            </aref>
            .
          </P>
          <P>
            (ii) For all policies terminated under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              sections 18(f)(2)(i)(D) and (E)
            </aref>
            , any indemnities paid subsequent to the termination date must be
            repaid.
          </P>
          <P>
            (iii) Once the policy is terminated, it cannot be reinstated for the
            current crop year unless the termination was in error. Failure to
            timely pay because of illness, bad weather, or other such
            extenuating circumstances is not grounds for reinstatement in the
            current crop year.
          </P>
          <P>
            (3) To regain eligibility, you must:
          </P>
          <P>
            (i) Repay the delinquent debt in full;
          </P>
          <P>
            (ii) Execute an agreement to pay any amounts owed and make payments
            in accordance with the agreement (We will not enter into an
            agreement with you to pay the amounts owed if you have previously
            failed to make a scheduled payment under the terms of any other
            agreement to pay with us or any other insurance provider); or
          </P>
          <P>
            (iii) File a petition to have your debts discharged in bankruptcy
            (Dismissal of the bankruptcy petition before discharge will
            terminate all policies in effect retroactive to the date your policy
            would have been terminated in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 18(f)(2)(i)
            </aref>
            );
          </P>
          <P>
            (4) After you become eligible for crop insurance, if you want to
            obtain coverage for your crops, you must submit a new application on
            or before the sales closing date for the crop (Since applications
            for crop insurance cannot be accepted after the sales closing date,
            if you make any payment after the sales closing date, you cannot
            apply for insurance until the next crop year);
          </P>
          <P>
            (5) For example, for the 2003 crop year, if crop A, with a
            termination date of October 31, 2003, and crop B, with a termination
            date of March 15, 2004, are insured and you do not pay the premium
            for crop A by the termination date, you are ineligible for crop
            insurance as of October 31, 2003, and crop A&apos;s policy is
            terminated as of that date. Crop B&apos;s policy does not terminate
            until March 15, 2004, and an indemnity for the 2003 crop year may
            still be owed. If you enter an agreement to repay amounts owed on
            September 25, 2004, the earliest date by which you can obtain crop
            insurance for crop A is to apply for crop insurance by the October
            31, 2004, sales closing date and for crop B is to apply for crop
            insurance by the March 15, 2005, sales closing date. If you fail to
            make a payment that was scheduled to be made on April 1, 2005, your
            policy will terminate as of October 31, 2004, for crop A, and March
            15, 2005, for crop B, and no indemnity will be due for that crop
            year for either crop. You will not be eligible to apply for crop
            insurance for any crop until after the amounts owed are paid in full
            or you file a petition to discharge the debt in bankruptcy.
          </P>
          <P>
            (6) If you are determined to be ineligible under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 18(f)
            </aref>
            , persons with a substantial beneficial interest in you may also be
            ineligible until you become eligible again.
          </P>
          <P>
            (g) If you die, disappear, or are judicially declared incompetent,
            or if you are an entity other than an individual and such entity is
            dissolved, the policy will terminate as of the date of death,
            judicial declaration, or dissolution. If such event occurs after
            coverage begins for any crop year, the policy will continue in force
            through the crop year and terminate at the end of the insurance
            period and any indemnity will be paid to the person or persons
            determined to be beneficially entitled to the indemnity. The premium
            will be deducted from the indemnity or collected from the estate.
            Death of a partner in a partnership will dissolve the partnership
            unless the partnership agreement provides otherwise. If two or more
            persons having a joint interest are insured jointly, death of one of
            the persons will dissolve the joint entity.
          </P>
          <P>
            (h) We may cancel your policy if no premium is earned for 3
            consecutive years.
          </P>
          <P>
            (i) The cancellation and termination dates are contained in the Crop
            Provisions.
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            19. Contract Changes
          </HD>
          <P>
            (a) We may change any terms and conditions of this policy from year
            to year.
          </P>
          <P>
            (b) Any changes in policy provisions, expected county yields,
            maximum amounts of protection, premium rates, and program dates
            (except as allowed herein) can be viewed on the RMA Web site at 
            <E T='03'>
              http://www.rma.usda.gov/
            </E>
             or a successor Web site not later than the contract change date
            contained in the Crop Provisions. We may only revise this
            information after the contract change date to correct clear errors
            (For example, the maximum amount of protection was announced at
            $2500.00 per acre instead of $250.00 per acre).
          </P>
          <P>
            (c) After the contract change date, all changes specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 19(b)
            </aref>
             will also be available upon request from your crop insurance agent.
            You will be provided, in writing, a copy of the changes to the Basic
            Provisions and Crop Provisions and a copy of the Special Provisions
            not later than 30 days prior to the cancellation date for the
            insured crop. 
            <PRTPAGE P='96' />
            Acceptance of the changes will be conclusively presumed in the
            absence of notice from you to change or cancel your insurance
            coverage.
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            20. [Reserved]
          </HD>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            21. Indemnity and Premium Limitations.
          </HD>
          <P>
            (a) With respect to acreage where you are due a loss for your first
            insured crop in the crop year, except in the case of double cropping
            described in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 21(c)
            </aref>
            :
          </P>
          <P>
            (1) You may elect to not plant or to plant and not insure a second
            crop on the same acreage for harvest in the same crop year and
            collect an indemnity payment that is equal to 100 percent of the
            insurable loss for the first insured crop; or
          </P>
          <P>
            (2) You may elect to plant and insure a second crop on the same
            acreage for harvest in the same crop year (you will pay the full
            premium and if there is an insurable loss to the second crop,
            receive the full amount of indemnity that may be due for the second
            crop, regardless of whether there is a subsequent crop planted on
            the same acreage) and:
          </P>
          <P>
            (i) Collect an indemnity payment that is 35 percent of the insurable
            loss for the first insured crop;
          </P>
          <P>
            (ii) Be responsible for a premium that is 35 percent of the premium
            that you would otherwise owe for the first insured crop; and
          </P>
          <P>
            (iii) If the second crop does not suffer an insurable loss:
          </P>
          <P>
            (A) Collect an indemnity payment for the other 65 percent of
            insurable loss that was not previously paid under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 21(a)(2)(i)
            </aref>
            ; and
          </P>
          <P>
            (B) Be responsible for the remainder of the premium for the first
            insured crop that you did not pay under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 21(a)(2)(ii)
            </aref>
            .
          </P>
          <P>
            (b) The reduction in the amount of indemnity and premium specified
            in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 21(a)
            </aref>
            , as applicable, will apply:
          </P>
          <P>
            (1) Notwithstanding the priority contained in the Agreement to
            Insure section, which states that the Crop Provisions have priority
            over the Basic Provisions when a conflict exists, to any premium
            owed or indemnity paid in accordance with the Crop Provisions, and
            any applicable endorsement.
          </P>
          <P>
            (2) Even if another person plants the second crop on any acreage
            where the first insured crop was planted.
          </P>
          <P>
            (3) If you fail to provide any records we require to determine
            whether an insurable loss occurred for the second crop.
          </P>
          <P>
            (c) You may receive a full indemnity for a first insured crop when a
            second crop is planted on the same acreage in the same crop year,
            regardless of whether or not the second crop is insured or sustains
            an insurable loss, if each of the following conditions are met:
          </P>
          <P>
            (1) It is a practice that is generally recognized by agricultural
            experts or the organic agricultural industry for the area to plant
            two or more crops for harvest in the same crop year;
          </P>
          <P>
            (2) The second or more crops are customarily planted after the first
            insured crop for harvest on the same acreage in the same crop year
            in the area;
          </P>
          <P>
            (3) Additional coverage insurance offered under the authority of the
            Act is available in the county on the two or more crops that are
            double cropped; and
          </P>
          <P>
            (4) You provide records acceptable to us of acreage and production
            that show you have double cropped acreage in at least two of the
            last four crop years in which the first insured crop was planted, or
            that show the applicable acreage was double cropped in at least two
            of the last four crop years in which the first insured crop was
            grown on it.
          </P>
          <P>
            (d) The receipt of a full indemnity on both crops that are double
            cropped is limited to the number of acres for which you can
            demonstrate you have double cropped or that have been historically
            double cropped as specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 21(c)
            </aref>
            .
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD2'>
            An Example To Demonstrate How GRP Works
          </HD>
          <P>
            Producer A buys 90 percent coverage and selects $160 protection per
            acre. Producer B buys 75 percent coverage and selects $185
            protection per acre. Both producers have 100 percent share and both
            plant 200 acres of a crop in the county. The expected county yield
            is 45 bushels per acre. The premium rate for 90 percent coverage is
            $6.14 per hundred dollars of protection and the premium rate for 75
            percent coverage is $3.30 per hundred dollars of protection.
          </P>
          <P>
            A&apos;s trigger yield is 40.5 bushels per acre (90% × 45), and the
            total premium due is $1,965 ($160 × $6.14 × 200 acres × 0.01). Of
            that amount, FCIC pays $614 (200 acres × the maximum subsidy of
            $3.07 per acre). A&apos;s policy protection is $32,000 ($160 × 200
            acres).
          </P>
          <P>
            B&apos;s trigger yield is 33.8 bushels per acre (75% of 45), and the
            total premium due is $1,221 ($185 × $3.30 × 200 acres × 0.01). Of
            that amount, FCIC pays $442 (200 acres × the subsidy amount of $2.21
            per acre). B&apos;s policy protection is $37,000 ($185 × 200 acres).
            
          </P>
          <FP>
            Scenario 1 (likely)
          </FP>
          <P>
            FCIC issues a payment yield of 46 bushels per acre. This is above
            both producers&apos; trigger yields, so no indemnity payment is
            made, even if one or both have individual yields that are below the
            trigger yield.
          </P>
          <FP>
            Scenario 2 (less likely)
          </FP>
          <P>
            FCIC issues a payment yield of 38 bushels per acre. A&apos;s payment
            calculation factor is 0.062 ((40.5 − 38) ÷ 40.5). This number
            multiplied by the policy protection yields an indemnity payment of
            $1,984 (.062 × $32,000). B&apos;s trigger yield is less than the
            payment yield, so no indemnity payment is made.
          </P>
          <FP>
            Scenario 3 (least likely)
          </FP>
          <P>
            FCIC issues a payment yield of 22 bushels per acre. A&apos;s payment
            calculation factor is 
            <PRTPAGE P='97' />
            0.457 ((40.5 − 22) ÷ 40.5). The payment is $14,624 (0.457 ×
            $32,000). B&apos;s payment calculation factor is 0.349 ((33.8 − 22)
            ÷ 33.8), and the final indemnity payment is $12,913 (0.349 ×
            $37,000).
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            22. Remedial Sanctions
          </HD>
          <P>
            If you willfully and intentionally provide false or inaccurate
            information to us or FCIC or you fail to comply with a requirement
            of FCIC, in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='400' tq='N'>
                400
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , subpart R, FCIC may impose on you:
          </P>
          <P>
            (a) A civil fine for each violation in an amount not to exceed the
            greater of:
          </P>
          <P>
            (1) The amount of the pecuniary gain obtained as a result of the
            false or inaccurate information provided or the noncompliance with a
            requirement of FCIC; or
          </P>
          <P>
            (2) $10,000; and
          </P>
          <P>
            (b) A disqualification for a period of up to 5 years from receiving
            any monetary or non-monetary benefit provided under each of the
            following:
          </P>
          <P>
            (1) Any crop insurance policy offered under the Act;
          </P>
          <P>
            (2) The Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='7333' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/7333.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 7333
              </subref>
            </aref>
             et seq.);
          </P>
          <P>
            (3) The Agricultural Act of 1949 (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='1421' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1421.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 1421
              </subref>
            </aref>
             et seq.);
          </P>
          <P>
            (4) The Commodity Credit Corporation Charter Act (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='15' sect='714' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/15/714.html'>
                15 U.S.C. 714
              </subref>
            </aref>
             et seq.);
          </P>
          <P>
            (5) The Agricultural Adjustment Act of 1938 (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='1281' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1281.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 1281
              </subref>
            </aref>
             et seq.);
          </P>
          <P>
            (6) Title XII of the Food Security Act of 1985 (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='16' sect='3801' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/3801.html'>
                16 U.S.C. 3801
              </subref>
            </aref>
             et seq.);
          </P>
          <P>
            (7) The Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='1921' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1921.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 1921
              </subref>
            </aref>
             et seq.); and
          </P>
          <P>
            (8) Any federal law that provides assistance to a producer of an
            agricultural commodity affected by a crop loss or a decline in the
            prices of agricultural commodities.
          </P>
        </EXTRACT>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            64 FR 30219
          </aref>
          , June 7, 1999, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            65 FR 40485
          </aref>
          , June 30, 2000; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            68 FR 37721
          </aref>
          , June 25, 2003; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            69 FR 48731
          </aref>
          , Aug. 10, 2004; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            73 FR 36408
          </aref>
          , June 27, 2008; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            73 FR 70864
          </aref>
          , Nov. 24, 2008; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            73 FR 76891
          </aref>
          , Dec. 18, 2008; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            74 FR 11643
          </aref>
          , Mar. 19, 2009; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            74 FR 45543
          </aref>
          , Sept. 3, 2009; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 4804
          </aref>
          , Jan. 27, 2011]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5874'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:IV:-:407:-:407.10
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        407.10
      </num>
      <head>
        Group risk plan for barley.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='407' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
              407.10
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Group risk plan for barley.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The provisions of the Group Risk Plan for Barley for the 2000 and
          succeeding crop years are as follows:
        </P>
        <EXTRACT>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            1. Definitions
          </HD>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Harvest.
            </E>
             Combining or threshing the barley for grain.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              NASS yield.
            </E>
             The yield calculated by dividing the NASS estimate of the barley
            production in the county, by the NASS estimate of the acres of
            barley in the county, as specified in the actuarial documents. The
            actuarial documents will specify whether harvested or planted
            acreage is used to calculate the yield used to establish the
            expected county yield and calculate indemnities.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Planted acreage.
            </E>
             Land in which the barley seed has been placed by a machine
            appropriate for the insured crop and planting method, at the correct
            depth, into a seedbed that has been properly prepared for the
            planting method and production practice. Land on which seed is
            initially spread onto the soil surface by any method and which
            subsequently is mechanically incorporated into the soil in a timely
            manner and at the proper depth, will also be considered planted.
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            2. Crop Insured
          </HD>
          <P>
            The insured crop will be all barley:
          </P>
          <P>
            (a) Grown on insurable acreage in the county or counties listed in
            the accepted application;
          </P>
          <P>
            (b) Properly planted and reported by the acreage reporting date;
          </P>
          <P>
            (c) Planted with the intent to be harvested as grain; and
          </P>
          <P>
            (d) Not planted into an established grass or legume, interplanted
            with another crop, or planted as a nurse crop, unless seeded at the
            normal rate and intended for harvest as grain.
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            3. Payment
          </HD>
          <P>
            (a) A payment will be made only if the payment yield for the insured
            crop year is less than your trigger yield.
          </P>
          <P>
            (b) Payment yields will be determined prior to the April 1 following
            the crop year.
          </P>
          <P>
            (c) We will issue any payment to you prior to the May 1 immediately
            following our determination of the payment yield.
          </P>
          <P>
            (d) The payment is equal to the payment calculation factor
            multiplied by your policy protection for each insured crop practice
            and type specified in the actuarial documents.
          </P>
          <P>
            (e) The payment will not be recalculated even though the NASS yield
            may be subsequently revised.
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            4. Program Dates
          </HD>
        </EXTRACT>
        <table class='gpotable' CDEF='s150,xs76,xs52' COLS='3' OPTS='L2,i1'>
          <caption />
          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th>
                State and county
              </th>
              <th>
                Cancellation and termination dates
              </th>
              <th>
                Contract change date
              </th>
            </tr>
          </thead>
          <tfoot />
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Kit Carson, Lincoln, Elbert, El Paso, Pueblo, Las Animas
                Counties, Colorado and all Colorado Counties south and east
                thereof; all New Mexico counties except Taos County; Kansas;
                Missouri; Illinois; Indiana; Ohio; Pennsylvania; New York;
                Massachusetts; and all states south and east thereof
              </td>
              <td>
                September 30
              </td>
              <td>
                June 30.
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Arizona; California; and Clark and Nye Counties, Nevada
              </td>
              <td>
                October 31
              </td>
              <td>
                June 30.
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                All Colorado counties except Kit Carson, Lincoln, Elbert, El
                Paso, Pueblo, and Las Animas Counties and all Colorado counties
                south and east thereof; all Nevada counties except Clark and Nye
                Counties; Taos County, New Mexico; and all other states except:
                Arizona, California, and (except) Kansas, Missouri, Illinois,
                Indiana, Ohio, Pennsylvania, New York, and Massachusetts and all
                States south and east thereof
              </td>
              <td>
                March 15
              </td>
              <td>
                November 30.
              </td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5875'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:IV:-:407:-:407.11
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        407.11
      </num>
      <head>
        Group risk plan for corn.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='407' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
              407.11
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Group risk plan for corn.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The provisions of the Group Risk Plan for Corn for the 2000 and
          succeeding crop years are as follows:
        </P>
        <EXTRACT>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            1. Definitions
          </HD>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Harvest.
            </E>
             Combining or picking corn for grain, or severing the stalk from the
            land and chopping the stalk and ear for the purpose of livestock
            feed.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              NASS yield.
            </E>
             The yield calculated by dividing the NASS estimate of the corn for
            grain production in the county, by the NASS estimate of the acres of
            corn for grain in the county, as specified in the actuarial
            documents. The actuarial documents will specify whether harvested or
            planted acreage is used to calculate the yield used to establish the
            expected county yield and calculate indemnities.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Planted acreage.
            </E>
             Land in which the corn seed has been placed by a machine
            appropriate for the insured crop and planting method, at the correct
            depth, into a seedbed that has been properly prepared for the
            planting method and production practice. Broadcast and subsequent
            mechanical incorporation of the corn seed is not allowed.
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            2. Crop Insured
          </HD>
          <P>
            (a) The insured crop will be all field corn:
          </P>
          <P>
            (1) Grown on insurable acreage in the county listed in the accepted
            application;
          </P>
          <P>
            (2) Properly planted and reported by the acreage reporting date;
          </P>
          <P>
            (3) Planted with the intent to be harvested as grain, silage, or
            green chop; and
          </P>
          <P>
            (4) Not planted into an established grass or legume or interplanted
            with another crop.
          </P>
          <P>
            (b) Hybrid seed corn, popcorn, sweet corn, and other specialty corn
            may only be insured if a written agreement exists between you and
            us. Your request to insure such crop must be in writing and
            submitted to your agent not later than the sales closing date.
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            3. Payment
          </HD>
          <P>
            (a) A payment will be made only if the payment yield for the insured
            crop year is less than your trigger yield.
          </P>
          <P>
            (b) Payment yields will be determined prior to April 16 following
            the crop year.
          </P>
          <P>
            (c) We will issue any payment to you prior to the May 16 immediately
            following our determination of the payment yield.
          </P>
          <P>
            (d) The payment is equal to the payment calculation factor
            multiplied by your policy protection for each insured crop practice
            and type specified in the actuarial documents.
          </P>
          <P>
            (e) The payment will not be recalculated even though the NASS yield
            may be subsequently revised.
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            4. Program Dates
          </HD>
        </EXTRACT>
        <table class='gpotable' CDEF='s150,xs76,xs52' COLS='3' OPTS='L2,i1'>
          <caption />
          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th>
                State and county
              </th>
              <th>
                Cancellation and termination dates
              </th>
              <th>
                Contract change date
              </th>
            </tr>
          </thead>
          <tfoot />
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Val Verde, Edwards, Kerr, Kendall, Bexar, Wilson, Karnes,
                Goliad, Victoria, and Jackson Counties, Texas, and all Texas
                counties lying south thereof
              </td>
              <td>
                January 15
              </td>
              <td>
                November 30.
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                El Paso, Hudspeth, Culberson, Reeves, Loving, Winkler, Ector,
                Upton, Reagan, Sterling, Coke, Tom Green, Concho, McCulloch, San
                Saba, Mills, Hamilton, Bosque, Johnson, Tarrant, Wise, and Cooke
                Counties, Texas, and all Texas Counties lying south and east
                thereof to and including Terrell, Crockett, Sutton, Kimble,
                Gillespie, Blanco, Comal, Guadalupe, Gonzales, De Witt, Lavaca,
                Colorado, Wharton, and Matagorda Counties, Texas
              </td>
              <td>
                February 15
              </td>
              <td>
                November 30.
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Alabama; Arizona; Arkansas; California; Florida; Georgia;
                Louisiana; Mississippi; Nevada; North Carolina; South Carolina
              </td>
              <td>
                February 28
              </td>
              <td>
                November 30.
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                All other Texas counties and all other states
              </td>
              <td>
                March 15
              </td>
              <td>
                November 30.
              </td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5876'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:IV:-:407:-:407.12
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        407.12
      </num>
      <head>
        Group risk plan for cotton.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='407' sect='12' psec='' tq='N'>
              407.12
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Group risk plan for cotton.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The provisions of the Group Risk Plan for Cotton for the 2000 and
          succeeding crop years are as follows:
        </P>
        <EXTRACT>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            1. Definitions
          </HD>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Harvest.
            </E>
             Removal of the seed cotton from the stalk.
            <PRTPAGE P='99' />
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              NASS yield.
            </E>
             The yield calculated by dividing the NASS estimate of upland cotton
            production in the county, by the NASS estimate of the acres of
            upland cotton in the county, as specified in the actuarial
            documents. The actuarial documents will specify whether harvested or
            planted acreage is used to calculate the yield used to establish the
            expected county yield and calculate indemnities.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Planted acreage.
            </E>
             Land in which the cotton seed has been placed by a machine
            appropriate for the insured crop and planting method, at the correct
            depth, into a seedbed that has been properly prepared for the
            planting method and production practice. Broadcast and subsequent
            mechanical incorporation of the cotton seed is not allowed.
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            2. Crop Insured
          </HD>
          <P>
            The insured crop will be all upland cotton:
          </P>
          <P>
            (a) Grown on insurable acreage in the county or counties listed in
            the accepted application;
          </P>
          <P>
            (b) Properly planted and reported by the acreage reporting date;
          </P>
          <P>
            (c) Planted with the intent to be harvested; and
          </P>
          <P>
            (d) That is not (unless allowed by the Special Provisions or by
            written agreement):
          </P>
          <P>
            (1) Colored cotton lint;
          </P>
          <P>
            (2) Planted into an established grass or legume;
          </P>
          <P>
            (3) Interplanted with another spring planted crop;
          </P>
          <P>
            (4) Grown on acreage in which a hay crop was harvested in the same
            calendar year unless the acreage is irrigated; or
          </P>
          <P>
            (5) Grown on acreage on which a small grain crop reached the heading
            stage in the same calendar year unless the acreage is irrigated or
            adequate measures are taken to terminate the small grain crop prior
            to heading and less than 50 percent of the small grain plants reach
            the heading stage.
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            3. Payment
          </HD>
          <P>
            (a) A payment will be made only if the payment yield for the insured
            crop year is less than your trigger yield.
          </P>
          <P>
            (b) Payment yields will be determined prior to July 16 following the
            crop year.
          </P>
          <P>
            (c) We will issue any payment to you prior to the August 16
            immediately following our determination of the payment yield.
          </P>
          <P>
            (d) The payment is equal to the payment calculation factor
            multiplied by your policy protection for each insured crop practice
            and type specified in the actuarial documents.
          </P>
          <P>
            (e) The payment will not be recalculated even though the NASS yield
            may be subsequently revised.
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            4. Program Dates
          </HD>
        </EXTRACT>
        <table class='gpotable' CDEF='s150,xs76,xs52' COLS='3' OPTS='L2,i1'>
          <caption />
          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th>
                State and county
              </th>
              <th>
                Cancellation and termination dates
              </th>
              <th>
                Contract change date
              </th>
            </tr>
          </thead>
          <tfoot />
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Val Verde, Edwards, Kerr, Kendall, Bexar, Wilson, Karnes,
                Goliad, Victoria, and Jackson Counties, Texas, and all Texas
                counties lying south thereof
              </td>
              <td>
                January 15
              </td>
              <td>
                November 30.
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Alabama; Arizona; Arkansas; California; Florida; Georgia;
                Louisiana; Mississippi; Nevada; North Carolina; South Carolina;
                El Paso, Hudspeth, Culberson, Reeves, Loving, Winkler, Ector,
                Upton, Reagan, Sterling, Coke, Tom Green, Concho, McCulloch, San
                Saba, Mills, Hamilton, Bosque, Johnson, Tarrant, Wise, and Cooke
                Counties, Texas, and all Texas counties lying south and east
                thereof to and including Terrell, Crockett, Sutton, Kimble,
                Gillespie, Blanco, Comal, Guadalupe, Gonzales, De Witt, Lavaca,
                Colorado, Wharton, and Matagorda Counties, Texas
              </td>
              <td>
                February 28
              </td>
              <td>
                November 30.
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                All other Texas counties and all other States
              </td>
              <td>
                March 15
              </td>
              <td>
                November 30.
              </td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5877'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:IV:-:407:-:407.13
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        407.13
      </num>
      <head>
        Group risk plan for forage.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='407' sect='13' psec='' tq='N'>
              407.13
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Group risk plan for forage.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The provisions of the Group Risk Plan for Forage for the 2000 and
          succeeding crop years are as follows:
        </P>
        <EXTRACT>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            1. Definitions
          </HD>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Harvest.
            </E>
             Removal of the forage from the field, and rotational grazing.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              NASS yield.
            </E>
             The yield calculated by dividing the NASS estimate of the
            production of hay in the county by the NASS estimate of the acres of
            hay in the county, as specified in the actuarial documents. The
            actuarial documents will specify whether the harvested or planted
            acreage is used to calculate the yield used to establish the
            expected county yield and calculate indemnities.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Planted acreage.
            </E>
             Land seeded to forage, by a planting method appropriate for forage,
            into a properly prepared seedbed.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Rotational grazing.
            </E>
             The defoliation of the insured forage by livestock, within a
            pasturing system whereby the forage field is subdivided into smaller
            parcels and livestock are moved from one area to another, allowing a
            period of grazing followed by a period for forage regrowth.
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            2. Crop Insured
          </HD>
          <P>
            The insured crop will be the forage types shown on the Special
            Provisions:
            <PRTPAGE P='100' />
          </P>
          <P>
            (a) Grown on insurable acreage in the county or counties listed in
            the accepted application;
          </P>
          <P>
            (b) Properly planted and reported by the acreage reporting date;
          </P>
          <P>
            (c) Intended for harvest; and
          </P>
          <P>
            (d) Not grown with another crop.
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            3. Insurable Acreage
          </HD>
          <P>
            In addition to 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 3 of
            </aref>
             the Basic Provisions of the Group Risk Plan Common Policy, acreage
            seeded to forage after July 1 of the previous crop year will not be
            insurable. Acreage physically located in another county not listed
            on the accepted application is not insured under this policy.
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            4. Payment
          </HD>
          <P>
            (a) A payment will be made only if the payment yield for the insured
            crop year is less than your trigger yield.
          </P>
          <P>
            (b) Payment yields will be determined prior to May 1 following the
            crop year.
          </P>
          <P>
            (c) We will issue any payment to you prior to the May 31 immediately
            following our determination of the payment yield.
          </P>
          <P>
            (d) The payment is equal to the payment calculation factor
            multiplied by your policy protection for each insured crop practice
            and type specified in the actuarial documents.
          </P>
          <P>
            (e) The payment will not be recalculated even though the NASS yield
            may be subsequently revised.
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            5. Program Dates
          </HD>
          <P>
            November 30 is the Cancellation and Termination Date for all states.
            The Contract Change Date is August 31 for all states.
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            6. Annual Premium
          </HD>
          <P>
            In lieu of 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 8(g) of
            </aref>
             the Basic Provisions of the Group Risk Plan Common Policy, the
            annual premium is earned and payable on the acreage reporting date.
            You will be billed for premium due on the date shown in the Special
            Provisions. The premium will be determined based on the rate shown
            on the actuarial documents.
          </P>
        </EXTRACT>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5878'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:IV:-:407:-:407.14
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        407.14
      </num>
      <head>
        Group risk plan for peanuts.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='407' sect='14' psec='' tq='N'>
              407.14
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Group risk plan for peanuts.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The provisions of the Group Risk Plan for Peanuts for the 2000 and
          succeeding crop years are as follows:
        </P>
        <EXTRACT>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            1. Definitions
          </HD>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Harvest.
            </E>
             Combining or threshing the peanuts.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              NASS yield.
            </E>
             The yield calculated by dividing the NASS estimate of peanut
            production in the county, by the NASS estimate of the acres of
            peanuts in the county, as specified in the actuarial documents. The
            actuarial documents will specify whether the harvested or planted
            acreage is used to calculate the yield used to establish the
            expected county yield and calculate indemnities.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Planted acreage.
            </E>
             Land in which the peanut seed has been placed by a machine
            appropriate for the insured crop and planting method, at the correct
            depth, into a seedbed that has been properly prepared for the
            planting method and production practice.
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            2. Crop Insured
          </HD>
          <P>
            The insured crop will be all peanuts:
          </P>
          <P>
            (a) Grown on insurable acreage in the county or counties listed in
            the accepted application;
          </P>
          <P>
            (b) Properly planted and reported by the acreage reporting date;
          </P>
          <P>
            (c) Planted with the intent to be harvested as peanuts; and
          </P>
          <P>
            (d) Not interplanted with an established grass or legume or
            interplanted with another crop.
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            3. Payment
          </HD>
          <P>
            (a) A payment will be made only if the payment yield for the insured
            crop year is less than your trigger yield.
          </P>
          <P>
            (b) Payment yields will be determined prior to June 16 following the
            crop year.
          </P>
          <P>
            (c) We will issue any payment to you prior to the July 16
            immediately following our determination of the payment yield.
          </P>
          <P>
            (d) The payment is equal to the payment calculation factor
            multiplied by your policy protection for each insured crop practice
            and type specified in the actuarial documents.
          </P>
          <P>
            (e) The payment will not be recalculated even though the NASS yield
            may be subsequently revised.
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            4. Program Dates
          </HD>
        </EXTRACT>
        <table class='gpotable' CDEF='s150,xs76,xs52' COLS='3' OPTS='L2,i1'>
          <caption />
          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th>
                State and county
              </th>
              <th>
                Cancellation and termination dates
              </th>
              <th>
                Contract change date
              </th>
            </tr>
          </thead>
          <tfoot />
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Jackson, Victoria, Goliad, Bee, Live Oak, McMullen, La Salle,
                and Dimmit Counties, Texas and all Texas Counties lying south
                thereof
              </td>
              <td>
                January 15
              </td>
              <td>
                November 30.
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                El Paso, Hudspeth, Culberson, Reeves, Loving, Winkler, Ector,
                Upton, Reagan, Sterling, Coke, Tom Green, Concho, McCulloch, San
                Saba, Mills, Hamilton, Bosque, Johnson, Tarrant, Wise, Cooke
                Counties, Texas, and all Texas counties south and east thereof;
                and all other states except New Mexico, Oklahoma, and Virginia
              </td>
              <td>
                February 28
              </td>
              <td>
                November 30.
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                New Mexico; Oklahoma; Virginia; and all other Texas Counties
              </td>
              <td>
                March 15
              </td>
              <td>
                November 30.
              </td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5879'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:IV:-:407:-:407.15
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        407.15
      </num>
      <head>
        Group risk plan for sorghum.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='101' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='407' sect='15' psec='' tq='N'>
              407.15
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Group risk plan for sorghum.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The provisions of the Group Risk Plan for Sorghum for the 2000 and
          succeeding crop years are as follows:
        </P>
        <EXTRACT>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            1. Definitions
          </HD>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Harvest.
            </E>
             Combining or threshing the sorghum for grain, or severing the stalk
            from the land and chopping the stalk and head for the purpose of
            livestock feed.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              NASS yield.
            </E>
             The yield calculated by dividing the NASS estimate of sorghum for
            grain production in the county, by the NASS estimate of the acres of
            sorghum for grain in the county, as specified in the actuarial
            documents. The actuarial documents will specify whether the
            harvested or planted acreage is used to calculate the yield used to
            establish the expected county yield and calculate indemnities.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Planted acreage.
            </E>
             Land in which the sorghum seed has been placed by a machine
            appropriate for the insured crop and planting method, at the correct
            depth, into a seedbed that has been properly prepared for the
            planting method and production practice. Broadcast and subsequent
            mechanical incorporation of the sorghum seed is not allowed.
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            2. Crop Insured
          </HD>
          <P>
            (a) The insured crop will be all sorghum:
          </P>
          <P>
            (1) Grown on insurable acreage in the county or counties listed in
            the accepted application;
          </P>
          <P>
            (2) Properly planted and reported by the acreage reporting date;
          </P>
          <P>
            (3) Planted with the intent to be harvested as grain or silage; and
          </P>
          <P>
            (4) Not interplanted with an established grass or legume or
            interplanted with another crop.
          </P>
          <P>
            (b) Hybrid sorghum seed may only be insured if a written agreement
            exists between you and us. Your request to insure such crop must be
            in writing and submitted to your agent not later than the sales
            closing date.
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            3. Payment
          </HD>
          <P>
            (a) A payment will be made only if the payment yield for the insured
            crop year is less than your trigger yield.
          </P>
          <P>
            (b) Payment yields will be determined prior to April 16 following
            the crop year.
          </P>
          <P>
            (c) We will issue any payment to you prior to the May 16 immediately
            following our determination of the payment yield.
          </P>
          <P>
            (d) The payment is equal to the payment calculation factor
            multiplied by your policy protection for each insured crop practice
            and type specified in the actuarial documents.
          </P>
          <P>
            (e) The payment will not be recalculated even though the NASS yield
            may be subsequently revised.
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            4. Program Dates
          </HD>
        </EXTRACT>
        <table class='gpotable' CDEF='s150,xs76,xs52' COLS='3' OPTS='L2,i1'>
          <caption />
          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th>
                State and county
              </th>
              <th>
                Cancellation and
                <LI>
                  termination dates
                </LI>
              </th>
              <th>
                Contract change date
              </th>
            </tr>
          </thead>
          <tfoot />
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Val Verde, Edwards, Kerr, Kendall, Bexar, Wilson, Karnes,
                Goliad, Victoria, and Jackson Counties, Texas, and all Texas
                counties lying south thereof
              </td>
              <td>
                January 15
              </td>
              <td>
                November 30.
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                El Paso, Hudspeth, Culberson, Reeves, Loving, Winkler, Ector,
                Upton, Reagan, Sterling, Coke, Tom Green, Concho, McCulloch, San
                Saba, Mills, Hamilton, Bosque, Johnson, Tarrant, Wise, and Cooke
                Counties, Texas, and all Texas counties south and east thereof
                to and including Terrell, Crockett, Sutton, Kimble, Gillespie,
                Blanco, Comal, Guadalupe, Gonzales, De Witt, Lavaca, Colorado,
                Wharton, and Matagorda Counties, Texas
              </td>
              <td>
                February 15
              </td>
              <td>
                November 30.
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Alabama; Arizona; Arkansas; California; Florida; Georgia;
                Louisiana; Mississippi; Nevada; North Carolina; and South
                Carolina
              </td>
              <td>
                February 28
              </td>
              <td>
                November 30.
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                All other Texas counties and all other states
              </td>
              <td>
                March 15
              </td>
              <td>
                November 30.
              </td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5880'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:IV:-:407:-:407.16
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        407.16
      </num>
      <head>
        Group risk plan for soybean.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='407' sect='16' psec='' tq='N'>
              407.16
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Group risk plan for soybean.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The provisions of the Group Risk Plan for Soybeans for the 2000 and
          succeeding crop years are as follows:
        </P>
        <EXTRACT>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            1. Definitions
          </HD>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Harvest.
            </E>
             Combining or threshing the soybeans.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              NASS yield.
            </E>
             The yield calculated by dividing the NASS estimate of soybean
            production in the county, by the NASS estimate of the acres of
            soybeans in the county, as specified in the actuarial documents. The
            actuarial documents will specify whether the harvested or planted
            acreage is used to calculate the yield used to establish the
            expected county yield and calculate indemnities.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Planted acreage.
            </E>
             Land in which the soybean seed has been placed by a machine
            appropriate for the insured crop and planting method, at the correct
            depth, into a seedbed that has been properly prepared for the
            planting method and production practice. Land on which seed is
            initially spread onto the soil surface by any method and which
            subsequently is mechanically incorporated into the soil in a timely
            manner and at the proper depth, will also be considered planted.
            <PRTPAGE P='102' />
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            2. Crop Insured
          </HD>
          <P>
            The insured crop will be all soybeans:
          </P>
          <P>
            (a) Grown on insurable acreage in the county or counties listed in
            the accepted application;
          </P>
          <P>
            (b) Properly planted and reported by the acreage reporting date;
          </P>
          <P>
            (c) Planted with the intent to be harvested as soybeans; and
          </P>
          <P>
            (d) Not planted into an established grass or legume or interplanted
            with another crop.
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            3. Payment
          </HD>
          <P>
            (a) A payment will be made only if the payment yield for the insured
            crop year is less than your trigger yield.
          </P>
          <P>
            (b) Payment yields will be determined prior to April 16 following
            the crop year.
          </P>
          <P>
            (c) We will issue any payment to you prior to the May 16 immediately
            following our determination of the payment yield.
          </P>
          <P>
            (d) The payment is equal to the payment calculation factor
            multiplied by your policy protection for each insured crop practice
            and type specified on the actuarial documents.
          </P>
          <P>
            (e) The payment will not be recalculated even though the NASS yield
            may be subsequently revised.
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            4. Program Dates
          </HD>
        </EXTRACT>
        <table class='gpotable' CDEF='s150,xs76,xs52' COLS='3' OPTS='L2,i1'>
          <caption />
          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th>
                State and county
              </th>
              <th>
                Cancellation and termination dates
              </th>
              <th>
                Contract change date
              </th>
            </tr>
          </thead>
          <tfoot />
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Jackson, Victoria, Goliad, Bee, Live Oak, McMullen, La Salle,
                and Dimmit Counties, Texas and all Texas counties lying south
                thereof
              </td>
              <td>
                February 15
              </td>
              <td>
                November 30.
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Alabama; Arizona; Arkansas; California; Florida; Georgia;
                Louisiana; Mississippi; Nevada; North Carolina; South Carolina;
                and El Paso, Hudspeth, Culberson, Reeves, Loving, Winkler,
                Ector, Upton, Reagan, Sterling, Coke, Tom Green, Concho,
                McCulloch, San Saba, Mills, Hamilton, Bosque, Johnson, Tarrant,
                Wise, and Cooke Counties, Texas, and all Texas counties lying
                south and east thereof to and including Maverick, Zavala, Frio,
                Atascosa, Karnes, De Witt, Lavaca, Colorado, Wharton, and
                Matagorda Counties, Texas
              </td>
              <td>
                February 28
              </td>
              <td>
                November 30.
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                All other Texas counties and all other States
              </td>
              <td>
                March 15
              </td>
              <td>
                November.
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                All other Texas counties and all other states.
              </td>
              <td>
                March 15
              </td>
              <td>
                November 30.
              </td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5881'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:IV:-:407:-:407.17
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        407.17
      </num>
      <head>
        Group risk plan for wheat.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='407' sect='17' psec='' tq='N'>
              407.17
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Group risk plan for wheat.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The provisions of the Group Risk Plan for Wheat for the 2000 and
          succeeding crop years are as follows:
        </P>
        <EXTRACT>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            1. Definitions
          </HD>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Harvest.
            </E>
             Combining or threshing the wheat for grain.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              NASS yield.
            </E>
             The yield calculated by dividing the NASS estimate of the wheat
            production in the county, by the NASS estimate of the acres of wheat
            in the county, as specified in the actuarial documents. The
            actuarial documents will specify whether the harvested or planted
            acreage is used to calculate the yield used to establish the
            expected county yield and calculate indemnities.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Planted acreage.
            </E>
             Land in which the wheat seed has been planted by a machine
            appropriate for the insured crop and planting method, at the correct
            depth, into a seedbed that has been properly prepared for the
            planting method and production practice. Land on which seed is
            initially spread onto the soil surface by any method and which
            subsequently is mechanically incorporated into the soil in a timely
            manner and at the proper depth, will also be considered planted.
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            2. Crop Insured
          </HD>
          <P>
            The insured crop will be all wheat:
          </P>
          <P>
            (a) Grown on insurable acreage in the county or counties listed in
            the accepted application;
          </P>
          <P>
            (b) Properly planted and reported by the acreage reporting date;
          </P>
          <P>
            (c) Planted with the intent to be harvested as grain; and
          </P>
          <P>
            (d) Not planted into an established grass or legume, interplanted
            with another crop, or planted as a nurse crop, unless seeded at the
            normal rate and intended for harvest as grain.
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            3. Payment
          </HD>
          <P>
            (a) A payment will be made only if the payment yield for the insured
            crop year is less than your trigger yield.
          </P>
          <P>
            (b) Payment yields will be determined prior to April 1 following the
            crop year.
          </P>
          <P>
            (c) We will issue any payment to you prior to the May 1 immediately
            following our determination of the payment yield.
          </P>
          <P>
            (d) The payment is equal to the payment calculation factor
            multiplied by your policy protection for each insured crop practice
            and type specified in the actuarial documents.
          </P>
          <P>
            (e) The payment will not be recalculated even though the NASS yield
            may be subsequently revised.
          </P>
        </EXTRACT>
        <PRTPAGE P='103' />
        <table class='gpotable' CDEF='s150,xs76,xs52' COLS='3' OPTS='L2,i1'>
          <caption />
          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th>
                State and county
              </th>
              <th>
                Cancellation and
                <LI>
                  termination dates
                </LI>
              </th>
              <th>
                Contract change date
              </th>
            </tr>
          </thead>
          <tfoot />
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                All Colorado counties except Alamosa, Conejos, Costilla, Rio
                Grande, and Saguache; all Montana counties except Daniels and
                Sheridan Counties; all South Dakota counties except Corson,
                Walworth, Edmonds, Faulk, Spink, Beadle, Kingsbury, Miner,
                McCook, Turner, and Yankton Counties and all South Dakota
                counties east thereof; all Wyoming counties except Big Horn,
                Fremont, Hot Springs, Park, and Washakie Counties; and all other
                states except Alaska, Arizona, California, Maine, Minnesota,
                Nevada, New Hampshire, North Dakota, Utah, and Vermont.
              </td>
              <td>
                September 30
              </td>
              <td>
                June 30.
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Arizona; California; Nevada; and Utah
              </td>
              <td>
                October 31
              </td>
              <td>
                June 30.
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Alaska; Alamosa, Conejos, Costilla, Rio Grande, and Saguache
                Counties, Colorado; Maine; Minnesota; Daniels and Sheridan
                Counties, Montana; New Hampshire; North Dakota; Corson,
                Walworth, Edmunds, Faulk, Spink, Beadle, Kingsbury, Miner,
                McCook, Turner, and Yankton Counties South Dakota, and all South
                Dakota counties east thereof; Vermont; and Big Horn, Fremont,
                Hot Springs, Park, and Washakie Counties, Wyoming.
              </td>
              <td>
                March 15
              </td>
              <td>
                November 30.
              </td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>