<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol1'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:7
    </extid>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <head>
      SELECTION AND FUNCTIONS OF FARM SERVICE AGENCY STATE AND COUNTY COMMITTEES
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='2279-1' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/2279-1.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 2279-1
            </subref>
            , 
            <subref title='7' sect='16' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/16.html'>
              16
            </subref>
          </aref>
           U.S.C. 590d and 590h.
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            77 FR 33070
          </aref>
          , June 5, 2012, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='440'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:7:-:7.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        7.1
      </num>
      <head>
        Administration.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='7' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              7.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Administration.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The regulations in this part apply to the election and functions of
            the Farm Service Agency (FSA) county committees and the functions of
            FSA State committees (“county committees” and “State committees,”
            respectively). State and county committees will be under the general
            supervision of the FSA Administrator.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State and county committees, and representatives and employees of
            those committees, do not have authority to modify or waive any of
            the provisions of this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State committees will take any actions required by these
            regulations that have not been taken by a county committee. State
            committees will also:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Correct, or require a county committee to correct, any action taken
            by such county committee that is not in accordance with this part,
            or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Require a county committee to withhold taking any action that is
            not in accordance with this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No provision or delegation to a State or county committee will
            preclude the FSA Administrator, or designee, from determining any
            question arising under this part, or from reversing or modifying any
            determination made by a State or county committee.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             These regulations will be administered in accordance with the
            Uniform Guidelines for Conducting FSA County Committee Elections.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Unless specifically provided in this part, the Deputy
            Administrator, Field Operations, FSA (Deputy Administrator), is
            authorized to issue the official instructions and procedures
            referred to in this part to implement the provisions of this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This part applies to the United States, its territories, and Puerto
            Rico.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='441'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:7:-:7.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        7.2
      </num>
      <head>
        General.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='351' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='7' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              7.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          State and county committees will, as directed by the Secretary, or a
          designee of the Secretary, carry out the programs and functions of the
          Secretary.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='442'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:7:-:7.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        7.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='7' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              7.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The following definitions apply to this part. The definitions in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='718' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              718.2
            </subref>
             of this title
          </aref>
           also apply to this part, except where they conflict with the
          definitions in this section.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Cooperate
          </E>
           means to enroll a farming operation or agricultural property with a
          county office.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Deputy Administrator
          </E>
           means Deputy Administrator for Field Operations, Farm Service Agency,
          U.S. Department of Agriculture or the designee.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Local administrative area
          </E>
           means an elective area for FSA committees in a single county or
          multi-county jurisdiction.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Participate
          </E>
           means to receive assistance, services, or benefits directly from the
          United States Department of Agriculture (USDA), or from USDA
          indirectly through another governmental agency.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Socially disadvantaged farmer or rancher
          </E>
           is an individual or entity who is a member of a group whose members
          have been subject to racial, ethnic, or gender prejudice because of
          their identity as members of a group without regard to their
          individual qualities. These groups consist of: American Indians or
          Alaskan Natives, Asians, Blacks or African Americans, Native Hawaiians
          or other Pacific Islanders, Hispanics, and women.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State committee
          </E>
           means the FSA State committee.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Uniform Guidelines
          </E>
           means the Uniform Guidelines for Conducting Farm Service Agency
          County Committee Elections, which are available in FSA Handbook 15-AO.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='443'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:7:-:7.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        7.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Selection of committee members.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='7' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              7.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Selection of committee members.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State committee members will be selected by the Secretary and will
            serve at the pleasure of the Secretary.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             County committee members will be elected as specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='7' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
                7.11
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
             or appointed as specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='7' sect='17' psec='' tq='N'>
                7.17
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='444'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:7:-:7.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        7.5
      </num>
      <head>
        Eligible voters.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='7' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              7.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Eligible voters.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Persons must meet the requirements of paragraphs (b) or (c) of this
            section to be eligible to vote in direct elections of county
            committee members.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Farmers and ranchers who are of legal voting age in the State in
            which their farms or ranches are located, regardless of race, color,
            national origin, gender, religion, age, disability, political
            beliefs, sexual orientation, and marital or family status, and any
            farmers or ranchers not of legal voting age who are in charge of the
            supervision and conduct of the farming operations on an entire farm,
            are eligible to vote for direct election of county committee
            members, if they:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Participated in a program administered within a county, or area
            under the jurisdiction of the county committee, within 1 year of the
            date of the election; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Not later than the final date to return ballots, cooperate as
            evidenced in county office records.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In any State having a community property law, the spouse of a
            person who is eligible to vote in accordance with paragraph (b) of
            this section is also eligible to vote.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If an eligible voter is a legal entity, the eligible voter&apos;s
            vote may be cast by a duly authorized representative of such entity,
            as determined by the Deputy Administrator, Field Operations, FSA.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each county office will maintain a list of eligible voters for each
            local administrative area within the county. A county office must
            disclose a list containing the names of eligible voters to the
            public. A county office must disclose a list containing the names
            and addresses of eligible voters to a candidate for a county
            committee position at the request of the candidate.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Farmers and ranchers who are not on the list of eligible voters who
            believe that they meet eligibility requirements may file a written
            challenge with the county committee and may appeal county committee
            voting ineligibility determinations to the State committee.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each eligible voter will be entitled to only one ballot in any
            election held in any one local administrative 
            <PRTPAGE P='352' />
            area. If the eligible voter has an interest in land located in more
            than one local administrative area in a single county, such voter
            will not be entitled to vote in more than one local administrative
            area in that county. There will be no voting by proxy.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='445'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:7:-:7.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        7.6
      </num>
      <head>
        Establishment of local administrative areas.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='7' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              7.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Establishment of local administrative areas.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Secretary, or the Secretary&apos;s designee, may designate
            local administrative areas within a county or a larger area under
            the jurisdiction of a county committee.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             There will be a minimum of three local administrative areas in each
            county. In counties that have been combined or consolidated into a
            multiple county office, there will be 3 to 11 local administrative
            areas. In single-county offices, there will be three to five local
            administrative areas. With respect to Alaska and Puerto Rico, the
            county will be the area so designated by the State committees. In
            Louisiana, the term “county” applies to parishes.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each local administrative area will have not more than one elected
            county committee member.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The boundaries of the local administrative areas will be determined
            by the State committee after considering recommendations by the
            county committee in which the local administrative areas are
            located.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The county committee must give public notice of the local
            administrative area boundaries in advance of the election and
            nomination processes.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             [Reserved]
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='446'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:7:-:7.7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        7.7
      </num>
      <head>
        Calling of elections.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='7' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              7.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Calling of elections.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Secretary will establish a county committee in each county or
            area under the jurisdiction of a multiple county office.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each election of county committee members must be held on a date,
            or within a specified period of time, determined by the Deputy
            Administrator. Each such election must be held in accordance with
            instructions issued by the Deputy Administrator, and the
            instructions must be available for public examination in each county
            office.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the number of eligible voters voting in any election of county
            committee members is so small that the State committee determines
            that the result of that election does not represent the views of a
            substantial number of eligible voters, the State committee may
            declare the election void and call a new election. If it is
            determined by the State committee that the election for any position
            on a county committee has not been held substantially in accordance
            with official instructions, the State committee will declare such
            election void and call a new election.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='447'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:7:-:7.8
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        7.8
      </num>
      <head>
        Nominations for county committee.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='7' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              7.8
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Nominations for county committee.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Nominations to the county committee will be publicly solicited with
            a closing date for nominations not less than 90 days prior to the
            election date.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each solicitation for nomination will include the nondiscrimination
            statement used by the Secretary.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be eligible for nomination for election in a single county
            jurisdiction in the local administrative area conducting the
            election, a person must be a farmer or rancher residing within that
            local administrative area under the jurisdiction of the county
            committee. In a multiple county jurisdiction, or in the case where
            an local administrative area or county boundary runs through a farm,
            a person will only be eligible for nomination in the jurisdiction
            and local administrative area in which the person&apos;s records are
            administered.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be eligible, nominees must be farmers or ranchers who:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Participated in a program administered within an area under the
            jurisdiction of the county committee; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             At the time of the deadline to submit nominations, cooperate as
            evidenced in county office records.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Nominations of eligible farmers and ranchers will be solicited and
            accepted from organizations representing the interests of socially
            disadvantaged farmers and ranchers.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Eligible farmers and ranchers may nominate themselves or other
            farmers and ranchers who meet the nomination criteria in paragraph
            (d) of this section, and who certify their willingness to serve on
            the county committee.
            <PRTPAGE P='353' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If elected, nominees must meet all the eligibility requirements in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='7' sect='18' psec='' tq='N'>
                7.18
              </subref>
            </aref>
             to serve as county committee members.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='448'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:7:-:7.9
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        7.9
      </num>
      <head>
        Slate of candidates.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='7' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
              7.9
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Slate of candidates.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as provided in paragraph (b) of this section, a slate of
            candidates will consist of one or more eligible farmers and ranchers
            nominated through public solicitation of nominees as specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='7' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
                7.8
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If no nominations are received by the closing date for nominations,
            the county committee must develop a slate of candidates in
            accordance with the Uniform Guidelines.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A slate developed by the county committee must include at least one
            individual representing the interests of socially disadvantaged
            farmers and ranchers.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Candidates must certify their willingness to serve on the county
            committee if elected as a member or alternate.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The county committee must accept write-in candidates on ballots.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Write-in candidates, if elected as a member or an alternate, must
            meet the eligibility requirements of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='7' sect='18' psec='' tq='N'>
                7.18
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and must certify their willingness to serve on the county committee
            before they will be certified as a member or alternate.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='449'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:7:-:7.10
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        7.10
      </num>
      <head>
        Conduct of county committee elections.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='7' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
              7.10
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Conduct of county committee elections.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The county committee serving at the time of the election will be
            responsible for the conduct of the county committee election in
            accordance with the Uniform Guidelines and with any instructions
            issued by the Deputy Administrator.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             County committee elections must not be associated with, or held in
            conjunction with, any other election or referendum conducted for any
            other purpose.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The county committee must give advance public notice at least 30
            calendar days prior to the election date of how, when, and where
            eligible voters may vote.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The county committee must provide at least 10 calendar days of
            public notice of the date, time, and place at which election ballots
            will be opened and counted.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The county committee must provide at least 10 calendar days of
            public notice that any person may observe the opening and counting
            of the election ballots.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The county executive director must notify all nominees of the
            outcome of the election within 5 calendar days of the election date.
            The notification must be in writing.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='450'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:7:-:7.11
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        7.11
      </num>
      <head>
        Election of county committee members.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='7' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
              7.11
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Election of county committee members.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Where there are three local administrative areas as specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='7' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
                7.6
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , there will be an election of a county committee member and, if
            available, any alternates, for a term of not more than 3 years, or
            until such person&apos;s successor is elected and qualified, in only
            one of the local administrative areas so that the term of office of
            one county committee member and any alternates within one of the
            local administrative areas will expire each year.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Where there are more than three local administrative areas as
            specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='7' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
                7.6
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , there will be an election in at least one of the local
            administrative areas each year, such that the term of office of the
            county committee member(s) and any alternates within at least
            one-third of the local administrative areas will expire each year.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Every 3 years, the eligible voters in a local administrative area
            will elect a county committee member and may elect first and second
            alternates, as available, to serve. The alternates will serve, in
            the order of the number of votes received, as acting members of the
            county committee, in case of the temporary absence of a member, or
            to become a member of the county committee in that same order
            elected in case of the resignation, disqualification, removal, or
            death of a member. In other words, the candidate receiving the most
            votes will be elected as the committee member, and the candidates
            receiving the second and third most votes, if there are multiple
            candidates, will be elected as first and second alternates,
            respectively.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An alternate serving as an acting member of the county committee
            will have the same duties, responsibilities, 
            <PRTPAGE P='354' />
            and authority as a regular member of such committee. In the event an
            alternate fills a permanent vacancy on the county committee, such
            person will assume the remainder of the unexpired term of the county
            committee member who was replaced.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The election must be conducted in all counties by mail or other
            distribution of ballots in accordance with the Uniform Guidelines,
            except that the Deputy Administrator may authorize use of the
            meeting or polling place method in any county where such exception
            is deemed justified.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Elections will be by secret ballot with each eligible voter allowed
            to cast one vote and having the option of writing in the name of a
            candidate.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Failure to elect alternates at the regular election will not
            invalidate such election or require a special election to elect
            alternates.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='451'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:7:-:7.12
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        7.12
      </num>
      <head>
        Composition of a county committee.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='7' sect='12' psec='' tq='N'>
              7.12
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Composition of a county committee.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A committee established under this part will consist of not fewer
            than 3 nor more than 11 elected members.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Committee members must be fairly representative of the farmers and
            ranchers within their respective LAA from which they are elected.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The county committee must select a secretary who must be the county
            executive director or other employee of the county committee. The
            secretary cannot be a county committee member.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The county committee must select a chairperson and
            vice-chairperson.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='452'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:7:-:7.13
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        7.13
      </num>
      <head>
        Tie votes.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='7' sect='13' psec='' tq='N'>
              7.13
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Tie votes.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Tie votes in county committee elections will be settled by lot in a
          manner that is open to the public.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='453'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:7:-:7.14
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        7.14
      </num>
      <head>
        Vacancies.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='7' sect='14' psec='' tq='N'>
              7.14
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Vacancies.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In case of a vacancy in the office of chairperson of a county
            committee, the respective vice chairperson will become chairperson.
            In case of a vacancy in the office of vice chairperson of a three
            member committee, the respective third member will become vice
            chairperson. In case of a vacancy in the office of a member, a
            respective first alternate, if available, will become a member. In
            case of a vacancy in the office of vice chairperson of a four to
            five member county committee, the first alternate, if available, for
            the LAA of the vice chairperson will become a member and the county
            committee will conduct an organizational meeting to select a vice
            chairperson; and in case of a vacancy in the office of the first
            alternate, a respective second alternate, if available, will become
            the first alternate. When unanimously recommended by the members of
            the county committee, as constituted under this paragraph, and
            approved by the State committee, the offices of chairperson and vice
            chairperson of the county committee may be filled by any county
            committee member without regard to the order of succession specified
            in this paragraph.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the event that a vacancy, other than one caused by temporary
            absence, occurs in the membership of the county committee and no
            alternate is available to fill the vacancy, a special election may
            be held to fill such vacancies as exist in the membership.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the event that a vacancy, other than one caused by temporary
            absence, occurs in the membership of the county committee and no
            alternate is available to fill the vacancy, the State committee may
            designate a person to serve out the balance of the term of the
            vacant position on the county committee.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='454'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:7:-:7.15
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        7.15
      </num>
      <head>
        Challenges and appeals.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='7' sect='15' psec='' tq='N'>
              7.15
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Challenges and appeals.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Challenges and appeals by nominees regarding voter eligibility or
            the results of a county committee election must be handled in
            accordance with the Uniform Guidelines.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any nominee has the right to challenge an election in writing, in
            person, or both within 15 calendar days after the results of the
            election are posted.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Challenges to the election must be made to the county committee,
            which will provide a decision on the challenge to the appellant
            within 7 calendar days of the receipt of the challenge.
            <PRTPAGE P='355' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The county committee&apos;s decision may be appealed to the State
            Committee within 15 calendar days of receipt of the notice of the
            decision if the appellant desires.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the event that an election is nullified as a result of a
            challenge or appeal, or an error in the election process, a special
            election must be conducted by the county office and closely
            monitored by the FSA State office.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='455'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:7:-:7.16
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        7.16
      </num>
      <head>
        Report of election.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='7' sect='16' psec='' tq='N'>
              7.16
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Report of election.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The county committee must file an election report with the
            Secretary through the Deputy Administrator&apos;s office not later
            than 20 days after the date an election is held.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The election report must include:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The number of eligible voters in the local administrative area;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The number of ballots cast in the election by eligible voters;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The percentage of eligible voters that cast ballots;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The number of ballots disqualified in the election;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The percentage of ballots disqualified;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The number of nominees for each seat up for election;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The race, ethnicity, and gender of each nominee, as provided by the
            voluntary self identification of each nominee; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The final election results, including the number of ballots
            received by each nominee.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='456'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:7:-:7.17
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        7.17
      </num>
      <head>
        Remedial measures.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='7' sect='17' psec='' tq='N'>
              7.17
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Remedial measures.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FSA will consider additional efforts to achieve the objective that
            county committees are fairly representative of farmers and ranchers
            within areas covered by the committees. Such efforts may include,
            but are not limited to, compliance reviews of selected counties,
            further centralization of the election process, and the appointment
            of socially disadvantaged farmers and ranchers to particular
            committees in accordance with a notice published in the 
            <E T='04'>
              Federal Register
            </E>
             issued by the Secretary authorizing such appointments.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Secretary may ensure inclusion of socially disadvantaged
            farmers and ranchers by appointment of 1 additional voting member to
            a county committee when a significant population of socially
            disadvantaged farmers and ranchers exist in the committee
            jurisdiction and no member is elected from that socially
            disadvantaged population. The appointment of the socially
            disadvantaged voting member will be in accordance with standards and
            qualifications furnished by the State committee.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='457'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:7:-:7.18
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        7.18
      </num>
      <head>
        Eligibility requirements of county committee members.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='7' sect='18' psec='' tq='N'>
              7.18
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Eligibility requirements of county committee members.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be eligible to hold office as a county committee member or an
            alternate to any county office, a person must meet the conditions
            specified in this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Such person must:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Meet the eligibility for nomination criteria specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='7' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
                7.8
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Reside in the local administrative area in which the election is
            held, in cases where a State line, a county line, or a local
            administrative area boundary runs through a farm, eligible farmers
            and ranchers residing on such farm may hold office in the county and
            local administrative area in which the farm has been determined to
            be located for program participation purposes;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Not be ineligible based on prohibited political activities, as
            specified in the Uniform Guidelines;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Not have been dishonorably discharged from any branch of the armed
            services; removed for cause from any public office; convicted of any
            fraud, larceny, embezzlement, or felony, unless any such
            disqualification is waived by the State committee or the Deputy
            Administrator;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Not have been removed as a county committee member, alternate to
            any county office, or as an employee for: Failure to perform the
            duties of the office; committing, attempting, or conspiring to
            commit fraud; incompetence; impeding the effectiveness of any
            program administered in the county; refusal to carry out or failure
            to comply with the Department&apos;s policy relating to equal
            opportunity and civil rights, including the equal employment policy,
            or interfering with others in carrying out such policy; or for
            violation of official instructions, unless any such disqualification
            is waived by the 
            <PRTPAGE P='356' />
            State committee or the Deputy Administrator;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Not have been disqualified for future service because of a
            determination by a State committee that during previous service as a
            county committee member, alternate to any county office, or as an
            employee of the county committee, the person has: Failed to perform
            the duties of such office or employment; committed, attempted, or
            conspired to commit fraud; impeded the effectiveness of any program
            administered in the county; in the course of their official duties,
            refused to carry out or failed to comply with the Department&apos;s
            policy relating to equal opportunity and civil rights, including the
            equal employment policy, or interfered with others in carrying out
            such policy; or violated official instructions, unless any such
            disqualification is waived by the State committee or the Deputy
            Administrator;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Not be an employee of the U.S. Department of Agriculture during the
            term of office;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Not be a sales agent or employee of the Risk Management Agency or
            their affiliates during the term of office;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Not be already serving as a county committee member with 1 or more
            years remaining in their current term of office; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Not have served more than 9 consecutive years (three consecutive
            terms as an elected member) as an elected or appointed county
            committee member just prior to the current election in which elected
            office is sought. After a break in service of at least 1 year, a
            member who has previously served 9 consecutive years may run for
            re-election or be re-appointed.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='458'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:7:-:7.19
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        7.19
      </num>
      <head>
        Eligibility requirements of all other personnel.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='7' sect='19' psec='' tq='N'>
              7.19
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Eligibility requirements of all other personnel.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The county executive director and other employees of the county
            committee must not have been: Dishonorably discharged from any
            branch of the armed services; removed for cause from any public
            office; or convicted of any fraud, larceny, embezzlement, or any
            other felony, unless any such disqualification is waived by the
            State committee or the Deputy Administrator.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The county executive director or any other employee of the county
            committee must not have been removed as a county committee member,
            alternate to any county office, county executive director, or other
            employee of the county committee for: Failure to perform the duties
            of the office; committing, attempting, or conspiring to commit
            fraud; incompetence; impeding the effectiveness of any program
            administered in the county; refusal to carry out or failure to
            comply with the Department&apos;s policy relating to equal
            opportunity and civil rights, including equal employment policy, or
            interfering with others in carrying out such policy; or for
            violation of official instructions, unless such disqualification is
            waived by the State committee or the Deputy Administrator.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The county executive director or any other employee of the county
            committee must not have been disqualified for future employment
            because of a determination by a State committee that during previous
            service as a county committee member, alternate to any county
            office, or as an employee of the county committee, the person has:
            Failed to perform the duties of such office or employment;
            committed, attempted, or conspired to commit fraud; impeded the
            effectiveness of any program administered in the county; refused to
            carry out or failed to comply with the Department&apos;s policy
            relating to equal opportunity and civil rights, including the equal
            employment policy, or interfered with others in carrying out such
            policy; or violated official instructions, unless such
            disqualification is waived by the State committee or the Deputy
            Administrator.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='459'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:7:-:7.20
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        7.20
      </num>
      <head>
        Prohibition on dual office.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='7' sect='20' psec='' tq='N'>
              7.20
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Prohibition on dual office.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A member of the county committee cannot, during the time they are a
            committee member, also serve as:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The secretary to the county committee;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A member of the State committee; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A county executive director or any other county office employee.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             [Reserved]
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='460'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:7:-:7.21
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        7.21
      </num>
      <head>
        Terms of office of county committee members.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='357' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='7' sect='21' psec='' tq='N'>
              7.21
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Terms of office of county committee members.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The term of office of county committee members and alternates to
            such office will begin on a date fixed by the Deputy Administrator,
            which will be after their election or appointment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Before any county committee member or alternate to the county
            committee may take office as a county committee member, such person
            must sign an oath of office to pledge that they will faithfully,
            fairly, and honestly perform to the best of their ability all of the
            duties devolving on them as committee members.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A term of office will continue until a successor is elected and
            qualified as specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='7' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
                7.8
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='7' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
                7.9
              </subref>
            </aref>
             or appointed as specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='7' sect='17' psec='' tq='N'>
                7.17
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='461'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:7:-:7.22
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        7.22
      </num>
      <head>
        State committee duties.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='7' sect='22' psec='' tq='N'>
              7.22
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          State committee duties.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The State committee, subject to the general direction and supervision
          of the Deputy Administrator, will be generally responsible for
          carrying out all Farm Programs in the State or any other functions
          assigned by the Secretary or a designee of the Secretary.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='462'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:7:-:7.23
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        7.23
      </num>
      <head>
        County committee duties.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='7' sect='23' psec='' tq='N'>
              7.23
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          County committee duties.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The county committee, subject to the general direction and
            supervision of the State committee, will be generally responsible
            for carrying out in the county Farm Programs and any other program
            or function assigned by the Secretary or a designee of the
            Secretary.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The county committee will:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Employ the county executive director, subject to standards and
            qualifications furnished by the State committee, except that
            incumbent directors must not be removed except as specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='7' sect='28' psec='' tq='N'>
                7.28
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . There must be no employment discrimination due to race, color,
            national origin, gender, religion, age, disability, political
            beliefs, sexual orientation, or marital or family status. The county
            executive director may not be removed for advocating or carrying out
            the Department&apos;s policy on equal opportunity and civil rights,
            including the equal employment policy. In the event it is claimed
            that dismissal is for such reasons, the dismissal will not become
            effective until the State committee and the Deputy Administrator
            have determined that dismissal was not because of such reasons;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Direct outreach activities to reach and inform socially
            disadvantaged farmers and ranchers of all programs and county
            committee election processes;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Follow official instructions to review, approve, and certify forms,
            reports, and documents requiring such action;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Recommend to the State committee needed changes in boundaries of
            local administrative areas;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Make available to farmers, ranchers, and the public information
            concerning the objectives and operations of the programs
            administered through the county committee;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Make available to agencies of the Federal Government and others
            information with respect to the county committee activities in
            accordance with official instructions issued;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Give public notice of the designation and boundaries of each local
            administrative area within the county prior to the election of
            county committee members;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Direct the giving of notices in accordance with applicable
            regulations and official instructions;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Recommend to the State committee desirable changes in or additions
            to existing programs;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Conduct such hearings and investigations as the State committee may
            request; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_11'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (11)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Perform such other duties as may be prescribed by the State
            committee.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='463'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:7:-:7.24
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        7.24
      </num>
      <head>
        Chairperson of the county committee duties.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='7' sect='24' psec='' tq='N'>
              7.24
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Chairperson of the county committee duties.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The chairperson of the county committee or the person acting as the
          chairperson will preside at meetings of the county committee, certify
          such documents as may require the chairperson&apos;s certification,
          and perform such other duties as may be prescribed by the State
          committee.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='464'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:7:-:7.25
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        7.25
      </num>
      <head>
        County executive director duties.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='7' sect='25' psec='' tq='N'>
              7.25
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          County executive director duties.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The county executive director will execute the policies established
            by 
            <PRTPAGE P='358' />
            the county committee and be responsible for the day-to-day
            operations of the county office.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The county executive director will:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In accordance with standards and qualifications furnished by the
            State committee, employ the personnel of the county office. There
            must be no employment discrimination due to race, color, national
            origin, gender, religion, age, disability, political beliefs, sexual
            orientation, and marital or family status. An employee may not be
            removed under this paragraph for advocating or carrying out the
            Department&apos;s policy on equal opportunity and civil rights,
            including the equal employment policy. In the event it is claimed
            that the dismissal is for such reason, the dismissal will not become
            effective until the State committee and the Deputy Administrator
            have determined that dismissal was not because of such reason;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Receive, dispose of, and account for all funds, negotiable
            instruments, or property coming into the custody of the county
            committee.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='465'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:7:-:7.26
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        7.26
      </num>
      <head>
        Private business activity and conflicts of interest.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='7' sect='26' psec='' tq='N'>
              7.26
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Private business activity and conflicts of interest.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No county committee member, alternate to any such office, or county
            office employee, may at any time use such office or employment to
            promote any private business interest.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             County committee members, alternates, and any person employed in
            the county office will be subject to the official instructions
            issued with respect to conflicts of interest and proper conduct.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='466'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:7:-:7.27
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        7.27
      </num>
      <head>
        Political activity.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='7' sect='27' psec='' tq='N'>
              7.27
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Political activity.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Permitted and prohibited political activities, with respect to any
          State committee member, county committee member, county executive
          director, or any other county employee, will be determined in
          accordance with applicable policies specified in FSA handbooks and
          directives.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='467'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:7:-:7.28
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        7.28
      </num>
      <head>
        Removal from office or employment for cause.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='7' sect='28' psec='' tq='N'>
              7.28
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Removal from office or employment for cause.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Adverse personnel actions involving any county committee member or
            alternate member, county executive director, or other county office
            employee will be taken for failing to perform the duties of their
            office, impeding the effectiveness of any program administered in
            the county, violating official instructions, or for misconduct.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any person whom FSA proposes to suspend or remove from office or
            employment must be given advance written notice of the reason for
            such action and must be advised of the right to reply to such a
            proposal and any right of further review and appeal if the person is
            removed or suspended.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='468'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:7:-:7.29
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        7.29
      </num>
      <head>
        Delegation of authority to Deputy Administrator.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='7' sect='29' psec='' tq='N'>
              7.29
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Delegation of authority to Deputy Administrator.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notwithstanding the authority vested by this part to a State
            committee, a county committee, and the county executive director,
            the Deputy Administrator has the authority to take adverse personnel
            actions involving any county committee member or alternate member,
            county executive director, or other county office employee for
            failing to perform the duties of their office or for misconduct.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any person whom FSA proposes to suspend or remove from office or
            employment must be given advance written notice of the reason for
            such action and must be advised of the right to reply to such a
            proposal and any right of further review and appeal if the person is
            removed or suspended.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='469'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:7:-:7.30
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        7.30
      </num>
      <head>
        Custody and use of books, records, and documents.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='7' sect='30' psec='' tq='N'>
              7.30
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Custody and use of books, records, and documents.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All books, records, and documents of or used by the county
            committee in the administration of programs assigned to it, or in
            the conduct of elections, will be the property of FSA or the United
            States Department of Agriculture, as applicable, and must be
            maintained in good order in the county office.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Voted ballots must be placed into and remain in sealed containers,
            such containers not being opened until the prescribed date and time
            for counting. Following the counting of ballots, the ballots must be
            placed in sealed containers and retained for 1 year unless otherwise
            determined by the Deputy Administrator.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The books, records, and documents referred to in paragraph (a) of 
            <PRTPAGE P='359' />
            this section must be available for use and examination:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             At all times by authorized representatives of the Secretary, the
            Administrator, or a designee of the Administrator.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             By State and county committee members, and authorized employees of
            the State and county office in the performance of duties assigned to
            them under this part, subject to instructions issued by the Deputy
            Administrator;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             At any reasonable time to any program participant insofar as such
            person&apos;s interests under the programs administered by the
            county committee may be affected, subject to instructions issued by
            the Deputy Administrator; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To any other person only in accordance with instructions issued by
            the Deputy Administrator.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='470'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:7:-:7.31
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        7.31
      </num>
      <head>
        Administrative operations.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='7' sect='31' psec='' tq='N'>
              7.31
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Administrative operations.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The administrative operations of county committees including, but not
          limited to, the following, must be conducted, except as otherwise
          provided in this part, in accordance with official instructions
          issued: Annual, sick, and other types of employee leave; the calling
          and conduct of elections; and the maintenance of records of county
          committee meetings.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='471'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:7:-:7.34
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        7.34
      </num>
      <head>
        Retention of authority.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='7' sect='34' psec='' tq='N'>
              7.34
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Retention of authority.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Nothing in this part will preclude the Secretary, the
            Administrator, or the Deputy Administrator from administering any or
            all programs, or exercising other functions delegated to the county
            committee, State committee, or any employee of such committees.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In exercising this authority, the Secretary, the Administrator, or
            the Deputy Administrator may designate for such period of time as
            deemed necessary a person or persons of their choice to be in charge
            with full authority to carry out the programs or other functions
            without regard to the normal duties of such committees or employees.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>