<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol6'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:D:631
    </extid>
    <num>
      631
    </num>
    <head>
      GREAT PLAINS CONSERVATION PROGRAM
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='16' sect='590p' note='' psec='#b' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/590p.html#b'>
              16 U.S.C. 590p(b)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            49 FR 11142
          </aref>
          , Mar. 27, 1984, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='6278'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:D:631:A:631.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        631.1
      </num>
      <head>
        Purpose.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='631' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              631.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Purpose.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Great Plains Conservation Program (GPCP) is a special program
            targeted to the total conservation treatment of farm or ranch units
            with the most severe soil and water resources problems. The purpose
            of the program is to assist farm, ranch and other land users to make
            changes in their cropping systems and land uses which are needed to
            conserve, develop, protect, and utilize the soil and water resources
            of their lands. This purpose is achieved by controlling erosion,
            conserving water, and adjusting land use to mitigate climatic, soil,
            topographic, flood, saline and other natural hazards.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Program participation is voluntary and is carried out by applying a
            conservation plan encompassing an entire operating unit. A
            conservation plan is developed with the land user in consultation
            with the local conservation district and is used to establish a GPCP
            contract. This contract provides for cost sharing between the land
            user and the Secretary of Agriculture for applying needed land use
            adjustments and conservation treatment within a specified time
            schedule. The program is supplemental to, not a substitution for,
            other programs in the Great Plains area.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6279'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:D:631:A:631.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        631.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='631' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              631.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The terms defined shall have the following meaning in this part and in
          all contracts, forms, documents, instructions, and procedures in
          connection therewith, unless the contract or subject matter requires
          otherwise.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Applicant.
          </E>
           A land user who has requested in writing to participate in the GPCP.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Area conservationist.
          </E>
           The NRCS employee who is the supervisor with primary responsibility
          for quality control. This person serves as contracting officer if
          designated by the state conservationist.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Chief.
          </E>
           The Chief of the Natural Resources Conservation Service (NRCS), USDA.
          <PRTPAGE P='503' />
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Conservation district (CD).
          </E>
           A conservation district, soil conservation district, soil and water
          conservation district, natural resource district, or similar legally
          constituted body with which the Secretary of Agriculture cooperates
          pursuant to the Soil Conservation and Domestic Allotment Act. The
          members of governing bodies of these organizations may be known as
          supervisors, directors, or commissioners.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Conservation plan.
          </E>
           A written record of the land user&apos;s decisions regarding planned
          land use and treatment, including estimates of extent and cost. The
          timing of applications for each practice and/or identifiable unit is
          scheduled in the conservation plan.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Conservation practice.
          </E>
           A specific treatment which is planned and applied according to NRCS
          standards and specifications as a part of a resource management system
          for land, water, and related resources.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Contract.
          </E>
           A legal document that binds both the participants and the federal
          government to carry out the terms and conditions of the conservation
          plan. The contract forms the basis for GPCP sharing the costs of
          implementing the conservation plan.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Contracting officer.
          </E>
           The NRCS employee authorized to sign GPCP contracts on behalf of
          NRCS.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            County program committee.
          </E>
           A group of Federal, State, and local officials selected by the
          designated conservationist. The committee provides ideas to the
          designated conservationist regarding program development and
          interagency program coordination.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Designated county.
          </E>
           A county within a Great Plains state that the Chief has designated
          for participation.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Designated conservationist.
          </E>
           A district conservationist or other NRCS employee who the state
          conservationist has designated to be responsible for administration of
          the GPCP in a designated county.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            District conservationist.
          </E>
           The NRCS employee assigned to direct and supervise NRCS activities in
          one or more conservation districts.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Great Plains area.
          </E>
           The area comprising those counties within the Great Plains states
          designated for GPCP participation.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Great Plains states.
          </E>
           Colorado, Kansas, Montana, Nebraska, New Mexico, North Dakota,
          Oklahoma, South Dakota, Texas, and Wyoming.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Identifiable unit.
          </E>
           A discernibly distinct component of a conservation practice.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Land user.
          </E>
           An individual, partnership, firm, joint-stock company, corporation,
          association, trust, estate, or other nonpublic legal entity having
          control of a unit of land. This definition includes two or more
          persons having a joint or common interest.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Life span.
          </E>
           The period of time specified in the contract and/or operation and
          maintenance agreement during which the resource management systems of
          component practices are to be maintained and used for the intended
          purpose. Most practices will have a useful life beyond the specified
          life span.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Operation and maintenance agreement.
          </E>
           A document signed by both the participant and the contracting officer
          outlining the operation and maintenance requirements for applied
          conservation treatment.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Operating unit.
          </E>
           A parcel or parcels of land, whether contiguous or noncontiguous,
          constituting a single management unit for agricultural purposes.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Other land.
          </E>
           Nonagricultural land on which erosion must be controlled to protect
          agricultural land and which can be covered by contract.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Participant.
          </E>
           A land user who is a party to a GPCP contract.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Resource management system.
          </E>
           A combination of conservation practices identified by the land or
          water use that, if installed, will protect or improve the soil or
          water resource base.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Specifications.
          </E>
           Minimum guantity or quality requirements established by NRCS to meet
          the standard for a specific conservation practice.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State conservationist.
          </E>
           The NRCS employee authorized to direct and supervise NRCS activities
          within the state.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State program committee.
          </E>
           A group of Federal, state, and local officials selected by the state
          conservationist. The committee provides ideas to the state
          conservationist regarding program development, coordination, general
          policies, and operating procedures of GPCP in the state.
          <PRTPAGE P='504' />
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Technical assistance.
          </E>
           Guidance provided to land users regarding the use and treatment of
          soil, water, plant, animal, and related resources. This assistance may
          include conservation plan formulation, application, and maintenance
          and is usually confined to those activities which the recipient could
          not reasonably be expected to do without specialized assistance.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Technical guide.
          </E>
           A document containing detailed information on the conservation of
          soil, water, plant, animal, and related resources applicable
          specifically to the area for which it is prepared.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6280'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:D:631:A:631.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        631.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Administration.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='631' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              631.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Administration.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS is responsible for the administration of the Great Plains
            Conservation Program (GPCP).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The program shall be carried out in close cooperation with
            interested Federal, state, and local government units and
            organizations. The program in designated counties shall be
            coordinated with the long-range program of conservation districts
            operating in such counties and with other USDA activities.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Applicants who have USDA-Farmers Home Administration (FmHA) loans
            must furnish to NRCS satisfactory evidence that the conservation
            plan used as a basis for the GPCP contract is compatible with
            assistance provided by FmHA. Such evidence may consist of written
            acknowledgement by the authorized FmHA official that the GPCP
            conservation plan is compatible with the farm management plan
            prepared for FmHA program purposes.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6281'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:D:631:A:631.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        631.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Program applicability.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='631' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              631.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Program applicability.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The program is applicable only to designated counties within the Great
          Plains states. County designation is a responsibility of the NRCS
          Chief.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6282'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:D:631:A:631.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        631.5
      </num>
      <head>
        Land user eligibility.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='631' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              631.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Land user eligibility.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Any land user in a designated county may file an application for
          participation in the GPCP with the NRCS field office. A land user who
          develops an acceptable conservation plan in cooperation with NRCS and
          the conservation district that is in compliance with the terms and
          conditions of the program is eligible to sign a contract.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6283'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:D:631:A:631.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        631.6
      </num>
      <head>
        Land eligible for the program.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='631' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              631.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Land eligible for the program.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The program is applicable to:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Privately owned land,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Nonfederally owned public land under private control for the
            contract period and included in the participant&apos;s operating
            unit, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Federally owned land, if installation of conservation practices
            would directly benefit nearby or adjoining privately owned land of
            persons who maintain and use the Federal land.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6284'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:D:631:A:631.7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        631.7
      </num>
      <head>
        Conservation treatment eligible for cost sharing.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='631' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              631.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Conservation treatment eligible for cost sharing.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The state conservationist, in consultation with the state program
            committee, shall select the resource management systems,
            conservation practices, or identifiable units eligible for GPCP cost
            sharing in the state.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The designated conservationist, in consultation with the county
            program committee, shall select from the state list the eligible
            conservation systems, practices, or identifiable units eligible for
            GPCP cost sharing in the county.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6285'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:D:631:A:631.8
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        631.8
      </num>
      <head>
        Cost-share rates.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='631' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              631.8
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Cost-share rates.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Federal rate may not exceed 80 percent.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The maximum Federal rate (percentage) within each state for each
            practice or identifiable unit shall be established by the state
            conservationist.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The maximum rate (percentage) for each county is established by the
            designated conservationist not to exceed the state rate
            (percentage).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The rate (percentage) established by a state conservationist or a
            designated conservationist shall not exceed the amount necessary and
            appropriate to apply conservation treatment.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6286'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:D:631:A:631.9
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        631.9
      </num>
      <head>
        Conservation plan.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='631' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
              631.9
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Conservation plan.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An applicant is responsible for developing a conservation plan, in
            cooperation with the conservation district, that protects the
            resource base in a manner acceptable to NRCS. This plan will be used
            as a basis for developing a contract. Conservation treatment is to
            be planned and implemented as a resource management system.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The applicant decides how the land will be used and selects the
            resource management systems that will 
            <PRTPAGE P='505' />
            achieve the applicant&apos;s objectives and provide protection of
            soil, water, and related resources acceptable to NRCS. Eligible
            practices may be included in the conservation plan to enhance fish
            and wildlife and recreation resources, promote the economic use of
            land, and reduce or control agriculture-related pollution.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Technical assistance will be provided by NRCS, as needed by the
            land user. NRCS may utilize the services of private, local, state,
            and other Federal agencies in discharging its responsibilities for
            technical assistance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Participants are responsible for accomplishing the conservation
            plan and may use all available sources of assistance, including
            other USDA programs that are consistent with the conservation plan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All conservation practices scheduled in the conservation plan are
            to be carried out in accordance with the applicable NRCS technical
            guide.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6287'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:D:631:B:631.10
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        631.10
      </num>
      <head>
        Contracts.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='631' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
              631.10
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Contracts.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To participate in the program, an applicant must enter into a
            contract agreeing to implement a conservation plan. All persons who
            control or share control of the operating unit for the proposed
            contract period must sign the contract or one person with
            power-of-attorney may sign the contract for all persons. The
            applicant must provide the contracting officer with satisfactory
            evidence of control of the operating unit for the life of the
            proposed contract.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Contracts may be entered into not later than September 30, 1991.
            The contract shall be for a period needed to establish the
            conservation treatment scheduled in the conservation plan and must
            extend at least 3 years but not more than 10 years.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Contracts may be transferred or modified by mutual consent. The
            transferee assumes full responsibility for the contract including
            operation and maintenance of all land treatment installed under the
            contract. Also included are payments made under the contract to the
            participant or preceding participants before and after the transfer.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Contracts may be terminated by mutual consent or by NRCS for cause.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6288'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:D:631:B:631.11
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        631.11
      </num>
      <head>
        Conservation practice maintenance.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='631' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
              631.11
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Conservation practice maintenance.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each participant is obligated to maintain the resource management
            systems or conservation practices applied under the contract for the
            duration of the contract. Practices installed before execution of
            the contract are to be maintained as specified in the contract.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the life span of the practices or resource management systems
            extends beyond the period of the contract, state conservationists
            may make the operation and maintenance of those practices or systems
            a condition of the contract. The length of such operation and
            maintenance shall extend for the expected life span.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6289'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:D:631:B:631.12
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        631.12
      </num>
      <head>
        Cost-share payments.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='631' sect='12' psec='' tq='N'>
              631.12
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Cost-share payments.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Federal cost sharing shall be adjusted so that the combined cost
            share by Federal and state government or subdivision of a state
            shall not exceed 100 percent of the cost.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Cost-share payments for completing resource management systems or a
            practice or an identifiable unit according to specifications will be
            made by NRCS as specified in the contract or as adjusted according
            to 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='631' sect='12' psec='#a' tq='N'>
                631.12(a)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6290'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:D:631:B:631.13
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        631.13
      </num>
      <head>
        Disputes and appeals for matters other than contract violations.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          60 FR 67316
        </aref>
        , Dec. 29, 1995]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='631' sect='13' psec='' tq='N'>
              631.13
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Disputes and appeals for matters other than contract violations.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Applicants or participants may appeal decisions regarding matters
          other than contract disputes under this part in accordance with 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='614' tq='N'>
              614 of this title
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            60 FR 67316
          </aref>
          , Dec. 29, 1995]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6291'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:D:631:B:631.14
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        631.14
      </num>
      <head>
        Contract violations.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='631' sect='14' psec='' tq='N'>
              631.14
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Contract violations.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Contract violations, determinations and appeals will be handled in
          accordance with the terms of the contract and attachments thereto.
          Violations involving fraud are to be handled in accordance with
          current USDA regulations.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6292'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:D:631:C:631.20
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        631.20
      </num>
      <head>
        Setoffs.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='631' sect='20' psec='' tq='N'>
              631.20
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Setoffs.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If any participant to whom compensation is payable under the
            program is indebted to U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA), or any
            agency thereof, or is indebted to any other agency of the United
            States, and such indebtedness is listed on the county claim control
            record maintained in the office of the county ASC committee, the
            compensation due the participant shall be set off against the
            indebtedness. Indebtedness owing to USDA, or any agency thereof,
            shall be given first consideration. Setoffs made pursuant to this
            section shall not deprive the participant of any right to contest
            the justness of the indebtedness involved either by administrative
            appeal or by legal action.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Participants who are indebted to this program for any reason will
            be placed on the USDA claim control record promptly by the state
            conservationist after the participant has been given opportunity to
            pay the debt.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6293'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:D:631:C:631.21
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        631.21
      </num>
      <head>
        Compliance with regulatory measures.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='631' sect='21' psec='' tq='N'>
              631.21
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Compliance with regulatory measures.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Participants who carry out conservation practices shall be responsible
          for obtaining the authorities, rights, easements, or other approvals
          necessary for the implementation and maintenance of the conservation
          practices in keeping with applicable laws and regulations.
          Participants shall save the United States harmless from any
          infringements upon the rights of others or from any failure to comply
          with applicable laws or regulations.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6294'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:D:631:C:631.22
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        631.22
      </num>
      <head>
        Access to operating unit.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='631' sect='22' psec='' tq='N'>
              631.22
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Access to operating unit.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Any authorized NRCS representative shall have the right to enter an
          operating unit for the purpose of ascertaining the accuracy of any
          representations made in a contract or leading up to a contract, and as
          to the performance of the terms and conditions of the contract. Access
          shall include the right to measure acreages, render technical
          assistance, and inspect any work undertaken under the contract.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6295'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:D:631:C:631.23
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        631.23
      </num>
      <head>
        State conservationist&apos;s authority.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='631' sect='23' psec='' tq='N'>
              631.23
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          State conservationist&apos;s authority.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The state conservationist may take the initiative to revise or require
          revision of any determination made by the contracting officer or the
          district conservationist in connection with the program, except that
          the state conservationist may not revise any executed contract other
          than as may specifically be authorized herein.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>