<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol12'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1778
    </extid>
    <num>
      1778
    </num>
    <head>
      EMERGENCY AND IMMINENT COMMUNITY WATER ASSISTANCE GRANTS
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='5' sect='301' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/5/301.html'>
              5 U.S.C. 301
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='1989' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1989.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 1989
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='16' sect='1005' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/1005.html'>
              16 U.S.C. 1005
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            68 FR 46078
          </aref>
          , Aug. 5, 2003, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='14394'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1778:-:1778.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1778.1
      </num>
      <head>
        General.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1778' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              1778.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This part outlines policies and procedures for making Emergency
            Community Water Assistance Grants (ECWAG) authorized under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              Section 306A of
            </aref>
             the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act, (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='1926' note='' psec='#a' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1926.html#a'>
                7 U.S.C. 1926(a)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ), as amended. Any processing or servicing activity conducted
            pursuant to this part involving authorized assistance to Agency
            employees, members of their families, known close relatives, or
            business or close personal associates, is subject to the provisions
            of subpart D of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1900' tq='N'>
                1900 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . Applicants for this assistance are required to identify any known
            relationship or association with an Agency employee.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Agency officials will maintain liaison with officials of other
            Federal, State, regional and local development 
            <PRTPAGE P='263' />
            agencies to coordinate related programs to achieve rural development
            objectives.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Agency officials shall cooperate with appropriate State agencies in
            making grants that support State strategies for rural area
            development.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Funds allocated for use in accordance with this part are also to be
            considered for use by Indian tribes within the State regardless of
            whether State development strategies include Indian reservations
            within the State&apos;s boundaries. Indians residing on such
            reservations must have an equal opportunity along with other rural
            residents to participate in the benefits of this program. This
            includes equal application of outreach activities of Field Offices.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Federal statutes provide for extending the Agency financial
            programs without regard to race, color, religion, sex, national
            origin, marital status, age, or physical/mental handicap (provided
            the participant possesses the capacity to enter into legal
            contracts).
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14395'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1778:-:1778.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1778.2
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1778' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              1778.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14396'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1778:-:1778.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1778.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Objective.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1778' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              1778.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Objective.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The objective of the ECWAG Program is to assist the residents of rural
          areas that have experienced a significant decline in quantity or
          quality of water, or in which such a decline is considered imminent,
          to obtain or maintain adequate quantities of water that meets the
          standards set by the Safe Drinking Water Act (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='42' sect='300f' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/42/300f.html'>
              42 U.S.C. 300f
            </subref>
          </aref>
           et seq.) (SDWA).
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14397'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1778:-:1778.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1778.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          68 FR 46078
        </aref>
        , Aug. 5, 2003, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          69 FR 65519
        </aref>
        , Nov. 15, 2004]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1778' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              1778.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Acute shortage.
          </E>
           An acute shortage is a situation in which the system either cannot
          deliver water at all through its distribution system or can only
          deliver water on a sporadic basis.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Emergency.
          </E>
           Occurrence of an incident such as, but not limited to, a drought;
          earthquake; flood; tornado; hurricane; disease outbreak; or chemical
          spill, leakage, or seepage.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Rural areas.
          </E>
           Includes any area not in a city or town with a population in excess
          of 10,000 inhabitants, according to the latest decennial census of the
          United States. located in any of the fifty States, the Commonwealth of
          Puerto Rico, the Western Pacific Territories, Marshall Islands,
          Federated States of Micronesia, Republic of Palau, and the U.S. Virgin
          Islands.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Significant decline in quality.
          </E>
           A significant decline in quality of potable water occurs when the
          present community source or delivery system does not meet, as a result
          of an emergency, the current SDWA requirements. For a private source
          or delivery system a significant decline in quality occurs when the
          water is no longer potable as a result of an emergency. As used in
          this Subpart, the term significant decline in quality may also include
          a situation where a significant decline is likely to occur within one
          year from the date of the filing of an application.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Significant decline in quantity.
          </E>
           A significant decline in the quantity is caused by a disruption of
          the potable water supply by an emergency. The disruption in quantity
          of water prevents the present source or delivery system from supplying
          potable water needs to rural residents. This would not include a
          decline in excess water capacity. As used in this Subpart, the term
          significant decline in quantity may also include a situation where a
          significant decline is likely to occur within one year from the date
          of the filing of an application.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Statewide Nonmetropolitan Median Household Income (SNMHI).
          </E>
           Median household income of the State&apos;s nonmetropolitan counties
          and portions of metropolitan counties outside of cities, towns or
          places of 50,000 or more population.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            68 FR 46078
          </aref>
          , Aug. 5, 2003, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            69 FR 65519
          </aref>
          , Nov. 15, 2004]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14398'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1778:-:1778.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1778.5
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1778' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              1778.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14399'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1778:-:1778.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1778.6
      </num>
      <head>
        Eligibility.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1778' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              1778.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Eligibility.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Grants may be made to public bodies and private nonprofit
            corporations serving rural areas. Public bodies include counties,
            cities, townships, incorporated towns and villages, boroughs,
            authorities, districts, and other political subdivisions of a State.
            Public bodies also include Indian tribes on Federal and State
            reservations and other Federally recognized Indian Tribal groups in
            rural areas.
            <PRTPAGE P='264' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the case of grants made to alleviate a significant decline in
            quantity or quality of water available from the water supplies of
            rural residents, the applicant must demonstrate that the decline
            occurred within two years of the date the application was filed with
            the Agency. This would not apply to grants made for repairs, partial
            replacement, or significant maintenance on an established water
            system. In situations involving imminent decline, evidence must be
            presented to demonstrate that the decline is likely to occur within
            one year of the date the application is filed with the Agency.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14400'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1778:-:1778.7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1778.7
      </num>
      <head>
        Project priority.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1778' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              1778.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Project priority.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Paragraph (d) of this section indicates items and conditions which
          must be considered in selecting applications for further development.
          When ranking eligible applications for consideration for limited
          funds, Agency officials must consider the priority items met by each
          application and the degree to which those priorities are met.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Applications.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The application and supporting information submitted with it will
            be used to determine the proposed project&apos;s priority for
            available funds.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              State Office review.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All applications will be reviewed and scored for funding priority
            using RUS Bulletin 1778-1. Eligible applicants that cannot be funded
            should be advised that funds are not available.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              National Office review.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each year all funding requests will be reviewed by the National
            Office beginning 30 days after funds from the annual appropriation
            are made available to the Agency. Reviews will continue throughout
            the fiscal year as long as funds are available. Projects selected
            for funding will be considered based on the priority criteria and
            available funds. Projects must compete on a national basis for
            available funds, and the National Office will allocate funds to
            State offices on a project by project basis.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Selection priorities.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The priorities described below will be used by the State Program
            Official to rate applications and by the Assistant Administrator of
            Water and Environmental Programs to select projects for funding.
            Points will be distributed as indicated in paragraphs (d)(1) through
            (d)(5) of this section and will be considered in selecting projects
            for funding. A copy of RUS Bulletins 1778-1 and 1778-2 used to rate
            applications, should be placed in the case file for future
            reference.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Population.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The proposed project will serve an area with a rural population:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Not in excess of 1,500—30 points.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             More than 1,500 and not in excess of 3,000—20 points.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             More than 3,000 and not in excess of 5,000—15 points.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Over 5,000—0 points.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Income.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The median household income of population to be served by the
            proposed project is:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Not in excess of 70% of the statewide nonmetropolitan median
            household income—30 points.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             More than 70% and not in excess of 80% of the statewide
            nonmetropolitan median household income—20 points.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             More than 80% and not in excess of 90% of the statewide
            nonmetropolitan median household income—10 points.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Over 90% of the statewide nonmetropolitan median household income—0
            points.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Significant decline.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Points will be assigned for only one of the following paragraphs
            when the primary purpose of the proposed project is to correct a
            significant decline that has occurred in the:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Quantity of water available from private individually owned wells
            or other individual sources of water—30 points; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Quantity of water available from an established system&apos;s
            source of water—20 points; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Quality of water available from private individually owned wells or
            other individual sources of water—30 points; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_3_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Quality of water available from an established system&apos;s source
            of water—20 points.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Imminent decline.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The proposed project will attempt to avert an imminent decline
            expected to occur during the one-year period following the filing of
            an application—10 points. 
            <PRTPAGE P='265' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <FP>
          (
          <E T='04'>
            Note:
          </E>
           If points were assigned above for a significant decline, no points
          will be awarded for imminent decline.)
        </FP>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Acute shortage.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Grants made in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1778' sect='11' psec='#b' tq='N'>
                1778.11(b)
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
             to assist an established water system remedy an acute shortage of
            quality water or correct a significant decline in the quantity or
            quality of water that is available—10 points.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Discretionary.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In certain cases the Administrator may assign up to 30 points for
            items such as geographic distribution of funds, rural residents
            hauling water, severe contamination levels, etc.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14401'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1778:-:1778.8
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1778.8
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1778' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              1778.8
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14402'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1778:-:1778.9
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1778.9
      </num>
      <head>
        Uses.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1778' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
              1778.9
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Uses.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Grant funds may be used for the following purposes:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Waterline extensions from existing systems.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Construction of new waterlines.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Repairs to an existing system.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Significant maintenance to an existing system.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Construction of new wells, reservoirs, transmission lines,
            treatment plants, and other sources of water.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Equipment replacement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Connection and/or tap fees.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Pay costs that were incurred within six months of the date an
            application was filed with the Agency to correct an emergency
            situation that would have been eligible for funding under this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any other appropriate purpose such as legal fees, engineering fees,
            recording costs, environmental impact analyses, archaeological
            surveys, possible salvage or other mitigation measures, planning,
            establishing or acquiring rights associated with developing sources
            of, treating, storing, or distributing water.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Assist rural water systems to comply with the requirements of the
            Federal Water Pollution Control Act (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='33' sect='1251' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/33/1251.html'>
                33 U.S.C. 1251
              </subref>
            </aref>
             et seq.) (FWPCA) or the SDWA when such failure to comply is
            directly related to a recent decline in quality of potable water.
            This would not apply to changes in the requirements of FWPCA or
            SDWA.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provide potable water to communities through means other than those
            covered above for not to exceed 120 days when a more permanent
            solution is not feasible in a shorter time frame.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14403'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1778:-:1778.10
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1778.10
      </num>
      <head>
        Restrictions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1778' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
              1778.10
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Restrictions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Grant funds may not be used to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Assist any city or town with a population in excess of 10,000
            inhabitants according to the most recent decennial census of the
            United States. Facilities financed by RUS may be located in
            non-rural areas. However, loan and grant funds may be used to
            finance only that portion of the facility serving rural areas,
            regardless of facility location.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Assist a rural area that has a median household income in excess of
            the statewide nonmetropolitan median household income according to
            the most recent decennial census of the United States.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Finance facilities which are not modest in size, design, cost, and
            are not directly related to correcting the potable water quantity or
            quality problem.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Pay loan or grant finder&apos;s fees.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Pay any annual recurring costs that are considered to be
            operational expenses.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Pay rental for the use of equipment or machinery owned by the rural
            community.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Purchase existing systems.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Refinance existing indebtedness, except for short-term debt
            incurred in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1778' sect='9' psec='#h' tq='N'>
                1778.9(h)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Make reimbursement for projects developed with other grant funds.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Finance facilities that are not for public use.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Nothing in paragraph (a)(1) of this section shall preclude rural
            areas from submitting joint proposals for assistance under this
            part. Each entity applying for financial assistance under this part
            to fund their share of a joint project will be considered
            individually.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14404'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1778:-:1778.11
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1778.11
      </num>
      <head>
        Maximum grants.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1778' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
              1778.11
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Maximum grants.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Grants not to exceed $500,000 may be made to alleviate a
            significant decline in quantity or quality of water available to a
            rural area that occurred within two years of filing an application
            with the Agency, or to attempt to avoid a significant decline that
            is expected to occur during the twelve 
            <PRTPAGE P='266' />
            month period following the filing of an application.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Grants made for repairs, partial replacement, or significant
            maintenance on an established system to remedy an acute shortage or
            significant decline in the quality or quantity of potable water, or
            an anticipated acute shortage or significant decline, cannot exceed
            $150,000.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Grants under this part, subject to paragraphs (a) and (b) of this
            section, shall be made for 100 percent of eligible project costs.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14405'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1778:-:1778.12
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1778.12
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1778' sect='12' psec='' tq='N'>
              1778.12
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14406'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1778:-:1778.13
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1778.13
      </num>
      <head>
        Set-aside.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1778' sect='13' psec='' tq='N'>
              1778.13
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Set-aside.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             At least 70 percent of all grants made under this grant program
            shall be for projects funded in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1778' sect='11' psec='#a' tq='N'>
                1778.11(a)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             At least 50 percent of the funds appropriated for this grant
            program shall be allocated to rural areas with populations not in
            excess of 3,000 inhabitants according to the most recent decennial
            census of the United States.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14407'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1778:-:1778.14
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1778.14
      </num>
      <head>
        Other considerations.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          68 FR 46078
        </aref>
        , Aug. 5, 2003, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          76 FR 80730
        </aref>
        , Dec. 27, 2011]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1778' sect='14' psec='' tq='N'>
              1778.14
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Other considerations.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Civil rights compliance requirements.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All grants made under this part are subject to Title VI of the
            Civil Rights Act of 1964 (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='42' sect='2000d' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/42/2000d.html'>
                42 U.S.C. 2000d
              </subref>
            </aref>
             et seq.) as outlined in subpart E of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1901' tq='N'>
                1901 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Environmental requirements.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All projects must have appropriate environmental reviews in
            accordance with RUS requirements.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Uniform Relocation and Real Property Acquisition Policies Act (
              <aref type='USC'>
                <subref title='42' sect='4601' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/42/4601.html'>
                  42 U.S.C. 4601
                </subref>
              </aref>
               et seq.).
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All projects must comply with the requirements set forth in 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='21' tq='N'>
                21
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Flood and mudslide hazard area precautions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the project is located in a flood or mudslide area, then flood
            or mudslide insurance must be provided as required in subpart A of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1806' tq='N'>
                1806 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
             (RD Instruction 426.2).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Governmentwide debarment and suspension
            </E>
             (nonprocurement) and requirements for drug-free work place. All
            projects must comply with the requirements set forth in the U.S.
            Department of Agriculture regulations 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3017' tq='N'>
                3017
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and RD Instruction 1940-M.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Intergovernmental review.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All projects funded under this part are subject to Executive Order
            12372 (3 CFR, 1983 Comp., p. 197), which requires intergovernmental
            consultation with State and local officials. These requirements are
            set forth in U.S. Department of Agriculture regulations 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3015' tq='N'>
                3015
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , subpart V, and RD Instruction 1970-I, ‘Intergovernmental Review,’
            available in any Agency office or on the Agency&apos;s Web site.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            68 FR 46078
          </aref>
          , Aug. 5, 2003, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 80730
          </aref>
          , Dec. 27, 2011]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14408'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1778:-:1778.15-1778.20
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1778.15-1778.20
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1778' sect='15-1778' psec='' tq='N'>
              1778.15-1778
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .20
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14409'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1778:-:1778.21
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1778.21
      </num>
      <head>
        Application processing.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1778' sect='21' psec='' tq='N'>
              1778.21
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Application processing.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The material submitted with the application should include the
            Preliminary Engineering Report, population and median household
            income of the area to be served, description of project, and nature
            of emergency that caused the problem(s) being addressed by the
            project. The documentation must clearly show that the applicant has
            had a significant decline in the quantity or quality of potable
            water or an acute shortage of potable water, or that such a decline
            or shortage is imminent, and that the proposed project will
            eliminate or alleviate the problem. For projects to be funded in
            accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1778' sect='11' psec='#a' tq='N'>
                1778.11 (a)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , evidence must be furnished that a significant decline in quantity
            or quality occurred within two years before filing the application
            with the Agency, or is expected to occur within one year after
            filing the application.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When favorable action will not be taken on an application, the
            applicant will be notified in writing by the State Program Official
            of the reasons why the request was not favorably considered.
            Notification to the applicant will state that a review of this
            decision by the Agency may be requested by the applicant in
            accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='11' tq='N'>
                11
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14410'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1778:-:1778.22
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1778.22
      </num>
      <head>
        Planning development and procurement.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1778' sect='22' psec='' tq='N'>
              1778.22
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Planning development and procurement.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Planning development and procurement for grants made under this part
          will be in accordance with subpart C of 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            Part 
            <subref title='7' part='1780' tq='N'>
              1780 of this chapter
            </subref>
          </aref>
          . A certification should be obtained from the 
          <PRTPAGE P='267' />
          State agency or the Environmental Protection Agency if the State does
          not have primacy, stating that the proposed improvements will be in
          compliance with requirements of the SDWA.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14411'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1778:-:1778.23
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1778.23
      </num>
      <head>
        Grant closing and disbursement of funds.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1778' sect='23' psec='' tq='N'>
              1778.23
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Grant closing and disbursement of funds.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Grants will be closed in accordance with 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              § 1780.45 of
            </aref>
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1780' tq='N'>
                1780 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             RUS Bulletin 1780-12, “Water or Waste Grant Agreement,” will be
            executed by all applicants.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Agency&apos;s policy is not to disburse grant funds from the
            Treasury until they are actually needed by the applicant. Grant
            funds will be disbursed by using multiple advances.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14412'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1778:-:1778.24-1778.30
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1778.24-1778.30
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1778' sect='24-1778' psec='' tq='N'>
              1778.24-1778
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .30
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14413'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1778:-:1778.31
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1778.31
      </num>
      <head>
        Performing development.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1778' sect='31' psec='' tq='N'>
              1778.31
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Performing development.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Applicable provisions of subpart C of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1780' tq='N'>
                1780 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
             will be followed in performing development for grants made under
            this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             After filing an application in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1778' sect='21' psec='' tq='N'>
                1778.21
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and when immediate action is necessary, the State Program Official
            may concur in an applicant&apos;s request to proceed with
            construction before funds are obligated provided the RUS
            environmental requirements are complied with. The applicant must be
            advised in writing that:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any authorization to proceed or any concurrence in bid awards,
            contract concurrence, or other project development activity, is not
            a commitment by the Agency to provide grant funds under this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Agency is not liable for any debt incurred by the applicant in
            the event that funds are not provided under this part.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14414'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1778:-:1778.32-1778.33
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1778.32-1778.33
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1778' sect='32-1778' psec='' tq='N'>
              1778.32-1778
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .33
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14415'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1778:-:1778.34
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1778.34
      </num>
      <head>
        Grant servicing.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1778' sect='34' psec='' tq='N'>
              1778.34
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Grant servicing.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Grants will be serviced in accordance with 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              § 1951.215 of
            </aref>
             subpart E of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1951' tq='N'>
                1951 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and subpart O of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1951' tq='N'>
                1951 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The grantee will provide an audit report in accordance with 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              § 1780.47 of
            </aref>
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1780' tq='N'>
                1780 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14416'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1778:-:1778.35
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1778.35
      </num>
      <head>
        Subsequent grants.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1778' sect='35' psec='' tq='N'>
              1778.35
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Subsequent grants.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Subsequent grants will be processed in accordance with the
          requirements set forth in this part. The initial and subsequent grants
          made to complete a previously approved project must comply with the
          maximum grant requirements set forth in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1778' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
              1778.11
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14417'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1778:-:1778.36
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1778.36
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1778' sect='36' psec='' tq='N'>
              1778.36
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14418'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1778:-:1778.37
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1778.37
      </num>
      <head>
        Forms, Instructions and Bulletins.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1778' sect='37' psec='' tq='N'>
              1778.37
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Forms, Instructions and Bulletins.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Bulletins, instructions and forms referenced are for use in
          administering grants made under this part and are available from any
          USDA/Rural Development office or the Rural Utilities Service, United
          States Department of Agriculture, Washington, DC 20250-1500.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14419'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1778:-:1778.38-1778.99
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1778.38-1778.99
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1778' sect='38-1778' psec='' tq='N'>
              1778.38-1778
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .99
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14420'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1778:-:1778.100
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1778.100
      </num>
      <head>
        OMB control number.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1778' sect='100' psec='' tq='N'>
              1778.100
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          OMB control number.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The information collection requirements contained in this part have
          been approved by the Office of Management and Budget and assigned OMB
          control number 0572-0110.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>