<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol10'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XV:-:1570
    </extid>
    <num>
      1570
    </num>
    <head>
      EXPORT BONUS PROGRAMS
    </head>
    <text>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            56 FR 42223
          </aref>
          , Aug. 27, 1991, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='13321'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XV:-:1570:A:1570.10
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1570.10
      </num>
      <head>
        General statement.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1570' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
              1570.10
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General statement.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          This subpart sets forth the criteria to be considered in evaluating
          and approving proposals for initiatives to facilitate export sales
          under the Sunflowerseed Oil Assistance Program (SOAP) and Cottonseed
          Oil Assistance Program (COAP) administered by the Foreign Agricultural
          Service (FAS). These criteria are interrelated and will be considered
          together in order to select eligible countries for SOAP and COAP
          initiatives which will best meet the programs&apos; objective. The
          objective of the programs is to encourage the sale of additional
          quantities of sunflowerseed oil and cottonseed oil in world markets at
          competitive prices. Under the SOAP and the COAP, bonuses are made
          available by FAS to enable exporters to meet prevailing world prices
          for sunflowerseed oil and cottonseed oil in targeted destinations. In
          the operation of the SOAP and the COAP, FAS will make reasonable
          efforts to avoid the displacement of usual marketings of U.S.
          agricultural commodities.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13322'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XV:-:1570:A:1570.20
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1570.20
      </num>
      <head>
        Criteria.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1570' sect='20' psec='' tq='N'>
              1570.20
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Criteria.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The criteria considered by FAS in reviewing proposals for SOAP and
          COAP initiatives will include, but not be limited to, the following:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The expected contribution which initiatives will make toward
            realizing U.S. agricultural export goals and, in particular, in
            developing, expanding, or maintaining markets for U.S. sunflowerseed
            and/or cottonseed oil;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The subsidy requirements of proposed initiatives in relation to the
            sums made available to operate the programs in any given fiscal
            year; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The likelihood that sales facilitated by initiatives would have the
            unintended effect of displacing normal commercial sales of
            sunflowerseed and/or cottonseed oil.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13323'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XV:-:1570:B:1570.1100
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1570.1100
      </num>
      <head>
        Drawback certification.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1570' sect='1100' psec='' tq='N'>
              1570.1100
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Drawback certification.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          An offer submitted by an exporter to FAS for an export bonus under the
          SOAP or the COAP must contain, in addition to any other information
          required by FAS, a certification stating the following: “None of the
          eligible commodity (sunflowerseed oil and/or cottonseed oil) has been
          or will be used as the basis for a claim of a refund, as drawback,
          pursuant to 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 313 of
          </aref>
           the Tariff Act of 1930 (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='19' sect='1313' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/19/1313.html'>
              19 U.S.C. 1313
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ) of any duty, tax, or fee imposed under Federal law on an imported
          commodity or product.” This certification must be signed by the
          exporter, if the exporter is an individual, or by a partner or officer
          of the exporter, if the exporter is a partnership or a corporation,
          respectively. FAS will reject any offer that does not contain the
          prescribed certification.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>