<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol6'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:V:-:501
    </extid>
    <num>
      501
    </num>
    <head>
      CONDUCT ON U.S. MEAT ANIMAL RESEARCH CENTER, CLAY CENTER, NEBRASKA
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            Secs. 2, 4, 62
          </aref>
           Stat. 281; 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='40' sect='318' note='' psec='#a' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/40/318.html#a'>
              40 U.S.C. 318(a)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , (c); 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            sec. 103, 63
          </aref>
           Stat. 380; 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='40' sect='753' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/40/753.html'>
              40 U.S.C. 753
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            sec. 205(d), 63
          </aref>
           Stat. 389; 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='40' sect='486' note='' psec='#d' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/40/486.html#d'>
              40 U.S.C. 486(d)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            36 FR 1293
          </aref>
           and 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            36 FR 21706
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            37 FR 2423
          </aref>
          , Feb. 1, 1972, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='5990'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:V:-:501:-:501.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        501.1
      </num>
      <head>
        General.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='501' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              501.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The rules and regulations in this part apply to all property of or
          under the charge or control of the U.S. Meat Animal Research Center,
          Clay Center, Nebr. (hereinafter referred to as the Research Center),
          and to all persons entering in or on such property. The Administrator,
          General Services Administration, has delegated to the Secretary of
          Agriculture, with authority to redelegate, the authority to make all
          the needful rules and regulations for the protection of the Research
          Center (
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            36 FR 1293
          </aref>
          ). The Secretary of Agriculture has delegated this authority to the
          Director of Science and Education (
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            36 FR 21706
          </aref>
          ) who in turn has delegated such authority to the Administrator,
          Agricultural Research Service (
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            36 FR 21706
          </aref>
          ). The rules and regulations in this part are issued pursuant to such
          delegations. It is the responsibility of occupant or cooperating
          agency to require observance of these rules and regulations.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5991'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:V:-:501:-:501.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        501.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Admission.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='501' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              501.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Admission.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Admission to the Research Center during “off duty” hours shall be
          restricted to the main arteries and any deviation therefrom by
          individuals shall be limited to authorized individuals who may be
          required to sign a register and display identification documents when
          requested by a guard or other authorized individuals. “Off duty” hours
          will be posted at the Research Center. Admission during “duty” hours
          when the Center is closed to the public in emergency situations will
          be limited to authorized individuals who may be required to sign a
          register and display identification documents when requested by a
          guard or other authorized individual.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5992'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:V:-:501:-:501.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        501.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Preservation of property.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='501' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              501.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Preservation of property.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          It is unlawful to willfully destroy, damage, or remove property or any
          part thereof. Hunting, fishing, motorcycling, using snowmobiles, and
          other disturbances or encroachment activities are prohibited except
          for official purposes.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5993'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:V:-:501:-:501.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        501.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Conformity with signs and emergency directions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='501' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              501.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Conformity with signs and emergency directions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Persons in and on property of the Research Center shall comply with
          official signs of a prohibitory or directory nature, and with the
          directions of authorized individuals.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5994'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:V:-:501:-:501.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        501.5
      </num>
      <head>
        Nuisances.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='501' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              501.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Nuisances.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The use of loud, abusive, or otherwise improper language, unwarranted
          loitering, sleeping, or assembly, the creation of any hazard to
          persons or things, improper disposal of rubbish, spitting, prurient
          prying, the commission of any obscene or indecent act, or any other
          unseemly or disorderly conduct, throwing articles of any kind from a
          building, or climbing upon any part of a building is prohibited.
          Further, conduct which obstructs the usual use of entrances, foyers,
          corridors, offices, elevators, stairways and parking lots, or which
          otherwise tends to impede or disturb Center employees in the
          performance of their duties or which otherwise impedes the general
          public from obtaining the administrative services provided by the
          Research Center is prohibited.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5995'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:V:-:501:-:501.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        501.6
      </num>
      <head>
        Gambling.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='501' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              501.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Gambling.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Participating in games for money or other personal property, or the
          operation of gambling devices, the conduct of a lottery or pool, or
          the selling or purchasing of numbers tickets, in or on Research Center
          property, is prohibited.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5996'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:V:-:501:-:501.7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        501.7
      </num>
      <head>
        Intoxicating beverages and narcotics.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='501' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              501.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Intoxicating beverages and narcotics.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Entering Research Center property or the operating of a motor vehicle 
          <PRTPAGE P='404' />
          thereon, by a person under the influence of intoxicating beverages or
          narcotic drug, hallucinogen, marijuana, barbiturate, or amphetamine
          (unless prescribed by a physician) or the consumption of such
          beverages, or the use of any such drug or substance in or on the
          Research Center property, is prohibited.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5997'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:V:-:501:-:501.8
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        501.8
      </num>
      <head>
        Soliciting, vending, debt collection, and distribution of handbills.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='501' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              501.8
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Soliciting, vending, debt collection, and distribution of handbills.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The soliciting of alms and contributions, commercial soliciting and
          vending of all kinds, the display or distribution of commercial
          advertising, or the collecting of private debts, in or on Research
          Center property, is prohibited. This section does not apply to
          national or local drives for funds for welfare, health, and other
          purposes sponsored or approved by the Agricultural Research Service,
          concessions, or personal notices posted by employees on authorized
          bulletin boards. Distribution of material such as pamphlets,
          handbills, and flyers or the posting of mateirals on bulletin boards
          or elsewhere, is prohibited without prior approval of authorized
          individuals.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5998'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:V:-:501:-:501.9
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        501.9
      </num>
      <head>
        Photographs for news, advertising, or commercial purposes.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='501' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
              501.9
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Photographs for news, advertising, or commercial purposes.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Except where security regulations apply, or a Federal court order or
          rules prohibit it, photographs for news purposes may be taken in
          entrances, lobbies, foyers or auditoriums when used for public
          meetings without prior permission. Photographs for advertising and
          commercial purposes may be taken only with the prior written
          permission of the Director, Research Center. Photographs for news,
          advertising, or commercial purposes may be taken in space or areas
          occupied by a cooperator only with the consent of the cooperator
          concerned and the Director, Research Center.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5999'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:V:-:501:-:501.10
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        501.10
      </num>
      <head>
        Pets.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='501' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
              501.10
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Pets.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Animals shall be brought or allowed, as applicable, upon the Research
          Center only with the prior written approval of the Director, Research
          Center, except seeing eye dogs may be brought to the reception area
          serving the offices of the Director, Research Center, without prior
          approval.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6000'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:V:-:501:-:501.11
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        501.11
      </num>
      <head>
        Mobile equipment and pedestrian traffic.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='501' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
              501.11
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Mobile equipment and pedestrian traffic.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Drivers, operators, or pilots of all equipment whether or not
            motorized in or on Research Center property, or within the scope of
            Research Center activity, shall operate in a careful and safe manner
            at all times and shall comply with the signals and directions of
            guards, special policemen, or other authorized individuals, and all
            posted traffic signs;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The blocking of entrances, driveways, walks, railways, runways,
            loading platforms, or fire hydrants in or on Research Center
            property is prohibited;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except in emergencies, parking or landing in or on Research Center
            property in other than designated areas is not allowed without a
            permit. Parking without authority, parking in unauthorized locations
            or in locations reserved for other persons, or parking continuously
            in excess of ten hours without permission, or contrary to the
            direction of posted signs is prohibited. This section may be
            supplemented from time to time by the issuance and posting of
            specific traffic directives as may be required, and when so issued
            and posted such directives shall have the same force and effect as
            if made a part hereof;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The operation of unlicensed gasoline powered vehicles is
            prohibited.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6001'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:V:-:501:-:501.12
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        501.12
      </num>
      <head>
        Weapons and explosives.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='501' sect='12' psec='' tq='N'>
              501.12
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Weapons and explosives.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          No person while in or on Research Center property shall carry
          firearms, bows and arrows, darts, other dangerous or deadly weapons,
          or explosives, either openly or concealed, except as officially
          authorized, for official purposes.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6002'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:V:-:501:-:501.13
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        501.13
      </num>
      <head>
        Nondiscrimination.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='501' sect='13' psec='' tq='N'>
              501.13
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Nondiscrimination.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          There shall be no discrimination by segregation or otherwise against
          any person or persons because of race, sex, religion, color, or
          national origin, in furnishing, or by refusing to furnish to such
          person or persons the use of any facility of a public nature,
          including all service, privileges, accommodations, and activities
          provided thereby on Research Center property.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6003'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:V:-:501:-:501.14
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        501.14
      </num>
      <head>
        Non-Federal law enforcement.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='405' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='501' sect='14' psec='' tq='N'>
              501.14
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Non-Federal law enforcement.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Research Center special policemen may be deputized by State or local
          law enforcement agencies to exercise police power on property outside
          the Research Center. With the consent of any State or local law
          enforcement agency, the facilities or services of such State or local
          law enforcement agency may be utilized by the Research Center.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6004'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:V:-:501:-:501.15
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        501.15
      </num>
      <head>
        Exceptions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='501' sect='15' psec='' tq='N'>
              501.15
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Exceptions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The Administrator, Agricultural Research Service, may in individual
          cases make prior, written exceptions to the rules and regulations in
          this part if he determines it to be not adverse to the public
          interest.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6005'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:V:-:501:-:501.16
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        501.16
      </num>
      <head>
        Penalties and other law.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='501' sect='16' psec='' tq='N'>
              501.16
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Penalties and other law.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Whoever shall be found guilty of violating the rules and regulations
          in this part where the United States has and exercises exclusive or
          concurrent legislative jurisdiction, is subject to fine of not more
          than $50 or imprisonment or not more than 30 days, or both (see 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='40' sect='318c' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/40/318c.html'>
              40 U.S.C. 318c
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ). Nothing contained in the rules, regulations, or penalties in this
          part shall be construed as abrogating or authorizing the abrogation of
          any other rules, regulations, penalties, or any Federal law, or any
          State and local laws and regulations which may be applicable.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>