<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol10'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1410
    </extid>
    <num>
      1410
    </num>
    <head>
      CONSERVATION RESERVE PROGRAM
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='15' sect='714b' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/15/714b.html'>
              15 U.S.C. 714b
            </subref>
             and 
            <subref title='15' sect='714c' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/15/714c.html'>
              714c
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='16' sect='3801-384' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/3801-384.html'>
              16 U.S.C. 3801-384
            </subref>
          </aref>
          7.
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            68 FR 24835
          </aref>
          , May 8, 2003, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='12280'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1410:-:1410.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1410.1
      </num>
      <head>
        Administration.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          68 FR 24835
        </aref>
        , May 8, 2003, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          74 FR 30911
        </aref>
        , June 29, 2009; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          76 FR 4805
        </aref>
        , Jan. 27, 2011]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              1410.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Administration.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The regulations in this part will be implemented under the general
            supervision and direction of the Executive Vice President, Commodity
            Credit Corporation (CCC), the Administrator, Farm Service Agency
            (FSA), or a designee, or the Deputy Administrator, FSA. In the
            field, the regulations in this part will be implemented by the FSA
            State and county committees (“State committees” and “county
            committees,” respectively).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State executive directors, county executive directors, and State
            and county committees do not have the authority to modify or waive
            any of the provisions in this part unless specifically authorized by
            the Deputy Administrator.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State committee may take any action authorized or required by
            this part to be taken by the county committee, but which has not
            been taken by such committee, such as:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Correct or require a county committee to correct any action taken
            by such county committee that is not in accordance with this part;
            or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Require a county committee to withhold taking any action that is
            not in accordance with this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No delegation of authority herein to a State or county committee
            shall preclude the Executive Vice President, CCC, the Administrator,
            FSA, or a designee, or the Deputy Administrator, from determining
            any question arising under this part or from reversing or modifying
            any determination made by a State or county committee.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Data furnished by prospective participants will be used to
            determine eligibility for program benefits. Furnishing the data is
            voluntary; however, the failure to provide data could result 
            <PRTPAGE P='464' />
            in program benefits being withheld or denied.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notwithstanding other provisions of this section, the Erodibility
            Index (EI), suitability of land for permanent vegetative or water
            cover, factors for determining the likelihood of improved water
            quality, and adequacy of the planned practice to achieve desired
            objectives shall be determined by the Natural Resource Conservation
            Service (NRCS) or other sources approved by CCC, in accordance with
            the Field Office Technical Guide (FOTG) of NRCS or other guidelines
            deemed appropriate by NRCS. In no case shall such determination
            compel CCC to execute a contract that CCC does not believe will
            serve the purposes of the program established by this part. Any
            approved technical authority shall utilize CRP guidelines
            established by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC may consult with the Forest Service (FS), a State forestry
            agency, or other organizations as determined by CCC to be necessary
            for developing and implementing conservation plans that include tree
            planting as the appropriate practice or as a component of a
            practice.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC may consult with the National Institute of Food and Agriculture
            (NIFA) to coordinate a related information and education program as
            deemed appropriate to implement the Conservation Reserve Program
            (CRP).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC may consult with the National Marine Fisheries Service, U.S.
            Fish and Wildlife Service (FWS), or State wildlife agencies for such
            assistance as is determined necessary by CCC to implement the CRP.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as agreed by CCC and the participant together:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The regulations in this part and others governing CRP as of
            September 30, 2008, will continue to govern contracts in effect as
            of that date (see 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1410' tq='N'>
                1410
              </subref>
            </aref>
             contained in the edition of 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR parts 
              <subref title='7' part='1200' tq='N'>
                1200
              </subref>
            </aref>
             to 1599 revised as of January 1, 2008); and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as specified in paragraph (j)(1) of this section, this part
            will apply to all CRP contracts.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            68 FR 24835
          </aref>
          , May 8, 2003, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            74 FR 30911
          </aref>
          , June 29, 2009; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 4805
          </aref>
          , Jan. 27, 2011]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12281'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1410:-:1410.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1410.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          68 FR 24835
        </aref>
        , May 8, 2003, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          69 FR 26763
        </aref>
        , May 14, 2004; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          71 FR 31917
        </aref>
        , Jun 2, 2006; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          74 FR 30911
        </aref>
        , June 29, 2009; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 27168
        </aref>
        , May 14, 2010; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 44071
        </aref>
        , July 28, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              1410.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The definitions in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='718' tq='N'>
                718 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
             shall be applicable to this part and all documents issued in
            accordance with this part, except as otherwise provided in this
            section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The following definitions shall be applicable to this part:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Agricultural commodity
          </E>
           means:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any crop planted and produced by annual tilling of the soil or on
            an annual basis by one-trip planters,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Sugarcane planted or produced in a State, or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Alfalfa and other multi-year grasses and legumes grown in a
            rotation practice as approved by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Annual rental payment
          </E>
           means, unless the context indicates otherwise, the annual payment
          specified in the CRP contract that, subject to the availability of
          funds, is made to a participant to compensate a participant for
          placing eligible land in CRP, including any incentive payments that
          are not specifically cost-shares.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Beginning farmer or rancher
          </E>
           means, as determined by CCC, a person or entity who:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Has not been a farm or ranch operator or owner for more than 10
            years,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Materially and substantially participates in the operation of the
            farm or ranch involved in the CRP contract modification, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If an entity, is an entity in which 50 percent of the members or
            stockholders of the entity meet the first two requirements of this
            definition.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Commercial pond-raised aquaculture facility
          </E>
           means, as determined by CCC, any earthen facility from which $1,000
          or more of freshwater food fish were sold or normally would have been
          sold during a calendar year.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Conservation district
          </E>
           means a political subdivision of a State, Indian Tribe, or territory,
          organized pursuant to the State or territorial soil conservation
          district law, or Tribal law. The subdivision may be a conservation
          district, soil conservation district, soil and water conservation
          district, resource conservation district, natural resource district,
          land conservation committee, or similar legally constituted body.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Conservation plan
          </E>
           means a record of the participant&apos;s decisions and supporting
          information for treatment of a 
          <PRTPAGE P='465' />
          unit of land or water, and includes a schedule of operations,
          activities, and estimated expenditures needed to solve identified
          natural resource problems by devoting eligible land to permanent
          vegetative cover, trees, water, or other comparable measures.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Conservation priority area
          </E>
           means an area designated with actual and adverse water quality,
          wildlife habitat, air quality, or other natural resource impacts
          related to agricultural production activities or to assist
          agricultural producers to comply with Federal and State environmental
          laws or to meet other conservation needs, such as for air quality, as
          determined by the Deputy Administrator.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Conserving use
          </E>
           means a use of land with any rotation requirements as may be
          specified by the Deputy Administrator: for alfalfa and other
          multi-year grasses and legumes planted during 2002 through 2007; as
          summer fallow during 2002 through 2007; and in which the land was
          previously enrolled in the program (for which the contract expired
          during the period 2002 through 2007) and where the grass cover
          required by the CRP contract continues to be maintained as though
          still enrolled. Where the land use for a year qualifies as a
          “conserving use” under this definition, then, the land for that year
          shall, for purposes of eligibility under 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='6' psec='#a_1' tq='N'>
              1410.6(a)(1)
            </subref>
          </aref>
           be considered to have been planted to an “agricultural commodity.”
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Considered planted
          </E>
           means: land devoted to a conserving use or land enrolled in the WBP
          during the crop year or during any of the 2 years preceding the crop
          year if the contract expired; cropland enrolled in CRP; or land for
          which the producer received insurance indemnity payment for prevented
          planting.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Contour grass strip
          </E>
           means a vegetation area that follows the contour of the land that
          complies with the FOTG and a conservation plan developed under this
          part.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Contract period
          </E>
           means the term of the contract which is not less than 10, nor more
          than 15 years.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Cost-share payment
          </E>
           means the payment made by CCC to assist program participants in
          establishing the practices required in a contract.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Cropland
          </E>
           means land defined as cropland in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='718' tq='N'>
              718 of this title
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , except for land in terraces that are no longer capable of being
          cropped.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Cropped wetlands
          </E>
           means farmed wetlands and wetlands farmed under natural conditions.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Deputy Administrator
          </E>
           means the Deputy Administrator for Farm Programs, FSA, the CRP
          Program Manager, or a designee.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Erodibility Index
          </E>
           (EI) is, as prescribed by CCC, used to determine the inherent
          erodibility (water or wind) of a soil.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Farmed wetlands
          </E>
           means land defined as farmed wetlands in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='12' tq='N'>
              12 of this title
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Federally-owned land
          </E>
           means land owned by the Federal Government or any department,
          instrumentality, bureau, or agency thereof, or any corporation whose
          stock is wholly owned by the Federal Government.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Field
          </E>
           means a part of a farm that is separated from the balance of the farm
          by permanent boundaries such as fences, roads, permanent waterways,
          woodlands, other similar features, or crop-lines, as determined by
          CCC.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Field Office Technical Guide
          </E>
           (FOTG) means the official USDA guidelines, criteria, and standards
          for planning and applying conservation treatments and conservation
          management systems. It contains detailed information on the
          conservation of soil, water, air, plant, animal resources, and
          cultural resources applicable to the local area for which it is
          prepared.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Field windbreak, shelterbelt, and/or living snowfence
          </E>
           mean a vegetative barrier with a linear configuration composed of
          trees, shrubs, or other vegetation, as determined by CCC, that are
          designated as such in a conservation plan and that are planted for the
          purpose of reducing wind erosion, controlling snow, improving wildlife
          habitat, or conserving energy.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Filter strip
          </E>
           means a strip or area of vegetation adjacent to a body of water the
          purpose of which is to remove nutrients, sediment, organic matter,
          pesticides, and other pollutants from surface runoff and subsurface
          flow by deposition, absorption, plant uptake, and other processes,
          thereby reducing pollution and protecting surface water and subsurface
          water quality and of a 
          <PRTPAGE P='466' />
          width determined appropriate for the purpose by the Deputy
          Administrator.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Highly Erodible Land
          </E>
           (HEL) means land determined to have an EI equal to or greater than 8
          on the acreage offered.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Infeasible to farm
          </E>
           means an area that is too small or isolated to be economically
          farmed, as determined by the Deputy Administrator.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Indian tribe
          </E>
           means any Indian tribe, band, nation, or other organized group, or
          community, including pueblos, rancherias, colonies and any Alaska
          Native Village, or regional or village corporation as defined in or
          established pursuant to the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='43' sect='1601-162' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/43/1601-162.html'>
              43 U.S.C. 1601-162
            </subref>
          </aref>
          9h), which is recognized as eligible for the special programs and
          services provided by the United States to Indians because of their
          status as Indians.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Landlord
          </E>
           means a person who rents or leases acreage to another person.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Limited resource farmer or rancher
          </E>
           means:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A person with direct or indirect gross farm sales of not more than
            $155,200 in each of the previous two calendar years preceding the
            year of enrollment (adjusted for inflation using Prices Paid by
            Farmer Index as compiled by the USDA National Agricultural
            Statistics Service), and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A total household income at or below the national poverty level for
            a family of four, or less than 50 percent of county median household
            income in each of the previous two years (to be determined annually
            using U.S. Department of Commerce data).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Local FSA office
          </E>
           means the FSA office serving the area in which the FSA records are
          located for the farm or ranch.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Merchantable timber
          </E>
           means timber grown for commercial purposes on private non-industrial
          forest land on which the average tree has a trunk diameter of at least
          6 inches measured at a point no less than 4.5 feet above the ground.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Offer
          </E>
           means, unless the context indicates otherwise, if required by CCC,
          the per-acre rental payment requested by the owner or operator in such
          owner&apos;s or operator&apos;s request to participate in the CRP.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Offeror
          </E>
           means an eligible person as determined by CCC who submits an offer of
          eligible acreage for enrollment into the CRP to enter into a CRP
          contract.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Operator
          </E>
           means a person who is in general control of the farming operation on
          the farm, as determined by CCC.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Payment period
          </E>
           means the 10- to 15-year contract period for which the participant
          receives an annual rental payment.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Perennial crop
          </E>
           means a crop that is produced from the same root structure for two or
          more years, as determined by CCC.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Permanent vegetative cover
          </E>
           means perennial stands of approved combinations of certain grasses,
          legumes, forbs, shrubs and trees with a life span of 10 or more years.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Permanent wildlife habitat
          </E>
           means a vegetative cover with the specific purpose of providing
          habitat, food, or cover for wildlife and protecting other
          environmental concerns for the life of the contract.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Pollinator
          </E>
           means an insect or other animal that carries pollen from one flower
          to another.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Practice
          </E>
           means a conservation, wildlife habitat, or water quality measure with
          appropriate operations and management as agreed to in the conservation
          plan to accomplish the desired program objectives according to CRP and
          FOTG standards and specifications as a part of a conservation
          management system.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Present value
          </E>
           means the value of a stream of future payments discounted by 5
          percent in accordance with Office of Management and Budget Circular
          A-94 (revised January 2006), Discount Rates To Be Used in Evaluating
          Time-Distributed Costs and Benefits.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Private non-industrial forest land
          </E>
           means, for purposes of 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='12' psec='' tq='N'>
              1410.12
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , lands with existing tree cover that are owned by a private
          non-industrial forest landowner and which were damaged by hurricanes
          occurring in calendar year 2005.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Private non-industrial forest landowner
          </E>
           means, for purposes of 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='12' psec='' tq='N'>
              1410.12
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , an individual, group, association, corporation, Indian Tribe, other
          legal private entity, or State School Trust, owning non-industrial
          private forest land or who 
          <PRTPAGE P='467' />
          receives concurrence from the landowner for making the claim in lieu
          of the owner, and for practice implementation and who holds a lease on
          the land for a minimum of 10 years. Corporations whose stocks are
          publicly traded or owners or lessees principally engaged in the
          primary processing of raw wood products are excluded from this
          definition. An owner of land leased to a lessee shall also be excluded
          who should be excluded under the previous sentence.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Retired or retiring owner or operator
          </E>
           means an owner or operator of land enrolled in a CRP contract who has
          ended active labor in farming operations as a producer of agricultural
          crops or expects to do so within 5 years of the CRP contract
          modification.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Riparian buffer
          </E>
           means a strip or area of vegetation adjacent to a river or stream of
          sufficient width as determined by the Deputy Administrator to remove
          nutrients, sediment, organic matter, pesticides, and other pollutants
          from surface runoff and subsurface flow by deposition, absorption,
          plant uptake, and other processes, thereby reducing pollution and
          protecting surface water and subsurface water quality, which are also
          intended to provide shade to reduce water temperature for improved
          habitat for aquatic organisms and supply large woody debris for
          aquatic organisms and habitat for wildlife.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Socially disadvantaged farmer or ranche
          </E>
          r means a farmer or rancher who is a member of a socially
          disadvantaged group whose members have been subjected to racial or
          ethnic prejudice because of their identity as members of a group
          without regard to their individual qualities. Gender is not included
          as a covered group. Socially disadvantaged groups include the
          following and no others unless approved in writing by the Deputy
          Administrator:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             American Indians or Alaskan Natives,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Asians or Asian-Americans,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Blacks or African Americans,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Hispanics, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Native Hawaiians or other Pacific Islanders.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Soil loss tolerance (T)
          </E>
           means the maximum average annual erosion rate specified in the FOTG
          that will not adversely impact the long-term productivity of the soil.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State
          </E>
           means State agencies, departments, districts, county or city
          governments, municipalities or any other State or local government of
          the State.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State school trust land
          </E>
           means land owned by a State with the explicit purpose of supporting
          public schools.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State Technical Committee
          </E>
           means a committee established pursuant to 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='610' tq='N'>
              610 of this chapter
            </subref>
          </aref>
           to provide information, analysis, and recommendations to the U.S.
          Department of Agriculture.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State water quality priority areas
          </E>
           means any area so designated by the State committee, in consultation
          with the State Technical Committee, where agricultural pollutants
          contribute to water degradation or create the potential for failure to
          meet applicable water quality standards or the goals and requirements
          of Federal or State water quality laws. These areas may include areas
          designated under 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 319 of
          </aref>
           the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='33' sect='1329' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/33/1329.html'>
              33 U.S.C. 1329
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ) as water quality protection areas, sole source aquifers or other
          designated areas that result from agricultural nonpoint sources of
          pollution. Acreage in these areas may be determined eligible as
          conservation priority areas.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Technical assistance
          </E>
           means assistance in regard to determining the eligibility of land and
          practices, implementing and certifying practices, ensuring contract
          performance, and providing annual rental rate surveys. The technical
          assistance provided in connection with CRP to owners or operators, as
          approved by CCC, includes technical expertise, information, and tools
          necessary for the conservation of natural resources on land; technical
          services provided directly to farmers, ranchers, and other eligible
          entities, such as conservation planning, technical consultation, and
          assistance with design and implementation of conservation practices;
          and, technical infrastructure, including activities, processes, tools,
          and agency functions needed to support delivery of technical services,
          such as technical standards, resource inventories, training, data,
          technology, monitoring, and effects analyses.
          <PRTPAGE P='468' />
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Violation
          </E>
           means an act by the participant, either intentional or unintentional,
          that would cause the participant to no longer be eligible for all or a
          portion of cost-share, incentive, or annual contract payments.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Water Bank Program (WBP)
          </E>
           means the program authorized by the Water Bank Act of 1970, as
          amended, in which eligible persons enter into 10-year agreements to
          preserve, restore, and improve wetlands.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Water cover
          </E>
           means flooding of land by water either to develop or restore shallow
          water areas for wildlife or wetlands, or as a result of a natural
          disaster.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Wellhead protection area
          </E>
           means the area designated by EPA or the appropriate State agency with
          an Environmental Protection Agency approved Wellhead Protection
          Program for water being drawn for public use, as defined for public
          use by the Safe Drinking Water Act, as amended.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Wetland
          </E>
           means land defined as wetland in accordance with provisions of 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='12' tq='N'>
              12 of this title
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Wetlands farmed under natural conditions
          </E>
           means land defined as wetlands farmed under natural conditions in
          accordance with provisions of 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='12' tq='N'>
              12 of this title
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Wetlands Reserve Program (WRP)
          </E>
           means the program authorized by 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='1467' tq='N'>
              1467 of this chapter
            </subref>
          </aref>
           in which eligible persons enter into long-term agreements to restore
          and protect wetlands.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            68 FR 24835
          </aref>
          , May 8, 2003, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            69 FR 26763
          </aref>
          , May 14, 2004; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            71 FR 31917
          </aref>
          , Jun 2, 2006; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            74 FR 30911
          </aref>
          , June 29, 2009; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 27168
          </aref>
          , May 14, 2010; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 44071
          </aref>
          , July 28, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12282'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1410:-:1410.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1410.3
      </num>
      <head>
        General description.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          68 FR 24835
        </aref>
        , May 8, 2003, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          74 FR 30912
        </aref>
        , June 29, 2009]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              1410.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General description.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Under the CRP, CCC will enter into contracts with eligible
            participants to convert eligible land to a conserving use during the
            contract period in return for financial and technical assistance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A participant must obtain and adhere to a conservation plan
            prepared in accordance with CRP guidelines, as established and
            determined by CCC. A conservation plan for eligible acreage must be
            obtained by a participant and must be approved by the conservation
            district in which the lands are located unless the conservation
            district declines to review the plan, in which case the provider of
            technical assistance may take such further action as is needed to
            account for lack of such review.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The objectives of the CRP are to cost-effectively reduce water and
            wind erosion, protect the Nation&apos;s long-term capability to
            produce food and fiber, reduce sedimentation, improve water quality,
            create and enhance wildlife habitat, and other objectives including,
            as appropriate, addressing issues raised by State, regional, and
            national conservation initiatives and encouraging more permanent
            conservation practices, such as, but not limited to, tree planting.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as otherwise provided, a participant may, in addition to any
            payments under this part, receive cost-share assistance, rental or
            easement payments, tax benefits, or other payments from a State or a
            private organization in return for enrolling lands in CRP. However,
            a participant may not receive or retain CRP cost-share assistance if
            other Federal cost-share assistance is provided for such acreage
            under any law, as determined by the Deputy Administrator. Further,
            under no circumstances may the cost-share payments received under
            this part, or otherwise, exceed the cost of the practice, as
            determined by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            68 FR 24835
          </aref>
          , May 8, 2003, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            74 FR 30912
          </aref>
          , June 29, 2009]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12283'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1410:-:1410.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1410.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Maximum county acreage.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          68 FR 24835
        </aref>
        , May 8, 2003, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 44071
        </aref>
        , July 28, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              1410.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Maximum county acreage.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as provided in paragraph (b) of this section, the maximum
            acreage that may be placed in the CRP and the WRP may not exceed 25
            percent of the total cropland in the county; further, no more than
            10 percent of the cropland may be subject, in the aggregate, to a
            CRP or WRP easement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The restrictions in paragraph (a) of this section may be waived by
            CCC as follows:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If CCC determines that such action would not adversely affect the
            local economy of the county and that operators in the county are
            having difficulties complying with conservation plans implemented
            under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='12' tq='N'>
                12 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Cropland in a county enrolled under continuous signup provisions as
            
            <PRTPAGE P='469' />
            specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='30' psec='' tq='N'>
                1410.30
              </subref>
            </aref>
             or 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='50' psec='' tq='N'>
                1410.50
              </subref>
            </aref>
             may be excluded from the restrictions in paragraph (a) of this
            section, as determined by CCC, provided that the county government
            concurs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             These restrictions on participation shall be in addition to any
            other restriction imposed by law.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            68 FR 24835
          </aref>
          , May 8, 2003, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 44071
          </aref>
          , July 28, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12284'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1410:-:1410.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1410.5
      </num>
      <head>
        Eligible persons.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          68 FR 24835
        </aref>
        , May 8, 2003, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 27169
        </aref>
        , May 14, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              1410.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Eligible persons.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In order to be eligible to enter into a CRP contract in accordance
            with this part, a person must be an owner, operator, or tenant of
            eligible land and:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If an operator of eligible land, seeking to participate without the
            owner, must have operated such land for at least 12 months prior to
            the close of the applicable signup period and must provide
            satisfactory evidence that such operator will be in control of such
            eligible land for the full term of the CRP contract period;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If an owner of eligible land, must have owned such land for at
            least 12 months prior to the close of the applicable signup period,
            unless:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The new owner acquired such land by will or succession as a result
            of the death of the previous owner;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The only ownership change in the 12-month period occurred due to
            foreclosure on the land and the owner of the land, immediately
            before the foreclosure, exercises a timely right of redemption from
            the mortgage holder in accordance with State law; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             As determined by the Deputy Administrator, the circumstances of the
            acquisition are such that present adequate assurance that the new
            owner of such eligible land did not acquire such land for the
            purpose of placing it in the CRP; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a tenant, the tenant is a participant with an eligible owner or
            operator.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notwithstanding paragraph (a) of this section, under continuous
            signup provisions authorized by 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='30' psec='' tq='N'>
                1410.30
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , an otherwise eligible person must have owned or operated, as
            appropriate, the eligible land for at least 12 months before
            submitting the offer.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The provisions of this section do not apply to beginning or
            socially disadvantaged farmers or ranchers who are eligible
            participants in the Transition Incentives Program as specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='64' psec='' tq='N'>
                1410.64
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            68 FR 24835
          </aref>
          , May 8, 2003, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 27169
          </aref>
          , May 14, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12285'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1410:-:1410.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1410.6
      </num>
      <head>
        Eligible land.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          68 FR 24835
        </aref>
        , May 8, 2003, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          69 FR 26763
        </aref>
        , May 14, 2004; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 44071
        </aref>
        , July 28, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              1410.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Eligible land.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In order to be eligible to be placed in the CRP, land must be one
            of the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Cropland that is subject to a conservation plan and has been
            annually planted or considered planted, as defined in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
                1410.2
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , to an agricultural commodity in 4 of the 6 crop years from 2002
            through 2007, as determined by the CCC, provided further that field
            margins that are incidental to the planting of crops may also be
            considered qualifying cropland to the extent determined appropriate
            by the CCC; and is physically and legally capable of being planted
            in a normal manner to an agricultural commodity, as determined by
            the CCC; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Marginal pasture land, as determined by the CCC, that:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is determined to be suitable for use as a riparian buffer or is
            made eligible in a CREP for similar water quality purposes as
            determined by the CCC. A field or portion of a field of marginal
            pasture land may be considered to be suitable for use as a riparian
            buffer only if, as determined by CCC, it:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_i_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is located adjacent to permanent stream corridors excluding
            corridors that are considered gullies or sod waterways; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_i_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is capable, when permanent grass, forbs, shrubs, or trees, are
            grown, or when planted with appropriate vegetation for the area,
            including vegetation suitable for wetland restoration or wildlife
            habitat, as determined appropriate by the CCC, of substantially
            reducing sediment and/or nutrient runoff that otherwise would be
            delivered to the adjacent stream or waterbody or for water quality
            purposes; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             [Reserved]
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Must be acreage enrolled in the CRP during the final year of the
            CRP contract provided the scheduled expiration date of the current
            CRP contract is before the effective date the new CRP contract, as
            determined by the CCC.
            <PRTPAGE P='470' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land qualifying under paragraphs (a)(1) or (a) (2) of this section
            must also meet one of the following criteria, to be eligible for a
            contract:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be a field or portion of a field determined to be suitable for use,
            as determined by the CCC, as a permanent wildlife habitat, filter
            strip, riparian buffer, contour grass strip, grass waterway, field
            windbreak, shelterbelt, living snowfence, other uses as determined
            by the CCC, land devoted to vegetation on salinity producing areas,
            including any applicable recharge area, or any area determined
            eligible for CRP based on wetland or wellhead protection area
            criteria. A field or portion of a field may be considered to be
            suitable for use as a filter strip or riparian buffer only if it, as
            determined by CCC:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is located adjacent to a stream, other waterbody of a permanent
            nature (such as a lake, pond, or sinkhole), or wetland; excluding
            such areas as gullies or sod waterways; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is capable, when permanent grass, forbs, shrubs or trees are grown,
            of substantially reducing sediment or nutrient runoff that otherwise
            would be delivered to the adjacent stream or waterbody;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be a field that has evidence of scour erosion caused by out-of-bank
            flows of water, as determined by CCC:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In addition, such land must:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_ii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be expected to flood a minimum of once every 10 years; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_ii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Have evidence of scour erosion as a result of such flooding.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To the extent practicable, be the actual affected cropland areas of
            a field; however, the entire cropland area of an eligible field may
            be enrolled if:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_ii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The size of the field is 9 acres or less; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_ii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             More than one third of the cropland in the field is land that lies
            between the water source and the inland limit of the scour erosion.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Or, if the full field is not eligible for enrollment under this
            paragraph, be the cropland between the waterbody and inland limit of
            the scour erosion together with, as determined by the CCC,
            additional areas that would otherwise be unmanageable and would be
            isolated by the eligible areas.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_2_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be planted to an appropriate tree species according to the FOTG,
            unless tree planting is determined to be inappropriate by NRCS, in
            consultation with the Forest Service, in which case the eligible
            cropland shall be devoted to another acceptable permanent vegetative
            cover in accordance with the FOTG;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be cropland that would facilitate a net savings in groundwater or
            surface water of the agricultural operation of the producer as
            determined by CCC;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be cropland in a portion of a field not enrolled in the CRP, if
            more than 50 percent of the remainder of the field is enrolled as a
            buffer practice, if the portion of the field not enrolled in the CRP
            will be enrolled as part of the buffer practice, and if as
            determined by CCC:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_4_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The remainder of the field is infeasible to farm; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_4_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The remainder of the field is enrolled at an annual payment rate
            not to exceed the maximum annual calculated soil rental rate;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be contributing to the degradation of water quality or posing an
            on-site or off-site environmental threat to water quality if such
            land remains in production;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be devoted to certain covers, as determined by the CCC, that are
            established and maintained according to the FOTG, provided such
            acreage is not required to be maintained as such under any life-span
            obligations, as determined by the CCC;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be non-irrigated or irrigated cropland that produces or serves as
            the recharge area, as determined by the CCC, for saline seeps, or
            acreage that is functionally related to such saline seeps, or where
            a rising water table contributes to increased levels of salinity at
            or near the ground surface;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Have an EI of greater than or equal to 8 calculated by using the
            weighted average of the EI&apos;s of soil map units within the
            field;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be within a public wellhead protection area;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be within a designated conservation priority area;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_11'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (11)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be designated as a cropped wetland and appropriate associated
            acreage, as determined by the CCC;
            <PRTPAGE P='471' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_12'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (12)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be cropland that, as determined by the CCC, is associated with
            noncropped wetlands and would provide significant environmental
            benefits; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_13'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (13)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notwithstanding paragraph (a)(1) of this section, be cropland
            devoted to a perennial crop, as determined by CCC; such cropland
            will only be eligible for continuous signup practices authorized by 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='30' psec='' tq='N'>
                1410.30
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and CREP practices authorized by 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='50' psec='#b' tq='N'>
                1410.50(b)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notwithstanding paragraphs (a) and (b) of this section, land shall
            be ineligible for enrollment if, as determined by the CCC, land is:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Federally-owned land unless the applicant has a lease for the
            contract period;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land on which the use of the land is restricted through deed or
            other restriction prior to enrollment in CRP prohibiting the
            production of agricultural commodities during any part of the
            contract term except for eligible land under paragraph (a)(2) and
            (3) of this section, as determined by CCC; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land already enrolled in the CRP unless authorized by 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='6' psec='#a_3' tq='N'>
                1410.6(a)(3)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , as determined by the CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            68 FR 24835
          </aref>
          , May 8, 2003, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            69 FR 26763
          </aref>
          , May 14, 2004; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 44071
          </aref>
          , July 28, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12286'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1410:-:1410.7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1410.7
      </num>
      <head>
        Duration of contracts.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              1410.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Duration of contracts.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as provided in paragraphs (b) or (c) of this section,
            contracts under this part shall be for a term of 10 years.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the case of land devoted to riparian buffers, filter strips,
            restoration of wetlands, hardwood trees, shelterbelts, windbreaks,
            wildlife corridors, or other practices deemed appropriate by CCC
            under the original terms of a contract subject to this part or for
            land devoted to eligible practices under a contract modified under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
                1410.10
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , the participant may specify the duration of the contract between
            10 years and 15 years in length.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All contracts shall expire on September 30 of the appropriate year.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12287'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1410:-:1410.8
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1410.8
      </num>
      <head>
        Conservation priority areas.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              1410.8
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Conservation priority areas.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC may designate National conservation priority areas according to
            paragraph (c) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subject to CCC review, State FSA committees, in consultation with
            NRCS and the State Technical Committee, may designate conservation
            priority areas within guidelines established by the Deputy
            Administrator. Such designation must clearly define conservation and
            environmental objectives and provide analysis of how CRP can
            cost-effectively address such objectives. Generally, the total
            acreage of all conservation priority areas, in aggregate, shall not
            total more than 33 percent of the cropland in a State unless there
            are identified and documented extraordinary environmental needs, as
            determined by the Deputy Administrator.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             As determined by the Deputy Administrator, a region shall be
            eligible for designation as a priority area only if the region has
            actual significant adverse water quality, air quality, wildlife
            habitat, or other natural resource impacts related to activities of
            agricultural production, or if the designation helps agricultural
            producers to comply with Federal and State environmental laws.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Conservation priority area designations shall expire after 5 years
            unless re-designated, except they may be withdrawn:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             At the request of the appropriate State water quality agency; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             By the Deputy Administrator.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In those areas designated as conservation priority areas, under
            this section, cropland is considered eligible for enrollment
            according 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='6' psec='#b_10' tq='N'>
                1410.6(b)(10)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             based on identified environmental concerns. These concerns may
            include water quality, such as assisting agricultural producers to
            comply with nonpoint source pollution requirements, air quality, or
            wildlife habitat (especially for threatened and endangered species
            or those species that may become threatened and endangered), as
            determined by the Deputy Administrator.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12288'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1410:-:1410.9
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1410.9
      </num>
      <head>
        Conversion to trees.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
              1410.9
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Conversion to trees.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          An owner or operator who has entered into a CRP contract prior to
          November 28, 1990, may elect to convert areas of highly erodible
          cropland, subject to such contract, that is devoted to permanent
          vegetative cover, from such cover to hardwood trees, (including alley
          cropping and riparian buffers 
          <PRTPAGE P='472' />
          of hardwood trees, where permitted by CCC), windbreaks, shelterbelts,
          or wildlife corridors.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For any contract modified under this section, the participant may
            elect to extend such contract in accordance with the provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='7' psec='#b' tq='N'>
                1410.7(b)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For any contract modified under this section in which such areas
            are converted to windbreaks, shelterbelts, or wildlife corridors,
            the owner must agree to maintain such plantings for a time period
            established by the Deputy Administrator at the time of the contract
            modification.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC shall, as it determines appropriate, pay up to 50 percent of
            the eligible cost of establishing new conservation measures
            authorized under this section, except that the total cost-share paid
            under such contract, including cost-share assistance paid when the
            original cover was established, may not exceed the amount by which
            CCC would have paid had such land been originally devoted to such
            new conservation measures.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For any contract modified under this section, the participant must
            participate in the Forest Stewardship Program (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='16' sect='2103a' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/2103a.html'>
                16 U.S.C. 2103a
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12289'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1410:-:1410.10
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1410.10
      </num>
      <head>
        Restoration of wetlands.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
              1410.10
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Restoration of wetlands.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An owner or operator who entered into a CRP contract on land that
            is suitable for restoration to wetlands or that was restored to
            wetlands while under such contract, may, if approved by CCC, subject
            to any restrictions as may be imposed by law, apply to transfer such
            eligible acres subject to such contract that are devoted to an
            approved cover from the CRP to the WRP. Transferred acreage shall be
            terminated from the CRP effective the day a WRP easement is filed.
            Participants will receive a prorated CRP annual payment for that
            part of the year the acreage was enrolled in the CRP according to 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='42' psec='' tq='N'>
                1410.42
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . Refunds of cost-share payments or applicable incentive payments
            need not be refunded unless specified by the Deputy Administrator.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An owner or operator who has enrolled acreage in the CRP may, as
            determined and approved by CCC, restore suitable acres to wetlands
            with cost-share assistance provided that Federal cost-share
            assistance has not been received for wetland restoration on the same
            land. In addition to the cost-share limitation in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='41' psec='' tq='N'>
                1410.41
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , an additional one-time financial incentive may be provided to
            encourage restoration of the hydrology of the site.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12290'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1410:-:1410.11
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1410.11
      </num>
      <head>
        Farmable Wetlands Program.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          74 FR 30912
        </aref>
        , June 29, 2009]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
              1410.11
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Farmable Wetlands Program.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In addition to other allowable enrollments, land may be enrolled in
            this program through the Farmable Wetlands Program (FWP) within the
            overall Conservation Reserve Program provided for in this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             As determined by CCC, eligible owners and operators may enroll land
            in FWP provided that the land:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is a wetland, including a converted wetland, as determined by CCC,
            that has been planted or considered planted to an agricultural
            commodity, as defined in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
                1410.2
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , in 3 of the 10 most recent crop years and that does not exceed the
            size limitations of this section;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is enrolled to be a constructed wetland that is to be developed to
            receive flow from a row crop agriculture drainage system and is
            designed to provide nitrogen removal in addition to other wetland
            functions and that does not exceed the size limitations of this
            section;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Was a commercial pond-raised aquaculture facility in any year
            during the period of calendar years 2002 through 2007; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Was cropped, after January 1, 1990, and before December 31, 2002,
            at least 3 of 10 crop years, was subject to the natural overflow of
            a prairie wetland, and does not exceed the size limitations of this
            section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In addition, land may be enrolled in FWP if the land is buffer
            acreage that provides protection for and is contiguous to land
            otherwise eligible under paragraphs (b)(1), (b)(2), or (b)(4) of
            this section, subject to other provisions of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Total enrollment in CRP under this section may not exceed 1 million
            acres. In addition, the maximum size of a land enrolled under this
            section may not exceed, as determined by CCC:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             40 contiguous acres for land made eligible by paragraph (b)(1) of
            this section;
            <PRTPAGE P='473' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             40 contiguous acres for land made eligible by paragraph (b)(2) of
            this section;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             20 contiguous acres for land made eligible by paragraph (b)(4) of
            this section; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A suitable buffer as determined by the Deputy Administrator for
            lands added under paragraph (c) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All participants subject to a CRP contract under this section must
            agree to establish and maintain, as appropriate, the practice
            described in paragraph (b) of this section to the maximum extent
            possible, as determined by CCC, in accordance with NRCS FOTG
            including, as appropriate, restoring the hydrology of the wetland
            and establishing vegetative cover (which may include emerging
            vegetation in water and bottomland hardwoods, cypress, and other
            appropriate tree species in shallow water areas), as determined by
            CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Offers for contracts under this section must be submitted under
            continuous signup provisions as authorized in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='30' psec='' tq='N'>
                1410.30
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as otherwise determined by CCC, all other requirements of
            this part apply to enrollments under this section, and CCC may add
            such other requirements or conditions as it deems necessary. Such
            additional conditions include, but are not limited to, payment
            limitations, adjusted gross income limitations, and limitations on
            the amount of acreage that can be enrolled in any one county.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            74 FR 30912
          </aref>
          , June 29, 2009]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12291'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1410:-:1410.12
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1410.12
      </num>
      <head>
        Emergency Forestry Program.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          71 FR 31917
        </aref>
        , Jun 2, 2006]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='12' psec='' tq='N'>
              1410.12
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Emergency Forestry Program.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In addition to other allowable enrollments, certain non-industrial
            private forest land located in Presidential- or Secretarial-declared
            primary disaster counties that suffered damage from hurricanes in
            calendar year 2005 may be enrolled through the Emergency Forestry
            Conservation Reserve Program (EFCRP) provided for in this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Owners and/or operators may enroll non-industrial private forest
            land, as defined in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
                1410.2
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , in the CRP provided that the private non-industrial forest land:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Has merchantable timber (timber on land on which the average tree
            has a trunk diameter of at least six inches measured at a point no
            less than four and one-half feet above the ground); and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Has experienced a loss of 35 percent or more of merchantable timber
            in a 2005 calendar year hurricane-affected county due to 2005
            hurricanes.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
                1410.4
              </subref>
            </aref>
             do not apply to this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any overall acreage enrollment limit imposed on CRP shall not apply
            to acreage enrolled under this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All participants subject to a CRP contract entered into pursuant to
            this section must agree:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To restore the land, through site preparation and planting of, to
            the maximum extent practicable, native species or similar species as
            existing prior to hurricane damages as may be specified in the
            contract, and comply with other requirements as may be specified in
            the contract;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To establish temporary vegetative cover; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             That the contract term shall be for a period of 10 years, during
            which time standing timber may not be harvested from the enrolled
            land except as may be approved by CCC in the conservation plan as
            part of the normal maintenance of the forest land.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Offers for contracts under this section shall be submitted under
            continuous signup provisions as authorized in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='30' psec='' tq='N'>
                1410.30
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In evaluating contract offers to which this section applies,
            different factors, as determined by CCC, may be considered for
            priority purposes. These include but are not limited to soil erosion
            prevention, water quality improvement, wildlife habitat restoration,
            and mitigation of economic loss.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In return for a contract entered into under this paragraph, a
            participant may opt for:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Annual rental payments authorized by 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='42' psec='' tq='N'>
                1410.42
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , except that the payment rate shall be equal to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The average rental rate for CRP contracts in the county in which
            the land is actually located; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the case where no CRP contracts are enrolled in a county, the
            average rental rate will be the CRP rate 
            <PRTPAGE P='474' />
            applicable to a nearby similarly-situated county.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In lieu of the annual payments provided for in paragraph (h)(1) of
            this section, lump sum payment equal to the present value of the
            total amount of annual rental payments that would otherwise be paid
            under paragraph (h)(1) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Cost-share assistance authorized under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='40' psec='' tq='N'>
                1410.40
              </subref>
            </aref>
             may be reduced by the value of salvaged timber or timber products
            which are removed to prepare the site for replanting.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='7' psec='#c' tq='N'>
                1410.7(c)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , which concern enrollment limits, do not apply to contracts to
            which this section applies.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To avoid duplicate payments, participants under this section are
            not eligible to receive EFCRP funding for land on which the
            participant has or will receive funding under any other program that
            covers the same expenses.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='l'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (l)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All other requirements of this part shall apply to enrollments
            under this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            71 FR 31917
          </aref>
          , Jun 2, 2006]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12292'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1410:-:1410.13-1410.19
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1410.13-1410.19
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='13-1410' psec='' tq='N'>
              1410.13-1410
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .19
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12293'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1410:-:1410.20
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1410.20
      </num>
      <head>
        Obligations of participant.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='20' psec='' tq='N'>
              1410.20
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Obligations of participant.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All participants subject to a CRP contract must agree to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Carry out the terms and conditions of such CRP contract;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Implement the conservation plan, which is part of such contract, in
            accordance with the schedule of dates included in such conservation
            plan unless the Deputy Administrator determines that the participant
            cannot fully implement the conservation plan for reasons beyond the
            participant&apos;s control, and CCC agrees to a modified plan.
            However, a contract will not be terminated for failure to establish
            an approved vegetative or water cover on the land if, as determined
            by the Deputy Administrator:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The failure to plant or establish such cover was due to excessive
            rainfall, flooding, or drought;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The land subject to the contract on which the participant could
            practicably plant or establish to such cover is planted or
            established to such cover; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The land on which the participant was unable to plant or establish
            such cover is planted or established to such cover after the wet or
            drought conditions that prevented the planting or establishment
            subside;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Establish temporary vegetative cover either when required by the
            conservation plan or, as determined by the Deputy Administrator, if
            the permanent vegetative cover cannot be timely established;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Comply with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='12' tq='N'>
                12 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Not allow grazing, harvesting, or other commercial use of any crop
            from the cropland subject to such contract except for those periods
            of time approved in accordance with instructions issued by the
            Deputy Administrator;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Establish and maintain the required vegetative or water cover and
            the required practices on the land subject to such contract and take
            other actions that may be required by CCC to achieve the desired
            environmental benefits and to maintain the productive capability of
            the soil throughout the contract period;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Comply with noxious weed laws of the applicable State or local
            jurisdiction on such land;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Control on land subject to such contract all weeds, insects, pests
            and other undesirable species to the extent necessary to ensure that
            the establishment and maintenance of the approved cover as necessary
            or may be specified in the CRP conservation plan and to avoid an
            adverse impact on surrounding land, taking into consideration water
            quality, wildlife, and other needs, as determined by the Deputy
            Administrator; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be jointly and severally responsible, if the participant has a
            share of the payment greater than zero, with the other contract
            participants in compliance with the provisions of such contract and
            the provisions of this part and for any refunds or payment
            adjustments that may be required for violations of any of the terms
            and conditions of the CRP contract and this part.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12294'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1410:-:1410.21
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1410.21
      </num>
      <head>
        Obligations of the Commodity Credit Corporation.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='21' psec='' tq='N'>
              1410.21
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Obligations of the Commodity Credit Corporation.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          CCC shall, subject to the availability of funds:
          <PRTPAGE P='475' />
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Share up to 50 percent of the cost with participants of
            establishing eligible practices specified in the conservation plan
            at the levels and rates of cost-sharing determined in accordance
            with the provisions of this part; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Pay to the participant for a period of years not in excess of the
            contract period an annual rental payment, including applicable
            incentive payments, in such amounts as may be specified in the CRP
            contract.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12295'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1410:-:1410.22
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1410.22
      </num>
      <head>
        CRP conservation plan.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          68 FR 24835
        </aref>
        , May 8, 2003, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          74 FR 30912
        </aref>
        , June 29, 2009]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='22' psec='' tq='N'>
              1410.22
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          CRP conservation plan.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The producer shall obtain a CRP conservation plan that complies
            with CCC guidelines and is approved by the conservation district for
            the land to be entered in the CRP. If the conservation district
            declines to review the CRP conservation plan, or disapproves the
            conservation plan, such approval may be waived by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The practices and management activities included in the CRP
            conservation plan and agreed to by the participant must
            cost-effectively reduce erosion necessary to maintain the productive
            capability of the soil, improve water quality, protect wildlife or
            wetlands, protect a public well head, or achieve other environmental
            benefits as applicable. The producer must undertake management
            activities on the land as needed throughout the term of the CRP
            contract to implement the conservation plan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If applicable, a tree planting plan shall be developed and included
            in the CRP conservation plan. Such tree planting plan may allow up
            to 3 years to complete plantings if 10 or more acres of hardwood
            trees are to be established.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If applicable, the CRP conservation plan shall address the goals
            included in the conservation priority area designation authorized
            under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
                1410.8
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All CRP conservation plans and revisions of such plans shall be
            subject to the approval of CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Mid-cover management shall be conducted according to an approved
            conservation plan as part of the CRP contractual obligation such as
            light discing and burning as determined by the Deputy Administrator.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            68 FR 24835
          </aref>
          , May 8, 2003, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            74 FR 30912
          </aref>
          , June 29, 2009]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12296'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1410:-:1410.23
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1410.23
      </num>
      <head>
        Eligible practices.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='23' psec='' tq='N'>
              1410.23
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Eligible practices.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Eligible practices are those practices specified in the
            conservation plan that meet all standards needed to
            cost-effectively:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Establish permanent vegetative or water cover, including introduced
            or native species of grasses and legumes, forest trees, and
            permanent wildlife habitat;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Meet other environmental benefits, as applicable, for the contract
            period; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Accomplish other purposes of the program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Water cover is eligible cover for purposes of paragraph (a) of this
            section only if approved by the Deputy Administrator for purposes
            such as the enhancement of wildlife or the improvement of water
            quality. Such water cover shall not include ponds for the purpose of
            watering livestock, irrigating crops, or raising aquiculture for
            commercial purposes.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12297'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1410:-:1410.24-1410.29
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1410.24-1410.29
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='24-1410' psec='' tq='N'>
              1410.24-1410
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .29
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12298'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1410:-:1410.30
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1410.30
      </num>
      <head>
        Signup.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='30' psec='' tq='N'>
              1410.30
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Signup.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Offers for contracts shall be submitted only during signup periods as
          announced periodically by the Deputy Administrator, except that CCC
          may hold a continuous signup for land to be devoted to particular
          uses, as CCC deems necessary. Generally, continuous signup is limited
          to those offers that would otherwise rank highly under 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='31' psec='#b' tq='N'>
              1410.31(b)
            </subref>
          </aref>
           and may include high priority practices such as filter strips,
          riparian buffers, shelterbelts, field windbreaks, and living snow
          fences, grass waterways, shallow water areas for wildlife,
          salt-tolerant vegetation, and practices to benefit certain approved
          public wellhead protection areas.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12299'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1410:-:1410.31
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1410.31
      </num>
      <head>
        Acceptability of offers.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          68 FR 24835
        </aref>
        , May 8, 2003, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 44071
        </aref>
        , July 28, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='31' psec='' tq='N'>
              1410.31
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Acceptability of offers.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as provided in paragraph (c) of this section, producers may
            submit offers for the amounts they are willing to accept as rental
            payments to 
            <PRTPAGE P='476' />
            enroll their acreage in the CRP. The offers may, to the extent
            practicable, be evaluated on a competitive basis in which the offers
            selected will be those where the greatest environmental benefits
            relative to cost are generated, and provided that the offer is not
            in excess of the maximum acceptable payment rate established by the
            Deputy Administrator for the for the area offered. Acceptance or
            rejection of any offer, however, shall be in the sole discretion of
            the CCC and offers may be rejected for any reason as determined
            needed to accomplish the goals of the program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In evaluating contract offers, different factors, as determined by
            CCC, may be considered from time to time for priority purposes to
            accomplish the goals of the program. Such factors may include, but
            are not limited to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Soil erosion;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Water quality (both surface and ground water);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Wildlife benefits;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Soil productivity;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Likelihood that enrolled land will remain in non-agriculture use
            beyond the contract period, considering, for example, tree planting,
            permanent wildlife habitat, or commitments by a participant to a
            State or other entity to extend the conservation plan;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Air quality; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Cost of enrolling acreage in the program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notwithstanding paragraph (b) of this section, when all other
            appropriate factors are equivalent, CCC may give preference to
            offers from residents of the county or contiguous county where the
            offered land is located.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Acreage determined eligible for continuous signup, as provided in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='30' psec='' tq='N'>
                1410.30
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , may be automatically accepted in the program if the:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land is eligible under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
                1410.6
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , as determined by the Deputy Administrator;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A producer is eligible under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
                1410.5
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A producer accepts either the maximum payment rate CCC is willing
            to offer to enroll the acreage in the program or a lesser rate.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            68 FR 24835
          </aref>
          , May 8, 2003, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 44071
          </aref>
          , July 28, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12300'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1410:-:1410.32
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1410.32
      </num>
      <head>
        CRP contract.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='32' psec='' tq='N'>
              1410.32
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          CRP contract.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In order to enroll land in the CRP, the participant must enter into
            a contract with CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The CRP contract is comprised of:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The terms and conditions for participation in the CRP;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The CRP conservation plan; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any other materials or agreements determined necessary by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In order to enter into a CRP contract, the producer must submit an
            offer to participate as provided in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='30' psec='' tq='N'>
                1410.30
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An offer to enroll land in the CRP shall be irrevocable for such
            period as is determined and announced by CCC. The producer shall be
            liable to CCC for liquidated damages if the applicant revokes an
            offer during the period in which the offer is irrevocable as
            determined by the Deputy Administrator. CCC may waive payment of
            such liquidated damages if CCC determines that the assessment of
            such damages, in a particular case, is not in the best interest of
            CCC and the program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The CRP contract must, within the dates established by CCC, be
            signed by:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The producer; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The owners of the cropland to be placed in the CRP and other
            eligible participants, if applicable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Deputy Administrator is authorized to approve CRP contracts on
            behalf of CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CRP contracts may be terminated by CCC before the full term of the
            contract has expired if:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The owner loses control of or transfers all or part of the acreage
            under contract and the new owner does not wish to continue the
            contract;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The participant voluntarily requests in writing to terminate the
            contract and obtains the approval of CCC according to terms and
            conditions as determined by CCC;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The participant is not in compliance with the terms and conditions
            of the contract;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Acreage is enrolled in another Federal, State or local conservation
            program;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The CRP practice fails or is not established after a certain time
            period, as determined by the Deputy Administrator, and the cost of
            restoring the 
            <PRTPAGE P='477' />
            practice outweighs the benefits received from the restoration;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The CRP contract was approved based on erroneous eligibility
            determinations; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC determines that such a termination is needed in the public
            interest.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Contracts for land enrolled in CRP before January 1, 1995, that
            have been continuously in effect may be unilaterally terminated by
            all CRP participants on a contract except for contract acreage:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Located within a certain distance determined appropriate by the
            applicable FOTG of a perennial stream, or other permanent waterbody
            to reduce pollution and to protect surface and subsurface water
            quality;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             On which a CRP easement is filed;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             That is considered to be a wetland by USDA according to 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='12' tq='N'>
                12 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Located within a wellhead protection area;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_1_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             That is subject to frequent flooding, as determined by the Deputy
            Administrator;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_1_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             That may be required to serve as a wetland buffer according to the
            FOTG to protect the functions and values of a wetland; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_1_vii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             On which there exist one or more of the following practices,
            installed or developed as a result of participation in the CRP or as
            otherwise required by the conservation plan:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='g_1_vii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Grass waterways;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='g_1_vii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Filter strips;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='g_1_vii_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Shallow water areas for wildlife;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='g_1_vii_D'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (D)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bottom land timber established on wetlands;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='g_1_vii_E'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (E)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Field windbreaks; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='g_1_vii_F'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (F)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Shelterbelts.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             With respect to terminations under this paragraph:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any land for which an early termination is sought by the
            participant must have an EI of 15 or less;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The termination shall become effective 60 days from the date the
            participant submits notification to CCC of the participant&apos;s
            desire to terminate the contract;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Acreage terminated under this provision is eligible to be
            re-offered for CRP during future signup periods, provided that the
            acreage otherwise meets the current eligibility criteria; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_2_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Participants must meet conservation compliance requirements of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='12' tq='N'>
                12 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
             to the extent applicable to other land.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as allowed and approved by CCC where the new owner of land
            enrolled in CRP is a Federal agency that agrees to abide by the
            terms and conditions of the terminated contract, the participant in
            a contract that has been terminated must refund all or part of the
            payments made with respect to the contract plus interest thereon, as
            determined by CCC, and shall pay liquidated damages as provided for
            in the contract. CCC may permit the amount to be repaid to be
            reduced to the extent that such a reduction will not impair the
            purposes of the program. Further, a refund of all payments need not
            be required from a participant who is otherwise in full compliance
            with the CRP contract when the land is purchased by or for the
            United States, as determined by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12301'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1410:-:1410.33
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1410.33
      </num>
      <head>
        Contract modifications.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          68 FR 24835
        </aref>
        , May 8, 2003, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 27169
        </aref>
        , May 14, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='33' psec='' tq='N'>
              1410.33
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Contract modifications.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             As agreed between CCC and the participant, a CRP contract may be
            modified in order to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Decrease acreage in the CRP;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Permit the production of an agricultural commodity under
            extraordinary circumstances during a crop year on all or part of the
            land subject to the CRP contract as determined by the Deputy
            Administrator;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Facilitate the practical administration of the CRP;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             During the final year of the CRP contract&apos;s term, facilitate a
            transition of land subject to the contract from a retired or
            retiring owner or operator to a beginning or socially-disadvantaged
            farmer or rancher for the purpose of returning some or all of the
            land into production using sustainable grazing or crop production
            methods; provided that for this purpose “sustainable grazing and
            crop production methods” will be considered, as determined by the
            Deputy Administrator, to be methods that would be designed as part
            of an overall plan defined on an ecosystem level to be useful in the
            creation of integrated systems of plant and animal production
            practices that have a site specific application that would:
            <PRTPAGE P='478' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_4_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Meet human needs for food and fiber;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_4_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Enhance the environment and the natural resource base;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_4_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Use nonrenewable resources efficiently; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_4_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Sustain the economic viability of farming operation; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Accomplish the goals and objectives of the CRP, as determined by
            the Deputy Administrator.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC may modify CRP contracts to add, delete, or substitute
            practices when, as determined by the Deputy Administrator:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The installed practice failed to adequately provide for the desired
            environmental benefit through no fault of the participant; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The installed measure deteriorated because of conditions beyond the
            control of the participant; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Another practice will achieve at least the same level of
            environmental benefit.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Offers to extend contracts may be made as allowed by law.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC may terminate a CRP contract if the participant agrees to such
            termination and CCC determines such termination to be in the public
            interest.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            68 FR 24835
          </aref>
          , May 8, 2003, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 27169
          </aref>
          , May 14, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12302'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1410:-:1410.34-1410.39
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1410.34-1410.39
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='34-1410' psec='' tq='N'>
              1410.34-1410
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .39
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12303'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1410:-:1410.40
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1410.40
      </num>
      <head>
        Cost-share payments.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          68 FR 24835
        </aref>
        , May 8, 2003, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          74 FR 30912
        </aref>
        , June 29, 2009]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='40' psec='' tq='N'>
              1410.40
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Cost-share payments.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Cost-share payments shall be made available upon a determination by
            CCC that an eligible practice, or an identifiable unit thereof, has
            been established in compliance with the appropriate standards and
            specifications.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as otherwise provided for in this part, cost-share payments
            may be made only for the cost-effective establishment or
            installation of an eligible practice, as determined by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as provided in paragraph (d) of this section, cost-share
            payments shall not be made to the same owner or operator on the same
            acreage for any eligible practices that have been previously
            established, or for which such owner or operator has received
            cost-share assistance from any Federal agency.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as provided for under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='9' psec='#c' tq='N'>
                1410.9(c)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , cost-share payments may be authorized for the replacement or
            restoration of practices for which cost-share assistance has been
            previously allowed under the CRP, only if:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Replacement or restoration of the practice is needed to achieve
            adequate erosion control, enhance water quality, wildlife habitat,
            or increase protection of public wellheads; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The failure of the original practice was due to reasons beyond the
            control of the participant.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The cost-share payment made to a participant shall not exceed the
            participant&apos;s actual contribution to the cost of establishing
            the practice and the amount of the cost-share may not be an amount
            that, when added to such assistance from other sources, exceeds the
            cost of the practices.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC shall not make cost-share payments with respect to a CRP
            contract if any other Federal cost-share assistance has been, or is
            being, made with respect to the establishment of the cover crop on
            land subject to such contract.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC may make cost-share payments for thinning of existing tree
            stands to benefit wildlife habitat and other resource conditions on
            enrolled land, as determined by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            68 FR 24835
          </aref>
          , May 8, 2003, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            74 FR 30912
          </aref>
          , June 29, 2009]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12304'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1410:-:1410.41
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1410.41
      </num>
      <head>
        Levels and rates for cost-share payments.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='41' psec='' tq='N'>
              1410.41
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Levels and rates for cost-share payments.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             As determined by the Deputy Administrator, CCC shall not pay more
            than 50 percent of the actual or average cost of establishing
            eligible practices specified in the conservation plan. CCC may allow
            cost-share payments for maintenance costs, consistent with the
            provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='40' psec='' tq='N'>
                1410.40
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and CCC may determine the period and amount of such cost-share
            payments.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The average cost of performing a practice may be determined by CCC
            based on recommendations from the State Technical Committee. Such
            cost may be the average cost in a State, a county, or a part of a
            State or county, as determined by the Deputy Administrator.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as otherwise provided, a participant may, in addition to any
            
            <PRTPAGE P='479' />
            payment under this part, receive cost-share assistance, rental
            payments, or tax benefits from a State or a private organization in
            return for enrolling lands in CRP. However, as provided under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='40' psec='#f' tq='N'>
                1410.40(f)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , a participant may not receive or retain CRP cost-share assistance
            if other Federal cost-share assistance is provided for such acreage,
            as determined by the Deputy Administrator. Further, under no
            circumstances may the cost-share payments received under this part,
            or otherwise, exceed the cost of the practice, as determined by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12305'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1410:-:1410.42
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1410.42
      </num>
      <head>
        Annual rental payments.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          68 FR 24835
        </aref>
        , May 8, 2003, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          74 FR 30912
        </aref>
        , June 29, 2009]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='42' psec='' tq='N'>
              1410.42
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Annual rental payments.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subject to the availability of funds, annual rental payments shall
            be made in such amount and in accordance with such time schedule as
            may be agreed upon and specified in the CRP contract.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Annual rental payments, except for land accepted that was formerly
            enrolled under the WBP, include a payment based on a weighted
            average soil rental rate or marginal pastureland rental rate, as
            appropriate, and an incentive payment as a portion of the annual
            payment of certain practices, as determined by the Deputy
            Administrator. Payments for land accepted that was formerly enrolled
            under the WBP are limited to annual rental payments received under
            the WBP.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The annual rental payment shall be divided among the participants
            on a single contract as agreed to in such contract.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The maximum amount of rental payments that a person or legal entity
            may receive, directly or indirectly, under CRP for any fiscal year
            must not exceed $50,000. The regulations in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
                1400 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
             will be applicable for determining whether the limit has been
            exceeded.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the case of a contract succession, annual rental payments shall
            be divided between the predecessor and the successor participants as
            agreed to among the participants and approved by CCC. If there is no
            agreement among the participants, annual rental payments shall be
            divided in such manner deemed appropriate by the Deputy
            Administrator and such distribution may be prorated based on the
            actual days of ownership of the property by each party.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC shall, when appropriate, prepare a schedule for each county
            that shows the maximum soil rental rate CCC may pay which may be
            supplemented to reflect special contract requirements. As determined
            by the Deputy Administrator, such schedule will be calculated based
            on the relative productivity of soils within the county using NRCS
            data and local FSA average cash rental estimates. The schedule will
            be available in the local FSA office and, as determined by the
            Deputy Administrator, shall indicate, when appropriate, that:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Offers of contracts by producers who request rental payments
            greater than the schedule for their soil(s) will be rejected;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Offers of contracts submitted under continuous signup authorized at
            
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='30' psec='' tq='N'>
                1410.30
              </subref>
            </aref>
             may be accepted without further evaluation when the requested
            rental rate is less than or equal to the calculated weighted soil
            rental rate, based on the three predominant soils listed; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Otherwise qualifying offers shall be ranked competitively based on
            factors established under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='31' psec='' tq='N'>
                1410.31
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
             in order to provide the most cost-effective environmental benefits,
            as determined by the Deputy Administrator.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Additional financial incentives may be provided to producers who
            offer contracts expected to provide especially high environmental
            benefits, as determined by the Deputy Administrator.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            68 FR 24835
          </aref>
          , May 8, 2003, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            74 FR 30912
          </aref>
          , June 29, 2009]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12306'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1410:-:1410.43
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1410.43
      </num>
      <head>
        Method of payment.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='43' psec='' tq='N'>
              1410.43
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Method of payment.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Except as provided in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='50' psec='' tq='N'>
              1410.50
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , payments made by CCC under this part may be made in cash or other
          methods of payment in accordance with 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='1401' tq='N'>
              1401 of this chapter
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , unless otherwise specified by CCC.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12307'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1410:-:1410.44
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1410.44
      </num>
      <head>
        Average adjusted gross income.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          74 FR 30912
        </aref>
        , June 29, 2009]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='44' psec='' tq='N'>
              1410.44
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Average adjusted gross income.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Benefits under this part will not be available to persons or legal
            entities whose average adjusted gross income exceeds $1,000,000 or
            as further specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
                1400
              </subref>
            </aref>
             subpart F of this chapter.
            <PRTPAGE P='480' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The limit specified in paragraph (a) of this section may be waived
            as specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
                1400
              </subref>
            </aref>
             subpart F of this chapter.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            74 FR 30912
          </aref>
          , June 29, 2009]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12308'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1410:-:1410.45-1410.49
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1410.45-1410.49
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='45-1410' psec='' tq='N'>
              1410.45-1410
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .49
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12309'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1410:-:1410.50
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1410.50
      </num>
      <head>
        Enhancement programs.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='50' psec='' tq='N'>
              1410.50
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Enhancement programs.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For contracts to which a State, political subdivision, or agency
            thereof, has succeeded in connection with an approved conservation
            reserve state enhancement program, payments shall be made in the
            form of cash only. The provisions that limit the amount of payments
            per year that a person may receive under this part shall not be
            applicable to payments received by such State, political
            subdivision, or agency thereof in connection with agreements entered
            into under such enhancement programs carried out by such State,
            political subdivision, or agency thereof that has been approved for
            that purpose by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC may enter into other conservation reserve enhancement program
            agreements in accordance with terms deemed appropriate by CCC, with
            a State, political subdivision, or agency thereof, to use the CRP to
            cost-effectively further specific conservation and environmental
            objectives of that State and the nation.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12310'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1410:-:1410.51
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1410.51
      </num>
      <head>
        Transfer of land.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='51' psec='' tq='N'>
              1410.51
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Transfer of land.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a new owner or operator purchases or obtains the right and
            interest in, or right to occupancy of, the land subject to a CRP
            contract, as determined by the Deputy Administrator, such new owner
            or operator, upon the approval of CCC, may become a participant to a
            new CRP contract with CCC for the transferred land.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For the transferred land, if the new owner or operator becomes a
            successor to the existing CRP contract, the new owner or operator
            shall assume all obligations of the CRP contract of the previous
            participant.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the new owner or operator is approved as a successor to a CRP
            contract with CCC, then, except as otherwise determined appropriate
            by the Deputy Administrator:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Cost-share payments shall be made to the past or present
            participant who established the practice; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Annual rental payments to be paid during the fiscal year when the
            land was transferred shall be divided between the new participant
            and the previous participant in the manner specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='42' psec='' tq='N'>
                1410.42
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a participant transfers all or part of the right and interest
            in, or right to occupancy of, land subject to a CRP contract and the
            new owner or operator does not become a successor to such contract
            within 60 days, or such other time as the Deputy Administrator
            determines to be appropriate, of such transfer, such contract shall
            be terminated with respect to the affected portion of such land and
            the original participant:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Forfeits all rights to any future payments for that acreage;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Shall refund all previous payments received under the contract by
            the participant or prior participants, plus interest, except as
            otherwise specified by the Deputy Administrator. The provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='32' psec='#h' tq='N'>
                1410.32(h)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             shall apply.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Federal agencies acquiring property, by foreclosure or otherwise,
            that contains CRP contract acreage cannot be a party to the contract
            by succession. However, through an addendum to the CRP contract, if
            the current operator of the property is one of the contract
            participants, such operator may, as permitted by CCC, continue to
            receive payments under such contract if:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The property is maintained in accordance with the terms of the
            contract;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Such operator continues to be the operator of the property; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Ownership of the property remains with such federal agency.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12311'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1410:-:1410.52
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1410.52
      </num>
      <head>
        Violations.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          68 FR 24835
        </aref>
        , May 8, 2003, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          69 FR 26763
        </aref>
        , May 14, 2004]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='52' psec='' tq='N'>
              1410.52
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Violations.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a participant fails to carry out the terms and conditions of a
            CRP contract, CCC may terminate the CRP contract.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the CRP contract is terminated by CCC in accordance with this
            paragraph:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The participant shall forfeit all rights to further payments under
            such 
            <PRTPAGE P='481' />
            contract and refund all payments previously received together, plus
            interest; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Pay liquidated damages to CCC in an amount as specified in the
            contract.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the Deputy Administrator determines such failure does not
            warrant termination of such contract, the Deputy Administrator may
            authorize relief as the Deputy Administrator deems appropriate.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC may reduce a demand for a refund under this section to the
            extent CCC determines that such relief would be appropriate and will
            not deter the accomplishment of the goals of the program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Crop insurance purchase requirements in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1405' tq='N'>
                1405 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
             apply to contracts executed in accordance with this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            68 FR 24835
          </aref>
          , May 8, 2003, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            69 FR 26763
          </aref>
          , May 14, 2004]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12312'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1410:-:1410.53
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1410.53
      </num>
      <head>
        Executed CRP contract not in conformity with regulations.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          74 FR 30912
        </aref>
        , June 29, 2009]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='53' psec='' tq='N'>
              1410.53
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Executed CRP contract not in conformity with regulations.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          If, after a CRP contract is approved by CCC, it is discovered that
          such CRP contract is found to contain material errors of fact or is
          not in conformity with this part, these regulations will prevail, and
          CCC may, at its sole discretion, terminate or modify the CRP contract,
          effective immediately or at a later date as CCC determines
          appropriate.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            74 FR 30912
          </aref>
          , June 29, 2009]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12313'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1410:-:1410.54
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1410.54
      </num>
      <head>
        Performance based upon advice or action of the Department.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='54' psec='' tq='N'>
              1410.54
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Performance based upon advice or action of the Department.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The provisions of 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='718' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              718.8
            </subref>
             of this chapter
          </aref>
           relating to performance based upon the action or advice of an
          authorized representative of the Department shall be applicable to
          this part, and may be considered as a basis to provide relief to
          persons subject to sanctions under this part to the extent that relief
          is otherwise required by this part.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12314'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1410:-:1410.55
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1410.55
      </num>
      <head>
        Access to land under contract.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='55' psec='' tq='N'>
              1410.55
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Access to land under contract.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any representative of the U.S. Department of Agriculture, or
            designee thereof, shall, for purposes related to this program, be
            provided by the offeror or participant as the case may be, with
            access to land that is:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The subject of an application for a contract under this part; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Under contract or otherwise subject to this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For land identified in paragraph (a) of this section, the
            participant or producer shall provide such representatives with
            access to examine records for the land to determine land
            classification, erosion rates, or other purposes and to determine
            whether it is in compliance with the terms and conditions of the CRP
            contract.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12315'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1410:-:1410.56
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1410.56
      </num>
      <head>
        Division of payments and provisions about tenants and sharecroppers.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='56' psec='' tq='N'>
              1410.56
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Division of payments and provisions about tenants and sharecroppers.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payments received under this part shall be divided as specified in
            the applicable contract and CCC shall ensure that producers who
            would have an interest in acreage being offered receive treatment
            that is equitable, as determined by the Deputy Administrator. CCC
            may refuse to enter into a contract when there is a disagreement
            among persons seeking enrollment as to a person&apos;s eligibility
            to participate in the contract as a tenant and there is insufficient
            evidence to indicate whether the person seeking participation as a
            tenant does or does not have an interest in the acreage offered for
            enrollment in the CRP.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC may remove an operator or tenant from a CRP contract when:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The operator or tenant requests in writing to be removed from the
            CRP contract;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The operator or tenant files for bankruptcy and the trustee or
            debtor in possession fails to affirm the contract, to the extent
            permitted by applicable bankruptcy laws;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The operator or tenant dies during the contract period and the
            administrator of the estate fails to succeed to the contract within
            a period of time determined by the Deputy Administrator; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A court of competent jurisdiction orders the removal from the CRP
            contract of the operator or tenant and such order is received by
            FSA, as determined by the Deputy Administrator.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In addition to paragraph (b) of this section, tenants shall
            maintain their tenancy throughout the contract 
            <PRTPAGE P='482' />
            period in order to remain on a contract. Tenants who fail to
            maintain tenancy on the acreage under contract, including failure to
            comply with applicable State law, may be removed from a contract by
            CCC. CCC shall assume the tenancy is being maintained unless
            notified otherwise by a party to contract.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12316'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1410:-:1410.57
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1410.57
      </num>
      <head>
        Payments not subject to claims.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='57' psec='' tq='N'>
              1410.57
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Payments not subject to claims.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Subject to 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='1403' tq='N'>
              1403 of this chapter
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , any cost-share or annual payment or portion thereof due any person
          under this part shall be allowed without regard to questions of title
          under State law, and without regard to any claim or lien in favor of
          any creditor, except agencies of the United States Government.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12317'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1410:-:1410.58
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1410.58
      </num>
      <head>
        Assignments.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='58' psec='' tq='N'>
              1410.58
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Assignments.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Participants may assign the right to receive such cash payments, in
          whole or in part, as provided in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='1404' tq='N'>
              1404 of this chapter
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12318'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1410:-:1410.59
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1410.59
      </num>
      <head>
        Appeals.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='59' psec='' tq='N'>
              1410.59
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Appeals.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as provided in paragraph (b) of this section, a participant
            or person seeking participation may appeal or request
            reconsideration of an adverse determination in accordance with the
            administrative appeal regulations at 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              parts 
              <subref title='7' part='11' tq='N'>
                11
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='780' tq='N'>
                780 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Determinations by NRCS assigned to make such determination for the
            Deputy Administrator may be appealed in accordance with procedures
            established under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='614' tq='N'>
                614 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
             or otherwise established by NRCS.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12319'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1410:-:1410.60
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1410.60
      </num>
      <head>
        Scheme or device.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='60' psec='' tq='N'>
              1410.60
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Scheme or device.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If CCC determines that a person has employed a scheme or device to
            defeat the purposes of this part, or any part, of any program,
            payment otherwise due or paid such person during the applicable
            period may be required to be refunded with interest thereon as
            determined appropriate by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A scheme or device includes, but is not limited to, coercion,
            fraud, misrepresentation, depriving any other person of cost-share
            assistance or annual rental payments, or obtaining a payment that
            otherwise would not be payable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A new owner or operator or tenant of land subject to this part who
            succeeds to the contract responsibilities shall report in writing to
            CCC any interest of any kind in the land subject to this part that
            is retained by a previous participant. Such interest shall include a
            present, future, or conditional interest, reversionary interest, or
            any option, future or present, on such land, and any interest of any
            lender in such land where the lender has, will, or can legally
            obtain, a right of occupancy to such land or an interest in the
            equity in such land other than an interest in the appreciation in
            the value of such land occurring after the loan was made. Failure to
            fully disclose such interest shall be considered a scheme or device
            under this section.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12320'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1410:-:1410.61
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1410.61
      </num>
      <head>
        Filing of false claims.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='61' psec='' tq='N'>
              1410.61
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Filing of false claims.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          If CCC determines that any participant has knowingly supplied false
          information or has knowingly filed a false claim, such participant
          shall be ineligible for payments under this part with respect to the
          program year in which the false information or claim was filed and the
          contract may be terminated, in which case a full refund of all prior
          payments may be demanded. False information or false claims include,
          but are not limited to, claims for payment for practices that do not
          comply with the conservation plan. Any amounts paid under these
          circumstances shall be refunded, together plus with interest as
          determined by CCC, and any amounts otherwise due to the participant
          shall be withheld. The remedies provided for in this section shall be
          in addition to any and all other remedies, criminal and/or civil, that
          may apply.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12321'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1410:-:1410.62
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1410.62
      </num>
      <head>
        Miscellaneous.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          68 FR 24835
        </aref>
        , May 8, 2003, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 27169
        </aref>
        , May 14, 2010; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 44071
        </aref>
        , July 28, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='62' psec='' tq='N'>
              1410.62
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Miscellaneous.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as otherwise provided in this part, in the case of death,
            incompetency, or disappearance of any participant, any payments due
            under this part shall be paid to the participant&apos;s successor(s)
            under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='707' tq='N'>
                707 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Unless otherwise specified in this part, payments under this part
            shall be subject to the requirements of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='12' tq='N'>
                12 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
             concerning highly erodible land and wetland conservation and
            payments.
            <PRTPAGE P='483' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any remedies permitted CCC under this part shall be in addition to
            any other remedy, including, but not limited to, criminal remedies,
            or actions for damages in favor of CCC, or the United States, as may
            be permitted by law; provided further the Deputy Administrator may
            add to the contract such additional terms as needed to enforce these
            regulations that shall be binding on the parties and may be enforced
            to the same degree as provisions of these regulations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Absent a scheme or device to defeat the purpose of the program,
            when an owner loses control of CRP acreage due to foreclosure and
            the new owner chooses not to continue the contract in accordance
            with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='51' psec='' tq='N'>
                1410.51
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , refunds shall not be required from any participant on the contract
            to the extent that the Deputy Administrator determines that
            forgiving such repayment is appropriate in order to provide fair and
            equitable treatment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Cropland enrolled in CRP shall be classified as cropland for the
            time period enrolled in CRP and, after the time period of
            enrollment, may be removed from such classification upon a
            determination by the county committee that such land no longer meets
            the definition in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='718' tq='N'>
                718 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Research projects may be submitted by the State committee and
            authorized by the Deputy Administrator to further the purposes of
            CRP. The research projects must include objectives that are
            consistent with this part, provide economic and environmental
            information, not adversely affect local agricultural markets, and be
            conducted and monitored by a bona fide research entity, as
            determined by the Deputy Administrator.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             As determined by CCC, incentives may be authorized to foster
            opportunities for Indian tribes and beginning, limited resource, and
            socially disadvantaged farmers and ranchers and to enhance long-term
            environmental goals.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             As determined by CCC, consistent with the purposes of CRP, the
            development of habitat for, and use of conservation practices for,
            native and managed pollinators may be authorized.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            68 FR 24835
          </aref>
          , May 8, 2003, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 27169
          </aref>
          , May 14, 2010; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 44071
          </aref>
          , July 28, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12322'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1410:-:1410.63
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1410.63
      </num>
      <head>
        Permissive uses.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          68 FR 24835
        </aref>
        , May 8, 2003, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          69 FR 26763
        </aref>
        , May 14, 2004; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 44071
        </aref>
        , July 28, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='63' psec='' tq='N'>
              1410.63
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Permissive uses.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Unless otherwise specified by the Deputy Administrator, no uses of
            any kind are authorized on designated CRP acreage during the
            contract period.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Commercial shooting preserves may be operated on CRP acreage
            provided:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The commercial shooting preserve is licensed by a State agency such
            as the State fish and wildlife agency or State department of natural
            resources;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The commercial shooting preserve is operated in a manner consistent
            with the applicable State agency rules governing commercial shooting
            preserves;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CRP cover is maintained according to the conservation plan; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No barrier fencing or boundary limitations exist that prohibit
            wildlife access to or from the CRP acreage unless required by State
            law.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The following activities may be permitted, as determined by CCC, on
            CRP enrolled land insofar as they are consistent with the
            conservation purposes of the program including timing, frequency,
            and duration as provided in an approved CRP conservation plan that
            identifies appropriate vegetative management requirements:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Managed harvesting, including harvest of biomass, but only in
            exchange for a payment reduction as determined by CCC and in
            accordance with harvest frequency and timing of harvesting
            activities outside the official nesting and broodrearing season only
            as identified in an approved CRP conservation plan;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Routine grazing, but only in exchange for a payment reduction as
            determined by CCC and in accordance with appropriate vegetative
            management requirements and stocking rates for the land, grazing
            frequency, and grazing periods outside the official nesting and
            broodrearing season only as identified in an approved CRP
            conservation plan;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Prescribed grazing to control invasive species, but only in
            exchange 
            <PRTPAGE P='484' />
            for a payment reduction as determined by CCC and in accordance with
            appropriate vegetative management requirements and stocking rates
            for the land, grazing frequency, and grazing periods outside the
            official nesting and broodrearing season only as identified in an
            approved CRP conservation plan;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Harvesting, grazing, or other commercial use of the forage on the
            land in response to a drought or other emergency, but only in
            exchange for a payment reduction as determined by CCC;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Wind turbines on CRP land installed in numbers and locations as
            determined appropriate by CCC considering the location, size, and
            other physical characteristics of the land, the extent to which the
            land contains wildlife and wildlife habitat, and the purposes of
            CRP, but only in exchange for a payment reduction as determined by
            CCC;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Spot grazing, if necessary for control of weed infestation, and not
            to exceed a 30-day period according to an approved conservation
            plan, but only in exchange for a payment reduction as determined by
            CCC;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Forestry maintenance such as pruning, thinning, and timber stand
            improvement on lands converted to forestry use, but only in
            accordance with a conservation plan, and only in exchange for a
            payment reduction as determined by CCC; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The sale of carbon, water quality, or other environmental credits,
            as determined appropriate by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            68 FR 24835
          </aref>
          , May 8, 2003, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            69 FR 26763
          </aref>
          , May 14, 2004; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 44071
          </aref>
          , July 28, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12323'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1410:-:1410.64
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1410.64
      </num>
      <head>
        Transition Incentives Program.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 27169
        </aref>
        , May 14, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='64' psec='' tq='N'>
              1410.64
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Transition Incentives Program.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be eligible for the Transition Incentives Program, the retired
            or retiring owner or operator must, except as specified in paragraph
            (f) of this section:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Have land that is expiring under an existing CRP contract with a 50
            percent or greater interest as provided at 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='42' psec='#c' tq='N'>
                1410.42 (c)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Sell or lease (under a qualifying nonrevocable lease of at least 5
            years in length) expiring CRP land to a beginning or socially
            disadvantaged farmer or rancher who will return some or all of the
            land to production using sustainable grazing or crop production
            methods;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Modify the CRP contract in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='33' psec='#a_4' tq='N'>
                1410.33(a)(4)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Allow the beginning or socially disadvantaged farmer or rancher to
            begin the organic certification process under the Organic Foods
            Production Act of 1990 during the last year of the contract, if
            requested by that farmer or rancher;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Allow the beginning or socially disadvantaged farmer or rancher to
            develop a conservation plan for the land; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Allow the beginning or socially disadvantaged farmer or rancher to
            install conservation practices and initiate land improvements that
            are consistent with the conservation plan during the last year of
            the contract.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be eligible for participation in the Transition Incentives
            Program, the beginning or socially disadvantaged farmers or ranchers
            must:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Certify that they meet the definition in 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              § 1410.2 of
            </aref>
             either a beginning farmer or rancher or a socially disadvantaged
            farmer or rancher;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Obtain and implement a conservation plan; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Implement sustainable grazing or crop production in compliance with
            the conservation plan by the time specified in the plan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Eligible beginning or socially disadvantaged farmers or ranchers
            will be eligible immediately to reenroll partial field conservation
            practices in CRP, in accordance with the conservation plan and the
            provisions of this part, following the expiration of the CRP
            contract of the qualified retired or retiring owner or operator,
            provided that the beginning or socially disadvantaged farmer or
            rancher has control of the property and meets all other qualifying
            conditions of CRP, as specified in this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Eligible beginning or socially disadvantaged farmers or ranchers
            will be eligible to enroll land in the Conservation Stewardship
            Program or the Environmental Quality Incentives Program, as
            specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              parts 
              <subref title='7' part='1470' tq='N'>
                1470
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='1466' tq='N'>
                1466 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , provided that their offer to enroll otherwise meets all program
            conditions, and provided that the CRP 
            <PRTPAGE P='485' />
            contract of the retired or retiring owner or operator has expired
            and the beginning or socially disadvantaged farmer or rancher has
            sufficient control of the property.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             As an incentive for selling or leasing land to a beginning or
            socially disadvantaged farmer or rancher who is not a family member,
            CCC will pay 2 years of additional CRP annual rental payments at the
            same contract rate to a retired or retiring owner or operator. The
            retired or retiring owner or operator must certify that the
            beginning or socially disadvantaged farmer or rancher is not a
            family member.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subject to all other program conditions, incentive payments may be
            allowed for contracts that have already expired if:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The contract expired on or after June 18, 2008, and contract
            modification began on or before September 30, 2010;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The transfer to the beginning or socially disadvantaged farmer or
            rancher will occur after the contract modification; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All other program conditions are otherwise met.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Eligible retired or retiring owner or operator and eligible
            beginning or socially disadvantaged farmer or rancher must agree to
            be jointly and severally responsible, if the participant has a share
            of the payment greater than zero, with the other Transition
            Incentive Program agreement participants in compliance with the
            provisions of such Transition Incentive Program agreement and the
            provisions of this part and for any payment adjustments that may be
            required for violations of any of the terms or conditions of the
            Transition Incentive Program agreement and this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 27169
          </aref>
          , May 14, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>