<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol3'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:91
    </extid>
    <num>
      91
    </num>
    <head>
      SERVICES AND GENERAL INFORMATION
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='1622' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1622.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 1622
            </subref>
            , 
            <subref title='7' sect='1624' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1624.html'>
              1624
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 42415
          </aref>
          , Aug. 9, 1993, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
      <EDNOTE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Editorial Note:
        </HD>
        <P>
          Nomenclature changes to 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='91' tq='N'>
              91
            </subref>
          </aref>
           appear at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            61 FR 51350
          </aref>
          , Oct. 2 1996.
        </P>
      </EDNOTE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='4004'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:91:A:91.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        91.1
      </num>
      <head>
        General.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 42415
        </aref>
        , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          65 FR 64309
        </aref>
        , Oct. 26, 2000]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='91' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              91.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          This part consolidates the procedural and administrative rules of the
          Science and Technology of the Agricultural Marketing Service for
          conducting the analytical testing and laboratory audits with quality
          assurance reviews. It also contains the fees, charges and laboratories
          applicable to such services.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 42415
          </aref>
          , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            65 FR 64309
          </aref>
          , Oct. 26, 2000]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4005'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:91:A:91.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        91.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 42415
        </aref>
        , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          65 FR 64309
        </aref>
        , Oct. 26, 2000]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='91' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              91.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Words used in the regulations in this part in the singular form will
          import the plural, and vice versa, as the case may demand. As used
          throughout the regulations in this part, unless the context requires
          otherwise, the following terms will be construed to mean:
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Agency.
          </E>
           The Agricultural Marketing Service agency of the United States
          Department of Agriculture.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Analyses.
          </E>
           Microbiological, chemical, or physical tests performed on a
          commodity.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Applicant.
          </E>
           Any person or organization requesting services provided by the
          Science and Technology (S&amp;T) programs.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Legal holidays.
          </E>
           Those days designated as legal public holidays specified by Congress
          in paragraph (a) of 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            section 6103
          </aref>
          , title 5 of the United States Code and any other day declared to be a
          holiday by Federal Statute or Executive Order. Under 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            section 6103
          </aref>
           and Executive Order 10357, as amended, if the specified legal public
          holiday falls on a Saturday, the preceding Friday shall be considered
          the holiday, or if the specified legal holiday falls on a Sunday, the
          following Monday shall be considered to be the holiday.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 42415
          </aref>
          , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            65 FR 64309
          </aref>
          , Oct. 26, 2000]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4006'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:91:A:91.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        91.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Authority.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 42415
        </aref>
        , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          65 FR 64309
        </aref>
        , Oct. 26, 2000]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='91' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              91.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Authority.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The Deputy Administrator is charged with the administration of this
          subchapter.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 42415
          </aref>
          , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            65 FR 64309
          </aref>
          , Oct. 26, 2000]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4007'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:91:B:91.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        91.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Kinds of services.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          65 FR 64309
        </aref>
        , Oct. 26, 2000, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          68 FR 69946
        </aref>
        , Dec. 16, 2003]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='91' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              91.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Kinds of services.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Analytical tests. Analytical laboratory testing services under the
            regulations in this subchapter consist of microbiological, chemical,
            and certain other analyses, requested by the applicant and performed
            on tobacco, seed, dairy, egg, fruit and vegetable, meat and poultry
            products, and related processed products. Analyses are performed to
            determine if products meet Federal specifications or specifications
            defined in purchase contracts and cooperative agreements. Laboratory
            analyses are also performed on egg products as part of the mandatory
            Egg Products Inspection Program under the management 
            <PRTPAGE P='240' />
            of USDA&apos;s Food Safety and Inspection Service (FSIS) as detailed
            in 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              9 CFR 
              <subref title='9' part='590' sect='580' psec='' tq='N'>
                590.580
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Examination and licensure.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The manager of a particular Science and Technology program
            administers examinations and licenses analysts in laboratories for
            competency in performing commodity testing services.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Quality assurance reviews. The Science and Technology
            representative performs on-site laboratory quality assurance reviews
            (both required and voluntary) to ensure that appropriate technical
            methods, equipment maintenance, and quality control procedures are
            being observed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Consultation. Technical advice, statistical science consultation,
            and quality assurance program assistance are provided by the
            representatives for the Science and Technology programs for domestic
            and foreign laboratories.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            65 FR 64309
          </aref>
          , Oct. 26, 2000, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            68 FR 69946
          </aref>
          , Dec. 16, 2003]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4008'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:91:B:91.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        91.5
      </num>
      <head>
        Where services are offered.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 17287
        </aref>
        , Apr. 6, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='91' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              91.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Where services are offered.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Services are offered to applicants at the Science and Technology
            laboratories and facilities as listed below.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Science and Technology Programs National Science Laboratory.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A variety of proximate for composition, chemical, physical,
            microbiological and biomolecular (DNA-based) tests and laboratory
            analyses performed on fruits and vegetables, poultry, dairy and
            dairy products, juices, fish, vegetative seed and oilseed, honey,
            meat and meat products, fiber products and processed foods are
            performed at the Science and Technology Programs (S&amp;T)
            laboratory located at: USDA, AMS, Science and Technology Programs,
            National Science Laboratory (NSL), 801 Summit Crossing Place, Suite
            B, Gastonia, North Carolina 28054-2193.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Science and Technology (S&amp;T) Programs Science Specialty
              Laboratories.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Science specialty laboratories performing aflatoxin and other
            testing on peanuts, peanut products, dried fruits, grains, edible
            seeds, tree nuts, shelled corn products, oilseed products, olive
            oil, vegetable oils, juices, citrus products, and other commodities
            are located as follows:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             USDA, AMS, Science &amp; Technology, Citrus Laboratory, 98 Third
            Street, SW., Winter Haven, Florida 33880-2905.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             USDA, AMS, Science &amp; Technology, Science Specialty Laboratory,
            6567 Chancey Mill Road, Blakely, Georgia 39823-2785.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Program laboratories.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Laboratory services are available in all areas covered by
            cooperative agreements providing for this laboratory work and
            entered on behalf of the Department with cooperating Federal or
            State laboratory agencies pursuant to authority contained in Act(s)
            of Congress. Also, services may be provided in other areas not
            covered by a cooperative agreement if the Administrator determines
            that it is possible to provide such laboratory services.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Other alternative laboratories.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Laboratory analyses may be conducted at alternative Science and
            Technology Programs laboratories and can be reached from any
            commodity market in which a laboratory facility is located to the
            extent laboratory personnel are available.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
            <head>
              The Plant Variety Protection (PVP) Office.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The PVP office and plant examination facility of the Science and
            Technology programs issues certificates of protection to developers
            of novel varieties of plants which reproduce sexually. The PVP
            office is located as follows: USDA, AMS, Science &amp; Technology
            Programs, Plant Variety Protection Office, National Agricultural
            Library Building, Room 401, 10301 Baltimore Boulevard, Beltsville,
            MD 20705-2351.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Science and Technology Programs headquarters offices.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The examination, licensure, quality assurance reviews, laboratory
            approval/certification and consultation services are provided by
            headquarters staff located in Washington, DC. The main headquarters
            office is located as follow: USDA, AMS, Science and Technology
            Programs, Office of the Deputy Administrator, Room 1092 South
            Agriculture Bldg., Mail Stop 0270, 1400 Independence Ave., SW.,
            Washington, DC 20250-0270.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Statistics Branch Office.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Statistics Branch office of Science and Technology Programs
            (S&amp;T) provides statistical services to the Agency and other
            agencies within the USDA. In addition, the Statistics Branch office 
            <PRTPAGE P='241' />
            generates sample plans and performs consulting services for research
            studies in joint efforts with or in a leading role with other
            program areas of AMS or of the USDA. The Statistics Branch office is
            located as follows: USDA, AMS, S&amp;T Statistics Branch, Room 0603
            South Agriculture Bldg., Mail Stop 0223, 1400 Independence Ave.,
            SW., Washington, DC 20250-0223.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Technical Services Branch Office.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Technical Services Branch office of Science and Technology
            (S&amp;T) provides technical support services to all Agency programs
            and other agencies within the USDA. In addition, the Technical
            Services Branch office provides certification and approval services
            of private and State government laboratories as well as oversees
            quality assurance programs; import and export certification of
            laboratory tested commodities. The Technical Services Branch mailing
            address is as follows: USDA, AMS, S&amp;T Technical Services Branch,
            South Agriculture Bldg., Mail Stop 0272, 1400 Independence Ave.,
            SW., Washington, DC 20250-0272. The Technical Services Branch office
            is located as follows: USDA, AMS, Science and Technology Technical
            Services Branch, Room 0604 South Agriculture Bldg., 1400
            Independence Ave., SW., Washington, DC 20250.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Monitoring Programs Office.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Services afforded by the Pesticide Data Program (PDP) and
            Microbiological Data Program (MDP) are provided by USDA, AMS,
            Science and Technology Monitoring Programs Office, 8609 Sudley Road,
            Suite 206, Manassas, VA 20110-8411.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Pesticide Records Branch Office.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Services afforded by the Federal Pesticide Record Keeping Program
            for restricted-use pesticides by private certified applicators are
            provided by USDA, AMS, Science and Technology, Pesticide Records
            Branch, 8609 Sudley Road, Suite 203, Manassas, VA 20110-8411.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The addresses of the various laboratories and offices appear in the
            pertinent parts of this subchapter. A prospective applicant may
            obtain a current listing of addresses and telephone numbers of
            Science and Technology Programs laboratories, offices, and
            facilities by addressing an inquiry to the Administrative Officer,
            Science and Technology Programs, Agricultural Marketing Service,
            United States Department of Agriculture (USDA), 1400 Independence
            Ave., SW., Room 0725 South Agriculture Building, Mail Stop 0271,
            Washington, DC 20250-0271.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 17287
          </aref>
          , Apr. 6, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4009'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:91:B:91.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        91.6
      </num>
      <head>
        Availability of services.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 42415
        </aref>
        , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          65 FR 64310
        </aref>
        , Oct. 26, 2000]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='91' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              91.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Availability of services.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Services may be furnished whenever a Science and Technology staff
            is available and the facilities and conditions are satisfactory for
            the conduct of such service.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Laboratories may provide limited service on Saturdays and Sundays
            at a premium fee. Weekend service may be obtained by contacting the
            laboratory director or supervisor.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Holiday and overtime laboratory service may be obtained with a
            minimum 24 hour advance notice, at a premium fee, by any prospective
            applicant through the laboratory director or supervisor.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 42415
          </aref>
          , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            65 FR 64310
          </aref>
          , Oct. 26, 2000]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4010'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:91:C:91.7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        91.7
      </num>
      <head>
        Nondiscrimination.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='91' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              91.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Nondiscrimination.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          All services under these regulations are provided to applicants
          without discrimination as to race, color, handicapped or disabled
          condition, religion, sex, age, or national origin.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4011'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:91:C:91.8
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        91.8
      </num>
      <head>
        Who may apply.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='91' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              91.8
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Who may apply.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          An application for service may be made by any individual or interested
          party including, but not limited to, the United States and any
          instrumentality or agency thereof, any State, county, municipality, or
          common carrier, and any authorized agent on behalf of the foregoing.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4012'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:91:C:91.9
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        91.9
      </num>
      <head>
        How to make an application.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          65 FR 64310
        </aref>
        , Oct. 26, 2000]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='91' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
              91.9
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          How to make an application.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Voluntary.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An application for analysis and testing may be made by contacting
            the director or supervisor of the Science and Technology laboratory
            where the service is provided, or by contacting the Technical
            Services Branch Chief at Science and Technology Headquarters,
            Washington, DC. 
            <PRTPAGE P='242' />
            A list of the Science and Technology laboratories is included in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='91' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
                91.5
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Mandatory.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the case of mandatory analyses, such as those required to be
            performed on eggs and egg products, application for services may be
            submitted to the office or USDA agency which administers the
            program, or by contacting an inspector or grader who is involved
            with the program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            65 FR 64310
          </aref>
          , Oct. 26, 2000]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4013'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:91:C:91.10
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        91.10
      </num>
      <head>
        Information required in connection with an application.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='91' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
              91.10
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Information required in connection with an application.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An application for laboratory service shall be made in the English
            language and may be made orally (in person or by telephone), in
            writing, or by facsimile. If an application for laboratory service
            is made orally, written confirmation may be required by the
            laboratory involved.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In connection with each application for a laboratory service,
            information that may be necessary to perform analyses on the
            processed product(s) shall also be furnished. The information shall
            include, but is not limited to, the name of the product, name and
            address of the packer or plant where such product was packed, the
            location of the product, its lot or load number, codes or other
            identification marks, the number of containers, the type and size of
            the containers, the analytical test requested, and the size of the
            sample. In addition, information regarding analysis of the lot by
            any federal agency previous to the application and the purpose of
            the desired laboratory service may be requested.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4014'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:91:C:91.11
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        91.11
      </num>
      <head>
        Filing of an application.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='91' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
              91.11
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Filing of an application.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          An application for a laboratory service shall be regarded as filed
          only when made in accordance with the regulations in this part.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4015'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:91:C:91.12
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        91.12
      </num>
      <head>
        Record of filing time and laboratory tests.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='91' sect='12' psec='' tq='N'>
              91.12
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Record of filing time and laboratory tests.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          A record showing the date of receipt for each application for a
          laboratory service or an appeal of a laboratory service shall be
          maintained. In addition, the requested laboratory analyses shall be
          recorded at the time of sample receipt.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4016'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:91:C:91.13
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        91.13
      </num>
      <head>
        When an application may be rejected.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='91' sect='13' psec='' tq='N'>
              91.13
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          When an application may be rejected.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An application for a laboratory service may be rejected by the
            Administrator when deemed appropriate as follows:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For non-compliance by the applicant with the regulations in this
            part,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For non-payment of previous laboratory services rendered,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When the sample is not properly identified by a code or other
            marks,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When the samples are received in an unsatisfactory condition and
            are rejected for analysis,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When there is evidence or knowledge of tampering with the sample,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When it appears that to perform the analytical testing or
            laboratory service specified in this part would not be to the best
            interests of the public welfare or of the Government, or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When it appears to the Administrator that prior commitments of the
            Department necessitate rejection of the application.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each such applicant shall be promptly notified by registered mail
            of the reasons for the rejection.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A written petition for reconsideration of such rejection may be
            filed by the applicant with the Administrator if postmarked or
            delivered within 10 days after the receipt of notice of the
            rejection. Such petition shall state specifically the errors alleged
            to have been made by the Administrator in rejecting the application.
            Within 20 days following the receipt of such a petition for
            reconsideration, the Administrator shall approve the application or
            notify the applicant by registered mail of the reasons for the
            rejection thereof.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4017'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:91:C:91.14
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        91.14
      </num>
      <head>
        When an application may be withdrawn.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='91' sect='14' psec='' tq='N'>
              91.14
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          When an application may be withdrawn.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          An application for a laboratory service may be withdrawn by the
          applicant at any time before the analytical testing is performed; 
          <E T='03'>
            Provided,
          </E>
           That, the applicant shall pay, at the hourly rate prescribed in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='91' sect='37' psec='' tq='N'>
              91.37
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , for the time incurred by the scientist or laboratory technician, in
          connection with such application and any travel expenses, telephone,
          facsimile, mailing, telegraph or 
          <PRTPAGE P='243' />
          other expenses, which have been incurred by the laboratory servicing
          office, in connection with such application.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4018'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:91:D:91.15
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        91.15
      </num>
      <head>
        Basis of a laboratory service.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='91' sect='15' psec='' tq='N'>
              91.15
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Basis of a laboratory service.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Analytical testing and laboratory determination for analyte or quality
          constituent shall be based upon the appropriate standards promulgated
          by the U.S. Department of Agriculture, applicable standards prescribed
          by the laws of the State where the particular product was produced,
          specifications of any governmental agency, written buyer and seller
          contract specifications, or any written specifications by an applicant
          which is approved by the Administrator; 
          <E T='03'>
            Provided,
          </E>
           That, if such product is regulated pursuant to the Agricultural
          Marketing Agreement Act of 1937, as amended (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='601' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/601.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 601
            </subref>
          </aref>
          <E T='03'>
            et seq.
          </E>
          ), or the comparable laws of any State, such testing and determination
          shall be on the basis of the standards, if any, prescribed in, or
          pursuant to, the marketing order and/or agreement effective
          thereunder.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4019'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:91:D:91.16
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        91.16
      </num>
      <head>
        Order of a laboratory service.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='91' sect='16' psec='' tq='N'>
              91.16
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Order of a laboratory service.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Laboratory service shall be performed, insofar as possible, in the
          order in which applications are made except that precedence may be
          given to any such applications which are made by the United States
          (including, but not being limited to, any instrumentality or agency
          thereof) and to any application for an appeal inspection.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4020'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:91:D:91.17
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        91.17
      </num>
      <head>
        Postponing a laboratory service.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='91' sect='17' psec='' tq='N'>
              91.17
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Postponing a laboratory service.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          If the scientist determines that it is not possible to accurately
          analyze or make a laboratory determination of a sample immediately
          after receipt because standard materials, laboratory equipment and
          supplies need replacement, or for any other substantial reason, the
          scientist may postpone laboratory service for such period as may be
          necessary.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4021'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:91:D:91.18
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        91.18
      </num>
      <head>
        Financial interest of a scientist.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='91' sect='18' psec='' tq='N'>
              91.18
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Financial interest of a scientist.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          No scientist shall perform a laboratory analysis on any product in
          which he is directly or indirectly financially interested.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4022'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:91:E:91.19
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        91.19
      </num>
      <head>
        General requirements of suitable samples.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='91' sect='19' psec='' tq='N'>
              91.19
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General requirements of suitable samples.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Samples must be representative of the product tested and provided
            in sufficient quantity for the analyses requested.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each sample must be identified with the following information:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Product type (specific description);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Lot number or production date;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Analyses desired;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Date/time collected;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Storage conditions prior to shipping;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Name of applicant;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Name of sampler;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any other information which is required by the specific program
            under which analysis or test is performed.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4023'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:91:E:91.20
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        91.20
      </num>
      <head>
        Shipping.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='91' sect='20' psec='' tq='N'>
              91.20
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Shipping.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Samples must be submitted to the laboratory in a condition
            (including temperature) that does not compromise the quality and
            validity of analytical results.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All samples must be submitted in sealed, leakproof containers.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Containers for perishable refrigerated samples should contain ice
            or ice packs to maintain temperatures of 0° to 5 °C, unless a
            different temperature is required for the sample to be tested.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Containers for frozen samples should contain dry ice or other
            effective methods of maintaining samples in a frozen state.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The applicant is responsible for providing shipping containers and
            paying shipping costs for fee basis tests.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A courier charge may apply for the shipment of some samples.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4024'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:91:E:91.21
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        91.21
      </num>
      <head>
        Protecting samples.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='91' sect='21' psec='' tq='N'>
              91.21
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Protecting samples.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Laboratory personnel shall protect each sample from manipulation,
          substitution, and improper or careless handling which would deprive
          the sample of its representative character from the time of receipt in
          the laboratory until the analysis is completed and the sample has been
          discarded.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4025'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:91:E:91.22
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        91.22
      </num>
      <head>
        Disposition of analyzed sample.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='244' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='91' sect='22' psec='' tq='N'>
              91.22
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Disposition of analyzed sample.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Excess samples not used in analyses will be placed in proper
            storage for a maximum period of 30 days after reporting results of
            tests.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any sample of a processed commodity that has been used for a
            laboratory service may be returned to the applicant at his or her
            request and expense; otherwise, it shall be destroyed or disposed of
            to a charitable institution.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4026'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:91:F:91.23
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        91.23
      </num>
      <head>
        Analytical methods.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          65 FR 64310
        </aref>
        , Oct. 26, 2000]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='91' sect='23' psec='' tq='N'>
              91.23
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Analytical methods.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Most analyses are performed according to approved procedures described
          in manuals of standardized methodology. These standard methods are the
          specific methods used. Alternatively, equivalent methods prescribed in
          cooperative agreements are used. The manuals of standard methods most
          often used by the Science and Technology laboratories are listed as
          follows:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Approved Methods of the American Association of Cereal Chemists
            (AACC), American Association of Cereal Chemists/Eagan Press, 3340
            Pilot Knob Road, St. Paul, Minnesota 55121-2097.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             ASTA&apos;s Analytical Methods Manual, American Spice Trade
            Association (ASTA), 560 Sylvan Avenue, P.O. Box 1267, Englewood
            Cliffs, New Jersey 07632.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Compendium Methods for the Microbiological Examination of Foods,
            Carl Vanderzant and Don Splittstoesser (Editors), American Public
            Health Association, 1015 Fifteenth Street, NW., Washington, DC
            20005.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Edwards, P.R. and W.H. Ewing, Edwards and Ewing&apos;s
            Identification of Enterobacteriaceae, Elsevier Science, Inc.,
            Regional Sales Office, 655 Avenue of the Americas, P.O. Box 945, New
            York, NY 10159-0945.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FDA Bacteriological Analytical Manual (BAM), AOAC INTERNATIONAL,
            481 North Frederick Avenue, Suite 500, Gaithersburg, MD 20877-2417.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Manual of Analytical Methods for the Analysis of Pesticide Residues
            in Human and Environmental Samples, EPA 600/9-80-038, U.S.
            Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) Chemical Exposure Research
            Branch, EPA Office of Research and Development (ORD), 26 West Martin
            Luther King Drive, Cincinnati, Ohio 45268.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Official Methods and Recommended Practices of the American Oil
            Chemists&apos; Society (AOCS), American Oil Chemists&apos; Society,
            P.O. Box 3489, 2211 West Bradley Avenue, Champaign, Illinois
            61821-1827.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Official Methods of Analysis of AOAC INTERNATIONAL, Volumes I &amp;
            II, AOAC INTERNATIONAL, 481 North Frederick Avenue, Suite 500,
            Gaithersburg, MD 20877-2417.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Standard Analytical Methods of the Member Companies of Corn
            Industries Research Foundation, Corn Refiners Association (CRA),
            1701 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW., Washington, DC 20006.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Standard Methods for the Examination of Dairy Products, American
            Public Health Association, 1015 Fifteenth Street, NW., Washington,
            DC 20005.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Standard Methods for the Examination of Water and Wastewater,
            American Public Health Association (APHA), the American Water Works
            Association (AWWA) and the Water Pollution Control Federation, AWWA
            Bookstore, 6666 West Quincy Avenue, Denver, CO 80235.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='l'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (l)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Test Methods for Evaluating Solid Waste Physical/Chemical Methods,
            Environmental Protection Agency, Office of Solid Waste, SW-846
            Integrated Manual (available from National Technical Information
            Service (NTIS), U.S. Department of Commerce, 5285 Port Royal Road,
            Springfield, VA 22161).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='m'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (m)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             U.S. Army Natick Research, Development and Engineering
            Center&apos;s Military Specifications, approved analytical test
            methods noted therein, Code NPP-9, Department of Defense Single
            Stock Point (DODSSP) for Military Specifications, Standards,
            Building 4/D, 700 Robbins Avenue, Philadelphia, PA 19111-5094.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='n'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (n)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             U.S. Food and Drug Administration, Pesticide Analytical Manuals
            (PAM), Volumes I and II, Food and Drug Administration, Center for
            Food Safety and Applied Nutrition (CFSAN), 200 C Street, SW.,
            Washington, DC 20204 
            <PRTPAGE P='245' />
            (available from National Technical Information Service (NTIS), U.S.
            Department of Commerce, 5285 Port Royal Road, Springfield, VA
            22161).
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            65 FR 64310
          </aref>
          , Oct. 26, 2000]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4027'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:91:G:91.24
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        91.24
      </num>
      <head>
        Reports of test results.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 17288
        </aref>
        , Apr. 6, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='91' sect='24' psec='' tq='N'>
              91.24
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Reports of test results.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Results of analyses are provided, in writing, by facsimile, by
            e-mail or other electronic means to the applicant.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Results of test analyses and laboratory determinations provided by
            AMS laboratory services only apply to the submitted samples and do
            not represent the quality, condition or disposition of the lot from
            which each sample was taken.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Applicants may call the appropriate Science and Technology
            laboratory for interim or final results prior to issuance of the
            formal report. The advance results may be telegraphed, e-mailed,
            telephoned, or sent by facsimile to the applicant. Any additional
            expense for advance information shall be borne by the requesting
            party.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A letter report in lieu of an official certificate of analysis may
            be issued by a laboratory representative when such action appears to
            be more suitable than a certificate: Provided, that, issuance of
            such report is approved by the Deputy Administrator.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 17288
          </aref>
          , Apr. 6, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4028'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:91:G:91.25
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        91.25
      </num>
      <head>
        Certificate requirements.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 17288
        </aref>
        , Apr. 6, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='91' sect='25' psec='' tq='N'>
              91.25
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Certificate requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Certificates of analysis and other memoranda concerning laboratory
          service and the reporting of results should have the following
          requirements:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Certificates of analysis shall be on standard printed forms
            approved by the Deputy Administrator;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Shall be printed in English;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Shall have results typewritten, computer generated, or handwritten
            in ink and shall be clearly legible;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Shall show the results of laboratory tests in a uniform, accurate,
            and concise manner with abbreviations identified on the form;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Shall show the information required by 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='91' sect='26' psec='' tq='N'>
                91.26
              </subref>
            </aref>
             through 91.29; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Show only such other information and statements of fact as are
            provided in the instructions authorized by the Deputy Administrator.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 17288
          </aref>
          , Apr. 6, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4029'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:91:G:91.26
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        91.26
      </num>
      <head>
        Issuance of certificates.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 42415
        </aref>
        , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          65 FR 64311
        </aref>
        , Oct. 26, 2000]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='91' sect='26' psec='' tq='N'>
              91.26
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Issuance of certificates.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The person signing and issuing the certificate of analysis shall be
            one of the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The scientist who performed the analysis;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Another technician of the laboratory facility, who has been given
            power of attorney by the scientist who performed the analytical
            testing and been authorized by the Deputy Administrator to affix the
            scientist&apos;s signature to a certificate. The power of attorney
            shall be on file with the employing office or laboratory of the
            Science and Technology program;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A person designated as the “laboratory director in charge,” when
            the certificate represents composite analyses by several
            technicians.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The laboratory certificate shall be prepared in accordance with the
            facts set forth in the official memoranda made by the scientist or
            technicians in connection with the analysis.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whenever a certificate is signed by a person under a power of
            attorney, the certificate should so indicate. The signature of the
            holder of power shall appear under the name of the scientist who
            personally analyzed the sample, and whenever a certificate issued is
            signed by a scientist in charge, that title must appear in
            connection with the signature.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 42415
          </aref>
          , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            65 FR 64311
          </aref>
          , Oct. 26, 2000]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4030'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:91:G:91.27
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        91.27
      </num>
      <head>
        Corrections to certificates prior to issuance.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='91' sect='27' psec='' tq='N'>
              91.27
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Corrections to certificates prior to issuance.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The accuracy of the statements and information shown on
            certificates of analysis must be verified by the individual whose
            name or signature, or both, is shown on the certificate or by the
            authorized agent who affixed the name or signature, or both. When a
            name or signature, or both, is affixed by an authorized agent, the
            initials of the agent shall appear directly below or following the
            name, or signature of the person. Errors found during this 
            <PRTPAGE P='246' />
            process shall be corrected according to this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Only official personnel or their authorized agents may make
            corrections, additions, or other changes to certificates.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No corrections, additions, or other changes shall be made which
            involve identification, quality, or quantity. If such errors are
            found, a new certificate shall be prepared and issued and the
            incorrect certificate marked “Void.” Otherwise, errors may be
            corrected, provided there is evidence of satisfactory correction
            procedures as follows:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The corrections are neat and legible;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each correction is initialed by the individual who corrects the
            certificate; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The corrections and initials are shown on the original and all
            copies.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4031'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:91:G:91.28
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        91.28
      </num>
      <head>
        Issuance of corrected certificates or amendments for analysis reports.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='91' sect='28' psec='' tq='N'>
              91.28
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Issuance of corrected certificates or amendments for analysis reports.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A corrected certificate of analysis or an amended letter report may
            be issued by the laboratory representative who issued the original
            certificate or report after distribution of the form if errors, such
            as incorrect dates, analytical results, or test determination
            statements, lot numbers, or errors in any other pertinent
            information require the issuance of a corrected certificate or an
            amended report.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whenever a corrected certificate or amended report is issued, such
            certificate or report shall supersede the original form which was
            issued in error. The superseded certificate or incorrect report
            shall become null and void after the issuance of the corrected
            certificate or the amended analysis report.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The corrected certificates or amended reports shall show the
            following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The terms “Corrected Original” and “Corrected Copy;”
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A statement identifying the superseded certificate or incorrect
            letter report and the corrections;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A new serial number or new date of issuance; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The same statements and information, including permissive
            statements, that were shown on the incorrect certificate or the
            incorrect report, along with the correct statement or information,
            shall be shown on the corrected form.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If all copies of the incorrect certificate or incorrect report can
            be obtained, then the superseded form shall be marked “Void” when
            submitted.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Corrected certificates or amended letter reports cannot be issued
            for a certificate that has been superseded by another certificate,
            or superseded on the basis of a subsequent analysis or an additional
            laboratory test determination.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4032'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:91:G:91.29
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        91.29
      </num>
      <head>
        Issuance of duplicate certificates or reissuance of an analysis report.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='91' sect='29' psec='' tq='N'>
              91.29
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Issuance of duplicate certificates or reissuance of an analysis
          report.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon request by an applicant, a duplicate certificate or an
            additional report may be issued for a lost, destroyed, or otherwise
            not obtainable original form.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The duplicate certificate or the reissuance of an analysis report
            shall be at the expense of the applicant.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Requests for duplicate certificates or additional analysis reports
            shall be filed as follows:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In writing;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             By the applicant who requested the service covered by the lost,
            destroyed, or otherwise not obtainable original form; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             With the office that issued the initial certificate or original
            laboratory analysis report.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The duplicate certificates or reissued analysis reports shall show
            the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The terms “Duplicate Original,” and the copies shall show
            “Duplicate Copy,”
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A statement that the certificate or letter report was issued in
            lieu of a lost or destroyed or otherwise not obtainable certificate
            or laboratory analysis report; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The same statements and information, including permissive
            statements, that were shown on the original certificate or the
            initial analysis report shall be shown on the duplicate form.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Duplicate certificates or duplicate analysis reports shall be
            issued as promptly as possible and distributed as 
            <PRTPAGE P='247' />
            the original certificates or original analysis reports and their
            copies.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Duplicate certificates shall not be issued for certificates that
            have been superseded.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4033'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:91:G:91.30
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        91.30
      </num>
      <head>
        Maintenance and retention of copies of certificates or analysis reports.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='91' sect='30' psec='' tq='N'>
              91.30
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Maintenance and retention of copies of certificates or analysis
          reports.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             At least one copy of each certificate or analysis report shall be
            filed in the laboratory for a period of not less than 3 years either
            from the date of issuance of the document, from the date of voiding
            a certificate, or from the date last payment is made by the
            applicant for a reported laboratory determination, whichever is
            later.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whenever any document, because of its condition, becomes unsuitable
            for its intended or continued use, the laboratory personnel shall
            make a copy of the original document.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             True copies shall be retained as photocopies, microfilm,
            microfiche, or other accurate reproductions and durable forms of the
            original document. Where reduction techniques, such as microfilming
            are used, suitable reader and photocopying equipment shall be
            readily available. Such reproductions shall be treated and
            considered for all purposes as though they were the original
            documents.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All documents required to be maintained under this part shall be
            kept confidential and shall be disclosed only to the applicants or
            other persons with the applicants&apos; knowledge and permission.
            Only such information as the Administrator deems relevant shall be
            disclosed to the public without the applicants&apos; permission, and
            then, only in a suit or administrative hearing brought at the
            direction, or on the request, of the Administrator, or to which the
            Administrator or any other officer of the United States is a party.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4034'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:91:H:91.31
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        91.31
      </num>
      <head>
        When an appeal of a laboratory service may be requested.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 42415
        </aref>
        , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          65 FR 64311
        </aref>
        , Oct. 26, 2000]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='91' sect='31' psec='' tq='N'>
              91.31
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          When an appeal of a laboratory service may be requested.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An application for an appeal of a laboratory service may be made by
            any interested party who is dissatisfied with the results of an
            analysis as stated in a certificate or laboratory report, if the lot
            of the commodity can be positively identified by the laboratory
            service as the lot from which originally drawn samples were
            previously analyzed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An application for an appeal of a laboratory service shall be made
            within thirty (30) days following the day on which the previous
            analysis was performed. However, upon approval by the Deputy
            Administrator, the filing time for an appeal application may be
            extended.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 42415
          </aref>
          , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            65 FR 64311
          </aref>
          , Oct. 26, 2000]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4035'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:91:H:91.32
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        91.32
      </num>
      <head>
        Where to file for an appeal of a laboratory service and information
        required.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          65 FR 64311
        </aref>
        , Oct. 26, 2000]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='91' sect='32' psec='' tq='N'>
              91.32
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Where to file for an appeal of a laboratory service and information
          required.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Application for an appeal of a laboratory service may be filed with
            the supervisor in the office or the director of the laboratory
            facility that issued the certificate or laboratory report on which
            the appeal analysis covering the commodity product is requested.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The application for an appeal of a laboratory service shall state
            the location of the lot of the commodity product and the reasons for
            the appeal; and date and serial number of the certificate covering
            the laboratory service of the commodity product on which the appeal
            is requested. In addition, such application shall be accompanied by
            the original and all available copies of the certificate or
            laboratory report.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Application for an appeal of a laboratory service may be made
            orally (in person or by telephone), in writing, by e-mail, by
            facsimile, or by telegraph. If made orally, written confirmation
            shall be made promptly.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            65 FR 64311
          </aref>
          , Oct. 26, 2000]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4036'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:91:H:91.33
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        91.33
      </num>
      <head>
        When an application for an appeal of a laboratory service may be
        withdrawn.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='91' sect='33' psec='' tq='N'>
              91.33
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          When an application for an appeal of a laboratory service may be
          withdrawn.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          An application for an appeal of a laboratory service may be withdrawn
          by the applicant at any time before the appealed laboratory service is
          performed; 
          <E T='03'>
            Provided,
          </E>
           That, the applicant shall pay, at the hourly rate prescribed in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='91' sect='37' psec='' tq='N'>
              91.37
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , for the time incurred by the laboratory personnel, any travel,
          telephone, telegraph, or other expenses 
          <PRTPAGE P='248' />
          which have been incurred by the laboratory service in connection with
          such application.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4037'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:91:H:91.34
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        91.34
      </num>
      <head>
        When an appeal of a laboratory service may be refused.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='91' sect='34' psec='' tq='N'>
              91.34
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          When an appeal of a laboratory service may be refused.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          An application for an appeal of a laboratory service may be refused
          if:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The reasons for the appealed laboratory service are frivolous or
            not substantial;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The quality or condition of the commodity product has undergone a
            material change since the laboratory service covering the commodity
            product on which the appealed laboratory service is requested;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The lot in question is not, or cannot be made accessible for
            sampling;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The lot relative to which the appealed laboratory service is
            requested cannot be positively identified as the lot from which
            samples were previously drawn and originally analyzed; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             There is noncompliance with the regulations in this part. Such
            applicant shall be notified promptly of the reason for such refusal.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4038'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:91:H:91.35
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        91.35
      </num>
      <head>
        Who shall perform an appealed laboratory service.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='91' sect='35' psec='' tq='N'>
              91.35
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Who shall perform an appealed laboratory service.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          An appealed laboratory service shall be performed, whenever possible,
          by another individual or other individuals than the scientist(s) or
          the technician(s) that performed the original analytical
          determination.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4039'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:91:H:91.36
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        91.36
      </num>
      <head>
        Appeal laboratory certificate.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='91' sect='36' psec='' tq='N'>
              91.36
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Appeal laboratory certificate.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An appeal laboratory certificate shall be issued showing the
            results of such appealed analysis. This certificate shall supersede
            the laboratory certificate previously issued for the commodity
            product involved.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each appeal laboratory certificate shall clearly identify the
            number and date of the laboratory certificate which it supersedes.
            The superseded certificate shall become null and void upon the
            issuance of the appealed laboratory certificate and shall no longer
            represent the analytical results of the commodity product.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The individual issuing an appeal laboratory certificate shall
            forward notice of such issuance to such persons as he or she
            considers necessary to prevent misuse of the superseded certificate
            if the original and all copies of such superseded certificate have
            not previously been delivered to the individual issuing the appeal
            certificate.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The provisions in the regulations in this part concerning forms and
            certificates, issuance of certificates, and retention and
            disposition of certificates shall apply to appeal laboratory
            certificates, except that copies of such appeal certificates shall
            be furnished to all interested parties who received copies of the
            superseded certificate.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4040'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:91:I:91.37
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        91.37
      </num>
      <head>
        Standard hourly fee rate for laboratory testing, analysis, and other
        services.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 17288
        </aref>
        , Apr. 6, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='91' sect='37' psec='' tq='N'>
              91.37
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Standard hourly fee rate for laboratory testing, analysis, and other
          services.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The standard hourly fee rate in this section for the individual
            laboratory analyses cover the costs of Science and Technology
            laboratory services, including issuance of certificates and
            personnel and overhead costs other than the commodity inspection
            fees referred to in 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR 
              <subref title='7' part='52' sect='42' psec='' tq='N'>
                52.42
              </subref>
            </aref>
             through 52.46, 52.48 through 52.51, 55.510 through 55.530, 55.560
            through 55.570, 58.38 through 58.43, 58.45 through 58.46, 70.71
            through 70.72, and 70.75 through 70.78. The hourly fee rates in this
            
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='91' tq='N'>
                91
              </subref>
            </aref>
             apply to all commodity and processed commodity products. The new
            fiscal year for Science and Technology Programs commences on October
            1 of each calendar year. The rate for laboratory services is $78.00
            per hour in fiscal year 2010, $81.00 per hour in fiscal year 2011,
            and $83.00 per hour in fiscal year 2012.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Printed updated schedules of the laboratory testing fees for
            processed fruits and vegetables (
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='93' tq='N'>
                93
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ), poultry and egg products (
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='94' tq='N'>
                94
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ), and meat and meat products (
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='98' tq='N'>
                98
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) will be available for distribution to Science and
            Technology&apos;s constituents and stakeholders by the individual
            Laboratory Directors of Science and Technology laboratories listed
            in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='91' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
                91.5
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . These single test laboratory fee schedules are based upon the
            applicable hourly fee rate stated in paragraph (a) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as otherwise provided in this section, charges will be made
            at the applicable hourly rate stated in paragraph (a) of this
            section for the time required to perform the service. A 
            <PRTPAGE P='249' />
            charge will be made for service pursuant to each request or
            certificate issued.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When a laboratory test service is provided for AMS by a commercial
            or State government laboratory, the applicant will be assessed a fee
            which covers the costs to the Science and Technology program for the
            service provided.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When Science and Technology staff provides applied and
            developmental research and training activities for microbiological,
            physical, chemical, and biomolecular analyses on agricultural
            commodities the applicant will be charged a fee on a reimbursable
            cost to AMS basis.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 17288
          </aref>
          , Apr. 6, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4041'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:91:I:91.38
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        91.38
      </num>
      <head>
        Additional fees for appeal of analysis.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 17288
        </aref>
        , Apr. 6, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='91' sect='38' psec='' tq='N'>
              91.38
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Additional fees for appeal of analysis.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The applicant for appeal sample testing will be charged a fee at
            the hourly rate for laboratory service that appears in this
            paragraph. The new fiscal year for Science and Technology Programs
            commences on October 1 of each calendar year. The appeal rate for
            laboratory service is $93.00 per hour in fiscal year 2010, $96.00
            per hour in fiscal year 2011, and $99.00 per hour in fiscal year
            2012.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The appeal fee will not be waived for any reason if analytical
            testing was completed in addition to the original analysis.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 17288
          </aref>
          , Apr. 6, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4042'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:91:I:91.39
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        91.39
      </num>
      <head>
        Premium hourly fee rates for overtime and legal holiday service.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 17288
        </aref>
        , Apr. 6, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='91' sect='39' psec='' tq='N'>
              91.39
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Premium hourly fee rates for overtime and legal holiday service.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When analytical testing in a Science and Technology facility
            requires the services of laboratory personnel beyond their regularly
            assigned tour of duty on any day or on a day outside the established
            schedule, such services are considered as overtime work. When
            analytical testing in a Science and Technology facility requires the
            services of laboratory personnel on a Federal holiday or a day
            designated in lieu of such a holiday, such services are considered
            holiday work. Laboratory analyses initiated at the request of the
            applicant to be rendered on Federal holidays, and on an overtime
            basis will be charged fees at hourly rates for laboratory service
            that appear in this paragraph. The new fiscal year for Science and
            Technology Programs commences on October 1 of each calendar year.
            The laboratory analysis rate for overtime service is $93.00 per hour
            in fiscal year 2010, $96.00 per hour in fiscal year 2011, and $99.00
            per hour in fiscal year 2012. The laboratory analysis rate for
            Federal holiday or designed holiday service is $108.00 per hour in
            fiscal year 2010, $111.00 per hour in fiscal year 2011, and $115.00
            per hour in fiscal year 2012.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Information on legal holidays or what constitutes overtime service
            at a particular Science and Technology laboratory is available from
            the Laboratory Director or facility manager.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 17288
          </aref>
          , Apr. 6, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4043'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:91:I:91.40
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        91.40
      </num>
      <head>
        Fees for courier service and facsimile of the analysis report.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          65 FR 64314
        </aref>
        , Oct. 26, 2000]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='91' sect='40' psec='' tq='N'>
              91.40
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Fees for courier service and facsimile of the analysis report.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Science and Technology laboratories have a courier charge per
            trip to retrieve the sample package. The courier service charge is
            determined from the established single standard mileage rate and
            from the total authorized distance based on the shortest round trip
            route from laboratory to sample retrieval site. Pursuant to the
            requirements of paragraph (a) (1) of 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              § 5704 of
            </aref>
             Title 5, United States Code (U.S.C.), the automobile reimbursement
            rate cannot exceed the single standard mileage rate established by
            the Internal Revenue Service (IRS).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The faxing of laboratory analysis reports or certificates is an
            optional service for each S&amp;T facility offered at a fee
            specified in table 8 in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='91' sect='37' psec='' tq='N'>
                91.37
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            65 FR 64314
          </aref>
          , Oct. 26, 2000]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4044'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:91:I:91.41
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        91.41
      </num>
      <head>
        Charges for demonstrations and courses of instruction.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 42415
        </aref>
        , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          65 FR 64314
        </aref>
        , Oct. 26, 2000]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='91' sect='41' psec='' tq='N'>
              91.41
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Charges for demonstrations and courses of instruction.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Charges, not in excess of the cost thereof and as approved by the
          Deputy Administrator, may be made for demonstrations, samples, or
          courses of instruction when such are furnished upon request.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 42415
          </aref>
          , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            65 FR 64314
          </aref>
          , Oct. 26, 2000]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4045'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:91:I:91.42
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        91.42
      </num>
      <head>
        Billing.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          72 FR 15021
        </aref>
        , Mar. 30, 2007]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='91' sect='42' psec='' tq='N'>
              91.42
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Billing.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each billing cycle will end on the 25th of the month. The applicant
            will 
            <PRTPAGE P='250' />
            be billed by the National Finance Center (NFC) using the Foundation
            Financial Information System (FFIS) on the 1st day, following the
            end of the billing cycle in which voluntary laboratory services and
            other services were rendered at a particular Science and Technology
            laboratory or office.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The total charge or fee shall normally be stated directly on the
            analysis report or on a standardized official certificate form for
            the laboratory analysis of a specific agricultural commodity and
            related commodity products.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The actual bill for collection will be issued by the USDA, National
            Finance Center Billings and Collection Branch, (Mail: P.O. Box
            60075), 13800 Old Gentilly Road, New Orleans, Louisiana 70160-0001.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            72 FR 15021
          </aref>
          , Mar. 30, 2007]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4046'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:91:I:91.43
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        91.43
      </num>
      <head>
        Payment of fees and charges.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 42415
        </aref>
        , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          65 FR 64315
        </aref>
        , Oct. 26, 2000]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='91' sect='43' psec='' tq='N'>
              91.43
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Payment of fees and charges.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Fees and charges for services shall be paid by the applicant, by
            check or money order payable, to the “Agricultural Marketing
            Service, USDA” and sent to the office indicated on the bill.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Fees and charges for services under a cooperative agreement with a
            State or other AMS programs or other governmental agency will be
            paid in accordance with the terms of the cooperative agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             As necessary, the Deputy Administrator may require that fees shall
            be paid in advance of the performance of the requested service. Any
            fees paid in excess of the amount due shall be used to offset future
            billings, unless a request for a refund is made by applicant.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 42415
          </aref>
          , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            65 FR 64315
          </aref>
          , Oct. 26, 2000]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4047'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:91:I:91.44
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        91.44
      </num>
      <head>
        Charges on overdue accounts and issuance of delinquency notices.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 42415
        </aref>
        , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          65 FR 64315
        </aref>
        , Oct. 26, 2000]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='91' sect='44' psec='' tq='N'>
              91.44
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Charges on overdue accounts and issuance of delinquency notices.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Accounts are considered overdue if payment is late with the
            National Finance Center (NFC). The timeliness of a payment will be
            based on the postmark date of the payment or the date of receipt by
            the NFC if no postmark date is present or legible. Bills are payable
            upon receipt and become delinquent 30 days from date of billing.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any amount due not paid by the due date will be increased by a late
            payment charge. The actual assessed rate applied to overdue accounts
            is set quarterly by the Department of the Treasury. This amount is
            one-twelfth of one year&apos;s late penalty interest rate computed
            at the prescribed rate.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Overtime or holiday laboratory service will not be performed for
            any applicant with a notice of delinquency.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Applicants with three notices of delinquency will be reviewed for
            possible termination of services. A deposit in advance sufficient to
            cover the fees and expenses for any subsequent service may be
            required of any person failing to pay in claim after issuance of
            such notice of delinquency.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Deputy Administrator of S&amp;T program and personnel of the
            USDA, NFC Billings and Collections Branch (address as listed in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='91' sect='42' psec='' tq='N'>
                91.42
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) will take such actions as may be necessary to collect any
            delinquent amounts due for accounts in claim status.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 42415
          </aref>
          , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            65 FR 64315
          </aref>
          , Oct. 26, 2000]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4048'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:91:I:91.45
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        91.45
      </num>
      <head>
        Charges for laboratory services on a contract basis.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          65 FR 64315
        </aref>
        , Oct. 26, 2000]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='91' sect='45' psec='' tq='N'>
              91.45
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Charges for laboratory services on a contract basis.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Irrespective of hourly fee rates and charges prescribed in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='91' sect='37' psec='' tq='N'>
                91.37
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , or in other sections of this subchapter E, the Deputy
            Administrator may enter into contracts with applicants to perform
            continuous laboratory services or other types of laboratory services
            pursuant to the regulations in this part and other requirements, as
            prescribed by the Deputy Administrator in such contract. In
            addition, the charges for such laboratory services, provided in such
            contracts, shall be on such basis as will reimburse the Agricultural
            Marketing Service of the Department for the full cost of rendering
            such laboratory services, including an appropriate overhead charge
            to cover administrative overhead expenses as may be determined by
            the Administrator.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Irrespective of hourly fee rates and charges prescribed in this
            subpart I, or in other parts of this subchapter E, the Deputy
            Administrator may enter into a written Memorandum of Understanding
            (MOU) or agreement with any administrative agency or governing party
            for the performance of 
            <PRTPAGE P='251' />
            laboratory services pursuant to said agreement or order on a basis
            that will reimburse the Agricultural Marketing Service of the
            Department for the full cost of rendering such laboratory service,
            including an appropriate overhead administrative overhead charge.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The conditions and terms for renewal of such Memorandum of
            Understanding or agreement shall be specified in the contract.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            65 FR 64315
          </aref>
          , Oct. 26, 2000]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4049'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:91:J:91.100
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        91.100
      </num>
      <head>
        Scope.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='91' sect='100' psec='' tq='N'>
              91.100
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Scope.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Two approved information symbols in the form of AMS shields are
          available to indicate official testing by an AMS laboratory. The two
          approved AMS shields with the words “USDA AMS TESTED” and “USDA
          LABORATORY TESTED FOR EXPORT” are added to the USDA symbol inventory
          to enhance the acceptance of AMS tested agricultural commodities on a
          national or international basis.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4050'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:91:J:91.101
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        91.101
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='91' sect='101' psec='' tq='N'>
              91.101
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Words used in the regulations in this part in the singular form will
          import the plural, and vice versa, as the case may demand. As used
          throughout the regulations in this part, unless the context requires
          otherwise, the following terms will be construed to mean:
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            AMS.
          </E>
           The abbreviation for the Agricultural Marketing Service (AMS) agency
          of the United States Department of Agriculture.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Export.
          </E>
           To send or transport a product originally created or manufactured in
          the United States of America to another country in the course of
          trade.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Laboratory.
          </E>
           An AMS Science and Technology (S&amp;T) laboratory listed in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='91' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              91.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
           that performs the official analyses.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Test.
          </E>
           To perform chemical, microbiological, or physical analyses on a
          sample to determine presence and levels or amounts of a substance or
          living organism of interest.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            USDA.
          </E>
           The abbreviation for the United States Department of Agriculture.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4051'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:91:J:91.102
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        91.102
      </num>
      <head>
        Form of official identification symbols.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='91' sect='102' psec='' tq='N'>
              91.102
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Form of official identification symbols.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Two information symbols in the form of AMS shields indicate commodity
          testing at an AMS laboratory listed in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='91' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              91.5
            </subref>
             of this part
          </aref>
          . The AMS shield set forth in figure 1 of this section, containing the
          words “USDA AMS TESTED”, and the shield set forth in figure 2,
          containing the words “USDA LABORATORY TESTED FOR EXPORT” have been
          approved by the USDA Office of Communications to be added to the
          USDA/AMS inventory of symbols. Each example of an AMS shield has a
          black and white background; however the standard red, white and blue
          colors are approved for the shields. They are approved for use with
          AMS materials. Shields with the same wording that are similar in form
          and design to the examples in figures 1 and 2 of this section may also
          be used.
        </P>
        <GPH DEEP='362' SPAN='1'>
          <PRTPAGE P='252' />
          <GID>
            ER16DE03.000
          </GID>
        </GPH>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>