<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol11'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1720
    </extid>
    <num>
      1720
    </num>
    <head>
      GUARANTEES FOR BONDS AND NOTES ISSUED FOR ELECTRIFICATION OR TELEPHONE
      PURPOSES
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='901' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/901.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 901
            </subref>
          </aref>
          <E T='03'>
            et seq.;
          </E>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='940C' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/940C.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 940C
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            69 FR 63049
          </aref>
          , Oct. 29, 2004, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='13728'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1720:-:1720.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1720.1
      </num>
      <head>
        Purpose.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 42573
        </aref>
        , July 22, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1720' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              1720.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Purpose.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          This part prescribes regulations implementing a guarantee program for
          bonds and notes issued for electrification or telephone purposes
          authorized by 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 313A of
          </aref>
           the Rural Electrification Act of 1936 (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='940c-1' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/940c-1.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 940c-1
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ).
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 42573
          </aref>
          , July 22, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13729'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1720:-:1720.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1720.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Background.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 42573
        </aref>
        , July 22, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1720' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              1720.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Background.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The Rural Electrification Act of 1936 (the “RE Act”) (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='901' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/901.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 901
            </subref>
          </aref>
          <E T='03'>
            et seq.
          </E>
          ) authorizes the Secretary to guarantee and make loans to persons,
          corporations, States, territories, municipalities, and cooperative,
          non-profit, or limited-dividend associations for the purpose of
          furnishing or improving electric and telephone service in rural areas.
          Responsibility for administering electrification and
          telecommunications loan and guarantee programs along with other
          functions the Secretary deemed appropriate have been assigned to RUS
          under the Department of Agriculture Reorganization Act of 1994 (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='6941' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/6941.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 6941
            </subref>
          </aref>
          <E T='03'>
            et seq.
          </E>
          ). The Administrator of RUS has been delegated responsibility for
          administering the programs and activities of RUS, 
          <E T='03'>
            see
          </E>
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR 
            <subref title='7' part='1700' sect='25' psec='' tq='N'>
              1700.25
            </subref>
          </aref>
          . 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            Section 6101 of
          </aref>
           the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 (
          <aref target='_blank' title='Pub. L. 107-171' alt='Pub. L. 107-171' href='http://www.gpo.gov/fdsys/pkg/PLAW-107publ171/html/PLAW-107publ171.htm'>
            Pub. L. 107-171
          </aref>
          ) (FSRIA) amended the RE Act to include a new program under 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            section 313A
          </aref>
           entitled Guarantees for Bonds and Notes Issued for Electrification or
          Telephone Purposes. This measure directed the Secretary of Agriculture
          to promulgate regulations that carry out the Program. The Secretary
          published the regulations for the program in the 
          <E T='04'>
            Federal Register
          </E>
           as a final rule on October 29, 2004, adding 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='1720' tq='N'>
              1720
            </subref>
          </aref>
           to title 7 of the Code of Federal Regulations. 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            Section 6106(a)(1)(A) of
          </aref>
           the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008 (
          <aref target='_blank' title='Pub. L. 110-246' alt='Pub. L. 110-246' href='http://www.gpo.gov/fdsys/pkg/PLAW-110publ246/html/PLAW-110publ246.htm'>
            Pub. L. 110-246
          </aref>
          ) amended 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 313A of
          </aref>
           the RE Act by replacing the level of “concurrent loans” as a factor
          limiting the amount of bonds and notes that could be guaranteed and
          inserted “for eligible electrification or telephone purposes” as the
          limitation on the amount of bonds and notes that can be guaranteed
          under 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            section 313A
          </aref>
           up to an annual program limit of $1,000,000,000, subject to
          availability of funds. 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            Section 6106(a)(1)(B)
          </aref>
           further amended 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 313A of
          </aref>
           the RE Act by removing the prohibition against the recipient using an
          amount obtained from the reduction in funding costs as a result of a
          new guarantee under 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            section 313A
          </aref>
           to reduce the interest rate charged on a new or concurrent loan.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 42573
          </aref>
          , July 22, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13730'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1720:-:1720.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1720.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          69 FR 63049
        </aref>
        , Oct. 29, 2004, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 42574
        </aref>
        , July 22, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='219' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1720' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              1720.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          For the purpose of this part:
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Administrator
          </E>
           means the Administrator of RUS.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Applicant
          </E>
           means a bank or other lending institution organized as a private,
          not-for-profit cooperative association, or otherwise on a non-profit
          basis, that is applying for RUS to guarantee a bond or note under this
          part.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Bond Documents
          </E>
           means the trust indenture, bond resolution, guarantee, guarantee
          agreement and all other instruments and documentation pertaining to
          the issuance of the guaranteed bonds.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Borrower
          </E>
           means any organization that has an outstanding loan made or
          guaranteed by RUS for rural electrification or rural telephone under
          the RE Act, or that is eligible for such financing.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Concurrent Loan
          </E>
           means a loan that a guaranteed lender extends to a borrower for up to
          30 percent of the cost of an eligible electrification or telephone
          purpose under the RE Act, concurrently with an insured loan made by
          the Secretary pursuant to 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 307 of
          </aref>
           the RE Act.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Eligible loan
          </E>
           means a loan that a guaranteed lender extends to a borrower for up to
          100 percent of the cost of eligible electrification or telephone
          purposes consistent with the RE Act.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Federal Financing Bank (FFB)
          </E>
           means a government corporation and instrumentality of the United
          States of America under the general supervision of the Secretary of
          the Treasury.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Guarantee
          </E>
           means the written agreement between the Secretary and a guaranteed
          bondholder, pursuant to which the Secretary guarantees full repayment
          of the principal, interest, and call premium, if any, on the
          guaranteed lender&apos;s guaranteed bond.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Guarantee Agreement
          </E>
           means the written agreement between the Secretary and the guaranteed
          lender which sets forth the terms and conditions of the guarantee.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Guaranteed Bond
          </E>
           means any bond, note, debenture, or other debt obligation issued by a
          guaranteed lender on a fixed or variable rate basis, and approved by
          the Secretary for a guarantee under this part.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Guaranteed Bondholder
          </E>
           means any investor in a guaranteed bond.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Guaranteed Lender
          </E>
           means an applicant that has been approved for a guarantee under this
          part.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Loan
          </E>
           means any credit instrument that the guaranteed lender extends to a
          borrower for any electrification or telephone purpose eligible under
          the RE Act, including loans as set forth in 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 4 of
          </aref>
           the RE Act for electricity transmission lines and distribution
          systems (excluding generating facilities) and as set forth in 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 201 of
          </aref>
           the RE Act for telephone lines, facilities and systems.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Loan documents
          </E>
           means the loan agreement and all other instruments and documentation
          between the guaranteed lender and the borrower evidencing the making,
          disbursing, securing, collecting, or otherwise administering of a
          loan.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Program
          </E>
           means the guarantee program for bonds and notes issued for
          electrification or telephone purposes authorized by 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 313A of
          </aref>
           the RE Act as amended.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Rating Agency
          </E>
           means a bond rating agency identified by the Securities and Exchange
          Commission as a nationally recognized statistical rating organization.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            RE Act
          </E>
           means the Rural Electrification Act of 1936 (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='901' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/901.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 901
            </subref>
          </aref>
          <E T='03'>
            et seq.
          </E>
          ) as amended.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            RUS
          </E>
           means the Rural Utilities Service, a Rural Development agency of the
          U.S. Department of Agriculture.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Secretary
          </E>
           means the Secretary of Agriculture acting through the Administrator
          of RUS.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Subsidy Amount
          </E>
           means the amount of budget authority sufficient to cover the
          estimated long-term cost to the Federal government of a guarantee,
          calculated on a net present value basis, excluding administrative
          costs and any incidental effects on government receipts or outlays, in
          accordance with the provisions of the Federal Credit Reform Act of
          1990 (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='2' sect='661' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/2/661.html'>
              2 U.S.C. 661
            </subref>
          </aref>
           et. seq.)
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            69 FR 63049
          </aref>
          , Oct. 29, 2004, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 42574
          </aref>
          , July 22, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13731'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1720:-:1720.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1720.4
      </num>
      <head>
        General standards.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          69 FR 63049
        </aref>
        , Oct. 29, 2004, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 42574
        </aref>
        , July 22, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1720' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              1720.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General standards.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In accordance with 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 313A of
            </aref>
             the RE Act, a guarantee will be issued by the Secretary only if the
            Secretary 
            <PRTPAGE P='220' />
            determines, in accordance with the requirements set forth in this
            part, that:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The proceeds of the guaranteed bonds will be used by the guaranteed
            lender to make loans to borrowers for electrification or telephone
            purposes eligible for assistance under this chapter, or to refinance
            bonds or notes previously issued by the guaranteed lender for such
            purposes;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             At the time the guarantee is executed, the total principal amount
            of guaranteed bonds outstanding would not exceed the principal
            amount of outstanding eligible loans previously made by the
            guaranteed lender;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The proceeds of the guaranteed bonds will not be used directly or
            indirectly to fund projects for the generation of electricity; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The guaranteed lender will not use any amounts obtained from the
            reduction in funding costs provided by a loan guarantee issued prior
            to June 18, 2008, to reduce the interest rates borrowers are paying
            on new or outstanding loans, other than new concurrent loans as
            provided in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1710' tq='N'>
                1710 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             During the term of the guarantee, the guaranteed lender shall:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Limit cash patronage refunds, for guaranteed lenders having a
            credit rating below “A−” on its senior secured debt without regard
            to the guarantee. For such guaranteed lenders, cash patronage
            refunds are limited to five percent of the total patronage refund
            eligible. The limit on patronage refunds must be maintained until
            the credit rating is restored to “A−” or above. For those guaranteed
            lenders subject to patronage limitations, equity securities issued
            as part of the patronage refund shall not be redeemable in cash
            during the term of any part of the guarantee, and the guaranteed
            lender shall not issue any dividends on any class of equity
            securities during the term of the guarantee.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Maintain sufficient collateral equal to the principal amount
            outstanding, for guaranteed lenders having a credit rating below
            “A−” on its senior secured debt without regard to the guarantee, or
            in the case of a lender that does not have senior secured debt, a
            corporate (counterparty) credit rating below “A−” without regard to
            the guarantee. Collateral shall be in the form of specific and
            identifiable unpledged securities equal to the value of the
            guaranteed amount. In the case of a guaranteed lender&apos;s
            default, the U.S. government claim shall not be subordinated to the
            claims of other creditors, and the indenture must provide that in
            the event of default, the government has first rights on the asset.
            Upon application and throughout the term of the guarantee,
            guaranteed lenders not subject to collateral pledging requirements
            shall identify, with the concurrence of the Secretary, specific
            assets to be held as collateral should the credit rating of its
            senior secured debt, or its corporate credit rating, as applicable,
            without regard to the guarantee fall below “A−.” The Secretary has
            discretion to require collateral at any time should circumstances
            warrant.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The final maturity of the guaranteed bonds shall not exceed 20
            years.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The guaranteed bonds shall be issued to the Federal Financing Bank
            on terms and conditions consistent with comparable
            government-guaranteed bonds and satisfactory to the Secretary.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Secretary shall guarantee payment son guaranteed bonds in such
            forms and on such terms and conditions and subject to such
            covenants, representations, warranties and requirements (including
            requirements for audits) as determined appropriate for satisfying
            the requirements of this part. The Secretary shall require the
            guaranteed lender to enter into a guarantee agreement to evidence
            its acceptance of the foregoing. Any guarantee issued under this
            part shall be made in a separate and distinct offering.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            69 FR 63049
          </aref>
          , Oct. 29, 2004, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 42574
          </aref>
          , July 22, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13732'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1720:-:1720.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1720.5
      </num>
      <head>
        Eligibility criteria.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          69 FR 63049
        </aref>
        , Oct. 29, 2004, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 42574
        </aref>
        , July 22, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1720' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              1720.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Eligibility criteria.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be eligible to participate in the program, a guaranteed lender
            must be:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A bank or other lending institution organized as a private,
            not-for-profit cooperative association, or otherwise organized on a
            non-profit basis; and
            <PRTPAGE P='221' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Able to demonstrate to the Secretary that it possesses the
            appropriate expertise, experience, and qualifications to make loans
            for electrification or telephone purposes.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be eligible to receive a guarantee, a guaranteed lender&apos;s
            bond must meet the following criteria:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The guaranteed lender must furnish the Secretary with a certified
            list of the principal balances of eligible loans then outstanding
            and certify that such aggregate balance is at least equal to the sum
            of the proposed principal amount of guaranteed bonds to be issued,
            and any previously issued guaranteed bonds outstanding; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The guaranteed bonds to be issued by the guaranteed lender must
            receive an underlying investment grade rating from a Rating Agency,
            without regard to the guarantee;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A lending institution&apos;s status as an eligible applicant does
            not assure that the Secretary will issue the guarantee sought in the
            amount or under the terms requested, or otherwise preclude the
            Secretary from declining to issue a guarantee.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            69 FR 63049
          </aref>
          , Oct. 29, 2004, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 42574
          </aref>
          , July 22, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13733'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1720:-:1720.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1720.6
      </num>
      <head>
        Application process.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          69 FR 63049
        </aref>
        , Oct. 29, 2004, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 42574
        </aref>
        , July 22, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1720' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              1720.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Application process.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Applications shall contain the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Background and contact information on the applicant;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A term sheet summarizing the proposed terms and conditions of, and
            the security pledged to assure the applicant&apos;s performance
            under, the guarantee agreement;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A statement by the applicant as to how it proposes to use the
            proceeds of the guaranteed bonds, and the financial benefit it
            anticipates deriving from participating in the program;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A pro-forma cash flow projection or business plan for the next five
            years, demonstrating that there is reasonable assurance that the
            applicant will be able to repay the guaranteed bonds in accordance
            with their terms;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Consolidated financial statements of the guaranteed lender for the
            previous three years that have been audited by an independent
            certified public accountant, including any associated notes, as well
            as any interim financial statements and associated notes for the
            current fiscal year;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Evidence of having been assigned an investment grade rating on the
            debt obligations for which it is seeking the guarantee, without
            regard to the guarantee;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Evidence of a credit rating, from a Rating Agency, on its senior
            secured debt or its corporate credit rating, as applicable, without
            regard to the government guarantee and satisfactory to the
            Secretary; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Such other application documents and submissions deemed necessary
            by the Secretary for the evaluation of applicants.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The application process occurs as follows:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The applicant submits an application to the Secretary;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The application is screened by RUS pursuant to 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR 
              <subref title='7' part='1720' sect='7' psec='#a' tq='N'>
                1720.7(a)
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
            , to ascertain its threshold eligibility for the program;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             RUS evaluates the application pursuant to the selection criteria
            set forth in 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR 
              <subref title='7' part='1720' sect='7' psec='#b' tq='N'>
                1720.7(b)
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If RUS provisionally approves the application, the applicant and
            RUS negotiate terms and conditions of the bond documents, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The applicant offers its guaranteed bonds, and the Secretary upon
            approval of the pricing, redemption provisions and other terms of
            the offering, executes the guarantee.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If requested by the applicant at the time it files its application,
            the General Counsel of the Department of Agriculture shall provide
            the Secretary with an opinion regarding the validity and authority
            of a guarantee issued to the lender under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 313A of
            </aref>
             the RE Act.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            69 FR 63049
          </aref>
          , Oct. 29, 2004, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 42574
          </aref>
          , July 22, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13734'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1720:-:1720.7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1720.7
      </num>
      <head>
        Application evaluation.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          69 FR 63049
        </aref>
        , Oct. 29, 2004, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 42574
        </aref>
        , July 22, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1720' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              1720.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Application evaluation.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Eligibility screening.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each application will be reviewed by the Secretary to determine
            whether it is eligible under 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR 
              <subref title='7' part='1720' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
                1720.5
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , the information required under 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR 
              <subref title='7' part='1720' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
                1720.6
              </subref>
            </aref>
             is complete and the proposed guaranteed bond complies with
            applicable statutes and regulations. The Secretary can at any time
            reject an application that fails to meet these requirements.
            <PRTPAGE P='222' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Evaluation.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Pursuant to paragraph (a) of this section, applications will be
            subject to a substantive review, on a competitive basis, by the
            Secretary based upon the following evaluation factors, listed in
            order of importance:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The extent to which the proposed provisions indicate the applicant
            will be able to repay the guaranteed bonds;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The adequacy of the proposed provisions to protect the Federal
            government, based upon items including, but not limited to the
            nature of the pledged security, the priority of the lien position,
            if any, pledged by the applicant, and the provision for an orderly
            retirement of principal such as an amortizing bond structure or an
            internal sinking fund;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The applicant&apos;s demonstrated performance of financially sound
            business practices as evidenced by reports of regulators, auditors
            and credit rating agencies;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The extent to which the applicant is subject to supervision,
            examination, and safety and soundness regulation by an independent
            federal agency;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The extent of concentration of financial risk that RUS may have
            resulting from previous guarantees made under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 313A of
            </aref>
             the RE Act; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The extent to which providing the guarantee to the applicant will
            help reduce the cost and/or increase the supply of credit to rural
            America, or generate other economic benefits, including the amount
            of fee income available to be deposited into the Rural Economic
            Development Subaccount, maintained under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 313(b)(2)(A) of
            </aref>
             the RE Act (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='940c' note='' psec='#b_2_A' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/940c.html#b_2_A'>
                7 U.S.C. 940c(b)(2)(A)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ), after payment of the subsidy amount.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Independent Assessment.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Before a guarantee decision is made by the Secretary, the Secretary
            shall request that the Federal Financing Bank review the adequacy of
            the determination by the Rating Agency, required under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1720' sect='5' psec='#b_2' tq='N'>
                1720.5(b)(2)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             as to whether the bond or note to be issued would be below
            investment grade without the guarantee.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Decisions by the Secretary.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Secretary shall approve or deny applications in a timely manner
            as such applications are received; provided, however, that in order
            to facilitate competitive evaluation of applications, the Secretary
            may from time to time defer a decision until more than one
            application is pending. The Secretary may limit the number of
            guarantees made to a maximum of five per year, to ensure a
            sufficient examination is conducted of applicant requests. RUS shall
            notify the applicant in writing of the Secretary&apos;s approval or
            denial of an application. Approvals for guarantees shall be
            conditioned upon compliance with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR 
              <subref title='7' part='1720' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
                1720.4
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='1720' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
                1720.6
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
            . The Secretary reserves the discretion to approve an application
            for an amount less than that requested.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            69 FR 63049
          </aref>
          , Oct. 29, 2004, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 42574
          </aref>
          , July 22, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13735'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1720:-:1720.8
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1720.8
      </num>
      <head>
        Issuance of the guarantee.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          69 FR 63049
        </aref>
        , Oct. 29, 2004, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 42574
        </aref>
        , July 22, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1720' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              1720.8
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Issuance of the guarantee.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The following requirements must be met by the applicant prior to
            the endorsement of a guarantee by the Secretary.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A guarantee agreement suitable in form and substance to the
            Secretary must be delivered.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bond documents must be executed by the applicant setting forth the
            legal provisions relating to the guaranteed bonds, including but not
            limited to payment dates, interest rates, redemption features,
            pledged security, additional borrowing terms including an explicit
            agreement to make payments even if loans made using the proceeds of
            such bond or note is not repaid to the lender, other financial
            covenants, and events of default and remedies;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Prior to the issuance of the guarantee, the applicant must certify
            to the Secretary that the proceeds from the guaranteed bonds will be
            applied to fund new eligible loans under the RE Act, to refinance
            concurrent loans, or to refinance existing debt instruments of the
            guaranteed lender used to fund eligible loans;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The applicant provides a certified list of eligible loans and their
            outstanding balances as of the date the guarantee is to be issued;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Counsel to the applicant must furnish an opinion satisfactory to
            the Secretary as to the applicant being legally authorized to issue
            the guaranteed bonds and enter into the bond documents;
            <PRTPAGE P='223' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No material adverse change occurs between the date of the
            application and date of execution of the guarantee;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The applicant shall provide evidence of an investment grade rating
            from a Rating Agency for the proposed guaranteed bond without regard
            to the guarantee;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The applicant shall provide evidence of a credit rating on its
            senior secured debt or its corporate credit rating, as applicable,
            without regard to the guarantee and satisfactory to the Secretary;
            and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Certification by the Chairman of the Board and the Chief Executive
            Officer of the applicant (or other senior management acceptable to
            the Secretary), acknowledging the applicant&apos;s commitment to
            submit to the Secretary, an annual credit assessment of the
            applicant by a Rating Agency, an annual review and certification of
            the security of the government guarantee that is audited by an
            independent certified public accounting firm or federal banking
            regulator, annual consolidated financial statements audited by an
            independent certified public accountant each year during which the
            guarantee bonds are outstanding, and other such information
            requested by the Secretary.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Secretary shall not issue a guarantee if the applicant is
            unwilling or unable to satisfy all requirements.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            69 FR 63049
          </aref>
          , Oct. 29, 2004, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 42574
          </aref>
          , July 22, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13736'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1720:-:1720.9
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1720.9
      </num>
      <head>
        Guarantee Agreement.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1720' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
              1720.9
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Guarantee Agreement.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The guaranteed lender will be required to sign a guarantee
            agreement with the Secretary setting forth the terms and conditions
            upon which the Secretary guarantees the payment of the guaranteed
            bonds.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The guaranteed bonds shall refer to the guarantee agreement as
            controlling the terms of the guarantee.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The guarantee agreement shall address the following matters:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Definitions and principles of construction;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The form of guarantee;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Coverage of the guarantee;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Timely demand for payment on the guarantee;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any prohibited amendments of bond documents or limitations on
            transfer of the guarantee;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Limitation on acceleration of guaranteed bonds;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Calculation and manner of paying the guarantee fee;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Consequences of revocation of payment on the guaranteed bonds;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Representations and warranties of the guaranteed lender;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Representations and warranties for the benefit of the holder of the
            guaranteed bonds;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_11'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (11)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Claim procedures;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_12'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (12)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             What constitutes a failure by the guaranteed lender to pay;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_13'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (13)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Demand on RUS;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_14'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (14)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Assignment to RUS;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_15'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (15)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Conditions of guarantee which may include requiring the guaranteed
            lender to adopt measures to ensure adequate capital levels are
            retained to absorb losses relative to risk in the guaranteed
            lender&apos;s portfolio and requirements on the guaranteed lender to
            hold additional capital against the risk of default;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_16'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (16)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payment by RUS;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_17'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (17)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             RUS payment does not discharge guaranteed lender;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_18'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (18)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Undertakings for the benefit of the holders of guaranteed bonds,
            including: notices, registration, prohibited amendments, prohibited
            transfers, indemnification, multiple bond issues;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_19'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (19)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Governing law;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_20'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (20)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notices;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_21'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (21)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Benefit of agreement;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_22'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (22)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Entirety of agreement;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_23'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (23)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Amendments and waivers;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_24'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (24)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Counterparts;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_25'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (25)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Severability, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_26'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (26)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Such other matters as the Secretary believes to be necessary or
            appropriate.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13737'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1720:-:1720.10
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1720.10
      </num>
      <head>
        Fees.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1720' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
              1720.10
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Fees.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Guarantee fee.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An annual fee equal to 30 basis points (0.3 percent) of the amount
            of the unpaid principal of the guarantee bond will be deposited into
            the Rural Economic Development Subaccount maintained under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 313(b)(2)(A) of
            </aref>
             the RE Act.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subject to paragraph (c) of this section, up to one-third of the 30
            basis point guarantee fee may be used to fund the subsidy amount of
            providing 
            <PRTPAGE P='224' />
            guarantees, to the extent not otherwise funded through appropriation
            actions by Congress.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notwithstanding subsections (c) and (e)(2) of 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 313A of
            </aref>
             the RE Act, the Secretary shall, with the consent of the lender and
            if otherwise authorized by law, adjust the schedule for payment of
            the annual fee, not to exceed an average of 30 basis points per year
            for the term of the loan, to ensure that sufficient funds are
            available to pay the subsidy costs for note guarantees.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13738'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1720:-:1720.11
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1720.11
      </num>
      <head>
        Servicing.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1720' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
              1720.11
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Servicing.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The Secretary, or other agent of the Secretary on his or her behalf,
          shall have the right to service the guaranteed bond, and periodically
          inspect the books and accounts of the guaranteed lender to ascertain
          compliance with the provisions of the RE Act and the bond documents.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13739'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1720:-:1720.12
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1720.12
      </num>
      <head>
        Reporting requirements.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          69 FR 63049
        </aref>
        , Oct. 29, 2004, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 42575
        </aref>
        , July 22, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1720' sect='12' psec='' tq='N'>
              1720.12
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Reporting requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             As long as any guaranteed bonds remain outstanding, the guaranteed
            lender shall provide the Secretary with the following items each
            year within 90 days of the guaranteed lender&apos;s fiscal year end:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Consolidated financial statements and accompanying footnotes,
            audited by independent certified public accountants;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A review and certification of the security of the government
            guarantee, audited by reputable, independent certified public
            accountants or a federal banking regulator, who in the judgment of
            the Secretary, has the requisite skills, knowledge, reputation, and
            experience to properly conduct such a review;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Pro forma projection of the guaranteed lender&apos;s balance sheet,
            income statement, and statement of cash flows over the ensuing five
            years;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Credit assessment issued by a Rating Agency;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Credit rating, by a Rating Agency, on its senior secured debt or
            its corporate credit rating, as applicable, without regard to the
            guarantee and satisfactory to the Secretary; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Other such information requested by the Secretary.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The bond documents shall specify such bond monitoring and financial
            reporting requirements as deemed appropriate by the Secretary.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            69 FR 63049
          </aref>
          , Oct. 29, 2004, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 42575
          </aref>
          , July 22, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13740'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1720:-:1720.13
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1720.13
      </num>
      <head>
        Limitations on guarantees.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 42575
        </aref>
        , July 22, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1720' sect='13' psec='' tq='N'>
              1720.13
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Limitations on guarantees.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          In a given year the maximum amount of guaranteed bonds that the
          Secretary may approve will be subject to budget authority, together
          with receipts authority from projected fee collections from guaranteed
          lenders, the principal amount of outstanding eligible loans made by
          the guaranteed lender, and Congressionally-mandated ceilings on the
          total amount of credit. The Secretary may also impose other
          limitations as appropriate to administer this guarantee program.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 42575
          </aref>
          , July 22, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13741'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1720:-:1720.14
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1720.14
      </num>
      <head>
        Nature of guarantee; acceleration of guaranteed bonds.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1720' sect='14' psec='' tq='N'>
              1720.14
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Nature of guarantee; acceleration of guaranteed bonds.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any guarantee executed by the Secretary under this part shall be an
            obligation supported by the full faith and credit of the United
            States and incontestable except for fraud or misrepresentation of
            which the guaranteed bondholder had actual knowledge at the time it
            purchased the guaranteed bonds.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Amounts due under the guarantee shall be paid within 30 days of
            demand by a bondholder, certifying the amount of payment then due
            and payable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The guarantee shall be assignable and transferable to any purchaser
            of guaranteed bonds as provided in the bond documents.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The following actions shall constitute events of default under the
            terms of the guarantee agreements:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The guaranteed lender failed to make a payment of principal or
            interest when due on the guaranteed bonds;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The guaranteed bonds were issued in violation of the terms and
            conditions of the bond documents;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The guarantee fee required by 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR 
              <subref title='7' part='1720' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
                1720.10
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
            , has not been paid;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The guaranteed lender made a misrepresentation to the Secretary in
            any material respect in connection with the application, the
            guaranteed 
            <PRTPAGE P='225' />
            bonds, or the reporting requirements listed in 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR 
              <subref title='7' part='1720' sect='12' psec='' tq='N'>
                1720.12
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The guaranteed lender failed to comply with any material covenant
            or provision contained in the bond documents.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the event the guaranteed lender fails to cure such defaults
            within the notice terms and the timeframe set forth in the bond
            documents, the Secretary may demand that the guaranteed lender
            redeem the guaranteed bonds. Such redemption amount will be in an
            amount equal to the outstanding principal balance, accrued interest
            to the date of redemption, and prepayment premium, if any. To the
            extent the Secretary makes any payments under the guarantee, the
            Secretary shall be deemed the guaranteed bondholder.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To the extent the Secretary makes any payments under the guarantee,
            the interest rate the government will charge to the guaranteed
            lender for the period of default shall accrue at an annual rate of
            the greater of 1.5 times the 91-day Treasury-Bill rate or 200 basis
            points (2.00%) above the rate on the guaranteed bonds.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon guaranteed lender&apos;s event of default, under the bond
            documents, the Secretary shall be entitled to take such other action
            as is provided for by law or under the bond documents.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13742'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1720:-:1720.15
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1720.15
      </num>
      <head>
        Equal opportunity requirements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1720' sect='15' psec='' tq='N'>
              1720.15
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Equal opportunity requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Executive Order 12898, “Environmental Justice.”
          </E>
           To comply with Executive Order 12898, RUS will conduct a Civil Rights
          Analysis for each guarantee prior to approval. Rural Development Form
          2006-28, “Civil Rights Impact Analysis”, will be used to document
          compliance in regards to environmental justice. The Civil Rights
          Impact Analysis will be conducted prior to application approval or a
          conditional commitment of guarantee.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>