<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol7'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:759
    </extid>
    <num>
      759
    </num>
    <head>
      DISASTER DESIGNATIONS AND NOTIFICATIONS
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='5' sect='301' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/5/301.html'>
              5 U.S.C. 301
            </subref>
            , 
            <subref title='5' sect='7' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/5/7.html'>
              7
            </subref>
          </aref>
           U.S.C. 1961 and 1989.
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            77 FR 41254
          </aref>
          , July 13, 2012, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='6657'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:759:-:759.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        759.1
      </num>
      <head>
        Administration.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='759' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              759.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Administration.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This part will be administered under the general supervision and
            direction of the Administrator, Farm Service Agency (FSA).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FSA representatives do not have authority to modify or waive any of
            the provisions of the regulations of this part as amended or
            supplemented.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Administrator will take any action required by the regulations
            of this part that the Administrator determines has not already been
            taken. The Administrator will also:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Correct or require correction of any action taken that is not in
            accordance with the regulations of this part; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Require withholding taking any action that is not in accordance
            with this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No provision or delegation in these regulations will preclude the
            Administrator or a designee or other such person, from determining
            any question arising under this part, or from reversing or modifying
            any determination made under this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Absent a delegation to the contrary, this part will be administered
            by the Deputy Administrator for Farm 
            <PRTPAGE P='69' />
            Programs of FSA on behalf of the Administrator of FSA or the
            Secretary, but nothing in this part will inhibit the ability of the
            Administrator of FSA or the person holding the equivalent position
            in the event of a reorganization to delegate the functions of DAFP
            under these regulations to another person. Likewise, nothing shall
            inhibit the ability of the Secretary to reassign any duties with
            respect to the designations of disasters under this part.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6658'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:759:-:759.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        759.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Purpose.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='759' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              759.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Purpose.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This part specifies the types of incidents that can result in an
            area being determined a disaster area, which under other regulations
            makes qualified farmers in such areas eligible for Emergency loans
            (EM) or eligible for such other assistance that may be available,
            based on Secretarial disaster designations. Nothing in this part
            overrides provision of those regulations that govern the actual
            administration and availability of the disaster assistance
            regulations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This part specifies the responsibility of the County Emergency
            Board (CEB), State Emergency Board (SEB), and the State Executive
            Director (SED) in regard to Secretarial Designations with regards to
            disasters. It also addresses matters relating to the handling of a
            Presidential declaration of disaster or the imposition of a USDA
            quarantine by the Secretary with respect to triggering the
            availability of EM loans.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6659'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:759:-:759.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        759.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Abbreviations and definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='759' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              759.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Abbreviations and definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Abbreviations.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The following abbreviations apply to this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            CEB
          </E>
           means the County Emergency Board.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            CED
          </E>
           means the County Executive Director.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            DAFP
          </E>
           means the Deputy Administrator for Farm Programs of the Farm Service
          Agency.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            EM
          </E>
           means Emergency loan administered under 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR part 
            <subref title='7' part='764' tq='N'>
              764
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            FSA
          </E>
           means the Farm Service Agency.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            LAR
          </E>
           means the Loss Assessment Report.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            SEB
          </E>
           means the State Emergency Board.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            SED
          </E>
           means the State Executive Director.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            USDA
          </E>
           means the United States Department of Agriculture.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Definitions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The following definitions apply to this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Administrator
          </E>
           means the Administrator of FSA.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Contiguous county
          </E>
           is used in reference to a primary county as defined in this section.
          A contiguous county is any county whose boundary touches at any point
          with that of the primary county. For programs other than the EM
          Program, disaster assistance regulations will specify whether benefits
          will be available only in the primary counties or also in the
          contiguous counties. For the EM Program that issue is addressed in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='759' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              759.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , unless specified otherwise in the disaster assistance regulations
          for other programs or in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='759' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              759.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
           for the EM Program, only the “primary” county will be considered the
          qualifying “disaster county.” Therefore, if the disaster assistance
          regulations specify that they cover the disaster area and contiguous
          counties, then the only eligible counties would be the primary county
          and those contiguous to that county. Coverage would not include
          coverage of those counties that are in turn contiguous to those
          counties that are contiguous to the primary county.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            County
          </E>
           is used when referring to a geographical area, a local administrative
          subdivision of a State or a similar political subdivision of the
          United States generally considered to be in county usage, for example,
          it includes an area referred to as a “county” or “parish.” Except
          where otherwise specified, the use of the term county or similar
          political subdivision is for administrative purposes only.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            CEB
          </E>
           is comprised of the representatives of several USDA agencies that
          have responsibilities for reporting the occurrence of, and assessing
          the damage caused by, a natural disaster, and for requesting approval
          in declaring a county a disaster area.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            CED
          </E>
           is the person in charge of administering the local FSA county office
          for a particular county.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Disaster area
          </E>
           is the county or counties declared or designated as a disaster area
          as a result of natural disaster related losses. The disaster area only
          includes the primary counties, but 
          <PRTPAGE P='70' />
          benefits may be available in the counties contiguous to the primary
          county if so provided by the disaster assistance regulations or, in
          the case of the EM Program, in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='759' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              759.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            LAR
          </E>
           is a loss assessment report prepared by the CEB relating to the State
          and county where the potential disaster occurred and for which county
          or counties the CEB is responsible. The LAR includes as applicable,
          but is not limited to, starting and ending dates of the disaster, crop
          year affected, type of disaster incident, area of county affected by
          disaster; total number of farms affected, crop loss or pasture loss
          data associated with the applicable disaster (or both types of
          losses), livestock destroyed, and other property losses.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Natural disaster
          </E>
           is a disaster in which unusual and adverse weather conditions or
          other natural phenomena have substantially affected farmers by causing
          severe physical losses, severe production losses, or both.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Primary county
          </E>
           is a county determined to be a disaster area.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Presidential declaration
          </E>
           is a declaration of a disaster by the President under the Robert T.
          Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='42' sect='5121-2' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/42/5121-2.html'>
              42 U.S.C. 5121-2
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ) requiring Federal emergency assistance to supplement State and local
          efforts to save lives and protect property, public health and safety,
          or to avert or lessen the threat of a disaster.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Production losses (severe)
          </E>
           within a county are those in which there has been a reduction
          county-wide of at least a 30 percent or more loss of production of at
          least one crop in the county.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            SEB
          </E>
           means the State Emergency Board which is comprised of the
          representatives of several USDA agencies having emergency program
          responsibilities at the State level. The board is required to respond
          to emergencies and carry out the Secretary&apos;s emergency
          preparedness responsibilities.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            SED
          </E>
           is the person who serves as the Chairperson of the USDA SEB in each
          State, is responsible for providing the leadership and coordination
          for all USDA emergency programs at the State level, and is subject to
          the supervision of DAFP.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Severe physical losses
          </E>
           means, for the purpose of determining an Administrator&apos;s
          declaration of physical loss, losses that consist of severe damage to,
          or destruction of: Physical farm property including farmland (except
          sheet erosion); structures on the land including, but not limited to,
          building, fences, dams; machinery, equipment, supplies, and tools;
          livestock, livestock products, poultry and poultry products; harvested
          crops and stored crops.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Substantially affected
          </E>
           when used to refer to producers and to the relationship of a
          particular producer to a particular disaster means a producer who has
          sustained qualifying physical or production losses, as defined in this
          section, as a result of the natural disaster.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            U.S. Drought Monitor
          </E>
           is a system for classifying drought severity according to a range of
          abnormally dry to exceptional drought. It is a collaborative effort
          between Federal and academic partners that is produced on a weekly
          basis to synthesize multiple indices, outlooks, and drought impacts on
          a map and in narrative form. This synthesis of indices is reported by
          the National Drought Mitigation Center.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            United States
          </E>
           means each of the several States, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico,
          the Virgin Islands of the United States, Guam, American Samoa, and the
          Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands. Extension of disaster
          assistance, following a disaster designation, to insular areas of the
          United States not covered by this definition of “United States” will
          be only as authorized by law, and as determined by the Administrator
          on behalf of the Secretary to be appropriate.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6660'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:759:-:759.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        759.5
      </num>
      <head>
        Secretarial disaster area determination and notification process.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='759' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              759.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Secretarial disaster area determination and notification process.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              U.S. Drought Monitor.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             With respect to drought and without requiring an LAR:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If any portion of a county is physically located in an area with a
            Drought Monitor Intensity Classification value of D3
            (drought-extreme) or higher during any part of the growing season of
            the crops affected by the disaster in the county, then the county
            will be designated a disaster area by the Secretary.
            <PRTPAGE P='71' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If any portion of a county meets the threshold Drought Monitor
            Intensity Classification value of D2 (drought-severe) for at least 8
            consecutive weeks during the growing season of affected crops, then
            the county will be designated a disaster area by the Secretary.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              CEB and SEB recommendations.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In instances where counties have been impacted by a disaster but
            the county has not been designated a disaster area under the
            provisions of paragraph (a) of this section, CEB will make a
            disaster designation recommendation request to SEB when a disaster
            has resulted in severe production losses. The determination of the
            sufficiency of the production losses will be governed by the
            provisions in paragraph (c) of this section. The CEB may make such
            efforts as are needed to identify counties that have been impacted
            and had such production losses. A farmer, Indian Tribal Council, or
            local governing body may initiate the process by reporting
            production losses or drought conditions to CEB and suggesting that
            there be a recommendation in favor of designating a county as a
            disaster area. Recommendations by a CEB in favor of a disaster
            designation by a CEB under this paragraph are subject to the
            following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A LAR is required as part of a CEB disaster designation request.
            CEB will submit a disaster designation request with a LAR to SEB for
            review and recommendation for approval by the Secretary. CEB&apos;s
            written request and SEB recommendation must be submitted within
            three months of the last day of the occurrence of a natural
            disaster.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If SEB determines a qualifying natural disaster and loss have
            occurred, SEB will forward the recommendation to the Administrator.
            The natural disaster may include drought conditions that were not
            sufficiently severe to meet the criteria in paragraph (a) of this
            section. Since the U.S. Drought Monitor tracks only drought
            conditions, not specifically agricultural losses resulting from
            those conditions, it is possible for a drought that does not meet
            the criteria in paragraph (a) of this section to result in
            production losses that constitute a natural disaster.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Secretary or the Secretary&apos;s designee will make disaster
            area determinations. The Secretary may delegate the authority to the
            SED. In such case, the SED will act on behalf of the Secretary,
            subject to review by DAFP as may be appropriate and consistent with
            the delegation. The delegation of authority to the SED may be
            revoked by the authority making that delegation or by other
            authorized person. In all cases, DAFP may reverse any SED
            determination made in accordance with this section unless the
            delegation to the SED specifies that such review is not allowed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Eligible production losses.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For purposes of making determinations under paragraph (b) of this
            section, in order for an area to be declared a disaster area under
            paragraph (b) of this section based on production losses, the county
            must have had production losses of 30 percent of at least one crop
            in the county as the result of a natural disaster.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Discretionary exception to production losses for designating a
              county as a disaster county.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For purposes of the EM program only, unless otherwise specified in
            the designation, a county may be designated by DAFP as a designated
            disaster county even though the conditions specified in paragraphs
            (a) through (c) of this section are not present so long as the
            disaster has otherwise produced such significant production losses,
            or other such extenuating circumstances so as to justify, in the
            opinion of the Secretary, the designation of a county as a disaster
            area. In making this determination, the Secretary may consider all
            relevant factors including such factors as the nature and extent of
            production losses; the number of farmers who have sustained
            qualifying production losses; the number of farmers that other
            lenders in the county indicate they will not be in position to
            provide emergency financing; whether the losses will cause undue
            hardship to a certain segment of farmers in the county; whether
            damage to particular crops has resulted in undue hardship; whether
            other Federal or State benefit programs, which are being made
            available due to the same 
            <PRTPAGE P='72' />
            disaster, will consequently lessen undue hardship and the demand for
            EM; and any other factors considered relevant.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6661'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:759:-:759.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        759.6
      </num>
      <head>
        EM to be made available.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='759' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              759.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          EM to be made available.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For purposes of the EM Program under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='764' tq='N'>
                764
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , subpart I, of this chapter, a county will be considered an
            eligible disaster area as designated by FSA for coverage of the EM
            Program as follows:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Secretarial designations.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When production losses meet the requirements in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='759' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
                759.5
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and the county has been designated as a disaster area for that
            reason, or when the discretionary exception to production losses for
            EM under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='759' sect='5' psec='#d' tq='N'>
                759.5(d)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             has been exercised, the primary and contiguous counties will be
            areas in which otherwise eligible producers can receive EM loans.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Physical loss notification.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When only qualifying physical losses occur, the SED will submit a
            request to the FSA Administrator to make a determination that a
            natural disaster has occurred in a county, resulting in severe
            physical losses. If the FSA Administrator determines that such a
            natural disaster has occurred, then EM can be made available to
            eligible farmers for physical losses only in the primary county (the
            county that was the subject of that determination) and the counties
            contiguous to that county.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              USDA quarantine.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any quarantine imposed by the Secretary of Agriculture under the
            Plant Protection Act or the animal quarantine laws, as defined in 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 2509 of
            </aref>
             the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990,
            automatically authorizes EM for production and physical losses
            resulting from the quarantine in a primary county (the county in
            which the quarantine was in force) and (where the quarantine effects
            extend beyond that county) the counties contiguous to that primary
            county.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Presidential declaration.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whenever the President declares a Major Disaster Declaration or an
            Emergency Declaration, FSA will make EM available to eligible
            applicants in declared and contiguous counties, provided:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_4_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Presidential declaration is not solely for Category A or
            Category B Public Assistance or Hazard Mitigation Grant Assistance,
            and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_4_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Presidential Major Disaster declaration is for losses due to
            severe, general disaster conditions including but not limited to
            conditions such as flood, hurricane, or earthquake.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             [Reserved]
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>