<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol10'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XV:-:1580
    </extid>
    <num>
      1580
    </num>
    <head>
      TRADE ADJUSTMENT ASSISTANCE FOR FARMERS
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='19' sect='2401' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/19/2401.html'>
              19 U.S.C. 2401
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 9089
          </aref>
          , Mar. 1, 2010, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='13324'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XV:-:1580:-:1580.101
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1580.101
      </num>
      <head>
        General statement.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='1040' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1580' sect='101' psec='' tq='N'>
              1580.101
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General statement.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          This part provides regulations for the Trade Adjustment Assistance
          (TAA) for Farmers program as authorized by the Trade Act of 1974,
          amended by Subtitle C of Title I of the Trade Act of 2002 (
          <aref target='_blank' title='Pub. L. 107-210' alt='Pub. L. 107-210' href='http://www.gpo.gov/fdsys/pkg/PLAW-107publ210/html/PLAW-107publ210.htm'>
            Pub. L. 107-210
          </aref>
          ), and re-authorized and modified by the American Recovery and
          Reinvestment Act of 2009 (
          <aref target='_blank' title='Pub. L. 111-5' alt='Pub. L. 111-5' href='http://www.gpo.gov/fdsys/pkg/PLAW-111publ5/html/PLAW-111publ5.htm'>
            Pub. L. 111-5
          </aref>
          ). The regulations establish procedures by which a group of producers
          of raw agricultural commodities or fishermen (jointly referred to as
          “producers”) can petition for certification of eligibility and through
          which individual producers covered by a certified petition can apply
          for technical assistance and cash benefits for the development and
          implementation of approved business adjustment plans.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13325'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XV:-:1580:-:1580.102
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1580.102
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1580' sect='102' psec='' tq='N'>
              1580.102
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          As used in the part, the following terms mean:
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Agricultural commodity
          </E>
           means any commodity in its raw or natural state; found in chapters 1,
          3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 10, 12, 14, 23, 24, 41, 51, and 52 of the Harmonized
          Tariff Schedule of the United States (HTS).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Articles like
          </E>
           or 
          <E T='03'>
            directly competitive
          </E>
           generally means products falling under the same HTS number used to
          identify the agricultural commodity in the petition. A “like” product
          means substantially identical in inherent or intrinsic
          characteristics, and the term “directly competitive” means articles
          that are substantially equivalent for commercial purposes (
          <E T='03'>
            i.e.,
          </E>
           adapted to the same uses and essentially interchangeable therefore).
          For fishery products, competition could be either from farm-raised or
          wild-caught products.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Authorized representative
          </E>
           means an entity that represents a group of agricultural commodity
          producers or fishermen.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Average price received by the producer
          </E>
           means the average of the 3 marketing year prices per unit received by
          the producer from the first level of sales for the commodity.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Cash receipts
          </E>
           mean the value of commodity marketings during the calendar year,
          irrespective of the year of production, as calculated by the Economic
          Research Service of the USDA.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Certification of eligibility
          </E>
           means the date on which the Administrator (FAS) announces in the 
          <E T='04'>
            Federal Register
          </E>
           or by Department news release, whichever comes first, a certification
          of eligibility to apply for trade adjustment assistance.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Contributed importantly
          </E>
           means a cause which is important, but not necessarily more important
          than any other cause.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            County price maintained by the Secretary
          </E>
           means a daily price obtained from a USDA agency for the commodity and
          producer location, except that weekly or monthly prices may be used if
          daily prices are unavailable.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Department
          </E>
           means the U.S. Department of Agriculture.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Deputy Administrator
          </E>
           means the Deputy Administrator for Farm Programs of the Farm Service
          Agency (FSA).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Family member
          </E>
           means an individual to whom a producer is related as spouse, lineal
          ancestor, lineal descendent, or sibling, including:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Great grandparent;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Grandparent;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Parent;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Children, including legally adopted children;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Grandchildren;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Great grandchildren;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Sibling of the family member in the farming operation; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Spouse of a person listed in paragraphs (1) through (7) of this
            definition.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Filing period
          </E>
           means the dates during which petitions may be submitted, as published
          in the 
          <E T='04'>
            Federal Register.
          </E>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            FSA
          </E>
           means the Farm Service Agency of the U.S. Department of Agriculture.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Group
          </E>
           means three or more producers who are not members of the same family.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Impacted area
          </E>
           means one or more States of the United States.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Marketing year
          </E>
           means the marketing season or year designated by the Administrator
          (FAS) with respect to an agricultural commodity. In the case of an
          agricultural commodity that does not have a designated marketing year,
          a calendar year will be used.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            National average price
          </E>
           means the average price paid to producers for an agricultural
          commodity in a marketing year as determined by the National
          Agricultural Statistics Service (NASS) of the U.S. Department of
          Agriculture, or 
          <PRTPAGE P='1041' />
          the National Marine Fisheries Service of the National Oceanic and
          Atmospheric Administration, when available, or when unavailable, as
          determined by the Administrator (FAS).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            NIFA
          </E>
           means the National Institute of Food and Agriculture, the Federal
          agency within the U.S. Department of Agriculture which administers the
          Federal agricultural extension programs.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Producer
          </E>
           means a person who shares in the risk of producing an agricultural
          commodity and is entitled to a share of the commodity for marketing;
          including an operator, a sharecropper, or a person who owns or rents
          the land on which the commodity is produced; or a person who reports
          gain or loss from the trade or business of fishing on the
          person&apos;s annual Federal income tax return for the taxable year
          that most closely corresponds to the marketing year with respect to
          which a petition is filed.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Raw
          </E>
           or 
          <E T='03'>
            natural state
          </E>
           means unaltered by any process other than cleaning, grading, coating,
          sorting, trimming, mixing, conditioning, drying, dehulling, shelling,
          chilling, cooling, blanching, irradiating, or fumigating.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State Cooperative Extension Service
          </E>
           means an organization established at the land-grant college or
          university under the Smith-Lever Act of May 8, 1914, as amended (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='341-349' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/341-349.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 341-349
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ); 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 209(b) of
          </aref>
           the Act of October 26, 1974, as amended (D.C. Code, through 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            section 31-1719(b)
          </aref>
          ); or 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 1444 of
          </aref>
           the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy
          Act of 1977, as amended (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='3221' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/3221.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 3221
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            United States
          </E>
           means the 50 States of the United States, the District of Columbia,
          and Puerto Rico.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Value of production
          </E>
           means the value of commodities produced during the crop year
          calculated as production times the marketing year average price. This
          may be equal to cash receipts when the crop year for the commodity
          runs from January through December.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13326'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XV:-:1580:-:1580.201
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1580.201
      </num>
      <head>
        Petitions for trade adjustment assistance.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1580' sect='201' psec='' tq='N'>
              1580.201
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Petitions for trade adjustment assistance.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A group of producers in the United States or its authorized
            representative may file a petition for trade adjustment assistance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Filings may be written or electronic, as provided for by the
            Administrator (FAS), and submitted to FAS no later than the last day
            of the filing period announced in the 
            <E T='04'>
              Federal Register.
            </E>
             Petitions received after this date will be returned to the sender.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Petitions shall include the following information.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Name, business address, phone number, and e-mail address (if
            available) of each producer in the group, or its authorized
            representative. The petition shall identify a contact person for the
            group.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The agricultural commodity and its Harmonized Tariff Schedule of
            the United States (HTS) number.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The production area represented by the group or its authorized
            representative. The petition shall indicate if the group is filing
            on behalf of all producers in the United States, or if it is filing
            solely on behalf of all producers in a specifically identified
            impacted area. In the latter case, at least one member of the group
            must reside in each State within the impacted area.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The beginning and ending dates for the marketing year upon which
            the petition is based. A petition may be filed for only the most
            recent full marketing year for which data are available for national
            average prices, or quantity of production, or value of production,
            or cash receipts.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A justification statement explaining why the petitioners should be
            considered eligible for adjustment assistance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Supporting information justifying the basis of the petition,
            including required data for the petitioned marketing year and the
            previous 3 marketing years.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_6_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whenever possible, the petitioners shall use national average data
            compiled by the National Agricultural Statistics Service (NASS) or
            the National Marine Fisheries Service (NMFS), to determine national
            average prices, or quantity of production, or value of production,
            or cash receipts. If NASS or NMFS has not compiled such data for the
            commodity, the petitioners shall provide alternative data for the
            marketing year under review and for the 
            <PRTPAGE P='1042' />
            previous 3 marketing years, and identify the source of the data. In
            such cases the Administrator (FAS) shall determine if the
            alternative data is acceptable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_6_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the petition is filed on behalf of producers in a specifically
            identified impacted area, the petitioners shall provide the national
            average prices or county prices if applicable, or quantity of
            production or value of production, or cash receipts for the
            petitioned commodity in the impacted area for the marketing year
            under review and for the previous 3 marketing years, and
            identification of the data source.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_6_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Administrator (FAS) may request petitioners to provide records
            to support their data.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Once the petition is received, the Administrator (FAS) shall
            determine if it meets the requirements of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1580' sect='201' psec='#c' tq='N'>
                1580.201(c)
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
            , and if so, publish notice in the 
            <E T='04'>
              Federal Register
            </E>
             that a petition has been filed and that an investigation is being
            initiated. The notice shall identify the agricultural commodity,
            including any like or directly competitive commodities, the
            marketing year being investigated, the data being used, and the
            production area covered by the petition. The notice may also
            announce the scheduling of a public hearing, if requested by the
            petitioner. If the petition does not meet the requirements of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1580' sect='201' psec='#c' tq='N'>
                1580.201(c)
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
            , the Administrator (FAS) shall notify as soon as practicable the
            contact person or the authorized representative for the group of the
            deficiencies.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13327'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XV:-:1580:-:1580.202
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1580.202
      </num>
      <head>
        Hearings, petition reviews, and amendments.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1580' sect='202' psec='' tq='N'>
              1580.202
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Hearings, petition reviews, and amendments.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the petitioner, or any other person found by the Administrator
            (FAS) to have a substantial interest in the proceedings, submits not
            later than 10 days after the date of publication of notice in the 
            <E T='04'>
              Federal Register
            </E>
             under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1580' sect='201' psec='#d' tq='N'>
                1580.201(d)
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
            , a request in writing for a hearing, the Administrator (FAS) shall
            provide for a public hearing and afford such interested person an
            opportunity to be present, to produce evidence, and to be heard.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the petitioner or any other person having an interest in the
            proceedings takes issue with any of the information published in the
            
            <E T='04'>
              Federal Register
            </E>
             concerning the petition, such person may submit to the
            Administrator (FAS) their comments in writing or electronically for
            consideration by the Administrator (FAS) not later than 10 days
            after the date of publication of notice in the 
            <E T='04'>
              Federal Register
            </E>
             under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1580' sect='201' psec='#d' tq='N'>
                1580.201(d)
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A producer or group of producers that resides outside of the State
            or region identified in the petition filed under paragraph (a) of
            this section, may file a request to become a party to that petition
            not later than 15 days after the date that the notice is published
            in the 
            <E T='04'>
              Federal Register
            </E>
             under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1580' sect='201' psec='#d' tq='N'>
                1580.201(d)
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
            . The Administrator (FAS) may amend the original petition to expand
            the impacted area and include the additional filer, or consider it a
            separate filing.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Administrator (FAS) shall publish in the 
            <E T='04'>
              Federal Register
            </E>
             as soon as practicable any changes to the original notice resulting
            from any actions taken under this section.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13328'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XV:-:1580:-:1580.203
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1580.203
      </num>
      <head>
        Determination of eligibility and certification by the Administrator
        (FAS).
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1580' sect='203' psec='' tq='N'>
              1580.203
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Determination of eligibility and certification by the Administrator
          (FAS).
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             As soon as practicable after the petition has been filed, but in
            any event not later than 40 days after that date, the Administrator
            (FAS) shall certify a group of producers as eligible to apply for
            adjustment assistance under this chapter if the Administrator (FAS)
            determines:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             At least one of the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The national average price of the agricultural commodity produced
            by the group during the most recent marketing year for which data
            are available is less than 85 percent of the average of the national
            average price for the commodity in the 3 marketing years preceding
            such marketing year; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The quantity of production of the agricultural commodity produced
            by the group during such marketing year is less than 85 percent of
            the average of the quantity of production of the commodity produced
            by the group in the 3 marketing years preceding such marketing year;
            or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The value of production of the agricultural commodity produced by 
            <PRTPAGE P='1043' />
            the group during such marketing year is less than 85 percent of the
            average value of production of the commodity produced by the group
            in the 3 marketing years preceding such marketing year; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The cash receipts for the agricultural commodity produced by the
            group during such marketing year are less than 85 percent of the
            average of the cash receipts for the commodity produced by the group
            in the 3 marketing years preceding such marketing year;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The volume of imports of articles like or directly competitive with
            the agricultural commodity produced by the group in the marketing
            year with respect to which the group files the petition increased
            compared to the average volume of such imports during the 3
            marketing years preceding such marketing year; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The increase in such imports contributed importantly to the
            decrease in the national average price, or quantity of production,
            or value of production, or cash receipts for, the agricultural
            commodity.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In any case in which there are separate classes of goods within an
            agricultural commodity, the Administrator (FAS) shall treat each
            class as a separate commodity in determining:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Group eligibility;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The national average price, or quantity of production, or value of
            production, or cash receipts; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The volume of imports.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon making a determination, whether affirmative or negative, the
            Administrator (FAS) shall promptly publish in the 
            <E T='04'>
              Federal Register
            </E>
             a summary of the determination, together with the reasons for
            making the determination.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In addition, the Administrator (FAS) shall notify producers covered
            by a certification how to apply for adjustment assistance.
            Notification methods may include direct mailings to known producers,
            messages to directly affected producer groups and organizations,
            electronic communications, Web site notices on the Internet, use of
            broadcast print media, and transmittal through local USDA offices.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whenever a group of agricultural producers is certified as eligible
            to apply for assistance, the Administrator (FAS) shall notify NIFA,
            the Agricultural Marketing Service, and FSA who will assist in
            informing other producers about the TAA for Farmers program and how
            they may apply for trade adjustment assistance.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13329'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XV:-:1580:-:1580.301
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1580.301
      </num>
      <head>
        Application for trade adjustment assistance.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1580' sect='301' psec='' tq='N'>
              1580.301
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Application for trade adjustment assistance.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Only producers covered by a certification of eligibility under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1580' sect='203' psec='' tq='N'>
                1580.203
              </subref>
               of this title
            </aref>
            , may apply for adjustment assistance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An eligible producer may submit an application for adjustment
            assistance by submitting to FSA a designated application form at any
            time after the certification date but not later than 90 days after
            the certification date. If the 90-day application period ends on a
            weekend or legal holiday, the producer may apply the following
            business day.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When submitting an application, the producer shall provide
            sufficient documentation to establish that:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The producer produced the agricultural commodity in the marketing
            year for which the petition is filed and in at least 1 of the 3
            marketing years preceding that marketing year;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             There has been a decrease in the quantity of the agricultural
            commodity produced by the producer in the marketing year for which
            the petition is certified from the most recent prior marketing year
            preceding that marketing year for which data is available; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             There has been a decrease in the price of the agricultural
            commodity based on:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The price received for the agricultural commodity by the producer
            during the marketing year with respect to which the petition is
            filed from the average price for the commodity received by the
            producer in the 3 marketing years preceding that marketing year; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The effective posted county price maintained by the Secretary for
            the agricultural commodity on the date on which the Administrator
            (FAS) accepts a petition for consideration as published in the 
            <E T='04'>
              Federal Register
            </E>
             from 
            <PRTPAGE P='1044' />
            the average effective posted county level price for the commodity in
            the 3 marketing years preceding that date. If USDA prices are not
            available, prices from verifiable sources, including universities,
            cooperatives, or local markets, may be used.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a petition is certified with respect to a commodity not produced
            by the producer every year, the producer may establish the average
            price received by the producer for the commodity in the 3 marketing
            years preceding the year in which the petition is filed by using
            annual price data for the 3 most recent marketing years in which the
            producer produced the commodity.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The producer must certify that the producer has not received cash
            benefits under the Trade Adjustment Assistance for Workers or Trade
            Adjustment Assistance for Firms programs; or TAA for Farmers
            benefits based on the production of an agricultural commodity
            covered by another TAA for Farmers petition.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The producer must certify that:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For petitions certified for 2008 crops, their compliance with
            person determinations set forth in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
                1400 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , subpart B and average adjusted gross income limitation
            requirements set forth in subpart G, effective July 18, 1996.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For petitions certified for 2009 and subsequent crops, their
            average gross nonfarm income and average adjusted gross farm income
            meet requirements set forth in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
                1400 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , subpart F, and payment limitation requirements set forth in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
                1400 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , subparts A and B, effective December 29, 2008; and,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The total amount of payments made to a producer for which the
            application was approved may not exceed the limitations on payments
            applicable to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For petitions certified for 2008 crops, counter-cyclical payments,
            set forth in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
                1400 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , subpart A, effective July 18, 1996.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For petitions certified for 2009 and subsequent crops, the
            counter-cyclical payments, including the Average Crop Revenue
            Election (ACRE) set forth in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
                1400 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , subparts A and B, effective December 29, 2008; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If requested by FSA, a producer must provide documentation
            regarding average adjusted gross income and payment limitations.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13330'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XV:-:1580:-:1580.302
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1580.302
      </num>
      <head>
        Technical assistance and services.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1580' sect='302' psec='' tq='N'>
              1580.302
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Technical assistance and services.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Initial Technical Assistance:
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A producer covered by a certification who has been determined by
            FSA to meet the requirements of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1580' sect='301' psec='' tq='N'>
                1580.301
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
            , is eligible to receive Initial Technical Assistance through NIFA
            to be completed within 180 days of petition certification. Such
            assistance shall include information regarding:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Improving the yield and marketing of that agricultural commodity,
            and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The feasibility and desirability, of substituting one or more
            agricultural commodities for that agricultural commodity.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Intensive Technical Assistance:
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon completion of Initial Technical Assistance, a producer is
            eligible to participate in Intensive Technical Assistance. Intensive
            Technical Assistance shall consist of:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A series of courses to further assist the producer in improving the
            competitiveness of producing the agricultural commodity certified
            under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1580' sect='203' psec='' tq='N'>
                1580.203
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
            , or another agricultural commodity, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Assistance in developing an initial business plan based on the
            courses completed under paragraph (a) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              During Intensive Technical Assistance:
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NIFA shall deliver and the producer shall be required to attend a
            series of Intensive Technical Assistance workshops relevant to the
            circumstances of the producer.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Initial Business Plan:
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon completion of the Initial and Intensive Technical Assistance,
            the producer shall be required to develop an Initial Business Plan
            recommended by NIFA and approved by the Administrator (FAS) before
            receiving an adjustment assistance payment. The Initial Business
            Plan will:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Reflect the skills gained by the producer through the courses
            described in paragraph (c) of this section; and
            <PRTPAGE P='1045' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Demonstrate how the producer will apply those skills to the
            circumstances of the producer.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon approval of the Initial Business Plan, the producer will
            receive an amount not to exceed $4,000 to implement the Initial
            Business Plan or develop a Long-Term Business Adjustment Plan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A producer who completes the Intensive Technical Assistance and
            whose Initial Business Plan has been approved shall be eligible, in
            addition to the amount under paragraph (e) of this section, for
            assistance in developing a Long-Term Business Adjustment Plan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Long-Term Business Adjustment Plan:
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Long-Term Business Adjustment Plan shall:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Include steps reasonably calculated to materially contribute to the
            economic adjustment of the producer to changing market conditions;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Take into consideration the interests of the workers employed by
            the producer; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Demonstrate that the producer will have sufficient resources to
            implement the business plan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon recommendation by NIFA and approval of the producer&apos;s
            Long-Term Business Adjustment Plan by the Administrator (FAS), the
            producer shall be entitled to receive an amount not to exceed $8,000
            to implement their Long-Term Business Adjustment Plan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Initial Business Plan and Long-Term Business Adjustment Plan
            must be completed and approved within 36 months after a petition is
            certified.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A producer shall not receive a combined total of more than $12,000
            for the Initial Business Plan and the Long Term Business Adjustment
            Plan in the 36-month period following petition certification.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Administrator (FAS) may authorize supplemental assistance
            necessary to defray reasonable transportation and subsistence
            expenses incurred by a producer in connection with the initial
            technical assistance, if such initial technical assistance is
            provided at facilities that are not within normal commuting distance
            of the regular place of residence of the producer. NIFA and FSA will
            work with the producer and the Administrator (FAS) to facilitate
            application for and proper payment of reasonable allowable
            supplemental expenses. The Administrator (FAS) will not authorize
            payments to a producer:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='k_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For subsistence expenses that exceed the lesser of:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='k_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The actual per diem expenses for subsistence incurred by a
            producer; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='k_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The prevailing per diem allowance rate authorized under Federal
            travel regulations; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='k_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For travel expenses that exceed the prevailing mileage rate
            authorized under the Federal travel regulations.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13331'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XV:-:1580:-:1580.303
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1580.303
      </num>
      <head>
        Adjustment assistance payments.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1580' sect='303' psec='' tq='N'>
              1580.303
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Adjustment assistance payments.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the Administrator (FAS) determines that insufficient
            appropriated fiscal year funds are available to provide maximum cash
            benefits to all eligible applicants, after having deducted estimated
            transportation and substance payments and administrative and
            technical assistance costs, the Administrator (FAS) shall prorate
            cash payments to producers for the approved initial and long-term
            business plans.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any producer who may be entitled to a payment may assign their
            rights to such payment in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1404' tq='N'>
                1404
              </subref>
            </aref>
             or successor regulations as designated by the Department.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the case of death, incompetency, disappearance, or dissolution
            of a producer that is eligible to receive benefits in accordance
            with this part, such producer or producers specified in 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='707' tq='N'>
                707
              </subref>
            </aref>
             may receive such benefits.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13332'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XV:-:1580:-:1580.401
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1580.401
      </num>
      <head>
        Subsequent year petition recertification.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1580' sect='401' psec='' tq='N'>
              1580.401
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Subsequent year petition recertification.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Prior to the anniversary of the petition certification date:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Groups or authorized representatives that provided the data to
            justify their initial petition shall provide the Administrator (FAS)
            data for the most recent marketing year, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Administrator (FAS) shall make a determination with respect to
            the re-certification of petitions for the subsequent year by
            applying criteria as set forth in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1580' sect='203' psec='' tq='N'>
                1580.203
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
             for the most recent marketing year.
            <PRTPAGE P='1046' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Administrator (FAS) will promptly publish in the 
            <E T='04'>
              Federal Register
            </E>
             the determination with the reasons for the determination.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a petition is re-certified, only eligible producers who did not
            receive training and cash benefits under this program may apply.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13333'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XV:-:1580:-:1580.501
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1580.501
      </num>
      <head>
        Administration.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1580' sect='501' psec='' tq='N'>
              1580.501
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Administration.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The petition process will be administered by FAS. FAS will publish
            in the 
            <E T='04'>
              Federal Register
            </E>
             the filing dates for commodity groups to file petitions.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FSA will administer the producer application and payment process.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State and county FSA committees and representatives do not have the
            authority to modify or waive any of the provisions of this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The technical assistance process and the recommendation for
            approval of all producer business plans will be under the general
            supervision of NIFA. NIFA may award the technical assistance and
            services to a state cooperative extension service.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Deputy Administrator may, in consultation with the
            Administrator, FAS, authorize the State and County committees to
            waive or modify non-statutory deadlines or other program
            requirements in cases where lateness or failure to meet such other
            requirements by applicants does not adversely affect the operation
            of the program.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13334'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XV:-:1580:-:1580.502
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1580.502
      </num>
      <head>
        Maintenance of records, audits, and compliance.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1580' sect='502' psec='' tq='N'>
              1580.502
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Maintenance of records, audits, and compliance.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Producers making application for benefits under this program must
            maintain accurate records and accounts that will document that they
            meet all eligibility requirements specified herein, as may be
            requested. Such records and accounts must be retained for 2 years
            after the date of the final payment to the producer under this
            program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             At all times during regular business hours, authorized
            representatives of the U.S. Department of Agriculture or any agency
            thereof, the Comptroller General of the United States shall have
            access to the premises of the producer in order to inspect, examine,
            and make copies of the books, records, and accounts, and other
            written data as specified in paragraph (a) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Audits of certifications of average adjusted gross income may be
            conducted as necessary to determine compliance with the requirements
            of this subpart. As a part of this audit, income tax forms may be
            requested and if requested, must be supplied. If a producer has
            submitted information to FSA, including a certification from a
            certified public accountant or attorney, that relied upon
            information from a form previously filed with the Internal Revenue
            Service, such producer shall provide FSA a copy of any amended form
            filed with the Internal Revenue Service within 30 days of the
            filing.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If requested in writing by the U.S. Department of Agriculture or
            any agency thereof, or the Comptroller General of the United States,
            the producer shall provide all information and documentation the
            reviewing authority determines necessary to verify any information
            or certification provided under this subpart, including all
            documents referred to in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1580' sect='301' psec='#c' tq='N'>
                1580.301(c)
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
            , within 30 days. Acceptable production documentation may be
            submitted by facsimile, in person, or by mail and may include copies
            of receipts, ledgers, income statements, deposit slips, register
            tapes, invoices for custom harvesting, records to verify production
            costs, contemporaneous measurements, truck scale tickets, fish
            tickets, landing reports, and contemporaneous diaries that are
            determined acceptable. Failure to provide necessary and accurate
            information to verify compliance, or failure to comply with this
            part&apos;s requirements, will result in ineligibility for all
            program benefits subject to this part for the year or years subject
            to the request.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13335'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XV:-:1580:-:1580.503
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1580.503
      </num>
      <head>
        Recovery of overpayments.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1580' sect='503' psec='' tq='N'>
              1580.503
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Recovery of overpayments.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the Administrator (FAS) determines that any producer has
            received any payment under this program to which the producer was
            not entitled, or has expended funds received under this program for
            purpose that was not approved by the Administrator (FAS) such
            producer will be liable to repay such amount. The Administrator
            (FAS) may waive such repayment if it is determined that:
            <PRTPAGE P='1047' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The payment was made without fault on the part of the producer; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Requiring such repayment would be contrary to equity and good
            conscience.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Unless an overpayment is otherwise recovered, or waived under
            paragraph (a) of this section, the Administrator (FAS), shall
            recover the overpayment as a debt following the procedures in 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3' tq='N'>
                3
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . The requirement for demand and notice and opportunity for a
            hearing under the debt collection procedures in 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3' tq='N'>
                3
              </subref>
            </aref>
             shall satisfy the notice and hearing requirements under 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='19' sect='2401f' note='' psec='#c' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/19/2401f.html#c'>
                19 U.S.C. 2401f(c)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , and the appeal procedures in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1580' sect='505' psec='' tq='N'>
                1580.505
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
             shall not apply to collection of overpayments
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13336'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XV:-:1580:-:1580.504
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1580.504
      </num>
      <head>
        Debarment, suspension, and penalties.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1580' sect='504' psec='' tq='N'>
              1580.504
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Debarment, suspension, and penalties.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Generally.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The regulations governing Governmentwide Debarment and Suspension
            (Nonprocurement), 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3017' tq='N'>
                3017
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , and Government Requirements for Drug-Free Workplace (Financial
            Assistance), 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3021' tq='N'>
                3021
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , apply to this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Additional specific suspension and debarment provision for this
              program.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In addition to any other debarment or suspension of a producer
            under paragraph (a) of this section, in connection with this
            program, if the Administrator (FAS) or a court of competent
            jurisdiction, determines that a producer:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Knowingly has made, or caused another to make, a false statement or
            representation of a material fact, or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Knowingly has failed, or caused another to fail, to disclose a
            material fact; and, as a result of such false statement or
            representation, or of such nondisclosure, such producer has received
            any payment under this program to which the producer was not
            entitled, the Administrator (FAS) shall suspend and debar such
            producer from any future payments under this program, as provided in
            
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='19' sect='2401f' note='' psec='#b' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/19/2401f.html#b'>
                19 U.S.C. 2401f(b)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Criminal penalty.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whoever makes a false statement of a material fact knowing it to be
            false, or knowingly fails to disclose a material fact, for the
            purpose of obtaining or increasing for himself or for any other
            producer any payments authorized to be furnished under this program
            shall be fined not more that $10,000 or imprisoned for not more than
            1 year, or both.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13337'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XV:-:1580:-:1580.505
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1580.505
      </num>
      <head>
        Appeals.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1580' sect='505' psec='' tq='N'>
              1580.505
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Appeals.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A producer adversely affected by a determination with respect to
            their application for trade adjustment assistance under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1580' sect='301' psec='' tq='N'>
                1580.301
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
             or with respect to the receipt of technical assistance or payments
            under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1580' sect='302' psec='' tq='N'>
                1580.302
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
             may file a notice of appeal within 30 days of the date that the
            notification of the adverse determination was sent.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A producer may not seek judicial review of any adverse decision
            under this paragraph without receiving a final determination
            pursuant to this paragraph.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13338'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XV:-:1580:-:1580.506
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1580.506
      </num>
      <head>
        Judicial review.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1580' sect='506' psec='' tq='N'>
              1580.506
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Judicial review.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Any producer aggrieved by a final agency determination under this part
          may appeal to the U.S. Court of International Trade for a review of
          such determination in accordance with its rules and procedures.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13339'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XV:-:1580:-:1580.602
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1580.602
      </num>
      <head>
        Paperwork Reduction Act assigned number.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1580' sect='602' psec='' tq='N'>
              1580.602
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Paperwork Reduction Act assigned number.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The information collection requirements contained in this part have
          been approved by the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) under the
          provisions of 44 U.S.C. Chapter 35 and been assigned OMB control
          number 0551-0040.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>