<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol3'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:62
    </extid>
    <num>
      62
    </num>
    <head>
      LIVESTOCK, MEAT, AND OTHER AGRICULTURAL COMMODITIES (QUALITY SYSTEMS
      VERIFICATION PROGRAMS)
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          7 U.S.C. 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            Sec. 1621-1627
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            70 FR 58791
          </aref>
          , Oct. 11, 2005, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='3749'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:62:A:62.000
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        62.000
      </num>
      <head>
        Meaning of terms.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='62' sect='000' psec='' tq='N'>
              62.000
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Meaning of terms.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Words used in this subpart in the singular form shall be deemed to
          impart the plural, and vice versa, as the case may demand. For the
          purposes of such regulations, unless the context otherwise requires,
          the following terms shall be construed, respectively, to mean:
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Administrator.
          </E>
           The Administrator of the Agricultural Marketing Service (AMS), or any
          officer or employee of AMS to whom authority has heretofore been
          delegated or to whom authority may hereafter be delegated, to act in
          the Administrator&apos;s stead.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Agricultural Marketing Service.
          </E>
           The Agricultural Marketing Service of the U.S. Department of
          Agriculture.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Applicant.
          </E>
           Any individual or business with financial interest in QSVP services
          who has applied for service under this part.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Assessment.
          </E>
           A systematic review of the adequacy of program or system
          documentation, or the review of the completeness of implementation of
          a documented program or system.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Auditor.
          </E>
           Person authorized by the Livestock and Seed Program to conduct
          official assessments.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Branch.
          </E>
           The Audit, Review, and Compliance Branch of the Livestock and Seed
          Program.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Chief.
          </E>
           The Chief of the ARC Branch, or any officer or employee of the Branch
          to whom authority has heretofore been delegated, or to whom authority
          may hereafter be delegated, to act in the Chief&apos;s stead.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Conformance.
          </E>
           A user&apos;s quality manual and supporting documentation.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Deputy Administrator.
          </E>
           The Deputy Administrator of the Livestock and Seed Program, or any
          officer or employee of the Livestock and Seed Program to whom
          authority has heretofore been delegated, or to whom authority may
          hereafter be delegated, to act in the Deputy Administrator&apos;s
          stead.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Financially interested person.
          </E>
           Any individual, partnership, corporation, other legal entity, or
          Government agency having a financial interest in the involved product
          or service.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Livestock.
          </E>
           Bovine, ovine, porcine, caprine, bison or class of Osteichthyes.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Official mark.
          </E>
           Official mark or other official identification means any form of mark
          or other identification, used under the regulations to show the
          conformance of products with applicable program requirements, or to
          maintain the identity of products for which service is provided under
          the regulations.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Official memoranda or assessment reports.
          </E>
           Official memorandum means any assessment report of initial or final
          record of findings made by an authorized person of services performed
          pursuant to the regulations.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Products.
          </E>
           Includes all agricultural commodities and services within the scope
          of the Livestock and Seed Program This includes livestock, meat, meat
          products, seed, feedstuffs, as well as processes involving the
          production of these products, agricultural product data storage,
          product traceability and identification.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            QSVP Procedures.
          </E>
           Audit rules and guidelines set forth by the Agricultural 
          <PRTPAGE P='184' />
          Marketing Service regarding the development, documentation, and
          implementation of QSVP.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Quality Manual.
          </E>
           A collection of documents that describe the applicant&apos;s quality
          management system, as it applies to the requested service.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Quality Systems Verification Programs (QSVP).
          </E>
           A collection of voluntary, audit-based, user-fee programs that allow
          applicants to have program documentation and program processes
          assessed by AMS auditor(s) and other USDA officials under this part.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Regulations.
          </E>
           The regulations in this part.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            USDA.
          </E>
           The U.S. Department of Agriculture.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3750'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:62:A:62.100
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        62.100
      </num>
      <head>
        Administrator.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='62' sect='100' psec='' tq='N'>
              62.100
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Administrator.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The LS Program Deputy Administrator is charged with the administration
          of official assessments conducted according to the regulations in this
          part and approved LS Program QSVP procedures.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3751'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:62:A:62.200
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        62.200
      </num>
      <head>
        Services.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='62' sect='200' psec='' tq='N'>
              62.200
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Services.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          QSVP, under this regulation, provide applicants, the ability to have
          USDA assess documented processes or systems.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Assessment services provided under the regulations shall consist
            of:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A review of the adequacy of an applicant&apos;s quality manual
            against LS Program QSVP procedures, internationally recognized
            guidelines, or other requirements as approved by the LS Program;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An onsite assessment of the applicant&apos;s program to ensure
            implementation of provisions within the quality manual and the
            applicant&apos;s conformance with applicable program requirements
            and LS Program QSVP procedures; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A reassessment of the applicant&apos;s program to ensure continued
            implementation of provisions within the quality manual and the
            applicant&apos;s conformance with program requirements and
            applicable LS Program QSVP procedures;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Developmental assistance in the form of training to explain LS
            Program QSVP procedures is available upon request.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3752'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:62:A:62.201
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        62.201
      </num>
      <head>
        Availability of service.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='62' sect='201' psec='' tq='N'>
              62.201
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Availability of service.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          QSVP services under these regulations are available to international
          and domestic government agencies, private agricultural businesses and
          any finically interested person.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3753'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:62:A:62.202
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        62.202
      </num>
      <head>
        How to apply for service.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='62' sect='202' psec='' tq='N'>
              62.202
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          How to apply for service.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Applicants may apply for QSVP services by submitting the following
          information to the ARC Branch headquarters office at USDA, AMS, LSP,
          ARC Branch, 1400 Independence Avenue, SW., STOP 0294, Room 2627-S,
          Washington, DC 20250-0294; by fax to: (202) 690-1038, or e-mail to: 
          <E T='03'>
            ARCBranch@usda.gov.
          </E>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The original completed form LS-313, Application for Service;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A letter requesting QSVP services; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A complete copy of the applicant&apos;s program documentation, as
            described in the LS Program QSVP procedures.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3754'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:62:A:62.203
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        62.203
      </num>
      <head>
        How to withdraw service.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='62' sect='203' psec='' tq='N'>
              62.203
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          How to withdraw service.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Service may be withdrawn by the applicant at any time; provided that,
          the applicant notifies the ARC Branch in writing of his/her desire to
          withdraw the application for service and pays any expenses the
          Department has incurred in connection with such application.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3755'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:62:A:62.204
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        62.204
      </num>
      <head>
        Authority to request service.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='62' sect='204' psec='' tq='N'>
              62.204
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Authority to request service.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Any person requesting service may be required to prove his/her
          financial interest in the product or service at the discretion of the
          Deputy Administrator.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3756'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:62:A:62.205
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        62.205
      </num>
      <head>
        Conflict of interest.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='62' sect='205' psec='' tq='N'>
              62.205
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Conflict of interest.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          No USDA official shall review any program documentation or determine
          conformance of any documented process or system in which the USDA
          official has financial holdings.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3757'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:62:A:62.206
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        62.206
      </num>
      <head>
        Access to program documents and activities.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='62' sect='206' psec='' tq='N'>
              62.206
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Access to program documents and activities.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The applicant shall make its products and program documentation
            available and easily accessible for assessment, with respect to the
            requested 
            <PRTPAGE P='185' />
            service. Auditors and other USDA officials responsible for
            maintaining uniformity and accuracy of service under the regulations
            shall have access to all parts of facilities covered by approved
            applications for service under the regulations, during normal
            business hours or during periods of production, for the purpose of
            evaluating products or processes. This includes products in
            facilities which have been or are to be examined for program
            conformance or which bear any official marks of conformance. This
            further includes any facilities or operation that is part of an
            approved program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Documentation and records relating to an applicant&apos;s program
            must be retained for at least one calendar year following the
            calendar year during which the record was created.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3758'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:62:A:62.207
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        62.207
      </num>
      <head>
        Official assessment.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='62' sect='207' psec='' tq='N'>
              62.207
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Official assessment.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Official assessment of an applicant&apos;s program shall include:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Documentation assessment.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Auditors and other USDA officials shall review the applicant&apos;s
            program documentation and issue finding of the review to the
            applicant.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Program assessment.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Auditors and USDA officials shall conduct an onsite assessment of
            the applicant&apos;s program to ensure provisions of the
            applicant&apos;s program documentation have been implemented and
            conform to LS Program QSVP procedures.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Program Determination.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Applicant&apos;s determined to meet or not meet LS Program QSVP
            procedures or the applicant&apos;s program requirements shall be
            notified of their program&apos;s approval or disapproval.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Corrective and/or preventative actions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Applicants may be required to implement corrective and/or
            preventative actions upon completion of assessment. After
            implementation of corrective and/or preventative actions, the
            applicant may request another assessment.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3759'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:62:A:62.208
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        62.208
      </num>
      <head>
        Publication of QSVP assessment status.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='62' sect='208' psec='' tq='N'>
              62.208
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Publication of QSVP assessment status.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Approved programs shall be posted for public reference on the ARC
          Branch Web site: 
          <E T='03'>
            http://www.ams.usda.gov/lsg/arc/audit.htm
          </E>
          . Such postings shall include:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Program name and contact information,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Products or services covered under the scope of approval,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Effective dates of approval, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Control numbers of official assessments, as appropriate, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any other information deemed necessary by the Branch Chief.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3760'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:62:A:62.209
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        62.209
      </num>
      <head>
        Reassessment.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='62' sect='209' psec='' tq='N'>
              62.209
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Reassessment.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Approved programs are subject to periodic reassessments to ensure
          ongoing conformance with the LS Program QSVP procedures covered under
          the scope of approval. The frequency of reassessments shall be based
          on the LS Program QSVP procedures, or as determined by the Deputy
          Administrator.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3761'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:62:A:62.210
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        62.210
      </num>
      <head>
        Denial, suspension, or cancellation of service.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='62' sect='210' psec='' tq='N'>
              62.210
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Denial, suspension, or cancellation of service.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             QSVP services may be denied if an applicant fails to meet its
            program requirements, or conform to LS Program QSVP procedures, such
            as:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Adequately address any program requirement resulting in a major
            non-conformance or an accumulation of minor non-conformances that
            result in the assignment of a major non-conformance for the program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Demonstrate capability to meet any program requirement resulting in
            a major non-conformance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Present truthful and accurate information to any auditor or other
            USDA official; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Allow access to facilities and records within the scope of the
            program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             QSVP services may be suspended if the applicant fails to meet its
            program requirements, or conform to LS Program QSVP procedures; such
            as failure to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Adequately address any program requirement resulting in a major
            non-conformance;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Demonstrate capability to meet any program requirement resulting in
            a major non-conformance;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Follow and maintain it&apos;s approved program or QSVP procedures;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provide corrective actions and correction as applicable in the
            timeframe specified;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Submit significant changes to and seek approval from the Chief
            prior to 
            <PRTPAGE P='186' />
            implementation of significant changes to an approved program;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Allow access to facilities and records within the scope of the
            approved program;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Accurately represent the eligibility of agricultural products or
            services distributed under an approved program;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Remit payment for QSVP services;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Abstain from any fraudulent or deceptive practice in connection
            with any application or request for service under the rule; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Allow any auditor or other USDA official to perform their duties
            under the regulations of this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             QSVP services maybe be cancelled, an application may be rejected,
            or program assessment may be terminated if the Deputy Administrator
            or his designee determines that a nonconformance has remained
            uncorrected beyond a reasonable amount of time.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3762'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:62:A:62.211
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        62.211
      </num>
      <head>
        Appeals.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='62' sect='211' psec='' tq='N'>
              62.211
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Appeals.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Appeals of adverse decisions under this part, may be made in writing
          to the Livestock and Seed Program Deputy Administrator at STOP 0249,
          Room 2092-South, 1400 Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC
          20250-0249. Appeals must be made within 30 days of receipt of adverse
          decision.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Procedure for Appeals.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Actions under this subparagraph concerning decision of appeals of
            the Deputy Administrator shall be conducted in accordance with the
            Rule of Practice Governing Formal Adjudicatory Proceedings
            Instituted by the Secretary Under Various Statutes set forth at 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR § 
              <subref title='7' part='1' sect='130' psec='' tq='N'>
                1.130
              </subref>
            </aref>
             through 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1' sect='151' psec='' tq='N'>
                1.151
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and the Supplemental Rules of Practice in 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='50' tq='N'>
                50
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             [Reserved]
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3763'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:62:A:62.212
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        62.212
      </num>
      <head>
        Official assessment reports.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='62' sect='212' psec='' tq='N'>
              62.212
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Official assessment reports.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Official QSVP assessment reports shall be generated by the auditor at
          the conclusion of each assessment and a copy shall be provided to the
          applicant.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3764'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:62:A:62.213
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        62.213
      </num>
      <head>
        Official identification.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='62' sect='213' psec='' tq='N'>
              62.213
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Official identification.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The following, as shown in figure 1, constitutes official
          identification to show product or services produced under an approved
          USDA, Process Verified Program (PVP):
        </P>
        <P>
          Figure 1.
        </P>
        <GPH DEEP='106' SPAN='1'>
          <GID>
            ER11OC05.174
          </GID>
        </GPH>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Products or services produced under an approved USDA, PVP may use
            the “USDA Process Verified” statement and the “USDA Process
            Verified” shield, so long as, both the statement and shield are used
            in direct association with a clear description of the process
            verified points that have been approved by the Branch.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Use of the “USDA Process Verified” statement and the “USDA Process
            Verified” shield shall be approved in writing by Chief prior to use
            by an applicant.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3765'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:62:A:62.300
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        62.300
      </num>
      <head>
        Fees and other costs for service.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='62' sect='300' psec='' tq='N'>
              62.300
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Fees and other costs for service.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Fees and other charges will be levied based on the following
          provisions:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Fees for service.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Fees for QSVP services shall be based on the time required to
            provide service calculated to the nearest quarter hour period,
            including, but not limited to, official assessment time, travel
            time, and time required to prepare assessment reports. The hourly
            fee rate shall be $108 per hour.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Transportation costs.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Applicants are responsible for paying actual travel costs incurred
            to provide QSVP services including but not limited to: Mileage
            charges for use of privately owned vehicles, rental vehicles and
            gas, parking, tolls, and public transportation costs such as
            airfare, train, and taxi service.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Per diem costs.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The applicant is responsible for paying per diem costs incurred to
            provide QSVP services away from the auditor&apos;s or USDA
            officials&apos; official duty station(s). Per diem costs 
            <PRTPAGE P='187' />
            shall be calculated in accordance with existing travel regulations
            (41 CFR, subtitle F—Federal Travel Regulation System, chapter 301).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Other costs.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When costs, other than those costs specified in paragraphs (a),
            (b), and (c) of this section, are involved in providing the QSVP
            services, the applicant shall be responsible for these costs. The
            amount of these costs shall be determined administratively by the
            Chief. However, the applicant will be notified of these costs before
            the service is rendered.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3766'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:62:A:62.301
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        62.301
      </num>
      <head>
        Payment of fees and other charges.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='62' sect='301' psec='' tq='N'>
              62.301
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Payment of fees and other charges.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Fees and other charges for QSVP services shall be paid in accordance
          with the following provisions. Upon receipt of billing for fees and
          other charges, the applicant shall remit payment within 10 business
          days by check, electronic funds transfer, draft, or money order made
          payable to USDA, AMS, in accordance with directions on the billing.
          Fees and charges shall be paid in advance if required by the auditor
          or other authorized USDA official.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='3767'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:C:62:A:62.400
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        62.400
      </num>
      <head>
        OMB control number assigned pursuant to the Paperwork Reduction Act.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='62' sect='400' psec='' tq='N'>
              62.400
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          OMB control number assigned pursuant to the Paperwork Reduction Act.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The information collection and recordkeeping requirements of this part
          have been approved by OMB under 44 U.S.C. Chapter 35 and have been
          assigned OMB Control Number 0581-0124.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>