<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol15'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIV:-:3402
    </extid>
    <num>
      3402
    </num>
    <head>
      FOOD AND AGRICULTURAL SCIENCES NATIONAL NEEDS GRADUATE AND POSTGRADUATE
      FELLOWSHIP GRANTS PROGRAM
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='3316' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/3316.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 3316
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            69 FR 62537
          </aref>
          , Oct. 26, 2004, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
      <EDNOTE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Editorial Note:
        </HD>
        <P>
          Nomenclature changes to 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='3402' tq='N'>
              3402
            </subref>
          </aref>
           appear at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 4807
          </aref>
          , Jan. 27, 2011.
        </P>
      </EDNOTE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='16446'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIV:-:3402:A:3402.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3402.1
      </num>
      <head>
        Applicability of regulations.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3402' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              3402.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Applicability of regulations.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The regulations of this part apply to competitive grants awarded
            under the provisions of 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 1417(b)(6) of
            </aref>
             the National Agricultural Research, Extension and Teaching Policy
            Act of 1977, as amended, 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='3152' note='' psec='#b_6' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/3152.html#b_6'>
                7 U.S.C. 3152(b)(6)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . The Act designates the U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA) as
            the lead Federal agency for agricultural research, extension, and
            teaching in the food and agricultural sciences. 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              Section 1417(b)(6)
            </aref>
             authorizes the Secretary of Agriculture, who has delegated the
            authority to theNational Institute of Food and Agriculture (NIFA),
            to make competitive grants to land-grant colleges and universities,
            colleges and universities having significant minority enrollments
            and a demonstrable capacity to carry out the teaching of food and
            agricultural sciences, and to other colleges and universities having
            a demonstrable capacity to carry out the teaching of food and
            agricultural sciences, to administer and conduct graduate and
            postdoctoral fellowship programs to help meet the Nation&apos;s
            needs for development of scientific and professional expertise in
            the food and agricultural sciences. The Graduate Fellowships are
            intended to encourage outstanding students to pursue and complete
            graduate degrees in the areas of food and agricultural sciences
            designated by NIFA through the Office of Higher Education Programs
            (HEP) as national needs. The postdoctoral Fellowships are intended
            to provide additional mentoring and training to outstanding USDA
            Graduate Fellows who completed their doctoral degrees no more than
            five (5) years before they begin the postdoctoral Fellowships.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The regulations of this part do not apply to grants awarded by the
            Department of Agriculture under any other authority.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16447'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIV:-:3402:A:3402.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3402.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3402' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              3402.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          As used in this part:
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Citizen or national of the United States
          </E>
           means—
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A citizen or native resident of a State; or,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A person defined in the Immigration and Nationality Act, 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='8' sect='1101' note='' psec='#a_22' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/8/1101.html#a_22'>
                8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(22)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , who, though not a citizen of the United States, owes permanent
            allegiance to the United States.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            College and university
          </E>
           means an educational institution in any State which—
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Admits as regular students only persons having a certificate of
            graduation from a school providing secondary education, or the
            recognized equivalent of such a certificate,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is legally authorized within such State to provide a program of
            education beyond secondary education,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provides an educational program for which a bachelor&apos;s degree
            or any other higher degree is awarded,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is a public or other nonprofit institution, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is accredited by a nationally recognized accrediting agency or
            association.
            <PRTPAGE P='369' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Food and agricultural sciences
          </E>
           means basic, applied, and developmental research, extension, and
          teaching activities in the food, agricultural, renewable natural
          resources, forestry, and physical and social sciences in the broadest
          sense of these terms including but not limited to research, extension
          and teaching activities concerned with the production, processing,
          marketing, distribution, conservation, consumption, research, and
          development of food and agriculturally related products and services,
          inclusive of programs in agriculture, natural resources, aquaculture,
          forestry, veterinary medicine, home economics, rural development, and
          closely allied fields.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Graduate degree
          </E>
           means a master&apos;s or doctoral degree.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State
          </E>
           means any one of the fifty States, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico,
          Guam, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Marianas, the
          Federated States of Micronesia, the Republic of the Marshall Islands,
          the Republic of Palau, the Virgin Islands of the United States, and
          the District of Columbia.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Teaching activities
          </E>
           means formal classroom instruction, laboratory instruction, and
          practicum experience specific to the food and agricultural sciences
          and matters relating thereto conducted by colleges and universities
          offering baccalaureate or higher degrees.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16448'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIV:-:3402:A:3402.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3402.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Institutional eligibility.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3402' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              3402.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Institutional eligibility.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Applications may be submitted by land-grant colleges and universities,
          by colleges and universities having significant minority enrollments
          and a demonstrable capacity to carry out the teaching of food and
          agricultural sciences, and by other colleges and universities having a
          demonstrable capacity to carry out the teaching of food and
          agricultural sciences. All applicants must be institutions that confer
          a graduate degree in at least one area of the food and agricultural
          sciences targeted for National Needs Fellowships, that have a
          significant on-going commitment to the food and agricultural sciences
          generally, and that have a significant ongoing commitment to the
          specific subject area for which a grant application is made. It is the
          objective to award grants to colleges and universities which have
          notable teaching and research competencies in the food and
          agricultural sciences. The Graduate Fellowships are specifically
          intended to support programs that encourage outstanding students to
          pursue and complete a graduate degree at such institutions in an area
          of the food and agricultural sciences for which there is a national
          need for the development of scientific and professional expertise. The
          postdoctoral Fellowships are designed to support academic programs
          that provide additional training and mentoring to USDA Graduate
          Fellows and have notable teaching and research competencies in the
          NIFA designated national need areas. Institutions which currently have
          excellent programs of graduate study and training in the food and
          agricultural sciences dealing with targeted national needs are
          particularly encouraged to apply for all National Needs Fellowships.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16449'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIV:-:3402:B:3402.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3402.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Food and agricultural sciences areas targeted for National Needs
        Graduate and Postdoctoral Fellowship Grants Program support.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3402' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              3402.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Food and agricultural sciences areas targeted for National Needs
          Graduate and Postdoctoral Fellowship Grants Program support.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Areas of the food and agricultural sciences, including
          multidisciplinary studies, appropriate for Fellowship grant
          applications are those in which developing shortages of expertise have
          been determined and targeted by HEP for National Needs Graduate and
          Postdoctoral Fellowship Grants Program support. When funds are
          available and HEP determines that a new competition is warranted, the
          specific areas and funds per area will be identified in a funding
          opportunity announcement announcing the program and soliciting program
          applications.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16450'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIV:-:3402:B:3402.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3402.5
      </num>
      <head>
        Overview of National Needs Graduate and Postdoctoral Fellowship Grants
        Program.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3402' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              3402.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Overview of National Needs Graduate and Postdoctoral Fellowship Grants
          Program.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The program will provide funds for a limited number of grants to
            support graduate student stipends and cost-of-education
            institutional allowances. These grants will be awarded competitively
            to eligible institutions. In order to encourage the development of
            special activities that are expected 
            <PRTPAGE P='370' />
            to contribute to Fellows&apos; advanced degree objectives, the
            program will also provide competitive, special international study
            or thesis/dissertation research travel allowances for a limited
            number of USDA Graduate Fellows. To encourage academic institutions
            to provide additional training/mentoring to outstanding USDA
            Graduate Fellows who have completed their doctoral degrees, the
            program will also provide postdoctoral Fellowship grants to a
            limited number of USDA Graduate Fellows.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Based on the amount of funds appropriated in any fiscal year, HEP
            will determine:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whether new competitions for graduate Fellowships, postdoctoral
            Fellowships, and/or special international study or
            thesis/dissertation research travel allowances will be held during
            that fiscal year;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The degree level(s) to be supported—master&apos;s, doctoral and/or
            postdoctoral;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The proportion of appropriations to be targeted for Fellowship
            stipends for each respective degree level supported;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The proportion of appropriations to be targeted for the
            cost-of-education institutional allowances for each respective
            degree level supported;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The proportion of appropriations to be targeted for the special
            international study or thesis/dissertation research travel
            allowances for each respective degree level supported;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The allowable stipend amount for each respective degree level
            supported, the cost-of-education institutional allowance for each
            respective degree level supported, and the maximum funds available
            for each special international study or thesis/dissertation research
            travel allowance for each respective degree level supported;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The activities for which the cost-of-education allowance may be
            used for awards made in that year; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The maximum total funds that may be awarded to an institution under
            the program in a given fiscal year.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             HEP will also determine:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The maximum number of national needs areas for which funding may be
            requested in a single application;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The degree levels for which funding may be requested in a single
            application;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The minimum and maximum number of fellowships for which an
            institution may apply in a single application; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The limits on the total number of applications that can be
            submitted by an institution, college, school, or other
            administrative unit.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             These determinations will be published as a part of the
            solicitation, which will be available at 
            <E T='03'>
              http://www.grants.gov.
            </E>
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16451'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIV:-:3402:B:3402.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3402.6
      </num>
      <head>
        Overview of the special international study and/or thesis/dissertation
        research travel allowance.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3402' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              3402.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Overview of the special international study and/or thesis/dissertation
          research travel allowance.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For each USDA Graduate Fellow who desires to be considered for a
            special international study or thesis/dissertation research travel
            allowance, the Project Director must apply to HEP for a supplemental
            grant in accordance with instructions published in the solicitation.
            Postdoctoral Fellows are not eligible to receive the special
            international study or thesis/dissertation research travel
            allowance. Each application must include a “Proposal Cover Page”
            (Form NIFA-2002), “Project Summary” (Form NIFA-2003), “Budget” (Form
            NIFA-2004) and National Environmental Policy Act Exclusions Form
            (Form NIFA—2006).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To provide HEP with sufficient information upon which to evaluate
            the merits of the requests for a special international study or
            thesis/dissertation research travel allowance, each application for
            a supplemental grant must contain a narrative which provides the
            following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The specific destination(s) and duration of the travel;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The specific study or thesis/dissertation research activities in
            which the Fellow will be engaged;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             How the international experience will contribute to the
            Fellow&apos;s program of study;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A budget narrative specifying and justifying the dollar amount
            requested for the travel;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Summary credentials of the faculty or other professionals with whom
            the Fellow will be working during the international experience
            (summary 
            <PRTPAGE P='371' />
            credentials must not exceed three pages per person);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A letter from the dean of the Fellow&apos;s college or equivalent
            administrative unit supporting the Fellow&apos;s travel request and
            certifying that the travel experience will not jeopardize the
            Fellow&apos;s satisfactory progress toward degree completion; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_vii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A letter from the fellowship grant Project Director certifying the
            Fellow&apos;s eligibility, the accuracy of the Fellow&apos;s travel
            request, and the relevance of the travel to the Fellow&apos;s
            advanced degree objectives.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The narrative portion of the application must not exceed the page
            limitation included in the program solicitation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All complete requests will be evaluated by professional staff from
            USDA or other Federal agencies, as appropriate. Evaluation criteria
            will be published in the solicitation. HEP will award grants in
            accordance with evaluation criteria and to the extent possible based
            on availability of funds.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any current Fellow with sufficient time to complete the
            international experience before the termination date of the grant
            under which he/she is supported is eligible for a special
            international study or thesis/dissertation research travel
            allowance. Before the international study or thesis/dissertation
            research travel may commence, a Fellow must have completed one
            academic year of full-time study, as defined by the institution,
            under the Fellowship appointment and arrangements must have been
            formalized for the Fellow to study and/or conduct research in the
            foreign location(s).
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16452'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIV:-:3402:B:3402.7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3402.7
      </num>
      <head>
        Fellowship appointments.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3402' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              3402.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Fellowship appointments.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Fellows must be identified and Fellowships must be awarded within
            18 months of the effective date of a grant. Institutions failing to
            meet this deadline will be required to refund monies associated with
            any unawarded Fellowship(s). Graduate Fellowship appointments may be
            held only by persons who enroll and pursue full-time study in a
            graduate degree program in the national need area and at the degree
            level supported by the grant. Postdoctoral Fellowship appointments
            may be held only by persons who pursue full-time traineeship in
            research, teaching or extension in the national need area and are
            supervised by the mentor indicated in the grant application.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             It will be the responsibility of the grantee institution to award
            fellowships to students of superior academic ability.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Graduate Fellows:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Must be appointed before completing two semesters or equivalent
            hours of full-time study, as defined by the institution, or
            immediately after passing of candidacy/qualifying examinations,
            whichever is later;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Must be citizens or nationals of the United States as determined in
            accordance with Federal law; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Must have strong interest, as judged by the institution, in
            pursuing a degree in a targeted national need area and in preparing
            for a career as a food or agricultural scientist or professional.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Postdoctoral Fellows:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_4_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Must have been USDA Graduate Fellows who successfully completed
            their doctoral degrees in areas of the food and agricultural
            sciences designated by NIFA as national need areas;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_4_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Must not have obtained their doctoral degrees more than five years
            prior to beginning their postdoctoral Fellowships;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_4_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Must have strong interest, as judged by the institution, in
            preparing for a career in agricultural research, teaching or
            extension.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_5_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A doctoral level Graduate Fellow who maintains satisfactory
            progress in his or her course of study is eligible for support for a
            maximum of 36 months within a 42-month period. A master&apos;s level
            Fellow who maintains satisfactory progress in his or her course of
            study is eligible for support for a maximum of 24 months during a
            30-month period. A postdoctoral Fellow who achieves his or her
            training objectives is eligible for support for a maximum of 36
            months during a 60-month period. It is the intent of this program
            that Graduate Fellows pursue full-time uninterrupted study or
            thesis/dissertation research, including time spent pursuing
            USDA-funded special international study or thesis/dissertation
            research activities.
            <PRTPAGE P='372' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_5_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Postdoctoral Fellowship appointments may be held only by persons
            who pursue full-time traineeship in research, teaching, or extension
            in the national need area and are supervised by the mentor indicated
            in the grant application.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          However, during the period of support, USDA Graduate and Postdoctoral
          Fellows are permitted, at the discretion of their institutions, to
          accept additional supplemental employment that would positively
          contribute to their training or research and provide eligibility for
          tuition waivers (e.g., full or partial tuition waivers with research
          or teaching assignments).
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_5_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For graduate Fellows requiring additional time to complete a
            degree, it is expected that the institution will endeavor to
            continue supporting individuals originally appointed to Fellowships
            through such other institutional means as teaching assistantships
            and research assistantships. For postdoctoral Fellows who terminate
            the Fellowships prematurely, the institution must return all
            unexpended monies to USDA. For USDA Graduate Fellows who complete
            the program of study early (less than 24 months for master&apos;s
            degree or 36 months for doctoral degree) or terminate their
            Fellowships prematurely, the institution may use any unexpended
            monies, within the time remaining on the project grant, to support
            pursuit of a doctoral degree in a discipline in the food and
            agricultural sciences by a master&apos;s degree level Fellow at the
            grantee institution; or a replacement Graduate Fellow. Where less
            than one semester/quarter remains before the expiration date of the
            Graduate Fellowship grant, the institution must refund any
            unexpended monies to the granting agency. Such funds cannot be used
            to increase the annual stipend amounts for current USDA Graduate or
            Postdoctoral Fellows.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Within the framework of the regulations in this part, all decisions
            with respect to the appointment of Fellows will be made by the
            institution. However, institutions are urged to take maximum
            advantage of opportunities for awarding Fellowships to members of
            underrepresented groups at the graduate and postdoctoral level in
            the food and agricultural sciences, particularly minorities and
            women. Throughout a USDA Graduate Fellow&apos;s tenure, the
            institution should satisfy itself that the Fellow is making
            satisfactory academic progress, and carrying out, or planning to
            carry out, national needs related research. If an institution finds
            it necessary to terminate support of a USDA Graduate Fellow or a
            postdoctoral Fellow for insufficient progress or by decision on the
            part of the Fellow, the Fellow may no longer receive funds from the
            active grant. However, termination does not automatically disqualify
            a Fellow from receiving future grant support under this program. If
            a graduate or postdoctoral Fellow finds it necessary to interrupt
            his or her program of study because of health, personal reasons, or
            outside employment, the institution must reserve the funds for the
            purpose of allowing the Fellow to resume funded training any time
            within a six (6) month period. However, a USDA Graduate or
            Postdoctoral Fellow who finds it necessary to interrupt his/her
            program of training more than one time cannot exceed a total of six
            (6) months&apos; cumulative leave status without forfeiting
            eligibility. For a USDA Graduate Fellowship terminated because of
            insufficient progress, by decision on the part of the Fellow, or
            reserved due to an interrupted program but not resumed within the
            required time period, the institution may use any unexpended monies
            to support, within the time remaining on the project grant, and
            subject to the limitations above, a replacement Fellow at the same
            master&apos;s or doctoral levels. For postdoctoral Fellowships
            terminated because of insufficient progress, by decision on the part
            of the Fellow, or reserved due to an interrupted program but not
            resumed within the required time period, the institution must return
            all the unexpended monies to NIFA.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Only Fellows enrolled in master&apos;s programs of study may be
            supported under master&apos;s Fellowship grants. Master&apos;s
            degree level Fellows who complete their degree early may be
            supported under master&apos;s Fellowship grants, if they are
            enrolled in Ph.D. 
            <PRTPAGE P='373' />
            programs in areas of the food and agricultural sciences designated
            as national need areas. Only Fellows enrolled in doctoral programs
            of study may be supported under doctoral degree Fellowship grants.
            Only USDA Graduate Fellows who have completed their doctoral degrees
            may be supported under postdoctoral Fellowship grants.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16453'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIV:-:3402:B:3402.8
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3402.8
      </num>
      <head>
        Fellowship activities.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3402' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              3402.8
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Fellowship activities.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          A USDA Graduate Fellow shall be enrolled as a full-time graduate
          student, as defined by the institution, at all times during the tenure
          of the Fellowship in the national need area and at the degree level
          supported by the grant. This includes the time used for special
          international study or thesis/dissertation research, if the
          international travel is funded through a special international study
          or thesis/dissertation research travel allowance under this grant
          program. However, the normal requirement for formal registration
          during part of this tenure may be waived if permitted by the policy of
          the Fellowship institution, provided that the Graduate Fellow is
          making satisfactory progress toward degree completion and remains
          engaged in appropriate full-time Fellowship activities such as
          thesis/dissertation research. Postdoctoral Fellowship appointments may
          be held only by persons who pursue full-time traineeship in research,
          teaching, or extension in the national need area and are supervised by
          the mentor indicated in the grant application. Graduate and
          postdoctoral Fellows in academic institutions are not entitled to
          vacations as such. They are entitled to the short normal student
          holidays observed by the institution. The time between academic
          semesters or quarters is to be utilized as an active part of the grant
          period. During the period of support, USDA Graduate and Postdoctoral
          Fellows are permitted, at the discretion of their institutions, to
          accept additional supplemental employment that would positively
          contribute to their training or research and provide eligibility for
          tuition waivers (e.g., full or partial tuition waivers provided with
          research or teaching assignments). A Fellow may accept from any other
          entity a grant supporting the Fellow&apos;s research costs.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16454'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIV:-:3402:B:3402.9
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3402.9
      </num>
      <head>
        Financial provisions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3402' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
              3402.9
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Financial provisions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          An institution may elect to apply the cost-of-education/training
          institutional allowance to a Fellow&apos;s tuition, fees and
          laboratory expenses and to defray other program expenses (e.g.,
          recruitment, travel, publications, or salaries of project personnel),
          unless stated otherwise in the solicitation. Tuition and fees are the
          responsibility of the Fellow unless an institution elects to use its
          cost-of-education institutional allowance for this purpose or elects
          to pay such costs out of non-USDA monies. No dependency allowances are
          provided to any USDA Graduate or Postdoctoral Fellows. Stipend
          payments and special international study or thesis/dissertation
          research travel allowances may be made to Fellows by the institution,
          in accordance with standard institutional procedures for graduate and
          postdoctoral fellowships and assistantships.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16455'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIV:-:3402:C:3402.10
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3402.10
      </num>
      <head>
        Application package.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3402' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
              3402.10
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Application package.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Applications will be available at 
          <E T='03'>
            http://www.grants.gov
          </E>
           and through the NIFA Web site. An application package will be made
          available to any potential grant applicant upon request. This package
          will include all necessary forms and instructions to apply for a grant
          under this program.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16456'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIV:-:3402:C:3402.11
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3402.11
      </num>
      <head>
        Proposal cover page.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3402' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
              3402.11
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Proposal cover page.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The Proposal Cover Page, Form NIFA-2002, must be completed in its
          entirety, including all authorizing signatures. One copy of each grant
          application must contain the original pen-and-ink signatures, or
          approved electronic equivalent, of:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Project Director(s); and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Authorized Organizational Representative for the institution.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16457'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIV:-:3402:C:3402.12
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3402.12
      </num>
      <head>
        Project summary.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3402' sect='12' psec='' tq='N'>
              3402.12
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Project summary.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Using the Project Summary, Form NIFA-2003, applicants must summarize
          the proposed graduate program of study and/or the academic and
          research 
          <PRTPAGE P='374' />
          strengths of the institution in the national need area for which
          funding is requested. To the extent possible, applicants should
          emphasize the uniqueness of the proposed program of training. The
          summary should not include any reference to the specific number of
          fellowships requested. The information on Form NIFA-2003 will be used
          in assigning the most appropriate panelists to review an application.
          If an application is supported, this Form may be used in program
          publications.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16458'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIV:-:3402:C:3402.13
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3402.13
      </num>
      <head>
        National need narrative.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3402' sect='13' psec='' tq='N'>
              3402.13
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          National need narrative.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          HEP will determine the composition of the narrative for each
          competition, including page limits, font size, the number and the
          order of sections, and other supporting information that may be
          required. Detailed instructions for preparing the narrative will be
          published in the solicitation.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16459'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIV:-:3402:C:3402.14
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3402.14
      </num>
      <head>
        Budget and budget narrative.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3402' sect='14' psec='' tq='N'>
              3402.14
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Budget and budget narrative.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Applicants must prepare the Budget, Form NIFA-2004, and a budget
          narrative identifying all costs associated with the application.
          Instructions for completing the Budget are provided with the form.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16460'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIV:-:3402:C:3402.15
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3402.15
      </num>
      <head>
        Faculty vitae.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3402' sect='15' psec='' tq='N'>
              3402.15
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Faculty vitae.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          This section should include a Summary Vita, no more than 2 pages
          excluding publications listing, for each faculty member contributing
          significantly to institutional competence at the level of graduate
          study for the national need area addressed in the application.
          Applicants should arrange the faculty vitae with the Project
          Director(s) first, followed by the remaining faculty, in alphabetical
          order.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16461'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIV:-:3402:C:3402.16
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3402.16
      </num>
      <head>
        Appendix.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3402' sect='16' psec='' tq='N'>
              3402.16
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Appendix.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Any additional supporting information deemed essential to enhancing
          the application should be included in an appendix and referenced in
          the national need narrative.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16462'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIV:-:3402:D:3402.17
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3402.17
      </num>
      <head>
        Where to submit an application.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3402' sect='17' psec='' tq='N'>
              3402.17
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Where to submit an application.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The solicitation will indicate the date for submission of applications
          and the number of application copies required to apply for a grant. In
          addition, the solicitation will provide the address to which the
          application, the required number of accompanying duplicate copies, and
          any other required forms and materials should be sent.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16463'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIV:-:3402:D:3402.18
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3402.18
      </num>
      <head>
        Evaluation criteria.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3402' sect='18' psec='' tq='N'>
              3402.18
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Evaluation criteria.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Applications addressing a particular national need area at a
          particular Fellowship level (master&apos;s, doctoral or postdoctoral)
          will be evaluated in competition with other applications addressing
          the same national need area at the same level. Both USDA internal
          staff and the panelists will evaluate applications on the basis of the
          criteria published in the solicitation.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16464'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIV:-:3402:E:3402.19
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3402.19
      </num>
      <head>
        Terms and conditions of grant awards.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3402' sect='19' psec='' tq='N'>
              3402.19
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Terms and conditions of grant awards.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Within the limit of funds available for such purpose, the awarding
          official shall make project grants to those responsible, eligible
          applicants whose applications are judged most meritorious according to
          evaluation criteria stated in the solicitation. The beginning of the
          project period shall be no later than September 30 of the Federal
          fiscal year in which the project is approved for support. All funds
          granted under this part shall be expended solely for the purpose for
          which the funds are granted in accordance with the approved
          application and budget, the regulations of this part, the terms and
          conditions of the award, the applicable Federal cost principles, and
          the Department&apos;s assistance regulations (
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            parts 
            <subref title='7' part='3015' tq='N'>
              3015
            </subref>
             and 3019 of
          </aref>
           7 CFR).
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16465'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIV:-:3402:E:3402.20
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3402.20
      </num>
      <head>
        Other Federal statutes and regulations that apply.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='375' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3402' sect='20' psec='' tq='N'>
              3402.20
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Other Federal statutes and regulations that apply.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Several Federal statutes and regulations apply to grant applications
          considered for review and to grants awarded under this program. These
          include, but are not limited to: 
        </P>
        <EXTRACT>
          <P>
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1' tq='N'>
                1
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , subpart A—USDA implementation of the Freedom of Information Act.
          </P>
          <P>
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3' tq='N'>
                3
              </subref>
            </aref>
            —USDA implementation of OMB Circular No. A-129 regarding debt
            collection.
          </P>
          <P>
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='15' tq='N'>
                15
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , subpart A—USDA implementation of title VI of the Civil Rights Act
            of 1964, as amended.
          </P>
          <P>
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='331' tq='N'>
                331
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='9' tq='N'>
                9
              </subref>
            </aref>
             CFR 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='121' tq='N'>
                121
              </subref>
            </aref>
            —USDA implementation of the Agricultural Bioterrorism Protection Act
            of 2002.
          </P>
          <P>
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3015' tq='N'>
                3015
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , or any successor rule—USDA Uniform Federal Assistance Regulations,
            as amended, implementing OMB directives (
            <E T='03'>
              i.e.
            </E>
            , Circular Nos. A-21 and A-122) and incorporating provisions of 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='31' sect='6301-630' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/31/6301-630.html'>
                31 U.S.C. 6301-630
              </subref>
            </aref>
            8 (formerly the Federal Grant and Cooperative Agreement Act of 1977,
            Pub. L. No. 95-224), as well as general policy requirements
            applicable to recipients of Departmental financial assistance.
          </P>
          <P>
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3017' tq='N'>
                3017
              </subref>
            </aref>
            —USDA implementation of Government wide Debarment and Suspension
            (Nonprocurement) and Government wide Requirements for Drug-Free
            Workplace (Grants).
          </P>
          <P>
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3018' tq='N'>
                3018
              </subref>
            </aref>
            —USDA implementation of New Restrictions on Lobbying. Imposes
            prohibitions and requirements for disclosure and certification
            related to lobbying on recipients of Federal contracts, grants,
            cooperative agreements, and loans.
          </P>
          <P>
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3019' tq='N'>
                3019
              </subref>
            </aref>
            —USDA implementation of OMB Circular No. A-110, Uniform
            Administrative Requirements for Grants and Other Agreements with
            Institutions of Higher Education, Hospitals, and Other Nonprofit
            Organizations.
          </P>
          <P>
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3052' tq='N'>
                3052
              </subref>
            </aref>
            —USDA implementation of OMB Circular No. A-133, Audits of States,
            Local Governments, and Nonprofit Organizations.
          </P>
          <P>
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3407' tq='N'>
                3407
              </subref>
            </aref>
            —NIFA implementation of the National Environmental Policy Act.
          </P>
          <P>
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='29' sect='794' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/29/794.html'>
                29 U.S.C. 794
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              Section 504
            </aref>
            —Rehabilitation Act of 1973, and
          </P>
          <P>
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='15b' tq='N'>
                15b
              </subref>
            </aref>
             (USDA implementation of statute), prohibiting discrimination based
            upon physical or mental handicap in Federally assisted programs.
          </P>
          <P>
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='35' sect='200' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/35/200.html'>
                35 U.S.C. 200
              </subref>
            </aref>
            <E T='03'>
              et seq.
            </E>
            —Bayh-Dole Act, controlling allocation of rights to inventions made
            by employees of small business firms and domestic nonprofit
            organizations, including universities, in Federally assisted
            programs (implementing regulations are contained in 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              37 CFR part 
              <subref title='37' part='401' tq='N'>
                401
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </P>
        </EXTRACT>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16466'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIV:-:3402:E:3402.21
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3402.21
      </num>
      <head>
        Confidential aspects of applications and awards.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3402' sect='21' psec='' tq='N'>
              3402.21
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Confidential aspects of applications and awards.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          When an application results in a grant, the application and supporting
          information become part of the record of NIFA transactions, and
          available to the public upon specific request. Information that the
          Secretary determines to be of a confidential, privileged, or
          proprietary nature will be held in confidence to the extent permitted
          by law. Therefore, any information that the applicant wishes to have
          considered as confidential, privileged, or proprietary should be
          clearly marked within the application. The original copy of an
          application that does not result in a grant will be retained by the
          Agency for a period of one year. Other copies will be destroyed. Such
          an application will be released only with the consent of the applicant
          or to the extent required by law. An application may be withdrawn at
          any time prior to the final action thereon.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16467'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIV:-:3402:E:3402.22
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3402.22
      </num>
      <head>
        Access to peer review information.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3402' sect='22' psec='' tq='N'>
              3402.22
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Access to peer review information.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          After final decisions have been announced, HEP will, upon request,
          inform the PD of the reasons for its decision on an application.
          Verbatim copies of summary reviews, not including the identity of the
          reviewers, will be made available to respective PDs upon specific
          request.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16468'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIV:-:3402:E:3402.23
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3402.23
      </num>
      <head>
        Documentation of progress on funded projects.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3402' sect='23' psec='' tq='N'>
              3402.23
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Documentation of progress on funded projects.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Fellowships/Scholarships Entry/Exit Forms (Form NIFA-2010) are
            available from NIFA upon request. Upon request by HEP, Project
            Directors awarded Graduate Fellowship (excluding supplemental
            international and postdoctoral) grants under the program shall
            complete and submit this form.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Appointment Information shall be submitted to HEP within 3 months
            of appointment of a Fellow;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Project Director shall submit an annual update of each
            Fellow&apos;s progress to HEP by September 30 each year. Additional
            progress reports may be needed to assess continuing progress of
            Fellows supported by any special 
            <PRTPAGE P='376' />
            international study or thesis/dissertation research allowance and/or
            institutional adherence to program guidelines.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Exit Information shall be completed and submitted to HEP by the
            Project Director for each Fellow supported by a grant as soon as a
            Fellow either: Graduates; is officially terminated from the
            Fellowship or the academic program due to unsatisfactory academic
            progress; or voluntarily withdraws from the Fellowship or the
            academic program. If a Fellow has not completed all degree
            requirements at the end of the five-year grant duration, HEP may
            request a preliminary exit report. In such a case, a final exit
            report shall be required at a later date. When a final exit report
            for each Fellow supported by a grant has been accepted by HEP, the
            grantee will have satisfied the requirement of a final performance
            report for the grant. Additional follow-up reports to track
            Fellows&apos; career patterns may be requested.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All grantees (supplemental international, graduate, and
            postdoctoral) shall submit initial project information and annual
            and summary reports to NIFA&apos; Current Research Information
            System (CRIS). The CRIS database contains narrative project
            information, progress/impact statements, and final technical reports
            that are made available to the public. For applications recommended
            for funding, instructions on preparation and submission of project
            documentation will be provided to the applicant by the agency
            contact. Documentation must be submitted to CRIS before NIFA funds
            will be released. Project reports will be requested by the CRIS
            office when required. For more information about CRIS, visit 
            <E T='03'>
              http://cris.nifa.usda.gov.
            </E>
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16469'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXIV:-:3402:E:3402.24
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3402.24
      </num>
      <head>
        Evaluation of program.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3402' sect='24' psec='' tq='N'>
              3402.24
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Evaluation of program.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Grantees should be aware that HEP may, as a part of its own program
          evaluation activities, carry out in-depth evaluations of assisted
          activities through independent third parties. Thus, grantees should be
          prepared to cooperate with evaluators retained by HEP to analyze both
          the institutional context and the impact of any supported project.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>