<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol4'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:A:240
    </extid>
    <num>
      240
    </num>
    <head>
      CASH IN LIEU OF DONATED FOODS
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='42' sect='612c' note='notes' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/42/612c.html'>
              42 U.S.C. 612c note,
            </subref>
          </aref>
           1751, 1755, 1762a, 1765, 1766, 1779.
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            47 FR 15982
          </aref>
          , Apr. 13, 1982, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='4652'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:A:240:-:240.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        240.1
      </num>
      <head>
        General purpose and scope.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          47 FR 15982
        </aref>
        , Apr. 13, 1982, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          52 FR 7267
        </aref>
        , Mar. 10, 1987; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 39120
        </aref>
        , July 22, 1993]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='240' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              240.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General purpose and scope.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each school year the Department programs agricultural commodities
            and other foods to States for delivery to program and commodity
            schools, nonresidential child care institutions, and service
            institutions pursuant to the regulations governing the donation of
            foods for use in the United States, its territories and possessions
            and areas under its jurisdiction (
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='250' tq='N'>
                250
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              Section 6(b) of
            </aref>
             the Act requires that not later than June 1 of each school year,
            the Secretary shall make an estimate of the value of the
            agricultural commodities and other foods that will be delivered
            during that school year for use in lunch programs by schools
            participating in the National School Lunch Program (
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='210' tq='N'>
                210
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ). If this estimate is less than the total level of assistance
            authorized under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 6(e) of
            </aref>
             the Act the Secretary shall pay to the State administering agency
            not later than July 1 of that school year, an amount of funds equal
            to the difference between the value of donated foods as then
            programmed for that school year and the total level of assistance
            authorized under such section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              Section 6(e)(1) of
            </aref>
             the Act requires:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             That for each school year, the total commodity assistance, or cash
            in lieu thereof, available to each State for the National School
            Lunch Program shall be the amount obtained by multiplying the
            national average value of donated foods, described in paragraph
            (c)(2) of this section, by the number of 
            <PRTPAGE P='310' />
            lunches served in that State in the preceding school year; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             That the national average value of foods donated to schools
            participating in the National School Lunch Program, or cash payments
            made in lieu thereof, shall be 11 cents, adjusted on July 1, 1982,
            and each July 1 thereafter to reflect changes in the Price Index for
            Food Used in Schools and Institutions. 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              Section 6(e)(1)
            </aref>
             further requires that not less than 75 percent of the assistance
            under that section shall be in the form of donated foods for the
            National School Lunch Program. After the end of each school year,
            FNS shall reconcile the number of lunches served by schools in each
            State with the number served in the preceding school year and, based
            on such reconciliation, shall increase or reduce subsequent
            commodity assistance or cash in lieu thereof provided to each State.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              Section 12(g) of
            </aref>
             the Act provides that whoever embezzles, willfully misapplies,
            steals, or obtains by fraud any funds, assets, or property that are
            the subject of a grant or other form of assistance under this Act or
            the Child Nutrition Act of 1966, whether received directly or
            indirectly from the United States Department of Agriculture, or
            whoever receives, conceals, or retains such funds, assets, or
            property to his use or gain, knowing such funds, assets, or property
            have been embezzled, willfully misapplied, stolen, or obtained by
            fraud shall, if such funds, assets, or property are of the value of
            $100 or more, be fined not more than $10,000 or imprisoned not more
            than five years, or both, or, if such funds, assets, or property are
            of a value of less than $100, shall be fined not more than $1,000 or
            imprisoned for not more than one year, or both.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              Section 14(f) of
            </aref>
             the Act provides that the value of foods donated to States for use
            in commodity schools for any school year shall be the sum of the
            national average value of donated foods established under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 6(e) of
            </aref>
             the Act and the national average payment established under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 4 of
            </aref>
             the Act. 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              Section 14(f)
            </aref>
             also provides that such schools shall be eligible to receive up to
            five cents of such value in cash for processing and handling
            expenses related to the use of the donated foods.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              Sections 17(h)(1) (B) and (C) of
            </aref>
             the Act provide that the value of commodities, or cash in lieu
            thereof, donated to States for use in nonresidential child or adult
            care institutions participating in the Child and Adult Care Food
            Program (
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='226' tq='N'>
                226
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) for any school year shall be, at a minimum, the amount obtained by
            multiplying the number of lunches and suppers served during the
            preceding school year by the rate established for lunches for that
            school year under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 6(e) of
            </aref>
             the Act. At the end of each school year, FNS shall reconcile the
            number of lunches and suppers served in participating institutions
            in each State during such school year with the number of lunches and
            suppers served in the preceding school year and, based on such
            reconciliation, shall increase or reduce subsequent commodity
            assistance or cash in lieu of commodities provided to each State.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              Section 16 of
            </aref>
             the Act provides that a State which has phased out its food
            distribution facilities prior to June 30, 1974, may elect to receive
            cash payments in lieu of donated foods for the purposes of the
            applicable child nutrition programs—i.e., the National School Lunch
            Program, the Summer Food Service Program for Children (
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='225' tq='N'>
                225
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) and the Child Care Food Program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             These regulations prescribe the methods for determination of the
            amount of payments, the manner of disbursement and the requirements
            for accountability for funds when these respective statutory
            authorities require the Department to make cash payments in lieu of
            donating agricultural commodities and other foods.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            47 FR 15982
          </aref>
          , Apr. 13, 1982, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            52 FR 7267
          </aref>
          , Mar. 10, 1987; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 39120
          </aref>
          , July 22, 1993]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4653'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:A:240:-:240.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        240.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='240' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              240.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          For the purpose of this part the term:
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Act
          </E>
           means the National School Lunch Act, as amended.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Child Care Food Program
          </E>
           means the Program authorized by 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 17 of
          </aref>
           the Act.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Commodity school
          </E>
           means a school that does not participate in the National School Lunch
          Program under 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='210' tq='N'>
              210 of this chapter
            </subref>
          </aref>
           but which operates a 
          <PRTPAGE P='311' />
          nonprofit lunch program under agreement with the State educational
          agency or FNSRO and receives donated foods, or donated foods and cash
          or services of a value of up to 5 cents per lunch in lieu of donated
          foods under this part for processing and handling the foods.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Department
          </E>
           means the U.S. Department of Agriculture.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Distributing agencies
          </E>
           means State, Federal or private agencies which enter into agreements
          with the Department for the distribution of donated foods to program
          schools, commodity schools, and nonresidential child care
          institutions.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Donated-food processing and handling expenses
          </E>
           means any expenses incurred by or on behalf of a commodity school for
          processing or other aspects of the preparation, delivery, and storage
          of donated foods for use in its lunch program.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Donated foods
          </E>
           means foods donated, or available for donation, by the Department
          under any of the legislation referred to in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='250' tq='N'>
              250 of this chapter
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Fiscal year
          </E>
           means the period of 12 months beginning October 1 of any calendar
          year and ending September 30 of the following calendar year.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            FNS
          </E>
           means the Food and Nutrition Service of the Department.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            FNSRO
          </E>
           means the appropriate Food and Nutrition Service Regional Office.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            National School Lunch Program
          </E>
           means the Program authorized by 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            sections 4 and 11 of
          </aref>
           the Act.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Nonprofit
          </E>
           means exempt from income tax under 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 501(c)(3) of
          </aref>
           the Internal Revenue Code of 1954, as amended; or in the Commonwealth
          of Puerto Rico, certified as nonprofit by its Governor.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Nonresidential child care institution
          </E>
           means any child care center, day care home, or sponsoring
          organization (as those terms are defined in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='226' tq='N'>
              226 of this chapter
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ) which participates in the Child Care Food Program.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Program school
          </E>
           means a school which participates in the National School Lunch
          Program.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            School
          </E>
           means (1) an educational unit of high school grade or under except
          for a private school with an average yearly tuition exceeding $1,500
          per child, operating under public or nonprofit private ownership in a
          single building or complex of buildings. The term “high school grade
          or under” includes classes of preprimary grade when they are conducted
          in a school having classes of primary or higher grade, or when they
          are recognized as a part of the educational system in the State,
          regardless of whether such preprimary grade classes are conducted in a
          school having classes of primary or higher grade; (2) with the
          exception of residential summer camps which participate in the Summer
          Food Service Program for Children, Job Corps centers funded by the
          Department of Labor and private foster homes, any public or nonprofit
          private child care institution, or distinct part of such institution,
          which (i) maintains children in residence, (ii) operates principally
          for the care of children, and (iii) if private, is licensed to provide
          residential child care services under the appropriate licensing code
          by the State or a subordinate level of government. The term “child
          care institutions” includes, but is not limited to: homes for the
          mentally retarded, the emotionally disturbed, the physically
          handicapped, and unmarried mothers and their infants; group homes;
          halfway houses; orphanages; temporary shelters for abused children and
          for runaway children; long-term care facilities for chronically ill
          children; and juvenile detention centers; and (3) with respect to the
          Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, nonprofit child care centers certified as
          such by the Governor of Puerto Rico.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            School food authority
          </E>
           means the governing body which is responsible for the administration
          of one or more schools and which has the legal authority to operate a
          nonprofit lunch program therein.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            School year
          </E>
           means the period of 12 months beginning July 1 of any calendar year
          and ending June 30 of the following calendar year.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Secretary
          </E>
           means the Secretary of Agriculture.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Service institutions
          </E>
           means camps or sponsors (as those terms are defined in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='225' tq='N'>
              225 of this chapter
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ) which participate in the Summer Food Service Program for Children.
          <PRTPAGE P='312' />
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Special needs children
          </E>
           means children who are emotionally, mentally or physically
          handicapped.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State
          </E>
           means any of the 50 States, the District of Columbia, the
          Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American-Samoa,
          the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, or the Commonwealth of the
          Northern Mariana Islands.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State agency
          </E>
           means the State educational agency or such other agency of the State
          as has been designated by the Governor or other appropriate executive
          or legislative authority of the State and approved by the Department
          to administer, in the State, the National School Lunch Program, the
          Child Care Food Program, the Summer Food Service Program for Children,
          or nonprofit lunch programs in commodity schools.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State educational agency
          </E>
           means, as the State legislature may determine, (1) the chief State
          school officer (such as the State Superintendent of Public
          Instruction, Commissioner of Education, or similar officer), or (2) a
          board of education controlling the State Department of Education.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Summer Food Service Program for Children
          </E>
           means the Program authorized by 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 13 of
          </aref>
           the Act.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Tuition
          </E>
           means any educational expense required by the school as part of the
          students&apos; educational program; not including transportation fees
          for commuting to and from school, and the cost of room and board. The
          following monies shall not be included when calculating a
          school&apos;s average yearly tuition per child:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Academic scholarship aid from public or private organizations or
            entities given to students, or to schools for students, and (2)
            state, county or local funds provided to schools operating
            principally for the purpose of educating handicapped or other
            special needs children for whose education the State, county or
            local government is primarily or solely responsible. In a school
            which varies tuition, the average yearly tuition shall be calculated
            by dividing the total tuition receipts for the current school year
            by the total number of students enrolled for purposes of determining
            if the average yearly tuition exceeds $1,500 per child.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4654'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:A:240:-:240.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        240.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Cash in lieu of donated foods for program schools.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          47 FR 15982
        </aref>
        , Apr. 13, 1982, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          52 FR 7267
        </aref>
        , Mar. 10, 1987; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 39120
        </aref>
        , July 22, 1993]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='240' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              240.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Cash in lieu of donated foods for program schools.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Not later than June 1 of each school year, FNS shall make an
            estimate of the value of agricultural commodities and other foods
            that will be delivered to States during the school year under the
            food distribution regulations (
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='250' tq='N'>
                250
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) for use in program schools. If the estimated value is less than
            the total value of assistance authorized under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 6(e) of
            </aref>
             the Act for the National School Lunch Program, FNS shall determine
            the difference between the value of the foods then programmed for
            each State for the school year and the required value and shall pay
            the difference to each State agency not later than July 1 of that
            school year.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, in any State
            in which FNS administers the National School Lunch Program in any of
            the schools of the State, FNS shall withhold from the funds payable
            to that State under this section an amount equal to the ratio of the
            number of lunches served in schools in which the program is
            administered by FNS to the total number of lunches served in all
            program schools in the State.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            47 FR 15982
          </aref>
          , Apr. 13, 1982, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            52 FR 7267
          </aref>
          , Mar. 10, 1987; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 39120
          </aref>
          , July 22, 1993]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4655'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:A:240:-:240.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        240.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Cash in lieu of donated foods for nonresidential child and adult care
        institutions.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          47 FR 15982
        </aref>
        , Apr. 13, 1982, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 39120
        </aref>
        , July 22, 1993]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='240' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              240.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Cash in lieu of donated foods for nonresidential child and adult care
          institutions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For each school year any State agency may, upon application to FNS
            prior to the beginning of the school year, elect to receive cash in
            lieu of donated foods for use in nonresidential child care or adult
            care institutions participating in the Child and Adult Care Food
            Program. FNS shall pay each State agency making such election, at a
            minimum, an amount calculated by multiplying the number of lunches
            and suppers served in the State&apos;s nonresidential child and
            adult care institutions which meet the meal pattern requirements
            prescribed in the regulations for the Child and Adult Care Food
            Program under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='226' tq='N'>
                226 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
             by the national average value of donated food prescribed in 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 6(e)(1) of
            </aref>
             the Act. However, if a 
            <PRTPAGE P='313' />
            State agency has elected to receive a combination of donated foods
            and cash, the required amount shall be reduced based upon the number
            of such lunches and suppers served for which the State receives
            donated foods.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notwithstanding any other provision of this section in any State in
            which FNS administers the Child Care Food Program in any
            nonresidential child care institution, FNS shall withhold from the
            funds payable to such State under this section an amount equal to
            the ratio of the number of lunches and suppers served in such
            institutions in which the program is administered by the FNS and for
            which cash payments are provided to the total number of lunches and
            suppers served in that program and for which cash in lieu of
            payments are received, in all nonresidential child care institutions
            in the State.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            47 FR 15982
          </aref>
          , Apr. 13, 1982, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 39120
          </aref>
          , July 22, 1993]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4656'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:A:240:-:240.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        240.5
      </num>
      <head>
        Cash in lieu of donated foods for commodity schools.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='240' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              240.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Cash in lieu of donated foods for commodity schools.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The school food authority of a commodity school may elect (1) to
            receive cash payments in lieu of up to five cents per lunch of the
            value specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='250' sect='4' psec='#b_2_ii' tq='N'>
                250.4(b)(2)(ii)
              </subref>
               of this chapter
            </aref>
             to be used for donated-food processing and handling expenses, or
            (2) to have such payments retained for use on its behalf by the
            State agency. The school food authority shall consult with commodity
            schools before making the election.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When a school food authority makes an election regarding receipt of
            cash payments and the amount of any payments to be received under
            this paragraph, such election shall be binding on the school food
            authority for the school year to which the election applies.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall (1) no later than May 14, 1982 for the
            school year ending June 30, 1982, and no later than August 15 of
            each subsequent school year, contact all school food authorities of
            commodity schools to learn their election regarding cash payments
            under this section and the amount of any such payments, and (2)
            forward this information to the distributing agency and FNSRO, in
            accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='210' sect='14' psec='#d_2' tq='N'>
                210.14(d)(2)
              </subref>
               of this chapter
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4657'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:A:240:-:240.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        240.6
      </num>
      <head>
        Funds for States which have phased out facilities.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          47 FR 15982
        </aref>
        , Apr. 13, 1982, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 39120
        </aref>
        , July 22, 1993]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='240' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              240.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Funds for States which have phased out facilities.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Notwithstanding any other provision of this part, any State which
          phased out its food distribution facilities prior to June 30, 1974,
          may, for purposes of the National School Lunch Program, the Summer
          Food Service Program for Children, and the Child Care Food Program,
          elect to receive cash payments in lieu of donated foods. Where such an
          election is made, FNS shall make cash payments to such State in an
          amount equivalent in value to the donated foods (or cash in lieu
          thereof) to which the State would otherwise have been entitled under 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 6(e) of
          </aref>
           the Act, if it had retained its food distribution facilities, except
          that the amount may be based on the number of meals served in the
          current school year, rather than on the number of meals served in the
          preceding school year with a subsequent reconciliation.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            47 FR 15982
          </aref>
          , Apr. 13, 1982, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 39120
          </aref>
          , July 22, 1993]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4658'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:A:240:-:240.7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        240.7
      </num>
      <head>
        Payments to States.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='240' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              240.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Payments to States.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Funds to be paid to any State agency under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='240' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
                240.3
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
             for disbursement to program schools shall be made available by
            means of United States Treasury Department checks. The State agency
            shall use the funds received without delay for the purpose for which
            issued.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Funds to be paid to any State agency under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='240' sect='4' psec='#a' tq='N'>
                240.4(a)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             for disbursement to nonresidential child care institutions and
            funds to be paid to any State agency under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='240' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
                240.6
              </subref>
            </aref>
             for disbursement to program schools, service institutions, or
            nonresidential child care institutions shall be made available by
            means of Letters of Credit issued by FNS in favor of the State
            agency. The State agency shall:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Obtain funds needed to pay school food authorities, nonresidential
            child care institutions, and service institutions, as applicable
            through presentation by designated State Officials of a Payment
            Voucher on Letter of Credit (Treasury Form GFO 7578) in accordance
            with procedures prescribed by 
            <PRTPAGE P='314' />
            FNS and approved by the United States Treasury Department;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Submit requests for funds on a monthly basis in such amounts as
            necessary to make payments with respect to meals served the previous
            month;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Use the funds received without delay for the purpose for which
            drawn.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS shall make any cash payments elected under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='240' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
                240.5
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
             by increasing the amount of the Letter of Credit or, where
            applicable, of the Federal Treasury check, in accordance with the
            information provided under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='240' sect='5' psec='#c' tq='N'>
                240.5(c)
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Funds received by State agencies pursuant to this part for
            disbursement to program schools and to commodity schools shall not
            be subject to the matching provisions of 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              § 210.6 of
            </aref>
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='210' tq='N'>
                210 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4659'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:A:240:-:240.8
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        240.8
      </num>
      <head>
        Payments to program schools, service institutions, nonresidential child
        care institutions and commodity schools.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='240' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              240.8
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Payments to program schools, service institutions, nonresidential
          child care institutions and commodity schools.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each State agency shall promptly and equitably disburse any cash
            received in lieu of donated foods under this part to eligible
            program schools, service institutions and nonresidential child care
            institutions, as applicable. Funds withheld from States under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='240' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
                240.3
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='240' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
                240.4
              </subref>
            </aref>
             shall be disbursed to eligible program schools, service
            institutions, and nonresidential child care institutions by
            FNSRO&apos;s in the same manner.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Unless the school food authority of a commodity school elects to
            have cash payments for donated-food processing and handling expenses
            retained for use on its behalf by the State agency, the State agency
            shall make such payments to the school food authority of such a
            school on a monthly basis in an amount equal to the number of
            lunches served (as reported in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='210' sect='13' psec='#a' tq='N'>
                210.13(a)
              </subref>
               of this chapter
            </aref>
            ) times the value per lunch elected by the school food authority in
            accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='240' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
                240.5
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
            . For the period November 11, 1981, through the close of the month
            in which this part is published in the 
            <E T='04'>
              Federal Register,
            </E>
             a retroactive payment shall be made, where applicable, to the
            school food authority of a commodity school based on the number of
            lunches served during that period which meet the nutritional
            requirements specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='210' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
                210.10
              </subref>
               of this chapter
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4660'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:A:240:-:240.9
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        240.9
      </num>
      <head>
        Use of funds.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='240' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
              240.9
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Use of funds.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Funds made available to school food authorities (for program
            schools), service institutions and nonresidential child care
            institutions under this part shall be used only to purchase United
            States agricultural commodities and other foods for use in their
            food service under the National School Lunch Program, Child Care
            Food Program, or Summer Food Service Program for Children, as
            applicable. Such foods shall be limited to those necessary to meet
            the requirements set forth in 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              § 210.10 of
            </aref>
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='210' tq='N'>
                210 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              § 225.10 of
            </aref>
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='225' tq='N'>
                225 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              § 226.10 of
            </aref>
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='226' tq='N'>
                226 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , respectively. On or before disbursing funds to school food
            authorities (for program schools), service institutions and
            nonresidential child care institutions, State agencies and
            FNSRO&apos;s shall notify them of the reason for special
            disbursement, the purpose for which these funds may be used, and, if
            possible, the amount of funds they will receive.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Cash payments received under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='240' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
                240.5
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
             shall be used only to pay donated-food processing and handling
            expenses of commodity schools.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Funds provided under this part shall be subject to the
            Department&apos;s Uniform Federal Assistance Regulations (
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3015' tq='N'>
                3015
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4661'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:A:240:-:240.10
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        240.10
      </num>
      <head>
        Unobligated funds.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='240' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
              240.10
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Unobligated funds.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          State agencies shall release to FNS any funds paid to them under this
          part which are unobligated at the end of each fiscal year. Release of
          funds by any State agency shall be made as soon as practicable, but in
          any event, not later than 30 days following demand by FNS. Release of
          funds shall be reflected by a related adjustment in the State
          agency&apos;s Letter of Credit where appropriate or payment by State
          check where the funds have been paid by United States Treasury
          Department check.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4662'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:A:240:-:240.11
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        240.11
      </num>
      <head>
        Records and reports.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='315' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='240' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
              240.11
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Records and reports.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State agencies and distributing agencies shall maintain records and
            reports on the receipt and disbursement of funds made available
            under this part, and shall retain such records and reports for a
            period of three years after the end of the fiscal year to which they
            pertain, except that, if audit findings have not been resolved, the
            records shall be retained beyond the three-year period as long as
            required for the resolution of the issues raised by the audit.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State agencies shall establish controls and procedures which will
            assure that the funds made available under this part are not
            included in determining the State&apos;s matching requirements under
            
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              § 210.6 of
            </aref>
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='210' tq='N'>
                210 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>