<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol6'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:IV:-:402
    </extid>
    <num>
      402
    </num>
    <head>
      CATASTROPHIC RISK PROTECTION ENDORSEMENT
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='1506' note='' psec='#l' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1506.html#l'>
              7 U.S.C. 1506(l)
            </subref>
            , 
            <subref title='7' sect='1506' psec='#o' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1506.html#o'>
              1506(o)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            61 FR 42985
          </aref>
          , Aug. 20, 1996, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='5861'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:IV:-:402:-:402.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        402.1
      </num>
      <head>
        General statement.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='402' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              402.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General statement.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The Federal Crop Insurance Act, as amended by the Federal Crop
          Insurance Reform Act of 1994, requires the Federal Crop Insurance
          Corporation to implement a catastrophic risk protection plan of
          insurance that provides a basic level of insurance coverage to protect
          producers in the event of a catastrophic crop loss due to loss of
          yield or prevented planting, if provided by the Corporation, provided
          the crop loss or prevented planting is due to an insured cause of loss
          specified in the crop insurance policy. This Catastrophic Risk
          Protection Endorsement is a continuous endorsement that is effective
          in conjunction with a crop insurance policy for the insured crop.
          Catastrophic risk protection coverage will be offered through approved
          insurance providers if there are a sufficient number available to
          service the area. If there are an insufficient number available, as
          determined by the Secretary, local offices of the Farm Service Agency
          will provide catastrophic risk protection coverage.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5862'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:IV:-:402:-:402.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        402.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Applicability.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='402' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              402.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Applicability.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          This Catastrophic Risk Protection Endorsement is applicable to each
          crop for which catastrophic risk protection coverage is available and
          for which the producer elects such coverage.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5863'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:IV:-:402:-:402.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        402.3
      </num>
      <head>
        OMB control numbers.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          61 FR 42985
        </aref>
        , Aug. 20, 1996, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          69 FR 48730
        </aref>
        , Aug. 10, 2004]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='76' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='402' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              402.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          OMB control numbers.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The information collection activity associated with this rule has been
          approved by the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) pursuant to the
          Paperwork Reduction Act of 1995 (44 U.S.C. chapter 35) under OMB
          control number 0563-0053.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            61 FR 42985
          </aref>
          , Aug. 20, 1996, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            69 FR 48730
          </aref>
          , Aug. 10, 2004]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='5864'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:IV:-:402:-:402.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        402.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Catastrophic Risk Protection Endorsement Provisions.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          61 FR 42985
        </aref>
        , Aug. 20, 1996, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          63 FR 40631
        </aref>
        , July 30, 1998; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          64 FR 40740
        </aref>
        , July 28, 1999; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          65 FR 40484
        </aref>
        , June 30, 2000; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          69 FR 48730
        </aref>
        , Aug. 10, 2004; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          73 FR 36408
        </aref>
        , June 27, 2008; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          73 FR 70864
        </aref>
        , Nov. 24, 2008]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='402' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              402.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Catastrophic Risk Protection Endorsement Provisions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <EXTRACT>
          <HD SOURCE='HD1'>
            Department of Agriculture
          </HD>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            Federal Crop Insurance Corporation
          </HD>
          <HD SOURCE='HD2'>
            Catastrophic Risk Protection Endorsement
          </HD>
          <FP>
            (This is a continuous endorsement)
          </FP>
          <P>
            If a conflict exists between this Endorsement and any of the
            policies specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 2
            </aref>
             or the Special Provisions for the insured crop, this endorsement
            will control.
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD2'>
            Terms and Conditions
          </HD>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            1. Definitions
          </HD>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Approved insurance provider.
            </E>
             A private insurance company, including its agents, that has been
            approved and reinsured by FCIC to provide insurance coverage to
            producers participating in the Federal Crop Insurance program.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Approved yield.
            </E>
             The amount of production per acre computed in accordance with
            FCIC&apos;s actual production history program (
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='400' tq='N'>
                400
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , subpart G) or for crops not included under 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='400' tq='N'>
                400
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , subpart G, the yield used to determine the guarantee in accordance
            with the Crop Provisions or the Special Provisions, and any
            adjustments elected in accordance with 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 36 of
            </aref>
             the Basic Provisions.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              County.
            </E>
             The political subdivision of a state listed in the actuarial table
            and designated on your accepted application, including land in an
            adjoining county, provided such land is part of a field that extends
            into the adjoining county and the county boundary is not readily
            discernable. For peanuts and tobacco, the county will also include
            any land identified by a FSA farm serial number for the county but
            physically located in another county.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Expected market price.
            </E>
             (price election) The price per unit of production (or other basis
            as determined by FCIC) anticipated during the period the insured
            crop normally is marketed by producers. This price will be set by
            FCIC before the sales closing date for the crop. The expected market
            price may be less than the actual price paid by buyers if such price
            typically includes remuneration for significant amounts of
            post-production expenses such as conditioning, culling, sorting,
            packing, etc.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              FCIC.
            </E>
             The Federal Crop Insurance Corporation, a wholly owned Government
            Corporation within USDA.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              FSA.
            </E>
             The Farm Service Agency, an agency of the United States Department
            of Agriculture or any successor agency.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Household.
            </E>
             A domestic establishment including the members of a family
            (parents, brothers, sisters, children, spouse, grandchildren, aunts,
            uncles, nieces, nephews, first cousins, or grandparents, related by
            blood, adoption or marriage, are considered to be family members)
            and others who live under the same roof.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Limited resource farmer.
            </E>
             A person with:
          </P>
          <P>
            (1) Direct or indirect gross farm sales not more than $100,000.00 in
            each of the previous two years (to be increased starting in fiscal
            year 2004 to adjust for inflation using Prices Paid by Farmer Index
            as compiled by National Agricultural Statistical Service (NASS));
            and
          </P>
          <P>
            (2) A total household income at or below the national poverty level
            for a family of four, or less than 50 percent of county median
            household income in each of the previous two years (to be determined
            annually using Commerce Department Data).
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Secretary.
            </E>
             The Secretary of the United States Department of Agriculture.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              USDA.
            </E>
             The United States Department of Agriculture.
          </P>
          <P>
            <E T='03'>
              Zero acreage report.
            </E>
             An acreage report filed by you that certifies you do not have a
            share in the crop for that crop year.
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            2. Eligibility, Life of Policy, Cancellation, and Termination
          </HD>
          <P>
            (a) You must have one of the following policies in force to elect
            this Endorsement:
          </P>
          <P>
            (1) The Common Crop Insurance Policy (
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR 
              <subref title='7' part='457' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
                457.8
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) and crop provisions;
          </P>
          <P>
            (2) The Group Risk Plan Policy, if available for catastrophic risk
            protection; or
          </P>
          <P>
            (3) A specific named crop insurance policy.
          </P>
          <P>
            (b) You must have made application for catastrophic risk protection
            on or before the sales closing date for the crop in the county.
          </P>
          <P>
            (c) You must be a “person” as defined in the crop policy to be
            eligible for catastrophic risk protection coverage.
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            3. Unit Division
          </HD>
          <P>
            (a) This section is in lieu of the unit provisions specified in the
            applicable crop policy.
          </P>
          <P>
            (b) For catastrophic risk protection coverage, a unit will be all
            insurable acreage of the insured crop in the county on the date
            coverage begins for the crop year:
          </P>
          <P>
            (1) In which you have one hundred percent (100%) crop share; or
          </P>
          <P>
            (2) Which is owned by one person and operated by another person on a
            share basis. 
            <PRTPAGE P='77' />
          </P>
          <FP>
            (Example: If, in addition to the land you own, you rent land from
            five landlords, three on a crop share basis and two on a cash basis,
            you would be entitled to four units; one for each crop share lease
            and one that combines the two cash leases and the land you own.)
          </FP>
          <P>
            (c) Further division of the units described in paragraph (b) above
            is not allowed under this Endorsement.
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            4. Insurance Guarantees, Coverage Levels, and Prices for Determining
            Indemnities
          </HD>
          <P>
            (a) Notwithstanding any provision contained in any other policy
            document,catastrophic coverage will offer protection equal to fifty
            percent (50%) of your approved yield indemnified at fifty-five
            percent (55%) of the expected market price, or a comparable coverage
            as established by FCIC.
          </P>
          <P>
            (b) If the crop policy denominates coverage in dollars per acre or
            other measure, or any other alternative method of coverage, such
            coverage will be converted to the amount of coverage that would be
            payable at fifty percent (50%) of your approved yield indemnified at
            fifty-five percent (55%) of the expected market price.
          </P>
          <P>
            (c) You may elect catastrophic coverage for any crop insured or
            reinsured by FCIC on either an individual yield and loss basis or an
            area yield and loss basis, if both options are offered as set out in
            the Actuarial Table or the Special Provisions.
          </P>
          <P>
            (d) To be eligible for an indemnity under this endorsement you must
            have suffered at least a 50 percent loss in yield.
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            5. Report of Acreage
          </HD>
          <P>
            (a) The report of crop acreage that you file in accordance with the
            crop policy must be signed on or before the acreage reporting date.
            For catastrophic risk protection, unless the other person with an
            insurable interest in the crop objects in writing prior to the
            acreage reporting date and provides a signed acreage report on their
            own behalf, the operator may sign the acreage report for all other
            persons with an insurable interest in the crop without a power of
            attorney. All persons with an insurable interest in the crop, and
            for whom the operator purports to sign and represent, are bound by
            the information contained in that acreage report.
          </P>
          <P>
            (b) For the purpose of determining the amount of indemnity only,
            your share will not exceed your insurable interest at the earlier of
            the time of loss or the beginning of harvest. Unless the accepted
            application clearly indicates that insurance is requested for a
            partnership or joint venture, insurance will only cover the crop
            share of the person completing the application. The share will not
            extend to any other person having an interest in the crop except as
            may otherwise be specifically allowed in this endorsement. Any
            acreage or interest reported by or for your spouse, child or any
            member of your household may be considered your share. A lease
            containing provisions for both a minimum payment (such as a
            specified amount of cash, bushels, pounds, etc.) 
            <E T='03'>
              and
            </E>
             a crop share will be considered a crop share lease. A lease
            containing provisions for either a minimum payment (such as a
            specified amount of cash, bushels, pounds, etc.,) 
            <E T='03'>
              or
            </E>
             a crop share will be considered a cash lease. Land rented for cash,
            a fixed commodity payment, or any consideration other than a share
            in the insured crop on such land will be considered as owned by the
            lessee.
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            6. Annual Premium and Administrative Fees
          </HD>
          <P>
            (a) Notwithstanding any provision contained in any other policy
            document, you will not be responsible to pay a premium, nor will the
            policy be terminated because the premium has not been paid. FCIC
            will pay a premium subsidy equal to the premium established for the
            coverage provided under this endorsement.
          </P>
          <P>
            (b) In return for catastrophic risk protection coverage, you must
            pay an administrative fee to us within 30 days after you have been
            billed, unless otherwise authorized in the Federal Crop Insurance
            Act (You will be billed by the date stated in the Special
            Provisions);
          </P>
          <P>
            (1) The administrative fee owed is $300 for each crop in the county
            unless otherwise specified in the Special Provisions.
          </P>
          <P>
            (2) Payment of an administrative fee will not be required if you
            file a bona fide zero acreage report on or before the acreage
            reporting date for the crop (if you falsely file a zero acreage
            report you may be subject to criminal and administrative sanctions).
          </P>
          <P>
            (c) The administrative fee provisions of paragraph (b) of this
            section do not apply if you meet the definition of a limited
            resource farmer (see 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 1
            </aref>
            ). The administrative fee will be waived if you request it and:
          </P>
          <P>
            (1) You qualify as a limited resource farmer; or
          </P>
          <P>
            (2) You were insured prior to the 2005 crop year or for the 2005
            crop year and your administrative fee was waived for one or more of
            those crop years because you qualified as a limited resource farmer
            under a policy definition previously in effect, and you remain
            qualified as a limited resource farmer under the definition that was
            in effect at the time the administrative fee was waived.
          </P>
          <P>
            (d) When a crop policy has provisions to allow you the option to
            separately insure individual crop types or varieties, you must pay a
            separate administrative fee in accordance with paragraph (b) of this
            section for each type or variety you elect to separately insure.
            <PRTPAGE P='78' />
          </P>
          <P>
            (e) If the administrative fee is not paid when due, you, and all
            persons with an insurable interest in the crop under the same
            contract, may be ineligible for certain other USDA program benefits.
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            7. Insured Crop
          </HD>
          <P>
            The crop insured is specified in the applicable crop policy,
            however:
          </P>
          <P>
            (a) Notwithstanding any other policy provision requiring the same
            insurance coverage on all insurable acreage of the crop in the
            county, if you purchase additional coverage for a crop, you may
            separately insure acreage under catastrophic coverage that has been
            designated as “high risk” land by FCIC, provided that you execute a
            High Risk Land Exclusion Option and obtain a catastrophic risk
            protection policy with the same approved insurance provider, if
            available, on or before the applicable sales closing date. If
            catastrophic coverage is not available from the same insurance
            provider, you may obtain the catastrophic risk protection policy for
            the high risk land from another approved insurance provider or FSA,
            if available. You will be required to pay a separate administrative
            fee for both the additional coverage policy and the catastrophic
            coverage policy.
          </P>
          <P>
            (b) A landowner will be allowed to obtain catastrophic coverage for
            all other landowners who hold an undivided interest in the insurable
            acreage, provided:
          </P>
          <P>
            (1) All the landowners must agree in writing to such arrangement and
            have their social security number or employer identification number
            listed on the application, without regard to the actual amount of
            their interest in the insured acreage;
          </P>
          <P>
            (2) All landowners must have an undivided interest in the insurable
            acreage;
          </P>
          <P>
            (3) None of the landowners may hold any share in other acreage for
            which they are required to obtain at least catastrophic coverage;
          </P>
          <P>
            (4) The total cumulative liability under the Catastrophic Risk
            Protection Endorsement for all landowners must be $2,500 or less;
          </P>
          <P>
            (5) The landowner insuring the crop will:
          </P>
          <P>
            (i) Make application for insurance and provide the name and social
            security number or employer identification number of each person
            with an undivided interest in the insurable acreage;
          </P>
          <P>
            (ii) Be responsible to pay the one administrative fee for all the
            producers within the county;
          </P>
          <P>
            (iii) Fulfill all requirements under the insurance contract; and
          </P>
          <P>
            (iv) Receive any indemnity payment under the landowner&apos;s social
            security number, or when applicable, employer identification number,
            and distribute the indemnity payments to the other persons sharing
            in the crop.
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            8. Replanting Payment
          </HD>
          <P>
            Notwithstanding any provision contained in any other crop insurance
            document, no replant payment will be paid whether or not replanting
            of the crop is required under the policy.
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            9. Claim for Indemnity
          </HD>
          <P>
            If two or more insured crop types, varieties, or classes are insured
            within the same unit, and multiple price elections are applicable,
            the dollar amount of insurance and the dollar amount of production
            to be counted will be determined separately for each type, variety,
            class, etc., that have separate price elections and then totaled to
            determine the total liability or dollar amount of production to be
            counted for the unit.
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            10. Concealment or Fraud
          </HD>
          <P>
            Notwithstanding any provision contained in any other crop insurance
            document, your CAT policy may be voided by us on all crops without
            waiving any of our rights, including the right to collect any
            amounts due:
          </P>
          <P>
            (a) If at any time you conceal or misrepresent any material fact or
            commit fraud relating to this or any other contract issued under the
            authority of the Federal Crop Insurance Act with any insurance
            provider; and
          </P>
          <P>
            (b) The voidance will be effective for the crop year during which
            any such act or omission occurred.
          </P>
          <HD SOURCE='HD3'>
            11. Exclusion of Coverage
          </HD>
          <P>
            (a) Options or endorsements that extend the coverage available under
            any crop policy offered by FCIC will not be available under this
            endorsement. Written agreements are not available for any crop
            insured under this endorsement.
          </P>
          <P>
            (b) Notwithstanding any provision contained in any other crop
            policy, hail and fire coverage and high-risk land may not be
            excluded under catastrophic risk protection.
          </P>
        </EXTRACT>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            61 FR 42985
          </aref>
          , Aug. 20, 1996, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            63 FR 40631
          </aref>
          , July 30, 1998; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            64 FR 40740
          </aref>
          , July 28, 1999; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            65 FR 40484
          </aref>
          , June 30, 2000; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            69 FR 48730
          </aref>
          , Aug. 10, 2004; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            73 FR 36408
          </aref>
          , June 27, 2008; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            73 FR 70864
          </aref>
          , Nov. 24, 2008]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>