<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol10'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1466
    </extid>
    <num>
      1466
    </num>
    <head>
      ENVIRONMENTAL QUALITY INCENTIVES PROGRAM
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='15' sect='714b' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/15/714b.html'>
              15 U.S.C. 714b
            </subref>
             and 
            <subref title='15' sect='714c' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/15/714c.html'>
              714c
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='16' sect='3839aa-383' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/3839aa-383.html'>
              16 U.S.C. 3839aa-383
            </subref>
          </aref>
          9-8
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            68 FR 32348
          </aref>
          , May 30, 2003, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='12938'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1466:A:1466.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1466.1
      </num>
      <head>
        Applicability.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1466' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              1466.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Applicability.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The purposes of the Environmental Quality Incentives Program (EQIP)
            are to promote agricultural production, forest management, and
            environmental quality as compatible goals, and to optimize
            environmental benefits. Through EQIP, the Natural Resources
            Conservation Service (NRCS) provides assistance to eligible farmers
            and ranchers to address soil, water, and air quality, wildlife
            habitat, surface and groundwater conservation, energy conservation,
            and related natural resource concerns. EQIP&apos;s financial and
            technical assistance helps producers comply with environmental
            regulations and enhance agricultural and forested lands in a
            cost-effective and environmentally beneficial manner. The purposes
            of the program are achieved by planning and implementing
            conservation practices on eligible land.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             EQIP is available in any of the 50 States, the District of
            Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, the Virgin Islands
            of the United States, American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the
            Northern Mariana Islands.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12939'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1466:A:1466.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1466.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Administration.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1466' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              1466.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Administration.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The funds, facilities, and authorities of the Commodity Credit
            Corporation (CCC) are available to NRCS for carrying out EQIP.
            Accordingly, where NRCS is mentioned in this Part, it also refers to
            the CCC&apos;s funds, facilities, and authorities where applicable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS supports “locally led conservation” by using State Technical
            Committees at the State level and local working groups at the county
            or parish level to advise NRCS on issues relating to the EQIP
            implementation such as:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Identification of priority resource concerns;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Identification of which conservation practices should be eligible
            for financial assistance; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Establishment of payment rates.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No delegation in this Part to lower organizational levels shall
            preclude the Chief from making any determinations under this Part,
            or from reversing or modifying any determination made under this
            Part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS may enter into agreements with other Federal or State
            agencies, Indian tribes, conservation districts, units of local
            government, public or private organizations, and individuals to
            assist NRCS with implementation of the program in this Part.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12940'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1466:A:1466.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1466.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1466' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              1466.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The following definitions will apply to this Part and all documents
          issued in accordance with this Part, unless specified otherwise:
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Agricultural land
          </E>
           means cropland, grassland, rangeland, pasture, and other agricultural
          land, on which agricultural and forest-related products, or livestock
          are produced and resource concerns may be addressed. Other
          agricultural lands include cropped woodland, marshes, incidental areas
          included in the agricultural operation, and other types of
          agricultural land used for production of livestock.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Agricultural operation
          </E>
           means a parcel or parcels of land whether contiguous or
          noncontiguous, which the producer is listed as the operator or
          owner/operator in the Farm Service Agency (FSA) record system, which
          is under the effective control of the producer at the time the
          producer applies for a contract, and which is operated by the producer
          with equipment, labor, management, and production, forestry, or
          cultivation practices that are substantially separate from other
          operations.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Animal waste management facility
          </E>
           means a structural conservation practice, implemented in the context
          of a Comprehensive Nutrient Management Plan and consistent with the
          Field Office Technical Guide, which is used for storing, treating, or
          handling animal waste or byproducts, such as animal carcasses.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Applicant
          </E>
           means a person, legal entity, joint operation, or tribe that has an
          interest in an agricultural operation, as defined in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
              1400 of this chapter
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , who has requested in writing to participate in EQIP.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            At-risk species
          </E>
           means any plant or animal species as determined by the State
          Conservationist, with advice 
          <PRTPAGE P='793' />
          from the State Technical Committee, to need direct intervention to
          halt its population decline.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Beginning Farmer or Rancher
          </E>
           means a person or legal entity who:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Has not operated a farm or ranch, or who has operated a farm or
            ranch for not more than 10 consecutive years. This requirement
            applies to all members of an entity, who will materially and
            substantially participate in the operation of the farm or ranch.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the case of a contract with an individual, individually or with
            the immediate family, material and substantial participation
            requires that the individual provide substantial day-to-day labor
            and management of the farm or ranch, consistent with the practices
            in the county or State where the farm is located.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the case of a contract with an entity or joint operation, all
            members must materially and substantially participate in the
            operation of the farm or ranch. Material and substantial
            participation requires that each of the members provide some amount
            of the management, or labor and management necessary for day-to-day
            activities, such that if each of the members did not provide these
            inputs, operation of the farm or ranch would be seriously impaired.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Chief
          </E>
           means the Chief of NRCS, United States Department of Agriculture
          (USDA), or designee.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Comprehensive Nutrient Management Plan (CNMP)
          </E>
           means a conservation system that is unique to an animal feeding
          operation (AFO). A CNMP is a grouping of conservation practices and
          management activities which, when implemented as part of a
          conservation system, will help to ensure that both production and
          natural resource protection goals are achieved. A CNMP incorporates
          practices to use animal manure and organic by-products as a beneficial
          resource. A CNMP addresses natural resource concerns dealing with soil
          erosion, manure, and organic byproducts and their potential impacts on
          all natural resources including water and air quality, which may
          derive from an AFO. A CNMP is developed to assist an AFO
          owner/operator in meeting all applicable local, Tribal, State, and
          Federal water quality goals or regulations. For nutrient impaired
          stream segments or water bodies, additional management activities or
          conservation practices may be required by local, Tribal, State, or
          Federal water quality goals or regulations.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Conservation district
          </E>
           means any district or unit of State, Tribal, or local government
          formed under State, Tribal, or territorial law for the express purpose
          of developing and carrying out a local soil and water conservation
          program. Such district or unit of government may be referred to as a
          “conservation district,” “soil conservation district,” “soil and water
          conservation district,” “resource conservation district,” “land
          conservation committee,” “natural resource district,” or similar name.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Conservation Innovation Grants
          </E>
           means competitive grants made under EQIP to individuals and
          governmental and non-governmental organizations to stimulate and
          transfer innovative technologies and approaches, to leverage Federal
          funds, and to enhance and protect the environment, in conjunction with
          agricultural production and forest management.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Conservation practice
          </E>
           means one or more conservation improvements and activities, including
          structural practices, land management practices, vegetative practices,
          forest management practices, and other improvements that achieve the
          program purposes, including such items as CNMPs, agricultural energy
          management plans, dryland transition plans, forest management plans,
          integrated pest management, and other plans determined acceptable by
          the Chief.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Contract
          </E>
           means a legal document that specifies the rights and obligations of
          any participant accepted into the program. An EQIP contract is a
          binding agreement for the transfer of assistance from USDA to the
          participant to share in the costs of applying conservation practices.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Cost-effectiveness
          </E>
           means the least costly option for achieving a given set of
          conservation objectives.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Designated conservationist
          </E>
           means an NRCS employee whom the State Conservationist has designated
          as responsible for EQIP administration in a specific area.
          <PRTPAGE P='794' />
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            EQIP plan of operations
          </E>
           means the document that identifies the location and timing of
          conservation practices that the participant agrees to implement on
          eligible land in order to address the priority resource concerns,
          optimize environmental benefits, and address program purposes as
          defined in 
          <E T='03'>
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1466' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
                1466.1
              </subref>
            </aref>
          </E>
          . The EQIP plan of operations is part of the EQIP contract.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Estimated income foregone
          </E>
           means an estimate of the net income loss associated with the adoption
          of a conservation practice, including from a change in land use or
          land taken out of production or the opportunity cost associated with
          the adoption of a conservation practice. This shall not include losses
          of income due to disaster or other events unrelated to the
          conservation practice.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Field office technical guide (FOTG)
          </E>
           means the official local NRCS source of resource information and
          interpretations of guidelines, criteria, and requirements for planning
          and applying conservation practices and conservation management
          systems. It contains detailed information on the conservation of soil,
          water, air, plant, and animal resources applicable to the local area
          for which it is prepared.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Forest management plan
          </E>
           means a site-specific plan that is prepared by a professional
          resource manager, in consultation with the participant, and is
          approved by the State Conservationist. Forest management plans may
          include a forest stewardship plan, as specified in 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 5 of
          </aref>
           the Cooperative Forestry Assistance Act of 1978 (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='16' sect='2103a' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/2103a.html'>
              16 U.S.C. 2103a
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ); another practice plan approved by the State Forester; or another
          plan determined appropriate by the State Conservationist. The plan is
          intended to comply with Federal, State, tribal, and local laws,
          regulations, and permit requirements.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Historically underserved producer
          </E>
           means an eligible person, joint operation, or legal entity who is a
          beginning farmer or rancher, socially disadvantaged farmer or rancher,
          or limited resource farmer or rancher.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Indian land
          </E>
           means:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land held in trust by the United States for individual Indians or
            Indian tribes; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land, the title to which is held by individual Indians or Indian
            Tribes subject to Federal restrictions against alienation or
            encumbrance; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land which is subject to rights of use, occupancy and/or benefit of
            certain Indian Tribes; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land held in fee title by an Indian, Indian family or Indian Tribe.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Indian Tribe
          </E>
           means any Indian Tribe, band, nation, or other organized group or
          community, including any Alaska Native village or regional or village
          corporation as defined in or established pursuant to the Alaska Native
          Claims Settlement Act (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='43' sect='1601' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/43/1601.html'>
              43 U.S.C. 1601
            </subref>
          </aref>
           et seq.) which is recognized as eligible for the special programs and
          services provided by the United States to Indians because of their
          status as Indians.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Integrated Pest Management
          </E>
           means a sustainable approach to managing pests by combining
          biological, cultural, physical, and chemical tools in a way that
          minimizes economic, health, and environmental risks.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Joint operation
          </E>
           means, as defined in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
              1400 of this chapter
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , a general partnership, joint venture, or other similar business
          organization in which the members are jointly and severally liable for
          the obligations of the organization.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Legal entity
          </E>
           means, as defined in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
              1400 of this chapter
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , an entity created under Federal or State law that:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Owns land or an agricultural commodity, product, or livestock; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Produces an agricultural commodity, product, or livestock.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Lifespan
          </E>
           means the period of time during which a conservation practice should
          be maintained and used for the intended purpose.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Limited Resource Farmer or Rancher
          </E>
           means:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A person with direct or indirect gross farm sales not more than
            $155,200 in each of the previous two years (adjusted for inflation
            using Prices Paid by Farmer Index as compiled by National
            Agricultural Statistical Service), and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Has a total household income at or below the national poverty level
            for a family of four, or less than 50 percent of county median
            household income in each of the previous two years (to be 
            <PRTPAGE P='795' />
            determined annually using Commerce Department Data).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Liquidated damages
          </E>
           means a sum of money stipulated in the EQIP contract that the
          participant agrees to pay NRCS if the participant fails to adequately
          complete the terms of the contract. The sum represents an estimate of
          the technical assistance expenses incurred to service the contract,
          and reflects the difficulties of proof of loss and the inconvenience
          or non-feasibility of otherwise obtaining an adequate remedy.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Livestock
          </E>
           means all animals produced on farms or ranches, as determined by the
          Chief.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Livestock production
          </E>
           means farm or ranch operations involving the production, growing,
          raising, or reproduction of livestock or livestock products.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Local Working Group
          </E>
           means the advisory body as defined in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='610' tq='N'>
              610 of this title
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            National measures
          </E>
           mean measurable criteria identified by the Chief, with the advice of
          other Federal agencies and State Conservationists, to help EQIP
          achieve the national priorities and statutory requirements.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            National Organic Program
          </E>
           means the national program, administered by the Agricultural
          Marketing Service, which regulates the standards for any farm, wild
          crop harvesting, or handling operation that wants to sell an
          agricultural product as organically produced.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            National priorities
          </E>
           means resource issues identified by the Chief, with advice from other
          Federal agencies and State Conservationists, which will be used to
          determine the distribution of EQIP funds and guide local EQIP
          implementation.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Natural Resources Conservation Service
          </E>
           is an agency of the USDA, which has responsibility for administering
          EQIP using the funds, facilities, and authorities of the CCC.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Nonindustrial private forest land
          </E>
           means rural land, as determined by the Secretary, that has existing
          tree cover or is suitable for growing trees; and is owned by any
          nonindustrial private individual, group, association, corporation,
          Indian Tribe, or other private legal entity that has definitive
          decision-making authority over the land.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Operation and maintenance
          </E>
           means work performed by the participant to keep the applied
          conservation practice functioning for the intended purpose during the
          conservation practice lifespan. Operation includes the administration,
          management, and performance of non-maintenance actions needed to keep
          the completed practice functioning as intended. Maintenance includes
          work to prevent deterioration of the practice, repairing damage, or
          replacement of the practice to its original condition if one or more
          components fail.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Operation and maintenance (O&amp;M) agreement
          </E>
           means the document that, in conjunction with the EQIP plan of
          operations, specifies the operation and maintenance responsibilities
          of the participant for conservation practices installed with EQIP
          assistance.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Organic System Plan
          </E>
           means a management plan for organic production or for an organic
          handling operation that has been agreed to by the producer or handler
          and the certifying agent. The Organic System Plan includes all written
          plans that govern all aspects of agricultural production or handling.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Participant
          </E>
           means a person, legal entity, joint operation, or tribe that is
          receiving payment or is responsible for implementing the terms and
          conditions of an EQIP contract.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Payment
          </E>
           means financial assistance provided to the participant based on the
          estimated costs incurred in performing or implementing conservation
          practices, including costs for: planning, design, materials,
          equipment, installation, labor, maintenance, management, or training,
          as well as the estimated income foregone by the producer for
          designated conservation practices.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Person
          </E>
           means, as defined in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
              1400 of this chapter
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , an individual, natural person, and does not include a legal entity.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Priority resource concern(s)
          </E>
           means a resource concern that is identified by the State
          Conservationist, in consultation with the State Technical Committee,
          as a priority for a State, geographic area, or watershed level.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Producer
          </E>
           means a person, legal entity, or joint operation who has an interest
          in the agricultural operation, according to 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
              1400 of this chapter
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , or 
          <PRTPAGE P='796' />
          who is engaged in agricultural production or forestry management.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Regional Assistant Chief
          </E>
           means the NRCS employee authorized to direct and supervise NRCS
          activities in an NRCS region.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Resource Concern
          </E>
           means a specific natural resource problem that represents a
          significant concern in a State or region, and is likely to be
          addressed successfully through the implementation of the conservation
          activities by producers.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Secretary
          </E>
           means the Secretary of the USDA.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Socially disadvantaged farmer or rancher
          </E>
           means a farmer or rancher who has been subjected to racial or ethnic
          prejudices because of their identity as a member of a group without
          regard to their individual qualities.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State Conservationist
          </E>
           means the NRCS employee authorized to implement EQIP and direct and
          supervise NRCS activities in a State, the Caribbean Area, or the
          Pacific Island Area.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State Technical Committee
          </E>
           means a committee established by the Secretary in a State pursuant to
          
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='16' sect='3861' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/3861.html'>
              16 U.S.C. 3861
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Structural practice
          </E>
           means a conservation practice, including a vegetative practice, that
          involves establishing, constructing, or installing a site-specific
          measure to conserve and protect a resource from degradation, or
          improve soil, water, air, or related natural resources in the most
          cost-effective manner. Examples include, but are not limited to,
          animal waste management facilities, terraces, grassed waterways,
          tailwater pits, livestock water developments, contour grass strips,
          filterstrips, critical area plantings, tree plantings, establishment
          or improvement of wildlife habitat, and capping of abandoned wells.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Technical assistance
          </E>
           means technical expertise, information, and tools necessary for the
          conservation of natural resources on land active in agricultural,
          forestry, or related uses. The term includes the following:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Technical services provided directly to farmers, ranchers, and
            other eligible entities, such as conservation planning, technical
            consultation, and assistance with design and implementation of
            conservation practices; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Technical infrastructure, including activities, processes, tools,
            and agency functions needed to support delivery of technical
            services, such as technical standards, resource inventories,
            training, data, technology, monitoring, and effects analyses.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Technical Service Provider (TSP)
          </E>
           means an individual, private-sector entity, or public agency
          certified by NRCS to provide technical services to program
          participants, in lieu of or on behalf of NRCS.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Wildlife
          </E>
           means non-domesticated birds, fishes, reptiles, amphibians,
          invertebrates, and mammals.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12941'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1466:A:1466.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1466.4
      </num>
      <head>
        National priorities.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1466' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              1466.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          National priorities.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The following national priorities, consistent with statutory
            resource concerns that include soil, water, wildlife, air quality,
            and related resource concerns, will be used in EQIP implementation:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Reductions of nonpoint source pollution, such as nutrients,
            sediment, pesticides, or excess salinity in impaired watersheds
            consistent with total maximum daily loads (TMDLs) where available;
            the reduction of surface and groundwater contamination; and the
            reduction of contamination from agricultural point sources, such as
            concentrated animal feeding operations;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Conservation of ground and surface water resources;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Reduction of emissions, such as particulate matter, nitrogen
            oxides, volatile organic compounds, and ozone precursors and
            depleters that contribute to air quality impairment violations of
            National Ambient Air Quality Standards;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Reduction in soil erosion and sedimentation from unacceptable
            levels on agricultural land; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Promotion of at-risk species habitat conservation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In consultation with other Federal agencies, NRCS will undertake
            periodic reviews of the national priorities and the effects of
            program delivery at the State and local level to adapt the program
            to address emerging resource issues. NRCS will:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Use the national priorities to guide the allocation of EQIP funds
            to the NRCS State offices,
            <PRTPAGE P='797' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Use the national priorities in conjunction with State and local
            priorities to assist with prioritization and selection of EQIP
            applications, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Periodically review and update the national priorities utilizing
            input from the public and affected stakeholders to ensure that the
            program continues to address priority resource concerns.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12942'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1466:A:1466.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1466.5
      </num>
      <head>
        National allocation and management.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1466' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              1466.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          National allocation and management.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The Chief allocates EQIP funds to the State Conservationists to
          implement EQIP at the State and local level. In order to optimize the
          overall environmental benefits over the program duration, the Chief
          will:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Use an EQIP fund allocation formula that reflects national
            priorities and that uses available natural resource and resource
            concerns data to distribute funds to the State level. This procedure
            will be updated periodically to reflect adjustments to national
            priorities and information about resource concerns and program
            performance. The data used in the allocation formula will be updated
            as they become available.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provide a performance incentive to NRCS in States that demonstrate
            a high level of program accomplishment in implementing EQIP. The
            Chief shall consider factors such as strategically planning EQIP
            implementation, effectively addressing national priorities and
            measures, State and local resource concerns, the program delivery
            effectiveness, the use of TSPs, and the number of contracts with
            historically underserved producers.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Establish State level EQIP performance goals based on national,
            regional, and State priorities.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Ensure that national, State and local level information regarding
            program implementation such as resource priorities, eligible
            practices, ranking processes, payment schedules, fund allocation,
            and program achievements are made available to the public.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Consult with other Federal agencies with the appropriate expertise
            and information when evaluating the considerations described in this
            section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Authorize the State Conservationist, with advice from the State
            Technical Committee and local working groups, to determine how funds
            will be used and how the program will be administered to achieve
            national priorities in each State.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Utilize assessment, evaluation, and accountability procedures based
            on actual natural resource and environmental outcomes and results.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12943'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1466:A:1466.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1466.6
      </num>
      <head>
        State allocation and management.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1466' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              1466.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          State allocation and management.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The State Conservationist will:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Identify State priority resource concerns, with the advice of the
            State Technical Committee, which directly contribute toward meeting
            national priorities and measures, and will use NRCS&apos;s
            accountability system and other accountability tools to establish
            local level goals and treatment objectives;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Identify, as appropriate and necessary, designated conservationists
            who are NRCS employees that are assigned the responsibility to
            administer EQIP in specific areas; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Use the following to determine how to manage EQIP and how to
            allocate funds within a State:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The nature and extent of priority resource concerns at the State
            and local level;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The availability of human resources, incentive programs,
            educational programs, and on-farm research programs from public,
            private, and Tribal sources, to assist with the activities related
            to the priority resource concerns;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The existence of multi-county and/or multi-State collaborative
            efforts to address regional priority resource concerns;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Program performance and results;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The degree of difficulty that producers face in complying with
            environmental laws; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The presence of additional priority resource concerns and
            specialized farming operations, including but not limited to,
            specialty crop producers, organic producers, and small-scale farms.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12944'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1466:A:1466.7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1466.7
      </num>
      <head>
        Outreach activities.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1466' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              1466.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Outreach activities.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          NRCS will establish program outreach activities at the national,
          State, and local levels in order to ensure that 
          <PRTPAGE P='798' />
          producers whose land has environmental problems and priority resource
          concerns are aware and informed that they may be eligible to apply for
          program assistance. Special outreach will be made to eligible
          producers with historically low participation rates, including but not
          restricted to, limited resource, socially disadvantaged, small-scale,
          or beginning farmers or ranchers, Indian Tribes, Alaska Natives, and
          Pacific Islanders.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12945'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1466:A:1466.8
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1466.8
      </num>
      <head>
        Program requirements.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          68 FR 32348
        </aref>
        , May 30, 2003, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          74 FR 25617
        </aref>
        , May 29, 2009]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1466' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              1466.8
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Program requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Program participation is voluntary. The applicant must develop an
            EQIP plan of operations for the agricultural or nonindustrial
            private forest land to be treated that serves as the basis for the
            EQIP contract. NRCS provides participants with technical assistance
            and payments to plan and apply needed conservation practices.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be eligible to participate in EQIP, an applicant must:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be in compliance with the highly erodible land and wetland
            conservation provisions found at 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='12' tq='N'>
                12 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Have an interest in the agricultural operation as defined in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
                1400 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Have control of the land for the term of the proposed contract
            period;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Chief may determine that land administered by the Bureau of
            Indian Affairs (BIA), Indian land, or other such circumstances
            provides sufficient assurance of control,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the applicant is a tenant of the land involved in agricultural
            production or forestry management, the applicant shall provide the
            Chief with the written concurrence of the landowner in order to
            apply a structural conservation practice,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Submit an EQIP plan of operations or plan developed for the
            purposes of acquiring an air or water quality permit, provided these
            plans contain elements equivalent to those elements required by an
            EQIP plan of operations and are acceptable to the State
            Conservationist as being consistent with the purposes of the
            program;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Supply information, as required by NRCS, to determine eligibility
            for the program, including but not limited to, information to verify
            the applicant&apos;s status as a limited resource, beginning farmer
            or rancher, and payment eligibility as established by 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
                1400 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provide a list of all members of the legal entity and embedded
            entities along with members&apos; tax identification numbers and
            percentage interest in the entity. Where applicable, American
            Indians, Alaska Natives, and Pacific Islanders may use another
            unique identification number for each individual eligible for
            payment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Eligible land includes agricultural land and nonindustrial private
            forest land, and other land on which agricultural products,
            livestock, or forest-related products are produced and resource
            concerns may be addressed. Other agricultural lands include cropped
            woodland, marshes, incidental areas included in the agricultural
            operation, and other types of agricultural land used for production
            of livestock. However, land may be considered for enrollment in EQIP
            only if NRCS determines that the land is:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Privately owned land;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Publicly owned land where:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The land is a working component of the participant&apos;s
            agricultural and forestry operation, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The participant has control of the land for the term of the
            contract, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The conservation practices to be implemented on the public land are
            necessary and will contribute to an improvement in the identified
            resource concern; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Indian land.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Sixty percent of available EQIP financial assistance will be
            targeted to conservation practices related to livestock production,
            including practices on grazing lands and other lands directly
            attributable to livestock production, as measured at the national
            level.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS will establish a national target to set aside five percent of
            EQIP funds for socially disadvantaged farmers or ranchers and an
            additional five percent of EQIP funds for beginning farmers or
            ranchers.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            68 FR 32348
          </aref>
          , May 30, 2003, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            74 FR 25617
          </aref>
          , May 29, 2009]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12946'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1466:A:1466.9
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1466.9
      </num>
      <head>
        EQIP plan of operations.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='799' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1466' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
              1466.9
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          EQIP plan of operations.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All conservation practices in the EQIP plan of operations must be
            approved by NRCS and developed and carried out in accordance with
            the applicable NRCS technical guidance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The participant is responsible for implementing the EQIP plan of
            operations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The EQIP plan of operations must include:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A description of the participant&apos;s specific conservation and
            environmental objectives to be achieved;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To the extent practicable, the quantitative or qualitative goals
            for achieving the participant&apos;s conservation, natural resource,
            and environmental objectives;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A description of one or more conservation practices in the
            conservation management system, including conservation planning,
            design, or installation activities, to be implemented to achieve the
            conservation and environmental objectives;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A description of the schedule for implementing the conservation
            practices, including timing, sequence, operation, and maintenance;
            and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Information that will enable evaluation of the effectiveness of the
            plan in achieving the environmental objectives.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If an EQIP plan of operations includes an animal waste storage or
            treatment facility, the participant must agree to develop and
            implement a CNMP or demonstrate to the satisfaction of the
            designated conservationist that a CNMP has been implemented.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If an EQIP plan of operations addresses forestland, the participant
            must develop and implement a forest management plan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A participant may receive assistance to implement an EQIP plan of
            operations for water conservation only if the assistance will
            facilitate a reduction in ground and surface water use on the
            agricultural operation, unless the producer is participating in a
            watershed-wide project, as approved by the State Conservationist,
            which will effectively conserve water in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1466' sect='20' psec='' tq='N'>
                1466.20
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12947'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1466:B:1466.10
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1466.10
      </num>
      <head>
        Conservation practices.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          74 FR 2313
        </aref>
        , Jan. 15, 2009]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1466' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
              1466.10
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Conservation practices.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS will determine the conservation practices for which
            participants may receive program payments. A list of eligible
            practices will be available to the public.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payments will not be made to a participant for a conservation
            practice that either the applicant or another producer has applied
            prior to application for the program. Payments will not be made for
            a conservation practice that has been initiated or implemented prior
            to contract approval, unless a waiver was granted by the State
            Conservationist or designated conservationist prior to the practice
            implementation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A participant will be eligible for payments for water conservation
            and irrigation related conservation practices only on land that has
            been irrigated for two of the last five years prior to application
            for assistance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Where new technologies or management approaches that provide a high
            potential for optimizing environmental benefits have been developed,
            NRCS may approve interim conservation practice standards that
            incorporate the new technologies and provide financial assistance
            for pilot work to evaluate and assess the performance, efficiency,
            and effectiveness of the new technology or management approach.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            74 FR 2313
          </aref>
          , Jan. 15, 2009]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12948'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1466:B:1466.11
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1466.11
      </num>
      <head>
        Technical services provided by qualified personnel not affiliated with
        USDA.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          74 FR 2313
        </aref>
        , Jan. 15, 2009]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1466' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
              1466.11
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Technical services provided by qualified personnel not affiliated with
          USDA.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS may use the services of qualified TSPs in performing its
            responsibilities for technical assistance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Participants may use technical services from qualified personnel of
            other Federal, State, and local agencies, Indian Tribes, or
            individuals who are certified as TSPs by NRCS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Technical services provided by qualified personnel not affiliated
            with USDA may include, but are not limited 
            <PRTPAGE P='800' />
            to: conservation planning; conservation practice survey, layout,
            design, installation, and certification; and information; education;
            and training for producers.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS retains approval authority of work done by non-NRCS personnel
            for the purpose of approving EQIP payments.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            74 FR 2313
          </aref>
          , Jan. 15, 2009]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12949'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1466:B:1466.20
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1466.20
      </num>
      <head>
        Application for contracts and selecting applications.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          74 FR 2313
        </aref>
        , Jan. 15, 2009]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1466' sect='20' psec='' tq='N'>
              1466.20
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Application for contracts and selecting applications.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In evaluating EQIP applications, the State Conservationist or
            designated conservationist, with advice from the State Technical
            Committee or local working group, takes into account the following
            guidelines:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any producer who has eligible land may submit an application for
            participation in EQIP. Applications are accepted throughout the
            year. Producers who are members of a joint operation may file a
            single application for the joint operation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State Conservationist, to the greatest extent practicable, will
            group applications of similar crop, forestry, and livestock
            operations for evaluation purposes.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State Conservationist will evaluate applications within each
            established grouping.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In selecting EQIP applications, the State Conservationist or
            designated conservationist, with advice from the State Technical
            Committee or local working group, may establish ranking pools to
            address a specific resource concern, geographic area, or
            agricultural operation type or develop a ranking process to
            prioritize applications for funding that address national, State,
            and local priority resource concerns, taking into account the
            following guidelines:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State Conservationist or designated conservationist will
            periodically select the highest ranked applications for funding
            based on applicant eligibility, fund availability, and the NRCS
            ranking process. The State Conservationist or designated
            conservationist will rank all applications according to the
            following factors:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The degree of cost-effectiveness of the proposed conservation
            practices;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The magnitude of the expected environmental benefits resulting from
            the conservation treatment and the priority of the resource concerns
            that have been identified at the local, State, and national levels;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             How effectively and comprehensively the project addresses the
            designated resource concern or resource concerns;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Use of conservation practices that provide long-term environmental
            enhancements;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Compliance with Federal, State, Tribal, or local regulatory
            requirements concerning soil, water and air quality; wildlife
            habitat; and ground and surface water conservation;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Willingness of the applicant to complete all conservation practices
            in an expedited manner;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_vii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The ability to improve existing conservation practices or systems,
            which are in place at the time the application is accepted, or that
            complete a conservation system;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_viii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (viii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Other locally defined pertinent factors, such as the location of
            the conservation practice, the extent of natural resource
            degradation, and the degree of cooperation by local producers to
            achieve environmental improvements.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For applications that include water conservation or irrigation
            efficiency practices, the State Conservationist will give priority
            to those applications where:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Consistent with State law in which the producer&apos;s eligible
            land is located, there is a reduction in water use in the
            agricultural operation, or where the producer agrees not to use any
            associated water savings to bring new land under irrigation
            production, other than incidental land needed for efficient
            operations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A producer who brings new land under irrigated production may be
            excluded from this latter condition if the producer is participating
            in a watershed-wide project that will effectively conserve water.
            The State Conservationist will designate eligible watershed-wide
            projects that effectively conserve water, using the following
            criteria:
            <PRTPAGE P='801' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='b_2_ii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The project area has a current, comprehensive water resource
            assessment;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='b_2_ii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The project plan has demonstrated effective water conservation
            management strategies; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='b_2_ii_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The project sponsors have consulted relevant State and local
            agencies.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the State Conservationist determines that the environmental
            values of two or more applications for payments are comparable, the
            State Conservationist will not assign a higher priority to the
            application solely because it would present the least cost to the
            program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The ranking will not give preferential treatment to applications
            based on size of the operation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The ranking process will determine the order in which applications
            will be selected for funding. The approving authority for EQIP
            contracts will be the State Conservationist or designee, except that
            the approving authority for any EQIP contract greater than $150,000
            and up to $300,000 will be the appropriate NRCS Regional Assistant
            Chief.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State Conservationist will make available to the public all
            information regarding priority resource concerns, the list of
            eligible practices, payment rates, and how the EQIP program is
            implemented in the State.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            74 FR 2313
          </aref>
          , Jan. 15, 2009]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12950'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1466:B:1466.21
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1466.21
      </num>
      <head>
        Contract requirements.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          74 FR 2313
        </aref>
        , Jan. 15, 2009]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1466' sect='21' psec='' tq='N'>
              1466.21
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Contract requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In order for a participant to receive payments, the participant
            must enter into a contract agreeing to implement one or more
            conservation practices. Technical services may be included in the
            contract.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An EQIP contract will:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Identify all conservation practices to be implemented, the timing
            of practice installation, the operation and maintenance requirements
            for the practices, and applicable payments allocated to the
            practices under the contract;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be for a minimum duration of one year after completion of the last
            practice, but not more than 10 years;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Incorporate all provisions as required by law or statute, including
            requirements that the participant will:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Not implement any practices within the agricultural or forestry
            operation that would defeat the program&apos;s purposes;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Refund any program payments received with interest, and forfeit any
            future payments under the program, on the violation of a term or
            condition of the contract, consistent with the provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1466' sect='26' psec='' tq='N'>
                1466.26
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Refund all program payments received on the transfer of the right
            and interest of the producer in land subject to the contract, unless
            the transferee of the right and interest agrees to assume all
            obligations, including operation and maintenance of the EQIP
            contract&apos;s conservation practices, consistent with the
            provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1466' sect='25' psec='' tq='N'>
                1466.25
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Implement a comprehensive nutrient management plan when the EQIP
            contract includes an animal waste management facility;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Implement a forest management plan when the EQIP plan of operations
            addresses nonindustrial private forest land;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Supply information as may be required by NRCS to determine
            compliance with the contract and program requirements;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_vii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Specify the participant&apos;s responsibilities for operation and
            maintenance of the applied conservation practices, consistent with
            the provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1466' sect='22' psec='' tq='N'>
                1466.22
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Specify any other provision determined necessary or appropriate by
            NRCS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The participant must start at least one financially assisted
            practice within the first 12 months of signing a contract. If a
            participant, for reasons beyond their control, is unable to start
            conservation practice within the first year of the contract, the
            participant can request a waiver from the State Conservationist.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each contract will be limited to no more than $300,000. The Chief
            may waive this contract limitation to allow up to $450,000 for
            projects of special environmental significance that include methane
            digesters, other innovative technologies, and projects that will
            result in significant environmental improvements. Projects of
            special environmental significance must meet the 
            <PRTPAGE P='802' />
            following criteria, as determined by the Chief:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Site-specific evaluation documents have been completed, documenting
            that the project will have substantial positive impacts on critical
            resources in or near the project area (e.g., impaired water bodies,
            at-risk species, drinking water supplies, or air quality
            attainment);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The project clearly addresses a national priority and State,
            Tribal, or local priority resource concerns, as applicable; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The project assists the participant in complying with Federal,
            State, and local regulatory requirements.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            74 FR 2313
          </aref>
          , Jan. 15, 2009]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12951'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1466:B:1466.22
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1466.22
      </num>
      <head>
        Conservation practice operation and maintenance.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          74 FR 2313
        </aref>
        , Jan. 15, 2009]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1466' sect='22' psec='' tq='N'>
              1466.22
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Conservation practice operation and maintenance.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The contract will incorporate the O&amp;M agreement that addresses
            the operation and maintenance of conservation practices applied
            under the contract.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS expects the participant to operate and maintain each
            conservation practice installed under the contract for its intended
            purpose for the conservation practice lifespan as specified in the
            O&amp;M agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Conservation practices installed before the contract execution, but
            included in the contract to obtain the environmental benefits agreed
            upon, must be operated and maintained as specified in the contract
            and O&amp;M agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS may periodically inspect the conservation practice during the
            contract duration as specified in the O&amp;M agreement to ensure
            that operation and maintenance requirements are being carried out,
            and that the conservation practice is fulfilling its intended
            objectives.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If NRCS finds during the contract that a participant is not
            operating and maintaining practices in an appropriate manner, NRCS
            may terminate and request a refund of payments made for that
            conservation practice under the contract.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            74 FR 2313
          </aref>
          , Jan. 15, 2009]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12952'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1466:B:1466.23
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1466.23
      </num>
      <head>
        Payment rates.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          74 FR 2313
        </aref>
        , Jan. 15, 2009]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1466' sect='23' psec='' tq='N'>
              1466.23
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Payment rates.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State Conservationist or designated conservationist will
            develop a list of conservation practices, eligible for payment under
            the program, which considers:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The conservation practice cost-effectiveness, implementation
            efficiency, and innovation,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The degree and effectiveness in treating priority resource
            concerns,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The number of resource concerns the practice will address,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The longevity of the practice&apos;s environmental benefits,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The conservation practice&apos;s ability to assist producers in
            meeting regulatory requirements, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Other pertinent local considerations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payment rates will be established by the State Conservationist or
            designated conservationist, with advice from the State Technical
            Committee and local working groups.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Determining payment rates. (1) A payment to a producer for
            performing a practice may not exceed, as determined by the State or
            designated conservationist:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             75 percent of the estimated costs incurred by implementing the
            conservation practice;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             100 percent of the estimated income foregone; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Both conditions in paragraphs (c)(1)(i) and (ii) of this section,
            where a producer incurs costs in implementing a conservation
            practice and foregoes income related to that practice
            implementation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When determining payments for income foregone, the State
            Conservationist may give higher priority to the following
            conservation practices:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='iv_6_i_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Residue management;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='iv_6_i_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Nutrient management;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='iv_6_i_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Air quality management;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='iv_6_i_D'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (D)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Invasive species management;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='iv_6_i_E'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (E)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Pollinator habitat development or improvement;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='iv_6_i_F'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (F)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Animal carcass management technology; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='iv_6_i_G'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (G)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Pest management.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='iv_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notwithstanding paragraph (c)(1)(ii) of this section, a farmer or
            rancher meeting the historically underserved producer designation in
            
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1466' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
                1466.3
              </subref>
            </aref>
             may be awarded the applicable 
            <PRTPAGE P='803' />
            payment rate and an additional rate that is not less than 25 percent
            above the applicable rate, provided this increase does not exceed 90
            percent of the incurred costs estimated for the conservation
            practice.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='iv_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The payments to a participant will be reduced proportionately below
            the rate established by the State Conservationist or designated
            conservationist, to the extent that total financial contributions
            for a conservation practice from other sources exceed 100 percent of
            the estimated costs incurred for implementing or performing the
            conservation practice.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='iv_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State Conservationist shall provide payments for conservation
            practices on some or all of the operations of a producer related to
            organic production and the transition to organic production.
            Payments may not be made to cover the costs associated with organic
            certification or for practices that are eligible for cost-share
            payments under the National Organic Program (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='6523' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/6523.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 6523
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Practice payment rates greater than 50 percent for estimated costs
            incurred, excluding those described in paragraph (c)(2) of this
            section, are to be approved by the Chief.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subject to fund availability, the payment rates for conservation
            practices scheduled after the year of contract obligation may be
            adjusted to reflect increased costs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            74 FR 2313
          </aref>
          , Jan. 15, 2009]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12953'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1466:B:1466.24
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1466.24
      </num>
      <head>
        EQIP payments.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          68 FR 32348
        </aref>
        , May 30, 2003, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          74 FR 10675
        </aref>
        , Mar. 12, 2009]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1466' sect='24' psec='' tq='N'>
              1466.24
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          EQIP payments.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except for contracts entered into prior to October 1, 2008, or as
            provided in paragraph (b) of this section, the total amount of
            payments paid to a person or legal entity under this Part may not
            exceed an aggregate of $300,000, directly or indirectly, for all
            contracts, including prior year contracts, entered into during any
            6-year period. For the purpose of applying this requirement, the
            6-year period will include those payments made in fiscal years
            2009-2014. Payments received for technical assistance shall be
            excluded from this limitation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Chief may waive the $300,000 payment limitation, allowing up to
            $450,000 per person or legal entity for projects of special
            environmental significance, as defined in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1466' sect='21' psec='#d' tq='N'>
                1466.21(d)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payments for conservation practices related to organic production
            to a person or legal entity, directly or indirectly, may not exceed
            in aggregate $20,000 per year or $80,000 during any 6-year period.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To determine eligibility for payments, NRCS will use the following
            criteria:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The provisions in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
                1400 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , Payment Limitation and Payment Eligibility, subparts A and G.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             States, political subdivisions, and entities thereof will not be
            considered to be persons or legal entities eligible for payment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be eligible to receive an EQIP payment, all legal entities or
            persons applying, either alone or as part of a joint operation, must
            provide a tax identification number and percentage interest in the
            legal entity. In accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR 1400
            </aref>
            , an applicant applying as a joint operation or legal entity must
            provide a list of all members of the legal entity and joint
            operation and associated embedded entities, along with the
            members&apos; social security numbers and percentage interest in the
            joint operation or legal entity. Where applicable, American Indians,
            Alaska Natives, and Pacific Islanders may use another unique
            identification number for each individual eligible for payment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             With regard to contracts with Indian tribes or Indians represented
            by BIA, payments exceeding the payment limitation may be made to the
            Tribal participant if a BIA or Tribal official certifies in writing
            that no one individual, directly or indirectly, will receive more
            than the payment limitation. The Tribal entity must also provide,
            annually, a listing of individuals and payments made, by social
            security or tax identification number or other unique identification
            number, during the previous year for calculation of overall payment
            limitations. The BIA or Tribal entity must also produce, at the
            request of NRCS, proof of payments made to the person or legal
            entity that incurred costs or sacrificed income related to
            conservation practice implementation.
            <PRTPAGE P='804' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any cooperative association of producers that markets commodities
            for producers will not be considered to be a person eligible for
            payment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Eligibility for payments in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
                1400
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , subpart G of this chapter, average adjusted gross income
            limitation, will be determined prior to contract approval.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be eligible for payments for conservation practices related to
            organic production or the transition to organic production, a
            participant will develop and implement an organic system plan as
            defined in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1466' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
                1466.3
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Eligibility for higher payments in accordance with paragraph (b) of
            this section will be determined at the time of contract approval.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any participant that utilizes a unique identification number as an
            alternative to a tax identification number will utilize only that
            identifier for any and all other EQIP contracts to which the
            participant is a party. Violators will be considered to have
            provided fraudulent representation and be subject to full penalties
            of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1466' sect='35' psec='' tq='N'>
                1466.35
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A participant will not be eligible for payments for conservation
            practices on eligible land if the participant receives payments or
            other benefits for the same practice on the same land under any
            other conservation program administered by USDA.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_11'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (11)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State Conservationist may issue advance payments to
            historically underserved producers up to 30 percent of the
            anticipated amount of the costs incurred for the purpose of
            purchasing materials or services to implement a conservation
            practice.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_12'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (12)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Before NRCS will approve and issue final payment, the participant
            must certify that the conservation practice has been completed in
            accordance with the contract, and NRCS, or an approved TSP, must
            certify that the practice has been carried out in accordance with
            the applicable NRCS technical guidance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            68 FR 32348
          </aref>
          , May 30, 2003, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            74 FR 10675
          </aref>
          , Mar. 12, 2009]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12954'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1466:B:1466.25
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1466.25
      </num>
      <head>
        Contract modifications and transfers of land.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          74 FR 2313
        </aref>
        , Jan. 15, 2009]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1466' sect='25' psec='' tq='N'>
              1466.25
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Contract modifications and transfers of land.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The participant and NRCS may modify a contract if both parties
            agree to the contract modification, the EQIP plan of operations is
            revised in accordance with NRCS requirements, and the contract is
            approved by the designated conservationist.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             It is the participant&apos;s responsibility to notify NRCS when
            he/she either anticipates the voluntary or involuntary loss of
            control of the land covered by an EQIP contract.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The participant and NRCS may agree to transfer a contract to
            another party.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To receive an EQIP payment, the transferee must be determined by
            NRCS to be eligible to participate in EQIP and must assume full
            responsibility under the contract, including the O&amp;M agreement
            for those conservation practices already installed and those
            conservation practices to be installed as a condition of the
            contract.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the transferee is ineligible or refuses to accept future
            payments, NRCS will terminate the contract and may require the
            transferor to refund and/or forfeit all payments received.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS may require a participant to refund all or a portion of any
            financial assistance earned under EQIP if the participant sells or
            loses control of the land covered by an EQIP contract and the new
            owner or controller is not eligible to participate in the program or
            refuses to assume responsibility under the contract.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the event a conservation practice fails through no fault of the
            participant, the State Conservationist may issue payments to
            re-establish the practice, at the rates established in accordance
            with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1466' sect='23' psec='' tq='N'>
                1466.23
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , provided such payments do not exceed the payment limitation
            requirements as set forth 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1466' sect='24' psec='' tq='N'>
                1466.24
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            74 FR 2313
          </aref>
          , Jan. 15, 2009]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12955'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1466:B:1466.26
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1466.26
      </num>
      <head>
        Contract violations and terminations.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          74 FR 2313
        </aref>
        , Jan. 15, 2009]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1466' sect='26' psec='' tq='N'>
              1466.26
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Contract violations and terminations.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State Conservationist may terminate, or by mutual consent with
            the parties, terminate the contract where:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The parties to the contract are unable to comply with the terms of
            the contract as the result of conditions beyond their control;
            <PRTPAGE P='805' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Termination of the contract would, as determined by the State
            Conservationist, be in the public interest; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A participant fails to correct a contract violation within the time
            period defined by NRCS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a contract is terminated in accordance with the provisions of
            paragraphs (a)(1) and (a)(2) of this section, the State
            Conservationist may allow the participant to retain a portion of any
            payments received appropriate to the effort the participant has made
            to comply with the contract, or, in cases of hardship, where forces
            beyond the participant&apos;s control prevented compliance with the
            contract. If a participant claims hardship, such claims must be
            clearly documented and cannot have existed when the applicant
            applied for participation in the program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If NRCS determines that a participant is in violation of the terms
            of a contract, O&amp;M agreement, or documents incorporated by
            reference into the contract, NRCS shall give the participant a
            period of time, as determined by NRCS, to correct the violation and
            comply with the terms of the contract and attachments thereto. If a
            participant continues in violation, NRCS may terminate the EQIP
            contract in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1466' sect='26' psec='#e' tq='N'>
                1466.26(e)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph (c) of this section, a
            contract termination shall be effective immediately upon a
            determination by NRCS that the participant has submitted false
            information or filed a false claim, or engaged in any act, scheme,
            or device for which a finding of ineligibility for payments is
            permitted under the provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1466' sect='35' psec='' tq='N'>
                1466.35
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , or in a case in which the actions of the party involved are deemed
            to be sufficiently purposeful or negligent to warrant a termination
            without delay.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If NRCS terminates a contract due to breach of contract, the
            participant will forfeit all rights to future payments under the
            contract, pay liquidated damages, and refund all or part of the
            payments received, plus interest. Participants violating EQIP
            contracts may be determined ineligible for future NRCS-administered
            conservation program funding.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS may require a participant to provide only a partial refund of
            the payments received if a previously installed conservation
            practice can function independently, is not adversely affected by
            the violation or the absence of other conservation practices that
            would have been installed under the contract.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State Conservationist will have the option to reduce or waive
            the liquidated damages, depending upon the circumstances of the
            case.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When terminating a contract, NRCS may reduce the amount of money
            owed by the participant by a proportion that reflects the good faith
            effort of the participant to comply with the contract or the
            existence of hardships beyond the participant&apos;s control that
            have prevented compliance with the contract. If a participant claims
            hardship, that claim must be well documented and cannot have existed
            when the applicant applied for participation in the program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In carrying out its role in this section, NRCS may consult with the
            local conservation district.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State Conservationist, in consultation with the State Technical
            Committee, may terminate a contract whereby a producer is receiving
            payments for conservation practices related to organic production,
            if the designated conservationist determines that the producer is
            not pursuing organic certification, or has been decertified.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            74 FR 2313
          </aref>
          , Jan. 15, 2009]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12956'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1466:B:1466.27
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1466.27
      </num>
      <head>
        Conservation Innovation Grants (CIG).
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          69 FR 16397
        </aref>
        , Mar. 29, 2004; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          70 FR 1791
        </aref>
        , Jan. 11, 2005; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          74 FR 2316
        </aref>
        , Jan. 15, 2009]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1466' sect='27' psec='' tq='N'>
              1466.27
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Conservation Innovation Grants (CIG).
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Definitions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In addition to the terms defined in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1466' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
                1466.3
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
            , the following definitions shall be applicable to this section:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              EQIP eligible
            </E>
             means any farming entity, land, and practice that meets the
            definitions of EQIP as defined in 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR 1466
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Grant agreement
            </E>
             means a document describing a relationship between NRCS and a State
            or local government, or other recipient whenever the principal
            purpose of the relationship is the 
            <PRTPAGE P='806' />
            transfer of a thing of value to a recipient in order to accomplish a
            public purpose of support or stimulation authorized by Federal law,
            and substantial Federal involvement is not anticipated.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Grant Review Board
            </E>
             consists of the NRCS Deputy Chief for Programs, Deputy Chief for
            Science and Technology, Deputy Chief for Soil Survey and Resource
            Assessment, one Regional Assistant Chief, and one State
            Conservationist. The Review Board makes recommendations for grant
            awards to the Chief.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Peer Review Panel
            </E>
             means a panel consisting of Federal and non-Federal technical
            advisors who possess expertise in a discipline or disciplines deemed
            important to provide a technical evaluation of project proposals
            submitted under this notice.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Project
            </E>
             means the activities as defined within the scope of the grant
            agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Project Director
            </E>
             means the individual responsible for the technical direction and
            management of the project as designated in the application.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Purpose and scope—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Purpose.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The purpose of CIG is to stimulate the development and adoption of
            innovative conservation approaches and technologies while leveraging
            Federal investment in environmental enhancement and protection, in
            conjunction with agricultural production. Notwithstanding any
            limitation of this part, NRCS will administer CIG in accordance with
            this section. Unless otherwise provided for in this section, the
            provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR 3015
            </aref>
             and related Departmental regulations will be used to administer
            grants under CIG.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Geographic scope.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Applications for CIG are accepted from the fifty States, the
            District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, the
            Virgin Islands of the United States, American Samoa, and the
            Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Program scope.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Grants will be awarded using a two-tiered process. A nationwide
            grants competition will be announced in the 
            <E T='04'>
              Federal Register.
            </E>
             In addition, at the Chief&apos;s discretion, each State
            Conservationist may implement a separate State-level component of
            CIG.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Program focus.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Applications for CIG should demonstrate the use of innovative
            approaches and technologies to leverage Federal investment in
            environmental enhancement and protection, in conjunction with
            agricultural production. CIG will fund projects that promote
            innovative on-the-ground conservation, including pilot projects and
            field demonstrations of promising approaches or technologies. CIG
            projects are expected to lead to the transfer of conservation
            technologies, management systems, and innovative approaches (such as
            market-based systems) into NRCS technical manuals and guides, or to
            the private sector. Technologies and approaches eligible for funding
            in a project&apos;s geographic area through EQIP are not eligible
            for CIG funding except where the use of those technologies and
            approaches demonstrates clear innovation. The burden falls on the
            applicant to sufficiently describe the innovative features of the
            proposed technology or approach.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Innovative conservation projects or activities.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For the purposes of CIG, the proposed innovative project or
            activity must encompass the development and field testing,
            evaluation, and implementation of:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_5_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Conservation adoption incentive systems, including market-based
            systems; or,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_5_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Promising conservation technologies, practices, systems,
            procedures, and approaches.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          To be given priority consideration, the innovative project or
          activity:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_5_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Will have been studied sufficiently to indicate a good probability
            for success;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_5_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Demonstrates, tests, evaluates, or verifies environmental (soil,
            water, air, plants, and animal) effectiveness, utility,
            affordability, and usability in the field;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_5_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Adapts conservation technologies, practices, systems, procedures,
            approaches, and incentive systems to improve performance, and
            encourage adoption;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_5_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Introduces conservation systems, approaches, and procedures from
            another geographic area or agricultural sector; and
            <PRTPAGE P='807' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_5_vii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Adapts conservation technology, management, or incentive systems to
            improve performance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Availability of funding.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CIG funding will be available for single-or multi-year projects.
            Funding for CIG will be announced in the 
            <E T='04'>
              Federal Register
            </E>
             through a Request for Proposals (RFP). The Chief will determine the
            funding level for CIG on an annual basis. Funds for CIG are derived
            from funds made available for EQIP. The Chief may establish funding
            limits for individual grants.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Selected applicants may receive grants of up to 50 percent of the
            total project cost. Applicants must provide non-Federal funding for
            at least 50 percent of the project cost, of which up to one-half (25
            percent of total project cost) may be from in-kind contributions. An
            exception regarding matching funds may be made for grants that are
            awarded to either a Beginning or Limited Resource Farmer or Rancher,
            or Indian Tribe, or a community-based organization comprised of or
            representing these entities. Up to 75 percent of the required
            matching funds for these projects may derive from in-kind
            contributions.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CIG is designed to provide financial assistance to grantees.
            Procurement of any technical assistance required to carry out a
            project is the responsibility of the grantee. Technical oversight
            for grant projects will be provided by a Federal grant
            representative, who will be designated by NRCS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             There are some costs that grantees may not cover using CIG funds,
            such as costs incurred prior to the effective date of the grant,
            entertainment costs, any indirect cost exceeding fifteen percent, or
            renovation or refurbishment of facilities. A detailed list of costs
            not allowed will be published in the Request for Proposals.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Natural resource conservation concerns.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CIG applications must describe the use of innovative approaches or
            technologies to address a natural resource conservation concern or
            concerns. The natural resource concerns for CIG will be identified
            by the Chief, and may change each year. The natural resource
            concerns will be published in the RFP.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Eligibility information—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Organization or individual eligibility.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be eligible, CIG applicants must be an Indian Tribe; State or
            local unit of government; non-governmental organization; or
            individual.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Project eligibility.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be eligible, projects must involve landowners who meet the
            eligibility requirements of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1466' sect='8' psec='#b_1' tq='N'>
                1466.8(b)(1)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             through (3) of this part. Further, all agricultural producers
            receiving a direct or indirect payment through participation in a
            CIG project must meet those eligibility requirements.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Beginning and Limited Resource Farmers and Ranchers, and Indian
              Tribes.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Up to 10 percent of the total funds available for CIG may be
            set-aside for applications from either a Beginning or Limited
            Resource Farmer or Rancher, or Indian Tribe, or a community-based
            organization comprised of or representing these entities. Funds not
            awarded from the set-aside pool will revert back into the general
            CIG funding pool.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Application and submission information.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The CIG RFP will contain guidance on how to apply for the grants
            competition. CIG will be advertised through the 
            <E T='04'>
              Federal Register,
            </E>
             the NRCS Web site, and 
            <E T='03'>
              grants.gov.
            </E>
             Grant applications will be available on the NRCS Web site, or by
            contacting NRCS at the address provided in the RFP. CIG grant
            applications will consist of standard cover sheet and budget forms,
            in addition to a narrative project description and required legal
            declarations and certifications.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Application review and grant awards.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Complete applications will be evaluated by a peer review panel and
            scored based on the Criteria for Proposal Evaluation identified in
            the RFP. Scored applications will be forwarded to a Grant Review
            Board. The Grant Review Board will make recommendations for awards
            to the Chief. Final award selections will be made by the Chief.
            Grant awards will be made by the NRCS National Office after
            selection of the grantees is made and after the grantee agrees to
            the terms and conditions of the NRCS Grant document.
            <PRTPAGE P='808' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
            <head>
              State component.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             At the discretion of the Chief, each State Conservationist has the
            option of implementing a State-level CIG component. A State program
            will follow the requirements of this section, except for those
            features described in this paragraph (h).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Funding availability, application, and submission information for
            State competitions will be announced through public notices (and on
            the State NRCS Web site), separately from the national program. The
            State component will emphasize projects that cover limited
            geographic areas, including individual farms, multi-county areas, or
            small watersheds.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State Conservationist will determine the funding level for the
            grants competition, with individual grants not to exceed $75,000.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State Conservationist may choose to adhere to the CIG national
            natural resource concerns, or may select a subset of those concerns
            that more closely match the natural resource concerns in his or her
            State.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Applications will be scored by the State Technical Committee, or a
            sub-committee thereof, based on the national Criteria for Proposal
            Evaluation published in the CIG RFP. Scored applications will be
            forwarded to the State Conservationist, who will make the award
            selections.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In addition to abiding by the in-kind contribution exception for
            Limited Resource and Beginning Farmers and Ranchers, and Indian
            Tribes in paragraph (c)(2) of this section, the State
            Conservationist in each participating State will determine if and
            how to provide additional special consideration to underserved
            groups.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Grant agreement.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The CCC, through NRCS, will use a grant agreement with selected
            grantees to document participation in CIG.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Patents and inventions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Allocation of rights to patents and inventions shall be in
            accordance with USDA regulation 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR 
              <subref title='7' part='3019' sect='36' psec='' tq='N'>
                3019.36
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . This regulation provides that small businesses normally may retain
            the principal worldwide patent rights to any invention developed
            with USDA support. In accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR 
              <subref title='7' part='3019' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
                3019.2
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , this provision will also apply to commercial organizations for the
            purposes of CIG. USDA receives a royalty-free license for Federal
            Government use, reserves the right to require the patentee to
            license others in certain circumstances, and requires that anyone
            exclusively licensed to sell the invention in the United States must
            normally manufacture it domestically.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Violations.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A person found in violation of this section is subject to the
            provisions contained in 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3015' tq='N'>
                3015
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and related Departmental regulations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            69 FR 16397
          </aref>
          , Mar. 29, 2004; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            70 FR 1791
          </aref>
          , Jan. 11, 2005; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            74 FR 2316
          </aref>
          , Jan. 15, 2009]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12957'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1466:C:1466.30
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1466.30
      </num>
      <head>
        Appeals.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1466' sect='30' psec='' tq='N'>
              1466.30
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Appeals.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          A participant may obtain administrative review of an adverse decision
          under EQIP in accordance with 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            parts 
            <subref title='7' part='11' tq='N'>
              11
            </subref>
             and 
            <subref title='7' part='614' tq='N'>
              614 of this title
            </subref>
          </aref>
          . Determination in matters of general applicability, such as payment
          rates, payment limits, the designation of identified priority resource
          concerns, and eligible conservation practices are not subject to
          appeal.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12958'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1466:C:1466.31
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1466.31
      </num>
      <head>
        Compliance with regulatory measures.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1466' sect='31' psec='' tq='N'>
              1466.31
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Compliance with regulatory measures.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Participants who carry out conservation practices shall be responsible
          for obtaining the authorities, rights, easements, permits, or other
          approvals necessary for the implementation, operation, and maintenance
          of the conservation practices in keeping with applicable laws and
          regulations. Participants shall be responsible for compliance with all
          laws and for all effects or actions resulting from the
          participant&apos;s performance under the contract.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12959'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1466:C:1466.32
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1466.32
      </num>
      <head>
        Access to operating unit.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1466' sect='32' psec='' tq='N'>
              1466.32
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Access to operating unit.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Any authorized NRCS representative shall have the right to enter an
          agricultural operation or tract for the purposes of determining
          eligibility and for ascertaining the accuracy of any representations
          related to contract performance. Access shall include the right to
          provide technical assistance, determine eligibility, inspect any work 
          <PRTPAGE P='809' />
          undertaken under the contract, and collect information necessary to
          evaluate the conservation practice performance, specified in the
          contract. The NRCS representative shall make an effort to contact the
          participant prior to the exercising this provision.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12960'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1466:C:1466.33
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1466.33
      </num>
      <head>
        Equitable relief.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1466' sect='33' psec='' tq='N'>
              1466.33
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Equitable relief.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a participant relied upon the advice or action of any authorized
            NRCS representative and did not know, or have reason to know, that
            the action or advice was improper or erroneous, NRCS may accept the
            advice or action as meeting program requirements and may grant
            relief, to the extent it is deemed desirable by NRCS, to provide a
            fair and equitable treatment because of the good-faith reliance on
            the part of the participant. The financial or technical liability
            for any action by a participant that was taken based on the advice
            of a NRCS certified non-USDA TSP is the responsibility of the
            certified TSP and will not be assumed by NRCS when NRCS authorizes
            payment. Where a participant believes that detrimental reliance on
            the advice or action of a NRCS representative resulted in an
            ineligibility or program violation, but the participant believes
            that a good faith effort to comply was made, the participant may
            request equitable relief under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='635' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
                635.3
              </subref>
            </aref>
             in chapter VI of this title.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If, during the term of an EQIP contract, a participant has been
            found in violation of a provision of the EQIP contract, the O&amp;M
            agreement, or any document incorporated by reference through failure
            to fully comply with that provision, the participant may be eligible
            for equitable relief under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='635' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
                635.4
              </subref>
            </aref>
             in chapter VI of this title.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12961'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1466:C:1466.34
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1466.34
      </num>
      <head>
        Offsets and assignments.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1466' sect='34' psec='' tq='N'>
              1466.34
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Offsets and assignments.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as provided in paragraph (b) of this section, any payment or
            portion thereof to any person, joint venture, legal entity or tribe
            shall be made without regard to questions of title under State law
            and without regard to any claim or lien against the crop, or
            proceeds thereof, in favor of the owner or any other creditor except
            agencies of the U.S. Government. The regulations governing offsets
            and withholdings found at 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1403' tq='N'>
                1403 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
             shall be applicable to contract payments.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             EQIP participants may assign any payments in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1404' tq='N'>
                1404 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12962'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1466:C:1466.35
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1466.35
      </num>
      <head>
        Misrepresentation and scheme or device.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1466' sect='35' psec='' tq='N'>
              1466.35
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Misrepresentation and scheme or device.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A person, joint venture, legal entity or tribe that is determined
            to have erroneously represented any fact affecting a program
            determination made in accordance with this Part shall not be
            entitled to contract payments and must refund to NRCS all payments,
            plus interest determined in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1403' tq='N'>
                1403 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A producer who is determined to have knowingly:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Adopted any scheme or device that tends to defeat the purpose of
            the program;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Made any fraudulent representation;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Adopted any scheme or device for the purpose of depriving any
            tenant or sharecropper of the payments to which such person would
            otherwise be entitled under the program; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Misrepresented any fact affecting a program determination, shall
            refund to NRCS all payments, plus interest determined in accordance
            with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR 1403
            </aref>
            , received by such producer with respect to all contracts. The
            producer&apos;s interest in all contracts shall be terminated.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1466' sect='26' psec='#e' tq='N'>
                1466.26(e)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , NRCS may determine the producer ineligible for future conservation
            programs funding.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12963'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1466:C:1466.36
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1466.36
      </num>
      <head>
        Environmental credits for conservation improvements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1466' sect='36' psec='' tq='N'>
              1466.36
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Environmental credits for conservation improvements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          NRCS recognizes that environmental benefits will be achieved by
          implementing conservation practices funded through EQIP, and
          environmental credits may be gained as a result of implementing
          activities compatible with the purposes of an EQIP contract. NRCS
          asserts no direct or indirect interest on these credits. However, NRCS
          retains the authority to ensure that operation and maintenance
          (O&amp;M) requirements for EQIP-funded improvements are met,
          consistent with 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1466' sect='21' psec='' tq='N'>
              1466.21
            </subref>
             and 
            <subref title='7' part='1466' sect='22' psec='' tq='N'>
              1466.22
            </subref>
          </aref>
          . Where activities may impact 
          <PRTPAGE P='810' />
          the land under an EQIP contract, participants are highly encouraged to
          request an O&amp;M compatibility determination from NRCS prior to
          entering into any credit agreements.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>