<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol15'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXII:-:3202
    </extid>
    <num>
      3202
    </num>
    <head>
      VOLUNTARY LABELING PROGRAM FOR BIOBASED PRODUCTS
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='8102' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/8102.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 8102
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 3806
          </aref>
          , Jan. 20, 2011. Redesignated at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 53632
          </aref>
          , Aug. 29, 2011.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='16357'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXII:-:3202:-:3202.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3202.1
      </num>
      <head>
        Purpose and scope.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3202' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              3202.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Purpose and scope.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The purpose of this part is to set forth the terms and conditions for
          voluntary use of the “USDA Certified Biobased Product” certification
          mark. This part establishes the criteria that biobased products must
          meet in order to be eligible to become certified biobased products to
          which the “USDA Certified Biobased Product” mark can be affixed, the
          process manufacturers and vendors must use to obtain and maintain USDA
          certification, and the recordkeeping requirements for manufacturers
          and vendors who obtain certification. In addition, this part
          establishes specifications for the correct and incorrect uses of the
          certification mark, which apply to manufacturers, vendors, and other
          entities. Finally, this part establishes actions that constitute
          voluntary labeling program violations.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16358'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXII:-:3202:-:3202.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3202.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          76 FR 3806
        </aref>
        , Jan. 20, 2011. Redesignated and amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          76 FR 53632
        </aref>
        , Aug. 29, 2011]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3202' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              3202.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Applicable minimum biobased content.
          </E>
           The biobased content at or above the level set by USDA to qualify for
          use of the certification mark.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            ASTM International (ASTM).
          </E>
           American Society for Testing and Materials is a nonprofit
          organization that provides an international forum for the development
          and publication of voluntary consensus standards for materials,
          products, systems, and services.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Biobased content.
          </E>
           The amount of biobased carbon in the material or product expressed as
          a percent of weight (mass) of the total organic carbon in the material
          or product. For BioPreferred Products (products that have been
          identified for Federal preferred procurement), the biobased content
          shall be defined and determined as specified in the applicable section
          of subpart B of 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='3201' tq='N'>
              3201
            </subref>
          </aref>
          . For all other products, the biobased content is to be determined
          using ASTM Method D6866, Standard Test Methods for Determining the
          Biobased Content of Solid, Liquid, and Gaseous Samples Using
          Radiocarbon Analysis.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Biobased product.
          </E>
           A product determined by the Secretary to be a commercial or
          industrial product (other than food or feed) that is:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Composed, in whole or in significant part, of biological products,
            including renewable domestic agricultural materials and forestry
            materials; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An intermediate ingredient or feedstock. For the purposes of this
            subpart, the term `biobased product&apos; does not include motor
            vehicle fuels, heating oil, electricity produced from biomass, or
            any mature market products.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            BioPreferred Product.
          </E>
           A biobased product that meets or exceeds minimum biobased content
          levels set by USDA, and that is found within any of the product
          categories that have been identified, in subpart B of 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR part 
            <subref title='7' part='3201' tq='N'>
              3201
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , whose products within are eligible for Federal preferred
          procurement/purchasing.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Certification mark.
          </E>
           A combination of the certification mark artwork (as defined in this
          subpart); one of three statements identifying whether the USDA
          certification applies to the product, the package, or both the product
          and package; and, where applicable, the letters “FP” to indicate that
          the product is within a designated product category and eligible for
          Federal preferred procurement. The certification mark is owned, and
          its use is managed by, USDA (standard trademark law definition
          applies).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Certification mark artwork.
          </E>
           The distinctive image, as shown in Figures 1-3, that identifies
          products as USDA Certified.
        </P>
        <GPH DEEP='125' SPAN='2'>
          <PRTPAGE P='317' />
          <GID>
            ER20JA11.000
          </GID>
        </GPH>
        <GPH DEEP='342' SPAN='2'>
          <GID>
            ER20JA11.001
          </GID>
        </GPH>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Certified biobased product.
          </E>
           A biobased product for which the manufacturer or vendor of the
          product has received approval from USDA to affix to the product the
          “USDA Certified Biobased Product” certification mark.
          <PRTPAGE P='318' />
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Days.
          </E>
           As used in this part means calendar days.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Designated item.
          </E>
           For the purposes of this part means product categories (generic
          groupings of products that perform the same function) within which the
          products have been afforded a procurement preference by Federal
          agencies under the BioPreferred Program. These BioPreferred Products
          have been identified for Federal preferred procurement under subpart B
          of 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='3201' tq='N'>
              3201 of this title
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Designated representative.
          </E>
           An entity authorized by a manufacturer or vendor to affix the USDA
          certification mark to the manufacturer&apos;s or vendor&apos;s
          certified biobased product or its packaging.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Intermediate ingredients or feedstocks.
          </E>
           Materials or compounds made in whole or in significant part from
          biological products, including renewable agricultural materials
          (including plant, animal, and marine materials) or forestry materials,
          that are subsequently used to make a more complex compound or product.
          For the purposes of this subpart, intermediate ingredients or
          feedstocks do not include raw agricultural or forestry materials, but
          represent those materials that can be put into a new cycle of
          production and finishing processes to create finished materials, ready
          for distribution and consumption.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            ISO.
          </E>
           The International Organization for Standardization, a network of
          national standards institutes working in partnership with
          international organizations, governments, industries, business, and
          consumer representatives.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            ISO 9001 conformant.
          </E>
           An entity that meets all of the requirements of the ISO 9001
          standard, but that is not required to be ISO 9001 certified. ISO 9001
          refers to the International Organization for Standardization&apos;s
          standards and guidelines relating to “quality management” systems.
          “Quality management” is defined as what the manufacturer does to
          ensure that its products or services satisfy the customer&apos;s
          quality requirements and comply with any regulations applicable to
          those products or services.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Manufacturer.
          </E>
           An entity that performs the necessary chemical and/or mechanical
          processes to make a final marketable product.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Mature market products.
          </E>
           Biobased products that are not eligible for Federal preferred
          procurement or labeling as defined under subpart B of 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='3201' tq='N'>
              3201 of this title
            </subref>
          </aref>
           because they had significant national market penetration in 1972.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Other entity.
          </E>
           Any person, group, public or private organization, or business other
          than USDA, or manufacturers or vendors of biobased products that may
          wish to use the “USDA Certified Biobased Product” certification mark
          in informational or promotional material related to a certified
          biobased product.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Program Manager.
          </E>
           The manager of the BioPreferred Program.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            USDA.
          </E>
           The United States Department of Agriculture.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Vendor.
          </E>
           An entity that offers for sale final marketable biobased products
          that are produced by manufacturers.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 3806
          </aref>
          , Jan. 20, 2011. Redesignated and amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 53632
          </aref>
          , Aug. 29, 2011]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16359'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXII:-:3202:-:3202.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3202.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Applicability.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3202' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              3202.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Applicability.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Manufacturers, vendors, and designated representatives.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The requirements in this part apply to all manufacturers and
            vendors, and their designated representatives, who wish to
            participate in the USDA voluntary labeling program for biobased
            products. Manufacturers and vendors wishing to participate in the
            voluntary labeling program are required to obtain and maintain
            product certification.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Other entities.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The requirements in this part apply to other entities who wish to
            use the certification mark in promoting the sales or the public
            awareness of certified biobased products.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16360'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXII:-:3202:-:3202.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3202.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Criteria for product eligibility to use the certification mark.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          76 FR 3806
        </aref>
        , Jan. 20, 2011. Redesignated and amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          76 FR 53632
        </aref>
        , Aug. 29, 2011]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3202' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              3202.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Criteria for product eligibility to use the certification mark.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          A product must meet each of the criteria specified in paragraphs (a)
          and (b) of this section in order to be eligible to receive biobased
          product certification.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Biobased product.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The product for which certification is sought must be a biobased
            product as defined in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='3202' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
                3202.2
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Minimum biobased content.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The biobased content of the product must 
            <PRTPAGE P='319' />
            be equal to or greater than the applicable minimum biobased content,
            as described in paragraphs (b)(1) through (b)(4) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              BioPreferred Products—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Product is within a single product category.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the product is within a single product category that, at the
            time the application for certification is submitted, has been
            designated by USDA for Federal preferred procurement, the applicable
            minimum biobased content is the minimum biobased content specified
            for the item as found in subpart B of 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3201' tq='N'>
                3201
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Product is within multiple product categories.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a biobased product is marketed within more than one product
            category identified for preferred Federal purchasing, uses the same
            packaging for each product, and the applicant seeks certification of
            the product, the product&apos;s biobased content must meet or exceed
            the specified minimum biobased content for each of the applicable
            product categories in order to use the certification mark on the
            product. However, if the manufacturer packages the product
            differently for each product category, then the applicable minimum
            biobased contents are those established under paragraph (b)(1)(i) of
            this section for each product category for which the applicant seeks
            to use the certification mark.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Finished biobased products that are not BioPreferred Products.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the product is not an intermediate ingredient or feedstock, and
            is not within a product category eligible for Federal preferred
            procurement at the time the application for certification is
            submitted, the applicable minimum biobased content is 25 percent.
            Manufacturers, vendors, groups of manufacturers and/or vendors, and
            trade associations may propose an alternative applicable minimum
            biobased content for the product by developing, in consultation with
            USDA, and conducting an analysis to support the proposed alternative
            applicable minimum biobased content. If approved by USDA, the
            proposed alternative applicable minimum biobased content would
            become the applicable minimum biobased content for the product to be
            labeled.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a product certified under paragraph (b)(2)(i) of this section is
            within a product category that USDA subsequently designates for
            Federal preferred procurement, the applicable minimum biobased
            content shall become, as of the effective date of the final
            designation rule, the minimum biobased content specified for the
            item as found in subpart B of 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3201' tq='N'>
                3201
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Products that are intermediate ingredients or feedstocks.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the product is an intermediate ingredient or feedstock that is
            not eligible for Federal preferred procurement at the time the
            application for certification is submitted, the applicable minimum
            biobased content is 25 percent. Manufacturers, vendors, groups of
            manufacturers and/or vendors, and trade associations may propose an
            alternative applicable minimum biobased content for the product by
            developing, in consultation with USDA, and conducting an analysis to
            support the proposed alternative applicable minimum biobased
            content. If approved by USDA, the proposed alternative applicable
            minimum biobased content would become the applicable minimum
            biobased content for the intermediate ingredient or feedstock
            product to be labeled.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a product certified under paragraph (b)(3)(i) of this section is
            within a category that USDA subsequently designates for Federal
            preferred procurement, the applicable minimum biobased content shall
            become, as of the effective date of the final designation rule, the
            minimum biobased content specified for the item as found in subpart
            B of 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3201' tq='N'>
                3201
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 3806
          </aref>
          , Jan. 20, 2011. Redesignated and amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 53632
          </aref>
          , Aug. 29, 2011]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16361'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXII:-:3202:-:3202.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3202.5
      </num>
      <head>
        Initial approval process.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          76 FR 3806
        </aref>
        , Jan. 20, 2011. Redesignated and amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          76 FR 53632
        </aref>
        , Aug. 29, 2011]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3202' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              3202.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Initial approval process.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Application.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Manufacturers and vendors seeking USDA approval to use the
            certification mark for an eligible biobased product must submit a
            USDA-approved application for each biobased product. A standardized
            application form and instructions are available on the USDA
            BioPreferred Program Web site (
            <E T='03'>
              http://www.biopreferred.gov
            </E>
            ). The contents of an acceptable application are as specified in
            paragraphs (a)(1) through (a)(4) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General content.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The applicant must provide contact information and 
            <PRTPAGE P='320' />
            product information including all brand names or other identifying
            information, biobased content and testing documentation, intended
            uses, and, if applicable, the corresponding product category
            classification for Federal preferred procurement. The applicant must
            attach to the application documentation demonstrating that the
            reported biobased content was tested by a third-party testing entity
            that is ISO 9001 conformant.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Certifications.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The applicant must certify in the application that the product for
            which use of the certification mark is sought is a biobased product
            as defined in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='3202' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
                3202.2
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Commitments.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The applicant must sign a statement in the application that commits
            the applicant to submitting to USDA the information specified in
            paragraph (c)(1) through (c)(4) of this section, which USDA will
            post to the USDA BioPreferred Program Web site, and to providing
            USDA with up-to-date information for posting on this Web site.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Application fee.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Effective (date to be added after authority to collect fee is
            granted), applicants must submit an application fee of $500 with
            each completed application for certification. Instructions for
            submitting the application fee are available on the USDA
            BioPreferred Program Web site (
            <E T='03'>
              http://www.biopreferred.gov
            </E>
            ), along with the application form and instructions.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Evaluation of applications.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             USDA will evaluate each application to determine if it contains the
            information specified in paragraph (a) of this section. If USDA
            determines that the application is not complete, USDA will return
            the application to the applicant with an explanation of its
            deficiencies. Once the deficiencies have been addressed, the
            applicant may resubmit the application, along with a cover letter
            explaining the changes made, for re-evaluation by USDA. USDA will
            evaluate resubmitted applications separately from first-time
            applications, and those with the earliest original application
            submittal date will be given first priority.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             USDA will evaluate each complete application to determine
            compliance with the criteria specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='3202' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
                3202.4
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . USDA will provide a written response to each applicant within 60
            days after the receipt of a complete application, informing the
            applicant of whether the application has been conditionally approved
            or has been disapproved.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For those applications that are conditionally approved, a notice of
            certification, as specified in paragraph (c) of this section, must
            be issued before the use of the certification mark can begin.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For those applications that are disapproved, USDA will issue a
            notice of denial of certification and will inform the applicant in
            writing of each criterion not met. Applicants who receive a notice
            of denial of certification may appeal using the procedures specified
            in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='3202' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
                3202.6
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Notice of certification.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             After notification that its application has been conditionally
            approved, the applicant must provide to USDA (for posting by USDA on
            the USDA BioPreferred Program Web site) the information specified in
            paragraphs (c)(1) through (c)(4) of this section. Once USDA confirms
            that the information is received and complete, USDA will issue a
            notice of certification to the applicant. Upon receipt of a notice
            of certification, the applicant may begin using the certification
            mark on the certified biobased product.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The product&apos;s brand name(s), or other identifying information.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Contact information, including the name, mailing address, email
            address, and telephone number of the applicant.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The biobased content of the product.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A hot link directly to the applicant&apos;s Web site (if
            available).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Term of certification.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The effective date of certification is the date that the applicant
            receives a notice of certification from USDA. Except as specified in
            paragraphs (d)(2)(i) through (d)(2)(iii) of this section,
            certifications will remain in effect as long as the product is
            manufactured and marketed in accordance with the approved
            application and the requirements of this subpart.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the product formulation of a certified product is changed such
            that 
            <PRTPAGE P='321' />
            the biobased content of the product is reduced to a level below that
            reported in the approved application, the existing certification
            will not be valid for the product under the revised conditions and
            the manufacturer or vendor, as applicable, and its designated
            representatives must discontinue affixing the certification mark to
            the product and must not initiate any further advertising of the
            product using the certification mark. USDA will consider a product
            under such revised conditions to be a reformulated product, and the
            manufacturer or vendor, as applicable, must submit a new application
            for certification using the procedures specified in paragraph (a) of
            this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the product formulation of a certified product is changed such
            that the biobased content of the product is increased from the level
            reported in the approved application, the existing certification
            will continue to be valid for the product.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the applicable required minimum biobased content for a product
            to be eligible to display the certification mark is revised by USDA,
            manufacturers and vendors may continue to label their previously
            certified product only if it meets the new minimum biobased content
            level. In those cases where the biobased content of a certified
            product fails to meet the new minimum biobased content level, USDA
            will notify the manufacturer or vendor that their certification is
            no longer valid. Such manufacturers and vendors must increase the
            biobased content of their product to a level at or above the new
            minimum biobased content level and must re-apply for certification
            within 60 days if they wish to continue to use the certification
            mark. Manufacturers and vendors who have re-applied for
            certification may continue using the existing certification mark
            until they receive notification from USDA on the results of their
            re-application for certification.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 3806
          </aref>
          , Jan. 20, 2011. Redesignated and amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 53632
          </aref>
          , Aug. 29, 2011]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16362'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXII:-:3202:-:3202.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3202.6
      </num>
      <head>
        Appeal processes.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          76 FR 3806
        </aref>
        , Jan. 20, 2011. Redesignated and amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          76 FR 53632
        </aref>
        , Aug. 29, 2011]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3202' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              3202.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Appeal processes.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          An applicant for certification may appeal a notice of denial of
          certification to the Program Manager. Entities that have received a
          notice of violation, and manufacturers and vendors of certified
          biobased products who have received a notice of suspension or
          revocation, may appeal to the Program Manager.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Appeals to the Program Manager must be filed within 30 days of
            receipt by the appellant of a notice of denial of certification, a
            notice of violation, a notice of suspension, or a notice of
            revocation. Appeals must be filed in writing and addressed to:
            Program Manager, USDA Voluntary Labeling Program for Biobased
            Products, Room 361, Reporters Building, 300 Seventh Street, SW.,
            Washington, DC 20024.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All appeals must include a copy of the adverse decision and a
            statement of the appellant&apos;s reasons for believing that the
            decision was not made in accordance with applicable program
            regulations, policies, or procedures, or otherwise was not proper.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the Program Manager sustains an applicant&apos;s appeal of a
            notice of denial of certification, USDA will issue a notice of
            certification to the applicant for its biobased product.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the Program Manager sustains a manufacturer&apos;s or
            vendor&apos;s appeal of a notice of violation, USDA will rescind the
            notice and no further action will be taken by USDA.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the Program Manager sustains a manufacturer&apos;s or
            vendor&apos;s appeal of a notice of suspension, the manufacturer,
            vendor, and their designated representative(s) may immediately
            resume affixing the certification mark to the certified biobased
            product and USDA will reinstate the product&apos;s information to
            the USDA BioPreferred Program Web site.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the Program Manager sustains a manufacturer&apos;s or
            vendor&apos;s appeal of a notice of revocation, the manufacturer or
            vendor, and its designated representatives may immediately resume
            affixing the certification mark to the certified biobased product
            and sell and distribute the certified biobased product with the
            certification mark. In addition, USDA will reinstate the
            product&apos;s information to the USDA BioPreferred Program Web
            site.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the Program Manager sustains a manufacturer&apos;s or
            vendor&apos;s appeal of its product&apos;s exclusion from the
            program, the manufacturers or vendors 
            <PRTPAGE P='322' />
            may then apply for certification to use the certification mark on
            that product, as specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='3202' sect='5' psec='#a' tq='N'>
                3202.5(a)
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Appeals of any of the Program Manager&apos;s decisions may be made
            to the USDA Assistant Secretary for Administration. Appeals must be
            made, in writing, within 30 days of receipt of the Program
            Manager&apos;s decision and addressed to: Assistant Secretary for
            Administration, Room 209A, Whitten Building, 1400 Independence
            Avenue, SW., Washington, DC 20250-0103. If the Assistant Secretary
            for Administration sustains an appeal, the provisions of paragraph
            (b) of this section will apply.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 3806
          </aref>
          , Jan. 20, 2011. Redesignated and amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 53632
          </aref>
          , Aug. 29, 2011]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16363'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXII:-:3202:-:3202.7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3202.7
      </num>
      <head>
        Requirements associated with the certification mark.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3202' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              3202.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Requirements associated with the certification mark.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Who may use the certification mark?
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text />
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Manufacturers and vendors.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Only manufacturers and vendors who have received a notice of
            certification, or designated representatives of the manufacturer or
            vendor, may affix the official certification mark (in one of the
            three variations, as applicable) to the product or its packaging. A
            manufacturer or vendor who has received a notice of certification
            for a product under this part:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             May use the certification mark on the product, its packaging, and
            other related materials including, but not limited to,
            advertisements, catalogs, specification sheets, procurement
            databases, promotional material, Web sites, or user manuals for that
            product, according to the requirements set forth in this section;
            and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is responsible for the manner in which the mark is used by its
            companies, as well as its designated representatives, including
            advertising agencies, marketing and public relations firms and
            subcontractors.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Other entities.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Other entities may use the mark to advertise or promote certified
            biobased products in materials including, but not limited to,
            advertisements, catalogs, procurement databases, Web sites, and
            promotional and educational materials, as long as the manufacturer
            or vendor of the product, or one of their designated
            representatives, has affixed the mark to the product or its
            packaging.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Other entities may use the certification mark; the phrase “USDA
            Certified Biobased Product/Package/Product &amp; Package,” as
            applicable; and the BioPreferred Program name in general statements
            as described in paragraph (b) of this section, as long as the
            statements do not imply that a non-certified biobased product is
            certified.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Correct usage of the certification mark.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The certification mark can be affixed only to certified biobased
            products and their associated packaging.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The certification mark may be used in material including, but not
            limited to, advertisements, catalogs, procurement databases, Web
            sites, and promotional and educational materials to distinguish
            products that are certified for use of the label from those that are
            not certified. The certification mark may be used in advertisements
            for both certified biobased products and non-certified/labeled
            products if the advertisement clearly indicates which products are
            certified/labeled. Care must be taken to avoid implying that any
            non-certified products are certified.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The certification mark may be used without reference to a specific
            certified biobased product only when informing the public about the
            purpose of the certification mark. For example, the following or
            similar claim is acceptable: “Look for the `USDA Certified Biobased
            Product&apos; certification mark. It means that the product meets
            USDA standards for the amount of biobased content and the
            manufacturer or vendor has provided relevant information on the
            product to be posted on the USDA BioPreferred Program Web site.”
            This exception allows manufacturers, vendors, and other entities to
            use the certification mark in documents such as corporate reports,
            but only in an informative manner, not as a statement of product
            certification.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The certification mark may appear next to a picture of the
            product(s) or text describing it.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The certification mark must stand alone and not be incorporated
            into any other certification mark or logo designs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The certification mark may be used as a watermark provided the use 
            <PRTPAGE P='323' />
            does not violate any usage restrictions specified in this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The text portion of the certification mark must be written in
            English and may not be translated, even when the certification mark
            is used outside of the United States.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Incorrect usage of the certification mark.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The certification mark shall not be used on any product that has
            not been certified by USDA as a “USDA Certified Biobased Product.”
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The certification mark shall not be used on any advertisements or
            informational materials where both certified biobased products and
            non-certified products are shown unless it is clear that the
            certification mark applies to only the certified biobased
            product(s).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The certification mark shall not be used to imply endorsement by
            USDA or the BioPreferred Program of any particular product, service,
            or company.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The certification mark shall not be used in any form that could be
            misleading to the consumer.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The certification mark shall not be used by manufacturers or
            vendors of certified products in a manner disparaging to USDA or any
            other government body.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The certification mark shall not be used with an altered
            certification mark or incorporated into other label or logo designs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The certification mark shall not be used on business cards, company
            letterhead, or company stationery.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The certification mark shall not be used in, or as part of, any
            company name, logo, product name, service, or Web site, except as
            may be provided for in this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The certification mark shall not be used in a manner that violates
            any of the applicable requirements contained in this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Imported products.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The certification mark can be used only with a product that is
            certified by USDA under this part. The certification mark cannot be
            used to imply that a product meets or exceeds the requirements of
            biobased programs in other countries. Products imported for sale in
            the U.S. must adhere to the same guidelines as U.S.-sourced biobased
            products. Any product sold in the U.S. as a “USDA Certified Biobased
            Product/Package/Product &amp; Package” must have received
            certification from USDA.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Contents of the certification mark.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The certification mark shall consist of the certification mark
            artwork, the biobased content percentage, and one of the three
            variations of text specified in paragraphs (e)(1) through (e)(3) of
            this section, as applicable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             USDA Certified Biobased Product.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             USDA Certified Biobased Product: Package.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             USDA Certified Biobased Product &amp; Package.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Physical aspects of the certification mark.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The certification mark artwork may not be altered, cut, separated
            into components, or distorted in appearance or perspective.
            Certification marks that are applied to biobased products that have
            been designated for preferred Federal procurement will include the
            letters “FP” as part of the certification mark artwork. The
            certification mark must appear only in the colors specified in
            paragraphs (f)(1) through (f)(3) of this section, unless approval is
            given by USDA for an exception.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A multi-color version of the certification mark is preferred. The
            certification mark colors to be applied will be stipulated in the
            “Marketing Guides” document available on the USDA BioPreferred
            Program Web site (
            <E T='03'>
              http://www.biopreferred.gov
            </E>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A one-color version of the certification mark may be substituted
            for the multi-color version as long as the one color used is one of
            the multi-color choices reapplied without modification. Further
            guidance on the one-color certification mark application will also
            be detailed in the “Marketing Guides.”
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A black and white version of the certification mark is acceptable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Placement of the certification mark.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The certification mark can appear directly on a product, its
            associated packaging, in user manuals, and in other materials
            including, but not limited to, advertisements, catalogs, procurement
            databases, and promotional and educational materials.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The certification mark shall not be placed in a manner that is
            ambiguous about which product is a certified 
            <PRTPAGE P='324' />
            biobased product or that could indicate certification of a
            non-certified product.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When used to distinguish a certified biobased product in material
            including, but not limited to, advertisements, catalogs, procurement
            databases, Web sites, and promotional and educational materials, the
            certification mark must appear near a picture of the product or the
            text describing it.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If all products on a page are certified biobased products, the
            certification mark may be placed anywhere on the page.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a page contains a mix of certified biobased products and
            non-certified products, the certification mark shall be placed in
            close proximity to the certified biobased products. An individual
            certification mark near each certified biobased product may be
            necessary to avoid confusion.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Minimum size and clear space recommendations for the certification
              mark.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The certification mark may be sized to fit the individual
            application as long as the correct proportions are maintained and
            the certification mark remains legible.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A border of clear space must surround the certification mark and
            must be of sufficient width to offset it from surrounding images and
            text and to avoid confusion. If the certification mark&apos;s color
            is similar to the background color of the product or packaging, the
            certification mark in a contrasting (
            <E T='03'>
              i.e.
            </E>
            , black, white) color may be used.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Where to obtain copies of the certification mark artwork.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The certification mark artwork is available at the USDA
            BioPreferred Program Web site 
            <E T='03'>
              http://www.biopreferred.gov
            </E>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16364'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXII:-:3202:-:3202.8
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3202.8
      </num>
      <head>
        Violations.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          76 FR 3806
        </aref>
        , Jan. 20, 2011. Redesignated and amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          76 FR 53632
        </aref>
        , Aug. 29, 2011]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3202' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              3202.8
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Violations.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          This section identifies the types of actions that USDA considers
          violations under this part and the penalties (e.g., the suspension or
          revocation of certification) associated with such violations.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Violations under this section occur on a per product basis and the
            penalties are to be applied on a per product basis. Entities cited
            for a violation under this section may appeal using the provisions
            in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='3202' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
                3202.6
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . If certification for a product is revoked, the manufacturer or
            vendor whose certification has been revoked may seek
            re-certification for the product using the procedures specified
            under the provisions in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='3202' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
                3202.5
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Types of violations.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Actions that will be considered violations of this part include,
            but are not limited to, the following specific examples:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Biobased content violations.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Program Manager will utilize occasional random testing of
            certified biobased products to compare the biobased content of the
            tested product with the product&apos;s applicable minimum biobased
            content and the biobased content reported by the manufacturer or
            vendor in its approved application. Such testing will be conducted
            using ASTM Method D6866. USDA will provide a copy of the results of
            its testing to the applicable manufacturer or vendor.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If USDA testing shows that the biobased content of a certified
            biobased product is less than its applicable minimum biobased
            content, then a violation of this part will have occurred.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If USDA testing shows that the biobased content is less than that
            reported by the manufacturer or vendor in its approved application,
            but is still equal to or greater than its applicable minimum
            biobased content(s), USDA will provide written notification to the
            manufacturer or vendor. The manufacturer or vendor must submit,
            within 90 days from receipt of USDA written notification, a new
            application for the lower biobased content. Failure to submit a new
            application within 90 days will be considered a violation of this
            part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='b_1_ii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The manufacturer or vendor can submit in the new application the
            biobased content reported to it by USDA in the written notification.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='b_1_ii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Alternatively, the manufacturer or vendor may elect to retest the
            product in question and submit the results of the retest in the new
            application. If the manufacturer or vendor elects to retest the
            product, it must test a sample of the current product.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Certification mark violations.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any usage or display of the certification mark that does not
            conform to the requirements specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='3202' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
                3202.7
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
            <PRTPAGE P='325' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Affixing the certification mark to any product prior to issuance of
            a notice of certification from USDA.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Affixing the certification mark to a certified biobased product
            during periods when certification has been suspended or revoked.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Application violations.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Knowingly providing false or misleading information in any
            application for certification of a biobased product constitutes a
            violation of this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
            <head>
              USDA BioPreferred Program Web site violations.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Failure to provide to USDA updated information when the information
            for a certified biobased product becomes outdated or when new
            information for a certified biobased product becomes available
            constitutes a violation of this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Notice of violations and associated actions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             USDA will provide the applicable manufacturer or vendor or their
            designated representatives and any involved other entity known to
            USDA written notification of any violations identified by USDA. USDA
            will first issue a preliminary notice that apparent violations have
            been identified. If satisfactory resolution of the apparent
            violation is not reached within 30 days from receipt of the
            preliminary notice, USDA will issue a notice of violation. Entities
            who receive a notice of violation for a biobased content violation
            must correct the violation(s) within 90 days from receipt of the
            notice of violation. Entities who receive a notice of violation for
            other types of violations also must correct the violation(s) within
            90 days from receipt of the notice of violation. If the entity
            receiving a notice of violation is a manufacturer, a vendor, or a
            designated representative of a manufacturer or vendor, USDA will
            pursue notices of suspensions and revocation, as discussed in
            paragraphs (c)(1) and (c)(2) of this section. USDA reserves the
            right to further pursue action against these entities as provided
            for in paragraph (c)(3) of this section. If the entity receiving a
            notice of violation is an “other entity” (
            <E T='03'>
              i.e.,
            </E>
             not a manufacturer, vendor, or designated representative), then
            USDA will pursue action according to paragraph (c)(3) of this
            section. Entities that receive notices of suspension or revocation
            may appeal such notices using the procedures specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='3202' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
                3202.6
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Suspension.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a violation is applicable to a manufacturer, vendor, or
            designated representative and the applicable entity fails to make
            the required corrections within 90 days of receipt of a notice of
            violation, USDA will notify the manufacturer or vendor, as
            appropriate, of the continuing violation, and the USDA certification
            for that product will be suspended. As of the date that the
            manufacturer or vendor receives a notice of suspension, the
            manufacturer or vendor and their designated representatives must not
            affix the certification mark to any of that product, or associated
            packaging, not already labeled and must not distribute any
            additional products bearing the certification mark. USDA will both
            remove the product information from the USDA BioPreferred Program
            Web site and actively communicate the product suspension to buyers
            in a timely and overt manner.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If, within 30 days from receipt of the notice of suspension, the
            manufacturer or vendor whose USDA product certification has been
            suspended makes the required corrections and notifies USDA that the
            corrections have been made, the manufacturer or vendor and their
            designated representatives may, upon receipt of USDA approval of the
            corrections, resume use of the certification mark. USDA will also
            restore the product information to the USDA BioPreferred Program Web
            site.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Revocation.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a manufacturer or vendor whose USDA product certification has
            been suspended fails to make the required corrections and notify
            USDA of the corrections within 30 days of the date of the
            suspension, USDA will notify the manufacturer or vendor that the
            certification for that product is revoked.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             As of the date that the manufacturer or vendor receives the notice
            revoking USDA certification, the manufacturer or vendor and their
            designated representatives must not affix the certification mark to
            any of that product not already labeled. In addition, the
            manufacturer or vendor and their designated representatives are
            prohibited from further sales of product to which the certification
            mark is affixed.
            <PRTPAGE P='326' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a manufacturer or vendor whose product certification has been
            revoked wishes to use the certification mark, the manufacturer or
            vendor must follow the procedures required for original
            certification.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Other remedies.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In addition to the suspension or revocation of the certification to
            use the label, depending on the nature of the violation, USDA may
            pursue suspension or debarment of the entities involved in
            accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3017' tq='N'>
                3017
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . USDA further reserves the right to pursue any other remedies
            available by law, including any civil or criminal remedies, against
            any entity that violates the provisions of this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 3806
          </aref>
          , Jan. 20, 2011. Redesignated and amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 53632
          </aref>
          , Aug. 29, 2011]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16365'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXII:-:3202:-:3202.9
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3202.9
      </num>
      <head>
        Recordkeeping requirements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3202' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
              3202.9
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Recordkeeping requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Records.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Manufacturers and vendors shall maintain records documenting
            compliance with this part for each product that has received
            certification to use the label, as specified in paragraphs (a)(1)
            through (a)(3) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The results of all tests, and any associated calculations,
            performed to determine the biobased content of the product.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The date the applicant receives certification from USDA, the dates
            of changes in formulation that affect the biobased content of
            certified biobased products, and the dates when the biobased content
            of certified biobased products was tested.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Documentation of analyses performed by manufacturers to support
            claims of environmental or human health benefits, life cycle cost,
            sustainability benefits, and product performance made by the
            manufacturer.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Record retention.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For each certified biobased product, records kept under paragraph
            (a) of this section must be maintained for at least three years
            beyond the end of the label certification period (
            <E T='03'>
              i.e.,
            </E>
             three years beyond the period of time when manufacturers and
            vendors cease using the certification mark). Records may be kept in
            either electronic format or hard copy format. All records kept in
            electronic format must be readily accessible, and/or provided by
            request during a USDA audit.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='16366'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XXXII:-:3202:-:3202.10
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3202.10
      </num>
      <head>
        Oversight and monitoring.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          76 FR 3806
        </aref>
        , Jan. 20, 2011. Redesignated and amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          76 FR 53632
        </aref>
        , Aug. 29, 2011]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3202' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
              3202.10
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Oversight and monitoring.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             USDA will conduct oversight and monitoring of manufacturers,
            vendors, designated representatives, and other entities involved
            with the voluntary product labeling program to ensure compliance
            with this part. This oversight will include, but not be limited to,
            conducting facility visits of manufacturers and vendors who have
            certified biobased products, and of their designated
            representatives. Manufacturers, vendors, and their designated
            representatives are required to cooperate fully with all USDA audit
            efforts for the enforcement of the voluntary labeling program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Biobased content testing.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             USDA will conduct biobased content testing of certified biobased
            products, as described in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='3202' sect='8' psec='#b_1' tq='N'>
                3202.8(b)(1)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             to ensure compliance with this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Inspection of records.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Manufacturers, vendors, and their designated representatives must
            allow Federal representatives access to the records required under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='3202' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
                3202.9
              </subref>
            </aref>
             for inspection and copying during normal Federal business hours.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 3806
          </aref>
          , Jan. 20, 2011. Redesignated and amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 53632
          </aref>
          , Aug. 29, 2011]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>