<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol1'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:23
    </extid>
    <num>
      23
    </num>
    <head>
      STATE AND REGIONAL ANNUAL PLANS OF WORK
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            Sec. 508, 86
          </aref>
           Stat. 674 (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='2668' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/2668.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 2668
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ).
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            38 FR 29023
          </aref>
          , Oct. 18, 1973, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='788'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:23:A:23.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        23.1
      </num>
      <head>
        General.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='23' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              23.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Title V of the Rural Development Act of 1972 (Pub. L. 92-419)
            hereafter referred to as “Title V” is the Research and Education
            component of the Rural Development Act of 1972. Title V provides the
            opportunity to utilize and build upon the research, extension, and
            community service capability of public and private institutions of
            higher education in each State to expand scientific inquiry and
            education backup for rural development. The higher educational and
            research institutions in each State, including the Land Grant
            Institutions of 1890, are authorized to assist in developing and
            disseminating through the most appropriate manner, scientific
            information, technical assistance, and feasibility studies required
            to improve the rural development capability of local citizens,
            agencies, and governments. Programs authorized under title V shall
            be organized and conducted by one or more colleges or universities
            in each State to provide a coordinated program in each State which
            will have the greatest impact on accomplishing the objectives of
            rural development in both the short and longer term and the use of
            these studies to support the State&apos;s comprehensive program to
            be supported under title V.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Title V operations will be consonant with the purpose that all
            Federal rural development activities be coordinated with other
            federally assisted rural development activities and with the
            State&apos;s ongoing rural development program. To effectuate such
            purpose, the Assistant Secretary for Conservation, Research and
            Education will implement title V plans and activities in close
            coordination with the Assistant Secretary for Rural Development.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='789'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:23:A:23.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        23.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Administration.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          38 FR 29023
        </aref>
        , Oct. 18, 1973, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          76 FR 4804
        </aref>
        , Jan. 27, 2011]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='23' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              23.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Administration.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Title V will be administered by the Director of the National
            Institute of Food and Agriculture in cooperation with the chief
            administrative officer of the State Land Grant University who will
            administer the program within his 
            <PRTPAGE P='516' />
            respective State. To assure national and State coordination with
            programs under the Smith-Lever Act of 1914 and the Hatch Act (as
            amended), August 11, 1955, the administration of the programs shall
            be in association with the programs conducted under the Smith-Lever
            Act and the Hatch Act as required by 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 504(b) of
            </aref>
             the Act.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Programs authorized under title V shall be conducted as mutually
            agreed upon by the Secretary and the chief administrative officer of
            the State Land Grant University responsible for administering said
            programs in a memorandum of understanding which shall provide for
            the coordination of the programs, coordination of these programs
            with other rural development programs of Federal, State, and local
            government, and such other matters as the Secretary shall determine.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            38 FR 29023
          </aref>
          , Oct. 18, 1973, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 4804
          </aref>
          , Jan. 27, 2011]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='790'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:23:A:23.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        23.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Coordination.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='23' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              23.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Coordination.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The chief administrative officer of the administratively responsible
          State Land Grant University will designate an official who will be
          responsible for the overall coordination of the authorized programs
          for the State. The designated official will be responsible for the
          overall coordination of planning, organizing, funding, conducting and
          evaluating programs in association with the person responsible for the
          administration of research programs, the person responsible for the
          administration of the extension programs, and the administrative head
          of agriculture of the University (chairman of the State Rural
          Development Advisory Council).
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='791'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:23:A:23.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        23.4
      </num>
      <head>
        State Rural Development Advisory Council.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='23' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              23.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          State Rural Development Advisory Council.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The chief administrative officer of the administratively
            responsible State Land Grant University will appoint a State Rural
            Development Advisory Council with membership as set forth in 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 504(e) of
            </aref>
             title V. The function of the Council shall be to review and approve
            annual program plans conducted under title V. The Council will also
            advise the chief administrative officer on all matters pertaining to
            the authorized programs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Chairman of the State Rural Development Advisory Council will
            insure that programs proposed under title V including regional
            programs applicable within the State are not inconsistent with and
            are, to a maximum extent practicable, in consonance with other rural
            development programs and activities approved in that State.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Those elements of the research and extension plan which would
            impact directly on rural development activities being developed or
            pursued by States will be considered jointly by the State Rural
            Development Advisory Council and appropriate State agencies to
            assure a constructive reinforcement of those State activities.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='792'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:23:A:23.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        23.5
      </num>
      <head>
        Availability of funds.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='23' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              23.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Availability of funds.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Funds available under title V for extension and research programs
          shall be allocated to, and following approval of a State Annual Plan
          of Work, paid to the official of the State Land Grant University
          designated to receive funds under the Smith-Lever and Hatch Acts
          respectively. Funds will be available for State programs for
          expenditures authorized by 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 503(c) of
          </aref>
           title V, in the fiscal year for which the funds were appropriated and
          the next fiscal year.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='793'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:23:A:23.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        23.6
      </num>
      <head>
        Plan of Work.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='23' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              23.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Plan of Work.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A State Annual Plan of Work for carrying out the programs
            authorized under title V shall be prepared. The Plan of Work should
            include:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Identification of major problems and needs which can be met by each
            related extension and research program in the geographic or problem
            area.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The relationship of this program to ongoing planning and
            development efforts.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The organizational structure for planning, conducting, and
            evaluating each pilot program, including the names and title of the
            members of the Rural Development Advisory Council and the
            composition of major committees and work groups.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A separate concise statement describing specific extension projects
            to be funded under each program. The statement should contain the
            following elements: Title, objectives, organization and operational
            procedures, probable duration, personnel, institutions 
            <PRTPAGE P='517' />
            involved, and relation to the research effort. In addition, a brief
            description of each regular or special extension project which is
            complementary and supports the title V pilot program, but which is
            funded from other sources shall be included.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A separate concise statement describing specific research projects
            to be funded under each program. The statement should contain the
            following elements: Title, objectives, organization, and operational
            procedures, probable duration, personnel, institutions involved, and
            relation to the extension effort. In addition, a brief description
            of each regular or special research project which is complementary
            and supports the title V program, but which is funded from other
            sources, shall be included.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A plan for evaluating the impact of each program on the development
            of the area, including the effectiveness of the extension and
            research program techniques, and organizational structure for
            planning and conducting each program. Appraisals by community
            leaders in the area should be included in the evaluation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provisions for making an annual progress report to the Assistant
            Secretary for Conservation, Research, and Education which will
            document achievements pertaining to the goals and objectives as
            stated in the Plan of Work.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A budget statement for each program to be submitted on forms
            provided by the Assistant Secretary for Conservation, Research, and
            Education.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Plan of Work shall include plans for all programs to be
            conducted with funds authorized under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 503(b)(3) and (4) of
            </aref>
             title V. The Plan of Work shall include plans for the programs to
            be conducted by each cooperating and participating university or
            college and such other information as included in these guidelines.
            Each State program must include research and extension activities
            directed toward identification of programs which are likely to have
            the greatest impact upon accomplishing the objectives of rural
            development in both the short and longer terms and the use of these
            studies to support the State&apos;s comprehensive program to be
            supported under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 505(b) of
            </aref>
             title V. In addition, all other rural development extension and
            research efforts funded from other sources that contribute directly
            to the proposed programs shall be described in the Plan of Work.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Since the appropriation authorization for title V is limited to a
            three-year period the Plan of Work should be developed to
            demonstrate extension and research program techniques and
            organizational structures for providing essential knowledge to
            assist and support rural development efforts within that time.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In accordance with the above criteria, the Plan of Work should:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Concentrate on limited geographic or problem areas where title V
            efforts would be expected to have high impact within the three-year
            authorization.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Give emphasis to rural areas, including towns and cities with
            populations of less than 50,000.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Involve the administratively responsible Land Grant University and
            other public or private colleges and universities, as appropriate,
            in meeting with high priority extension and research needs of the
            area(s).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Give priority to education and research assistance leading to
            increasing job and income opportunities, improving quality of life,
            improving essential community services and facilities, improving
            housing and home improvements, and enhancing those social processes
            necessary to achieve these goals.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be consistent with Statewide comprehensive planning and development
            efforts and objectives. Procedures set forth under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='23' sect='4' psec='#c' tq='N'>
                23.4(c)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             are designed to achieve attainment of this requirement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Four copies of the Plan of Work approved by the State Rural
            Development Advisory Council shall be submitted by the person
            responsible for the overall coordination of the title V programs in
            the State to the Assistant Secretary for Conservation, Research and
            Education, U.S. Department of Agriculture, Washington, DC 20250,
            within 60 days after enactment of the annual Appropriation Act for
            the Department of Agriculture.
            <PRTPAGE P='518' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Plans of Work not meeting the above criteria will not be approved
            by the Assistant Secretary for Conservation, Research and Education.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='794'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:23:B:23.9
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        23.9
      </num>
      <head>
        General.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='23' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
              23.9
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              Section 503(b)(2)
            </aref>
            , title V, of the Rural Development Act of 1972 (Pub. L. 92-419)
            hereafter referred to as “Title V” authorizes funds to finance work
            authorized under title V which serve two or more States; in which
            universities in two or more States cooperate; or which is conducted
            by one University serving two or more States. The authorized funding
            under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 503(b)(2)
            </aref>
             is hereafter referred to as the “Regional Programs.”
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Regional Programs shall develop and provide knowledge essential
            to assist and support rural development in the region, and shall
            provide for technical consultation and personnel development for the
            research and extension staff in the several States of the region to
            help them to be more responsive to rural development needs and
            activities.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Regional Programs will concentrate on the high priority
            knowledge, training, and personnel needs required for the research
            and extension staff in the several States to conduct effective rural
            development research and extension to carry out the provisions of
            title V. These efforts may include personnel development and
            consultation; synthesis of existing research knowledge and the
            interpretation of this knowledge for rural development program and
            policy purposes; the development of strategies and procedures on
            high priority rural development problems of regional significance;
            as funds permit, the conduct of research on one of two high priority
            problems for which information is lacking but is urgently needed for
            rural development, and the evaluation of rural development programs
            and policies.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Regional Programs will be consonant with all rural development
            activities under the Act and other pertinent Federal development
            programs. To effectuate such purpose, the Assistant Secretary for
            Conservation, Research and Education will implement title V plans
            and activities in close cooperation with the Assistant Secretary for
            Rural Development. In order to insure such consonance, the Director
            of each Regional Center will insure that regional programs having an
            impact within one or more States are brought to the attention of the
            appropriate State overall coordinator for consideration pursuant to
            procedures in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='23' sect='4' psec='#c' tq='N'>
                23.4(c)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='795'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:23:B:23.10
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        23.10
      </num>
      <head>
        Administration.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          38 FR 29023
        </aref>
        , Oct. 18, 1973, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          76 FR 4804
        </aref>
        , Jan. 27, 2011]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='23' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
              23.10
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Administration.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Regional Programs will be administered through four Regional
            Rural Development Centers hereafter referred to as “Regional
            Centers” in cooperation with the National Institute of Food and
            Agriculture. The Director of each Regional Center shall be
            responsible for compliance with all appropriate provisions of title
            V and the regulations of this subpart. Regions as delineated for
            purposes under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 503(b)(2)
            </aref>
             will be coterminous with the regional delineation by the National
            Association of State Universities and Land Grant Colleges. Each
            Regional Center will be established by the regional association of
            State Agricultural Experiment Station Directors and the regional
            organization of Cooperative Extension Directors in the region to be
            served by the Regional Center. These associations and organizations
            will designate the location of the Regional Center.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Although the Regional Center will administer the program, it is
            also expected that it will draw on expertise from outside the
            Regional Center. The Director of each Regional Center shall seek
            advice and assistance from regional and subregional committees,
            groups or persons who can contribute to the Regional Center&apos;s
            program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            38 FR 29023
          </aref>
          , Oct. 18, 1973, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 4804
          </aref>
          , Jan. 27, 2011]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='796'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:23:B:23.11
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        23.11
      </num>
      <head>
        Board of Directors.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='23' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
              23.11
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Board of Directors.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For each Regional Center there shall be a Board of Directors
            selected by the Regional Association of Agricultural Experiment
            Station Directors and the Regional Organization of Cooperative State
            Extension Directors. Membership on the Board of Directors shall
            include representatives from 
            <PRTPAGE P='519' />
            State Cooperative Extension Services and State Agricultural
            Experiment Stations from the States in the region and/or other State
            administrators of programs carried out under title V in the region.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Director of each Regional Center will be responsible to the
            Board of Directors for the Regional Program conducted at that
            Regional Center. The Regional Annual Plan of Work will be developed
            by the Director and reviewed and approved by the Board of Directors.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='797'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:23:B:23.12
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        23.12
      </num>
      <head>
        Availability of funds.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='23' sect='12' psec='' tq='N'>
              23.12
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Availability of funds.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Available funds will be allocated equally and following approval of a
          Regional Annual Plan of Work paid to the Directors of the four
          Regional Centers. Funds will be available for Regional Programs for
          expenditures authorized by 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 503(c) of
          </aref>
           title V, in the fiscal year for which the funds were appropriated and
          the next fiscal year.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='798'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:23:B:23.13
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        23.13
      </num>
      <head>
        Plan of Work.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='23' sect='13' psec='' tq='N'>
              23.13
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Plan of Work.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A Regional Plan of Work for carrying out the programs authorized to
            be funded under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 503(b)(2) of
            </aref>
             title V shall be prepared. The Plan of Work should include:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A brief narrative statement including identification of high
            priority knowledge, skill, and organization needs for rural
            development program and policy purposes in the region and
            identification of technical consultation, training, and personnel
            needs of research and extension workers in support of rural
            development programs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A statement indicating:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The types of personnel to be trained, technical consultation to be
            conducted, the estimated number of participants, the location or
            locations where the program will be conducted, and the staff who
            will conduct the work;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The types of topical areas of rural development for which the
            synthesis of available research knowledge for rural development
            purposes is planned;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The type of high priority rural development research which will be
            undertaken as funds permit and the staff which would do the
            research;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The type of evaluation studies which will be made and the staff
            which will do the evaluation; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The relationship of the Plan of Work to priorities activated under
            subpart A of this part, which in turn support State development
            strategies.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A concise statement of the organization structure for planning and
            conducting the program funded under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 503(b)(2)
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A plan for evaluating the usefulness of the program and the
            effectiveness of the organizational structure.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provision for making an annual progress report to the Assistant
            Secretary for Conservation, Research and Education which will
            document achievements pertaining to the goals and objectives as
            stated in the Plan of Work.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A budget statement to be submitted on forms provided by the
            Assistant Secretary for Conservation, Research and Education.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Plan of Work shall be coordinated with the work program of
            other pertinent multi-State organizations or bodies for those
            activities of the Regional Rural Development Centers which go beyond
            direct assistance to individual State programs conducted under title
            V.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Director of the Center will forward four copies of the Plan of
            Work to the Assistant Secretary for Conservation, Research and
            Education, U.S. Department of Agriculture, Washington, D.C. 20250,
            by a time to be specified by the Assistant Secretary for
            Conservation, Research and Education.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Regional Annual Plans of Work not meeting the above criteria will
            not be approved by the Assistant Secretary for Conservation,
            Research and Education.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>