<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol7'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:755
    </extid>
    <num>
      755
    </num>
    <head>
      REIMBURSEMENT TRANSPORTATION COST PAYMENT PROGRAM FOR GEOGRAPHICALLY
      DISADVANTAGED FARMERS AND RANCHERS
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='8792' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/8792.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 8792
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 34340
          </aref>
          , June 17, 2010, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='6644'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:755:-:755.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        755.1
      </num>
      <head>
        Administration.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='755' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              755.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Administration.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This part establishes the terms and conditions under which the
            Reimbursement Transportation Cost Payment (RTCP) Program for
            geographically disadvantaged farmers and ranchers will be
            administered.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The RTCP Program will be administered under the general supervision
            of the FSA Administrator, or a designee, and will be carried out in
            the field by FSA State and county committees and FSA employees.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FSA State and county committees, and representatives and employees
            thereof, do not have the authority to modify or waive any of the
            provisions of the regulations of this part, except as provided in
            paragraph (e) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The FSA State committee will take any action required by the
            provisions of this part that has not been taken by the FSA county
            committee. The FSA State committee will also:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Correct or require an FSA county committee to correct any action
            taken by the county committee that is not in compliance with the
            provisions of this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Require an FSA county committee to not take an action or implement
            a decision that is not in compliance with the provisions of this
            part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No provision or delegation of this part to an FSA State committee
            or a county committee will preclude the FSA Administrator, or a
            designee, from determining any question arising under the program or
            from reversing or modifying any determination made by a State
            committee or a county committee.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Deputy Administrator for Farm Programs, FSA, may waive or
            modify program requirements of this part in cases where failure to
            meet requirements does not adversely affect the operation of the
            program and where the requirement is not statutorily mandated.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6645'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:755:-:755.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        755.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='755' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              755.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The following definitions apply to this part. The definitions in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            parts 
            <subref title='7' part='718' tq='N'>
              718
            </subref>
             and 
            <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
              1400 of this title
            </subref>
          </aref>
           also apply, except where they may conflict with the definitions in
          this section.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Actual transportation rate
          </E>
           means the transportation rate that reflects the actual transportation
          costs incurred and can be determined by supporting documentation.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Agricultural commodity
          </E>
           means any agricultural commodity (including horticulture,
          aquaculture, and floriculture), food, feed, fiber, livestock
          (including elk, reindeer, bison, horses, or deer), or insects, and any
          product thereof.
          <PRTPAGE P='64' />
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Agricultural operation
          </E>
           means a parcel or parcels of land; or body of water applicable to
          aquaculture, whether contiguous or noncontiguous, constituting a
          cohesive management unit for agricultural purposes. An agricultural
          operation will be regarded as located in the county in which the
          principal dwelling is situated, or if there is no dwelling thereon, it
          will be regarded to be in the county in which the major portion of the
          land or applicable body of water is located.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Application period
          </E>
           means the period established by the Deputy Administrator for
          geographically disadvantaged farmers and ranchers to apply for program
          benefits.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            County office or FSA county office
          </E>
           means the FSA offices responsible for administering FSA programs in a
          specific area, sometimes encompassing more than one county, in a
          State.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Department or USDA
          </E>
           means the U.S. Department of Agriculture.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Eligible reimbursement amount
          </E>
           means the reported costs incurred to transport an agricultural
          commodity or input used to produce an agricultural commodity in an
          insular area, Alaska, or Hawaii, over a distance of more than 30
          miles. The amount is calculated by multiplying the number of units of
          the reported transportation amount times the applicable transportation
          fixed, set, or actual rate times the applicable FY allowance (COLA).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Farm Service Agency or FSA
          </E>
           means the Farm Service Agency of the USDA.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Fiscal year or FY
          </E>
           means the year beginning October 1 and ending the following September
          30. The fiscal year will be designated for this part by year reference
          to the calendar year in which it ends. For example, FY 2010 is from
          October 1, 2009, through September 30, 2010 (inclusive).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Fixed transportation rate
          </E>
           means the per unit transportation rate determined by FSA to reflect
          the transportation cost applicable to an agricultural commodity or
          input used to produce an agricultural commodity in a particular
          region.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            FY allowance (COLA)
          </E>
           means the nonforeign area cost of living allowance or post
          differential, as applicable, for that FY set by Office of Personnel
          Management for Federal employees stationed in Alaska, Hawaii, and
          other insular areas, as authorized by 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='5' sect='5941' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/5/5941.html'>
              5 U.S.C. 5941
            </subref>
          </aref>
           and E.O. 10000 and specified in 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            5 CFR part 
            <subref title='5' part='591' tq='N'>
              591
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , subpart B, appendices A and B.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Geographically disadvantaged farmer or rancher
          </E>
           means a farmer or rancher in an insular area, Alaska, or Hawaii.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Input transportation costs
          </E>
           means those transportation costs of inputs used to produce an
          agricultural commodity including, but not limited to, air freight,
          ocean freight, and land freight of chemicals, feed, fertilizer, fuel,
          seeds, plants, supplies, equipment parts, and other inputs as
          determined by FSA.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Insular area
          </E>
           means the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico; Guam; American Samoa; the
          Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands; the Federated States of
          Micronesia; the Republic of the Marshall Islands; the Republic of
          Palau; and the Virgin Islands of the United States.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Payment amount
          </E>
           means the amount due a producer that is the sum of all eligible
          reimbursement amounts, as calculated by FSA subject to the
          availability of funds, and subject to an $8,000 cap per producer per
          FY.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Producer
          </E>
           means any geographically disadvantaged farmer or rancher who is an
          individual, group of individuals, partnership, corporation, estate,
          trust, association, cooperative, or other business enterprise or other
          legal entity, as defined in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1400' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              1400.3
            </subref>
             of this title
          </aref>
          , who is, or whose members are, a citizen of or legal resident alien
          in the United States, and who, as determined by the Secretary, shares
          in the risk of producing an agricultural commodity in substantial
          commercial quantities, and who is entitled to a share of the
          agricultural commodity from the agricultural operation.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Reported transportation amount
          </E>
           means the reported number of units (such as pounds, bushels, pieces,
          or parts) applicable to an agricultural commodity or input used to
          produce an agricultural commodity, which is used in calculating the
          eligible reimbursement amount.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Set transportation rate
          </E>
           means the transportation rate established by FSA for a commodity or
          input for which there is not a fixed transportation rate 
          <PRTPAGE P='65' />
          or supporting documentation of the actual transportation rate.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            United States
          </E>
           means the 50 States of the United States of America, the District of
          Columbia, the Commonwealths of Puerto Rico and the Northern Mariana
          Islands, and any other territory or possession of the United States.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Verifiable records
          </E>
           means evidence that is used to substantiate the amount of eligible
          reimbursements by geographically disadvantaged farmers and ranchers in
          an agricultural operation that can be verified by FSA through an
          independent source.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6646'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:755:-:755.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        755.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Time and method of application.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='755' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              755.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Time and method of application.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be eligible for payment, producers must obtain and submit a
            completed application for payment and meet other eligibility
            requirements specified in this part. Producers may obtain an
            application in person, by mail, or by facsimile from any county FSA
            office. In addition, producers may download a copy of the
            application at 
            <E T='03'>
              http://www.sc.egov.usda.gov.
            </E>
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An application for payment must be submitted on a completed
            application form. Applications and any other supporting
            documentation must be submitted to the FSA county office serving the
            county where the agricultural operation is located, but, in any
            case, must be received by the FSA county office by the close of
            business on the last day of the application period established by
            the Deputy Administrator.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All producers who incurred transportation costs for eligible
            reimbursements and who share in the risk of an agricultural
            operation must certify to the information on the application before
            the application will be considered complete. FSA may require the
            producer to provide documentation to support all verifiable records.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each producer requesting payment under this part must certify to
            the accuracy and truthfulness of the information provided in their
            application and any supporting documentation. All information
            provided is subject to verification by FSA. Refusal to allow FSA or
            any other agency of the Department of Agriculture to verify any
            information provided will result in a denial of eligibility.
            Furnishing the information is voluntary; however, without it program
            benefits will not be approved. Providing a false certification to
            the Federal Government may be punishable by imprisonment, fines and
            other penalties or sanctions.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To ensure all producers are provided an opportunity to submit
            actual costs for reimbursement at the actual cost rate, applicants
            will have 30 days after the end of the FY to provide supporting
            documentation of actual transportation costs to the FSA County
            Office. The actual costs documented in supporting documentation will
            override previously reported costs of eligible reimbursable costs at
            the fixed or set rate made during the application period.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If verifiable records are not provided to FSA, the producer will be
            ineligible for payment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If supporting documentation is provided within 30 days after the
            end of the FY, but an application was not submitted to the
            applicable FSA County Office before the end of the application
            period, the producer is not eligible for payment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Producers who submit applications after the application period are
            not entitled to any payment consideration or determination of
            eligibility. Regardless of the reason why an application is not
            submitted to or received by FSA, any application received after the
            close of business on such date will not be eligible for benefits
            under this program.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6647'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:755:-:755.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        755.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Eligibility.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='755' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              755.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Eligibility.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be eligible to receive payments under this part, a
            geographically disadvantaged farmer or rancher must:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be a producer of an eligible agricultural commodity in substantial
            commercial quantities;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Incur transportation costs for the transportation of the
            agricultural commodity or input used to produce the agricultural
            commodity;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Submit an accurate and complete application for payment as
            specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='755' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
                755.3
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be in compliance with the wetland and highly erodible conservation
            requirements in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='12' tq='N'>
                12 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and meet the adjusted gross income and 
            <PRTPAGE P='66' />
            pay limit eligibility requirements in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
                1400 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , as applicable, except that the $8,000 cap provided for in this
            rule is a per producer cap, not a per person cap. For example, a
            partnership of four individuals would be considered one producer,
            not four persons, for the purposes of this cap and thus the
            partnership could only generate a single $8,000 payment under this
            program if the cap holds because of full subscription of the
            program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Individual producers in an agricultural operation that is an entity
            are only eligible for a payment based on their share of the
            operation. A producer is not eligible for payment based on the share
            of production of any other producer.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Multiple producers, such as the buyer and seller of a commodity
            (for example, a producer of hay and a livestock operation that buys
            the hay), are not eligible for payments for the same eligible
            transportation cost. Unless the multiple producers agree otherwise,
            only the last buyer will be eligible for the payment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A person or entity determined to be a “foreign person” under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
                1400 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
             is not eligible to receive benefits under this part, unless that
            person provides land, capital, and a substantial amount of active
            personal labor in the production of crops on such farm.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State and local governments and their political subdivisions and
            related agencies are not eligible for RTCP payments.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6648'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:755:-:755.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        755.5
      </num>
      <head>
        Proof of eligible reimbursement costs incurred.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='755' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              755.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Proof of eligible reimbursement costs incurred.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be eligible for reimbursement based on FSA fixed or set rates as
            specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='755' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
                755.7
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , the requirements specified in paragraphs (b) and (c) of this
            section must be met at the time of the application. To be eligible
            for reimbursement of actual costs, the requirements of paragraph (d)
            must also be met, within 30 days after the end of the applicable
            fiscal year.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Eligible verifiable records to support eligible reimbursement costs
            include, but are not limited to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Invoices;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Account statements;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Contractual Agreements; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bill of Lading.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Verifiable records must show:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Name of producer(s);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Commodity and unit of measure;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Type of input(s) associated with transportation costs;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Date(s) of service;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Name of person or entity providing the service, as applicable, and;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Retail sales receipts with verifiable records handwritten as
            applicable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be eligible for reimbursement based on actual costs, the
            producer must provide supporting documentation that documents the
            specific costs incurred for transportation of each commodity or
            input. Such documentation must:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Show transportation costs for each specific commodity or input, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Show the units of measure for each commodity or input, such that
            FSA can determine the transportation cost per unit.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6649'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:755:-:755.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        755.6
      </num>
      <head>
        Availability of funds.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='755' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              755.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Availability of funds.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payments under this part are subject to the availability of funds.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A reserve will be created to handle appeals and errors.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6650'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:755:-:755.7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        755.7
      </num>
      <head>
        Transportation rates.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='755' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              755.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Transportation rates.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payments may be based on fixed, set, or actual transportation
            rates. Fixed and set transportation rates will be established by
            FSA, based on available data for transportation costs for that
            commodity or input in the applicable State or insular region.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Fixed transportation rates will establish per unit transportation
            costs for each eligible commodity or input used to produce the
            eligible commodity.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Set transportation rates will be established for those
            transportation costs that are not on the FSA list of fixed rates and
            for which an actual rate cannot be documented. The set
            transportation rate will be set by FSA, based on available data of
            transportation costs for similar commodities and inputs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Actual transportation rates will be determined based on supporting
            documentation.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6651'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:755:-:755.8
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        755.8
      </num>
      <head>
        Calculation of individual payments.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='67' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='755' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              755.8
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Calculation of individual payments.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Transportation cost for each commodity or input will be calculated
            by multiplying the number of reported eligible units (the reported
            transportation amount) times the fixed, set, or actual
            transportation rate, as applicable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Eligible reimbursement amounts will be calculated by multiplying
            the result of paragraph (a) of this section times the appropriate FY
            COLA percentage, as provided in this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If transported inputs are used for both eligible and ineligible
            commodities, the eligible reimbursable costs will be determined on a
            revenue share of eligible commodities times input cost, as
            determined by FSA, and transportation may be allowed only for those
            commodities which were produced for the commercial market.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The total payment amount for a producer is the sum of all eligible
            reimbursable amounts determined in paragraph (b) of this section for
            all commodities and inputs used to produce the eligible commodities
            listed on the application.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payment amounts are subject to $8,000 cap per FY per producer as
            defined in this part, not per “person” or “legal entity” as those
            terms might be defined in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
                1400 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the event that approval of all calculated payment amounts would
            result in expenditures in excess of the amount available, FSA will
            recalculate the payment amounts in a manner that FSA determines to
            be fair and reasonable.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6652'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:755:-:755.9
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        755.9
      </num>
      <head>
        Misrepresentation and scheme or device.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='755' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
              755.9
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Misrepresentation and scheme or device.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In addition to other penalties, sanctions or remedies as may apply,
            a producer will be ineligible to receive payments under this part if
            the producer is determined by FSA to have:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Adopted any scheme or device that tends to defeat the purpose of
            this part;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Made any fraudulent representation; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Misrepresented any fact affecting a program determination.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any payment to any producer engaged in a misrepresentation, scheme,
            or device, must be refunded with interest together with such other
            sums as may become due. Any producer engaged in acts prohibited by
            this section and receiving payment under this part will be jointly
            and severally liable with other producers involved in such claim for
            benefits for any refund due under this section and for related
            charges. The remedies provided in this part will be in addition to
            other civil, criminal, or administrative remedies that may apply.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6653'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:755:-:755.10
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        755.10
      </num>
      <head>
        Death, incompetence, or disappearance.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='755' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
              755.10
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Death, incompetence, or disappearance.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the case of the death, incompetency, or disappearance of a
            person or the dissolution of an entity that is eligible to receive a
            payment in accordance with this part, such alternate person or
            persons specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='707' tq='N'>
                707 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
             may receive such payment, as determined appropriate by FSA.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payments may be made to an otherwise eligible producer who is now
            deceased or to a dissolved entity if a representative who currently
            has authority to enter into an application for the producer or the
            producer&apos;s estate signs the application for payment. Proof of
            authority over the deceased producer&apos;s estate or a dissolved
            entity must be provided.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a producer is now a dissolved general partnership or joint
            venture, all members of the general partnership or joint venture at
            the time of dissolution or their duly authorized representatives
            must be identified in the application for payment.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6654'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:755:-:755.11
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        755.11
      </num>
      <head>
        Maintaining records.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='755' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
              755.11
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Maintaining records.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Persons applying for payment under this part must maintain records and
          accounts to document all eligibility requirements specified in this
          part. Such records and accounts must be retained for 3 years after the
          date of payment to the producer under this part.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6655'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:755:-:755.12
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        755.12
      </num>
      <head>
        Refunds; joint and several liability.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='755' sect='12' psec='' tq='N'>
              755.12
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Refunds; joint and several liability.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any producer that receives excess payment, payment as the result of
            erroneous information provided by any person, or payment resulting
            from a 
            <PRTPAGE P='68' />
            failure to comply with any requirement or condition for payment
            under this part, must refund the amount of that payment to FSA.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any refund required will be due from the date of the disbursement
            by the agency with interest determined in accordance with paragraph
            (d) of this section and late payment charges as provided in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1403' tq='N'>
                1403 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each producer that has an interest in the agricultural operation
            will be jointly and severally liable for any refund and related
            charges found to be due to FSA.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Interest will be applicable to any refunds to FSA required in
            accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              parts 
              <subref title='7' part='792' tq='N'>
                792
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='1403' tq='N'>
                1403 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
             except as otherwise specified in this part. Such interest will be
            charged at the rate that the U.S. Department of the Treasury charges
            FSA for funds, and will accrue from the date FSA made the payment to
            the date the refund is repaid.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FSA may waive the accrual of interest if it determines that the
            cause of the erroneous payment was not due to any action of the
            person or entity, or was beyond the control of the person or entity
            committing the violation. Any waiver is at the discretion of FSA
            alone.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6656'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:755:-:755.13
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        755.13
      </num>
      <head>
        Miscellaneous provisions and appeals.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='755' sect='13' psec='' tq='N'>
              755.13
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Miscellaneous provisions and appeals.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Offset.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FSA may offset or withhold any amount due to FSA from any benefit
            provided under this part in accordance with the provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1403' tq='N'>
                1403 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Claims.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Claims or debts will be settled in accordance with the provisions
            of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1403' tq='N'>
                1403 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Other interests.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payments or any portion thereof due under this part will be made
            without regard to questions of title under State law and without
            regard to any claim or lien against the eligible reimbursable costs
            thereof, in favor of the owner or any other creditor except agencies
            and instrumentalities of the U.S. Government.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Assignments.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any producer entitled to any payment under this part may assign any
            payments in accordance with the provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1404' tq='N'>
                1404 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Violations regarding controlled substances.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='718' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
                718.6
              </subref>
               of this chapter
            </aref>
            , which generally limit program payment eligibility for persons who
            have engaged in certain offenses with respect to controlled
            substances, will apply to this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Appeals.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The appeal regulations specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              parts 
              <subref title='7' part='11' tq='N'>
                11
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='780' tq='N'>
                780 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
             apply to determinations made under this part.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>