<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol3'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:K:202
    </extid>
    <num>
      202
    </num>
    <head>
      FEDERAL SEED ACT RULES OF PRACTICE
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            Secs. 302, 305, 402, 408, 409, 413, 414, 53
          </aref>
           Stat. 1275, as amended; 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='1582' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1582.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 1582
            </subref>
            , 
            <subref title='7' sect='1585' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1585.html'>
              1585
            </subref>
            , 
            <subref title='7' sect='1592' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1592.html'>
              1592
            </subref>
            , 
            <subref title='7' sect='1598' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1598.html'>
              1598
            </subref>
            , 
            <subref title='7' sect='1599' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1599.html'>
              1599
            </subref>
            , 
            <subref title='7' sect='1603' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1603.html'>
              1603
            </subref>
            , 
            <subref title='7' sect='1604' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1604.html'>
              1604
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            36 FR 1314
          </aref>
          , Jan. 27, 1971, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='4395'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:K:202:A:202.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        202.1
      </num>
      <head>
        Meaning of words.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='202' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              202.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Meaning of words.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          As used in this part, words in the singular form shall be deemed to
          import the plural, and vice versa, as the case may require.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4396'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:K:202:A:202.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        202.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='202' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              202.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          For the purposes of this part, the following terms shall be construed,
          respectively, to mean:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The term 
            <E T='03'>
              Act
            </E>
             means the Federal Seed Act, approved August 9, 1939 (
            <aref target='_blank' href='http://frwebgate.access.gpo.gov/cgi-bin/getpage.cgi?dbname=76_statutes_at_large&amp;position=all&amp;page=1275'>
              53 Stat. 1275
            </aref>
            , 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='1551' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1551.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 1551
              </subref>
            </aref>
            <E T='03'>
              et seq
            </E>
            .) and any legislation amendatory thereof.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Complaint
            </E>
             means any formal complaint and notice of hearing or other document
            by virtue of which a proceeding under the Act is instituted.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Complainant
            </E>
             means the party upon whose complaint the proceeding is instituted.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Decision and Order
            </E>
             includes the Secretary&apos;s findings, conclusions, order, and
            rulings on motions, exceptions, statements of objections, and
            proposed findings, conclusions and orders submitted by the parties
            not theretofore ruled upon.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Director
            </E>
             means the Director of the Grain Division, Agricultural Marketing
            Service, U.S. Department of Agriculture, or any officer or employee
            of the Department to whom authority is delegated to act in his
            stead.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Administrative Law Judge
            </E>
             means an Administrative Law Judge in the Office of Administrative
            Law Judge, U.S. Department of Agriculture.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Administrative Law Judge Recommended Decision
            </E>
             means the Administrative Law Judge&apos;s report to the Secretary
            consisting of the proposed: (1) Findings of facts and conclusions
            with respect to all material issues of fact, law or discretion, as
            well as the reasons or basis for conclusions and (2) order.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The term 
            <E T='03'>
              hearing
            </E>
             means that part of a proceeding which involves the submission of
            evidence and means either an oral or written hearing.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Hearing Clerk
            </E>
             means the Hearing Clerk, U.S. Department of Agriculture,
            Washington, DC 20250.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The term 
            <E T='03'>
              person
            </E>
             includes any individual, partnership, corporation, company,
            society, association, receiver, or trustee.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The term 
            <E T='03'>
              regulations
            </E>
             means the regulations promulgated pursuant to the Act (
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='201' tq='N'>
                201
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='l'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (l)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Respondent
            </E>
             means the party proceeded against.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='m'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (m)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Secretary
            </E>
             means the Secretary of Agriculture of the United States, or any
            officer or employee of the U.S. Department of Agriculture to whom
            authority has heretofore been delegated, or to whom authority may
            hereafter be delegated, to act in his stead, including the Judicial
            Officer.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4397'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:K:202:A:202.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        202.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Institution of proceedings.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='202' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              202.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Institution of proceedings.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Any person having information of any violation of the Act or of any of
          the regulations promulgated thereunder may file with the Director an
          application requesting the institution of such proceedings as may be
          authorized under the Act. Such application shall be in writing, signed
          by or on behalf of the applicant, and shall contain a short and simple
          statement of the facts constituting the alleged violation and the name
          and address of the applicant and the party complained of. If, after
          investigation of the matters complained of in the application or after
          investigation made on his own motion, the Director has reason to
          believe that any person has violated or is violating any of the
          provisions of the Act or the regulations made and promulgated
          thereunder, he may institute such proceedings as may be authorized by
          the Act.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4398'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:K:202:A:202.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        202.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Status of applicant.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='202' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              202.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Status of applicant.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The person filing an application shall not be a party to any
          proceeding which may be instituted under the Act, unless he be
          permitted by the Secretary or by the Administrative Law Judge to
          intervene therein. The Director shall 
          <PRTPAGE P='386' />
          not be required to divulge the name of the applicant and such person
          will have no legal status in the proceeding which may be instituted,
          except where allowed to intervene or as such person may be called as a
          witness. At any time after the institution of the proceeding, and
          before it has been submitted to the Secretary for final consideration,
          the Secretary or the Administrator, may upon petition in writing and
          upon good cause shown, permit any person to intervene.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4399'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:K:202:C:202.40
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        202.40
      </num>
      <head>
        Proceedings prior to reporting for criminal prosecution.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='202' sect='40' psec='' tq='N'>
              202.40
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Proceedings prior to reporting for criminal prosecution.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The Director shall, before any violation of this act is reported to
          any U.S. attorney for institution of a criminal proceeding, notify the
          person against whom such proceeding is contemplated that action is
          contemplated, inform him regarding the facts involved, and afford him
          an opportunity to present his views, either orally or in writing, with
          regard to such contemplated proceeding. Notice shall be served upon
          such person in the manner provided in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='202' sect='27' psec='' tq='N'>
              202.27
            </subref>
             of this part
          </aref>
          . If the person desires to explain the transaction or otherwise to
          present his views, he shall file with the Director, within 20 days
          after the service of the notice, an answer, in duplicate, signed by
          him or by his attorney, or shall request, within the 20 days, an
          opportunity to express his views orally. The request shall be embodied
          in a writing signed by the person or by his attorney or agent. Such
          opportunity to present his views orally shall be afforded at a time
          and place to be designated by the Director and it shall be given
          within a time not to exceed 10 days after the date of the filing of
          the request therefor.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4400'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:K:202:C:202.41
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        202.41
      </num>
      <head>
        Notice and hearing prior to promulgation of rules and regulations.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='202' sect='41' psec='' tq='N'>
              202.41
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Notice and hearing prior to promulgation of rules and regulations.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Prior to the promulgation of any rule or regulation contemplated by 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 402 of
          </aref>
           the Act (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='1592' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1592.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 1592
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ), notice shall be given by publication in the 
          <E T='04'>
            Federal Register
          </E>
           of intention to promulgate such rule or regulation and of the time
          and place of a public hearing to be held with reference thereto. Such
          hearings shall be conducted by the Director or by such employee or
          employees of the Department of Agriculture as may be designated to
          preside thereat, except that hearings with respect to rules or
          regulations contemplated by 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 402(b) of
          </aref>
           the Act relating to title III of the Act (Foreign Commerce), shall be
          conducted by the Secretary of the Treasury and the Secretary of
          Agriculture, acting jointly or separately, or by such employee or
          employees of the Department of Agriculture or the Department of the
          Treasury as may be designated to preside thereat. The presiding
          officer shall conduct the hearing in an orderly and informal manner,
          according to such procedure as he may announce at the commencement of
          the hearing. Any rule or regulation promulgated under 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 402 of
          </aref>
           the Act shall become effective on the date fixed in the promulgation,
          which date shall be not less than 30 days after publication in the 
          <E T='04'>
            Federal Register.
          </E>
           Any rule or regulation may be amended or revoked in the same manner
          as is provided for its promulgation.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4401'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:K:202:C:202.42
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        202.42
      </num>
      <head>
        Publication of judgments, settlements, and orders.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='202' sect='42' psec='' tq='N'>
              202.42
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Publication of judgments, settlements, and orders.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          After judgment or settlement, or the issuance of a cease and desist
          order, in any case or proceeding arising under this Act, notice
          thereof containing any information pertinent to the judgment or
          settlement or the issuance of the cease and desist order, shall be
          given by issuing a press release or by such other media as the
          Administrator of the Agricultural Marketing Service may designate from
          time to time.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4402'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:K:202:C:202.43
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        202.43
      </num>
      <head>
        Proceedings under section 302(a) to show cause why seed or screenings
        should be admitted into the United States.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='202' sect='43' psec='' tq='N'>
              202.43
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Proceedings under 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            section 302(a)
          </aref>
           to show cause why seed or screenings should be admitted into the
          United States.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          When seed or screenings have been refused admission into the United
          States under the Act or the joint regulations promulgated thereunder,
          the owner or consignee of such seed or screenings may submit a request
          to the Director for a hearing in which he may show cause, if any he
          have, why such 
          <PRTPAGE P='387' />
          seed or screenings should be admitted. Request for such hearing shall
          be embodied in a writing signed by the owner or consignee or by his
          attorney or agent. The Director shall thereupon fix, and notify the
          owner or consignee of, the time when and place at which the hearing
          will be held. The hearing shall be conducted in an orderly and
          informal manner by the Director or by a presiding officer duly
          designated by him, and it shall be governed by such rules of procedure
          as the presiding officer shall announce at the opening of the hearing.
          The determination as to whether the seed or screenings may be admitted
          into the United States shall be made by the Administrator of the
          Agricultural Marketing Service, within a reasonable time after the
          close of the hearing, and the owner or consignee of the seed or
          screenings who requested the hearing and the Secretary of the Treasury
          shall be duly notified as to such determination.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4403'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:K:202:C:202.44
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        202.44
      </num>
      <head>
        Proceedings under section 305(b) to determine whether foreign alfalfa or
        red clover seed is not adapted for general agricultural use in the
        United States.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='202' sect='44' psec='' tq='N'>
              202.44
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Proceedings under 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            section 305(b)
          </aref>
           to determine whether foreign alfalfa or red clover seed is not
          adapted for general agricultural use in the United States.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The public hearings which shall be held from time to time for the
          purpose of determining whether seed of alfalfa or red clover from any
          foreign country or region is not adapted for general agricultural use
          in the United States shall be conducted by the Director, or by a
          presiding officer duly designated by him. Such hearings shall be
          conducted in an orderly and informal manner in accordance with such
          procedure as the presiding officer shall announce at the opening of
          each hearing. The Administrator of the Agricultural Marketing Service
          shall, within a reasonable time after the close of the public hearing,
          make and publish his determination as to whether the said seed is
          adapted for general agricultural use in the United States. Publication
          of the determination shall be made in the 
          <E T='04'>
            Federal Register,
          </E>
           and through such other media as the said Administrator may deem
          appropriate.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>