<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol7'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:780
    </extid>
    <num>
      780
    </num>
    <head>
      APPEAL REGULATIONS
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='5' sect='301' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/5/301.html'>
              5 U.S.C. 301
            </subref>
             and 
            <subref title='5' sect='574' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/5/574.html'>
              574
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='6995' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/6995.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 6995
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='15' sect='714b' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/15/714b.html'>
              15 U.S.C. 714b
            </subref>
             and 
            <subref title='15' sect='714c' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/15/714c.html'>
              714c
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='16' sect='590h' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/590h.html'>
              16 U.S.C. 590h
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            70 FR 43266
          </aref>
          , July 27, 2005, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='7196'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:780:-:780.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        780.1
      </num>
      <head>
        General.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='780' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              780.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          This part sets forth rules applicable to appealability reviews,
          reconsiderations, appeals and alternative dispute resolution
          procedures comprising in aggregate the informal appeals process of 
          <PRTPAGE P='345' />
          FSA. FSA will apply these rules to facilitate and expedite
          participants&apos; submissions and FSA reviews of documentary and
          other evidence material to resolution of disputes arising under agency
          program regulations.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='7197'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:780:-:780.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        780.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='780' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              780.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          For purposes of this part:
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            1994 Act
          </E>
           means the Federal Crop Insurance Reform and Department of Agriculture
          Reorganization Act of 1994 (
          <aref target='_blank' title='Pub. L. 103-354' alt='Pub. L. 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Pub. L. 103-354
          </aref>
          ).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Adverse decision
          </E>
           means a program decision by an employee, officer, or committee of FSA
          that is adverse to the participant. The term includes any denial of
          program participation, benefits, written agreements, eligibility,
          etc., that results in a participant receiving less funds than the
          participant believes should have been paid or not receiving a program
          benefit to which the participant believes the participant was
          entitled.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Agency
          </E>
           means FSA and its county and State committees and their personnel,
          CCC, NRCS, and any other agency or office of the Department which the
          Secretary may designate, or any successor agency.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Agency record
          </E>
           means all documents and materials maintained by FSA that are related
          to the adverse decision under review that are compiled and reviewed by
          the decision-maker or that are compiled in the record provided to the
          next level reviewing authority.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Appeal
          </E>
           means a written request by a participant asking the next level
          reviewing authority within FSA to review a decision. However,
          depending on the context, the term may also refer to a request for
          review by NAD.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Appealability review
          </E>
           means review of a decision-maker&apos;s determination that a decision
          is not appealable under this part. That decision is, however, subject
          to review according to 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='780' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              780.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
           or 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR part 
            <subref title='7' part='11' tq='N'>
              11
            </subref>
          </aref>
           to determine whether the decision involves a factual dispute that is
          appealable or is, instead, an attempt to challenge generally
          applicable program policies, provisions, regulations, or statutes that
          were not appealable.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Appellant
          </E>
           means any participant who appeals or requests reconsideration or
          mediation of an adverse decision in accordance with this part or 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR part 
            <subref title='7' part='11' tq='N'>
              11
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Authorized representative
          </E>
           means a person who has obtained a Privacy Act waiver and is
          authorized in writing by a participant to act for the participant in a
          reconsideration, mediation, or appeal.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            CCC
          </E>
           means the Commodity Credit Corporation, a wholly owned Government
          corporation within USDA.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Certified State
          </E>
           means, in connection with mediation, a State with a mediation
          program, approved by the Secretary, that meets the requirements of 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR part 
            <subref title='7' part='785' tq='N'>
              785
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Confidential mediation
          </E>
           means a mediation process in which neither the mediator nor parties
          participating in mediation will disclose to any person oral or written
          communications provided to the mediator in confidence, except as
          allowed by 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='5' sect='574' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/5/574.html'>
              5 U.S.C. 574
            </subref>
          </aref>
           or 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR part 
            <subref title='7' part='785' tq='N'>
              785
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            County committee
          </E>
           means an FSA county or area committee established in accordance with 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 8(b) of
          </aref>
           the Soil Conservation and Domestic Allotment Act (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='16' sect='590h' note='' psec='#b' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/590h.html#b'>
              16 U.S.C. 590h(b)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Determination of NRCS
          </E>
           means a decision by NRCS made pursuant to Title XII of the Food
          Security Act of 1985 (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='16' sect='3801' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/3801.html'>
              16 U.S.C. 3801
            </subref>
          </aref>
          <E T='03'>
            et seq.
          </E>
          ), as amended.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            FSA
          </E>
           means the Farm Service Agency, an agency within USDA.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Final decision
          </E>
           means a program decision rendered by an employee or officer of FSA
          pursuant to delegated authority, or by the county or State committee
          upon written request of a participant. A decision that is otherwise
          final shall remain final unless the decision is timely appealed to the
          State committee or NAD. A decision of FSA made by personnel
          subordinate to the county committee is considered “final” for the
          purpose of appeal to NAD only after that decision has been appealed to
          the county committee under the provisions of this part.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Hearing
          </E>
           means an informal proceeding on an appeal to afford a participant
          opportunity to present testimony, documentary evidence, or both to
          show why an adverse decision is in error and why the adverse decision
          should be reversed or modified.
          <PRTPAGE P='346' />
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Implement
          </E>
           means the taking of action by FSA, NRCS, or CCC that is necessary to
          effectuate fully and promptly a final decision.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Mediation
          </E>
           means a technique for resolution of disputes in which a mediator
          assists disputing parties in voluntarily reaching mutually agreeable
          settlement of issues within the laws, regulations, and the
          agency&apos;s generally applicable program policies and procedures,
          but in which the mediator has no authoritative decision making power.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Mediator
          </E>
           means a neutral individual who functions specifically to aid the
          parties in a dispute during a mediation process.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            NAD
          </E>
           means the USDA National Appeals Division established pursuant to the
          1994 Act.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            NAD rules
          </E>
           means the NAD rules of procedure published at 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR part 
            <subref title='7' part='11' tq='N'>
              11
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , implementing title II, subtitle H of the 1994 Act.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Non-certified State
          </E>
           means a State that is not approved to participate in the certified
          mediation program under 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR part 
            <subref title='7' part='785' tq='N'>
              785
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , or any successor regulation.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            NRCS
          </E>
           means the Natural Resources Conservation Service of USDA.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Participant
          </E>
           means any individual or entity who has applied for, or whose right to
          participate in or receive, a payment, loan, loan guarantee, or other
          benefit in accordance with any program of FSA to which the regulations
          in this part apply is affected by a decision of FSA. The term includes
          anyone meeting this definition regardless of whether, in the
          particular proceeding, the participant is an appellant or a third
          party respondent. The term does not include individuals or entities
          whose claim(s) arise under the programs excluded in the definition of
          “participant” published at 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR 
            <subref title='7' part='11' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              11.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Qualified mediator
          </E>
           means a mediator who meets the training requirements established by
          State law in the State in which mediation services will be provided
          or, where a State has no law prescribing mediator qualifications, an
          individual who has attended a minimum of 40 hours of core mediator
          knowledge and skills training and, to remain in a qualified mediator
          status, completes a minimum of 20 hours of additional training or
          education during each 2-year period. Such training or education must
          be approved by USDA, by an accredited college or university, or by one
          of the following organizations: State Bar of a qualifying State, a
          State mediation association, a State approved mediation program, or a
          society of dispute resolution professionals.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Reconsideration
          </E>
           means a subsequent consideration of a program decision by the same
          level of decision-maker or reviewing authority.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Reviewing authority
          </E>
           means a person or committee assigned the responsibility of making a
          decision on reconsideration or an appeal filed by a participant in
          accordance with this part.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State committee
          </E>
           means an FSA State committee established in accordance with 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            Section 8(b) of
          </aref>
           the Soil Conservation and Domestic Allotment Act (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='16' sect='590h' note='' psec='#b' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/590h.html#b'>
              16 U.S.C. 590h(b)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ) including, where appropriate, the Director of the Caribbean Area FSA
          office for Puerto Rico and the Virgin Islands.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State Conservationist
          </E>
           means the NRCS official in charge of NRCS operations within a State,
          as set forth in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='600' tq='N'>
              600 of this title
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State Executive Director
          </E>
           means the executive director of an FSA State office with
          administrative responsibility for a FSA State office as established
          under the Reorganization Act.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            USDA
          </E>
           means the U.S. Department of Agriculture.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Verbatim transcript
          </E>
           means an official, written record of proceedings in an appeal hearing
          or reconsideration of an adverse decision appealable under this part.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='7198'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:780:-:780.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        780.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Reservations of authority.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='780' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              780.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Reservations of authority.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Representatives of FSA and CCC may correct all errors in data
            entered on program contracts, loan agreements, and other program
            documents and the results of the computations or calculations made
            pursuant to the contract or agreement. FSA and CCC will furnish
            appropriate notice of such corrections when corrections are deemed
            necessary.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Nothing contained in this part shall preclude the Secretary, or the
            Administrator of FSA, Executive Vice President of CCC, the Chief of
            NRCS, if 
            <PRTPAGE P='347' />
            applicable, or a designee, from determining at any time any question
            arising under the programs within their respective authority or from
            reversing or modifying any decision made by a subordinate employee
            of FSA or its county and State committees, or CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='7199'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:780:-:780.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        780.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Applicability.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='780' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              780.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Applicability.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as provided in other regulations, this part applies to
            decisions made under programs and by agencies, as set forth herein:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Decisions in programs administered by FSA to make, guarantee or
            service farm loans set forth in chapters VII and XVIII of this title
            relating to farm loan programs;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Decisions in those domestic programs administered by FSA on behalf
            of CCC through State and county committees, or itself, which are
            generally set forth in chapters VII and XIV of this title, or in
            part VII relating to conservation or commodities;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Appeals from adverse decisions, including technical determinations,
            made by NRCS under title XII of the Food Security Act of 1985, as
            amended;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Penalties assessed by FSA under the Agricultural Foreign Investment
            Disclosure Act of 1978, 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='5' sect='501' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/5/501.html'>
                5 U.S.C. 501
              </subref>
            </aref>
            <E T='03'>
              et seq.
            </E>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Decisions on equitable relief made by a State Executive Director or
            State Conservationist pursuant to 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 1613 of
            </aref>
             the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002, 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Pub. L. 107-171' alt='Pub. L. 107-171' href='http://www.gpo.gov/fdsys/pkg/PLAW-107publ171/html/PLAW-107publ171.htm'>
              Pub. L. 107-171
            </aref>
            ; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Other programs to which this part is made applicable by specific
            program regulations or notices in the 
            <E T='04'>
              Federal Register
            </E>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The procedures contained in this part may not be used to seek
            review of statutes or regulations issued under Federal law or review
            of FSA&apos;s generally applicable interpretations of such laws and
            regulations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For covered programs, this part is applicable to any decision made
            by an employee of FSA or of its State and county committees, CCC,
            the personnel of FSA, or CCC, and by the officials of NRCS to the
            extent otherwise provided in this part, and as otherwise may be
            provided in individual program requirements or by the Secretary.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             With respect to matters identified in paragraph (a) of this
            section, participants may request appealability review,
            reconsideration, mediation, or appeal under the provisions of this
            part, of decisions made with respect to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Denial of participation in a program;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Compliance with program requirements;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Issuance of payments or other program benefits to a participant in
            a program; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Determinations under Title XII of the Food Security Act of 1985, as
            amended, made by NRCS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Only a participant directly affected by a decision may seek
            administrative review under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='780' sect='5' psec='#c' tq='N'>
                780.5(c)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='7200'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:780:-:780.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        780.5
      </num>
      <head>
        Decisions that are not appealable.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='780' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              780.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Decisions that are not appealable.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Decisions that are not appealable under this part shall include the
            following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any general program provision or program policy or any statutory or
            regulatory requirement that is applicable to similarly situated
            participants;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Mathematical formulas established under a statute or program
            regulation and decisions based solely on the application of those
            formulas;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Decisions made pursuant to statutory provisions that expressly make
            agency decisions final or their implementing regulations;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Decisions on equitable relief made by a State Executive Director or
            State Conservationist pursuant to 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              Section 1613 of
            </aref>
             the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002, 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Pub. L. 107-171' alt='Pub. L. 107-171' href='http://www.gpo.gov/fdsys/pkg/PLAW-107publ171/html/PLAW-107publ171.htm'>
              Pub. L. 107-171
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Decisions of other Federal or State agencies;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Requirements and conditions designated by law to be developed by
            agencies other than FSA.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Disapprovals or denials because of a lack of funding.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Decisions made by the Administrator or a Deputy Administrator.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A participant directly affected by an adverse decision that is
            determined not to be subject to appeal under this part may request
            an appealability review of the determination by the State Executive
            Director of the State from which the underlying decision arose in
            accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='780' sect='15' psec='' tq='N'>
                780.15
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
            <PRTPAGE P='348' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Decisions that FSA renders under this part may be reviewed by NAD
            under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='11' tq='N'>
                11 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
             to the extent otherwise allowed by NAD under its rules and
            procedures. An appealability determination of the State Executive
            Director in an administrative review is considered by FSA to be a
            new decision.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='7201'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:780:-:780.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        780.6
      </num>
      <head>
        Appeal procedures available when a decision is appealable.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='780' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              780.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Appeal procedures available when a decision is appealable.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For covered programs administered by FSA for CCC, the following
            procedures are available:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Appeal to the county committee of decisions of county committee
            subordinates;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Reconsideration by the county committee;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Appeal to the State committee;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Reconsideration by the State committee;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Appeal to NAD;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Mediation under guidelines specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='780' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
                780.9
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For decisions in agricultural credit programs administered by FSA,
            the following procedures are available:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Reconsideration under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='780' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
                780.7
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Mediation under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='780' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
                780.9
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Appeal to NAD.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For programs and regulatory requirements under Title XII of the
            Food Security Act of 1985, as amended, to the extent not covered by
            paragraph (a) of this section, the following procedures are
            available:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Appeal to the county committee;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Appeal to the State committee;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Mediation under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='780' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
                780.9
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Appeal to NAD.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='7202'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:780:-:780.7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        780.7
      </num>
      <head>
        Reconsideration.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          70 FR 43266
        </aref>
        , July 27, 2005, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          71 FR 30573
        </aref>
        , May 30, 2006]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='780' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              780.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Reconsideration.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A request for reconsideration must be submitted in writing by a
            participant or by a participant&apos;s authorized representative and
            addressed to the FSA decision maker as will be instructed in the
            adverse decision notification.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A participant&apos;s right to request reconsideration is waived if,
            before requesting reconsideration, a participant:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Has requested and begun mediation of the adverse decision;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Has appealed the adverse decision to a higher reviewing authority
            in FSA; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Has appealed to NAD.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provided a participant has not waived the right to request
            reconsideration, FSA will consider a request for reconsideration of
            an adverse decision under these rules except when a request concerns
            a determination of NRCS appealable under the procedures in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='780' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
                780.11
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , the decision has been mediated, the decision has previously been
            reconsidered, or the decision-maker is the Administrator, Deputy
            Administrator, or other FSA official outside FSA&apos;s informal
            appeals process.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A request for reconsideration will be deemed withdrawn if a
            participant requests mediation or appeals to a higher reviewing
            authority within FSA or requests an appeal by NAD before a request
            for reconsideration has been acted upon.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Federal Rules of Evidence do not apply to reconsiderations.
            Proceedings may be confined to presentations of evidence to material
            facts, and evidence or questions that are irrelevant, unduly
            repetitious, or otherwise inappropriate may be excluded.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The official decision on reconsideration will be the decision
            letter that is issued following disposition of the reconsideration
            request.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A decision on reconsideration is a new decision that restarts
            applicable time limitations periods under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='780' sect='15' psec='' tq='N'>
                780.15
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='11' tq='N'>
                11 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            70 FR 43266
          </aref>
          , July 27, 2005, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            71 FR 30573
          </aref>
          , May 30, 2006]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='7203'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:780:-:780.8
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        780.8
      </num>
      <head>
        County committee appeals.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='780' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              780.8
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          County committee appeals.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A request for appeal to a county committee concerning a decision of
            a subordinate of the county committee must be submitted by a
            participant or by a participant&apos;s authorized representative in
            writing and must be addressed to the office in which the subordinate
            is employed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Federal Rules of Evidence do not apply to appeals to a county
            committee. However, a county committee may confine presentations of
            evidence to material facts and may exclude evidence or questions
            that are irrelevant, unduly repetitious, or otherwise inappropriate.
            <PRTPAGE P='349' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The official county committee decision on an appeal will be the
            decision letter that is issued following disposition of the appeal.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Deliberations shall be in confidence except to the extent that a
            county committee may request the assistance of county committee or
            FSA employees during deliberations.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='7204'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:780:-:780.9
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        780.9
      </num>
      <head>
        Mediation.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          70 FR 43266
        </aref>
        , July 27, 2005, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          71 FR 30573
        </aref>
        , May 30, 2006]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='780' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
              780.9
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Mediation.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any request for mediation must be submitted after issuance of an
            adverse decision but before any hearing in an appeal of the adverse
            decision to NAD.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An adverse decision and any particular issues of fact material to
            an adverse decision may be mediated only once:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If resolution of an adverse decision is not achieved in mediation,
            a participant may exercise any remaining appeal rights under this
            part or appeal to NAD in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='11' tq='N'>
                11 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and NAD procedures.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If an adverse decision is modified as a result of mediation, a
            participant may exercise any remaining appeal rights as to the
            modified decision under this part or appeal to NAD, unless such
            appeal rights have been waived pursuant to agreement in the
            mediation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any agreement reached during, or as a result of, the mediation
            process shall conform to the statutory and regulatory provisions
            governing the program and FSA&apos;s generally applicable
            interpretation of those statutes and regulatory provisions.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FSA will participate in mediation in good faith and to do so will
            take steps that include the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Designating a representative in the mediation;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Instructing the representative that any agreement reached during,
            or as a result of, the mediation process must conform to the
            statutes, regulations, and FSA&apos;s generally applicable
            interpretations of statutes and regulations governing the program;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Assisting as necessary in making pertinent records available for
            review and discussion during the mediation; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Directing the representative to forward any written agreement
            proposed in mediation to the appropriate FSA official for approval.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Mediations will be treated in a confidential manner consistent with
            the purposes of the mediation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For requests for mediation in a Certified State, if the factual
            issues implicated in an adverse decision have not previously been
            mediated, notice to a participant of an adverse decision will
            include notice of the opportunity for mediation, including a mailing
            address and facsimile number, if available, that the participant may
            use to submit a written request for mediation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the participant desires mediation, the participant must request
            mediation in writing by contacting the certified mediation program
            or such other contact as may be designated by FSA in an adverse
            decision letter. The request for mediation must include a copy of
            the adverse decision to be mediated.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Participants in mediation may be required to pay fees established
            by the mediation program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A listing of certified State mediation programs and means for
            contact may be found on the FSA Web site at 
            <E T='03'>
              http://www.usda.gov/fsa/disputemediation.htm.
            </E>
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For requests for mediation in a Non-certified State, if the factual
            issues implicated in an adverse decision have not previously been
            mediated, notice to a participant of an adverse decision will, as
            appropriate, include notice of the opportunity for mediation,
            including the mailing address of the State Executive Director and a
            facsimile number, if available, that the participant may use to
            submit a written request for mediation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             It is the duty of the participant to contact the State Executive
            Director in writing to request mediation. The request for mediation
            must include a copy of the adverse decision to be mediated.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If resources are available for mediation, the State Executive
            Director will select a qualified mediator and provide written notice
            to the participant that mediation is available and the fees that the
            participant will incur for mediation.
            <PRTPAGE P='350' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the participant accepts such mediation, FSA may give notice of
            the mediation to interested parties and third parties whose
            interests are known to FSA.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Mediation will be considered to be at an end on that date set out
            in writing by the mediator or mediation program, as applicable, or
            when the participant receives written notice from the State
            Executive Director that the State Executive Director believes the
            mediation is at an impasse, whichever is earlier.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To provide for mediator impartiality:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No person shall be designated as mediator in an adverse program
            dispute who has previously served as an advocate or representative
            for any party in the mediation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             As a condition of retention to mediate in an adverse program
            dispute under this part, the mediator shall agree not to serve
            thereafter as an advocate or representative for a participant or
            party in any other proceeding arising from or related to the
            mediated dispute, including, without limitation, representation of a
            mediation participant before an administrative appeals entity of
            USDA, or any other Federal Government department.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            70 FR 43266
          </aref>
          , July 27, 2005, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            71 FR 30573
          </aref>
          , May 30, 2006]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='7205'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:780:-:780.10
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        780.10
      </num>
      <head>
        State committee appeals.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          70 FR 43266
        </aref>
        , July 27, 2005, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          71 FR 30573
        </aref>
        , May 30, 2006]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='780' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
              780.10
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          State committee appeals.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A request for appeal to the State committee from a decision of a
            county committee must be submitted by a participant or by a
            participant&apos;s authorized representative in writing and
            addressed to the State Executive Director.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A participant&apos;s right to appeal a decision to a State
            committee is waived if a participant has appealed the adverse
            decision to NAD before requesting an appeal to the State Committee.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a participant requests mediation or requests an appeal to NAD
            before a request for an appeal to the State Committee has been acted
            upon, the appeal to the State Committee will be deemed withdrawn.
            The deemed withdrawal of a participant&apos;s appeal to the State
            Committee will not preclude a subsequent request for a State
            Committee hearing on appealable matters not resolved in mediation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Federal Rules of Evidence do not apply in appeals to a State
            committee. Notwithstanding, a State committee may confine
            presentations of evidence to material facts and exclude evidence or
            questions as irrelevant, unduly repetitious, or otherwise
            inappropriate.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The official record of a State committee decision on an appeal will
            be the decision letter that is issued following disposition of the
            appeal.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Deliberations shall be in confidence except to the extent that a
            State committee may request the assistance of FSA employees during
            deliberations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            70 FR 43266
          </aref>
          , July 27, 2005, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            71 FR 30573
          </aref>
          , May 30, 2006]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='7206'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:780:-:780.11
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        780.11
      </num>
      <head>
        Appeals of NRCS determinations.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='780' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
              780.11
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Appeals of NRCS determinations.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notwithstanding any other provision of this part, a determination
            of NRCS issued to a participant pursuant to Title XII of the Food
            Security Act of 1985, as amended, including a wetland determination,
            may be appealed to the county committee in accordance with the
            procedures in this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the county committee hears the appeal and believes that the
            challenge to the NRCS determination is not frivolous, the county
            committee shall refer the case with its findings on other issues to
            the NRCS State Conservationist to review the determination, or may
            make such a referral in advance of resolving other issues.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A decision of the county committee not to refer the case with its
            findings to the NRCS State Conservationist may be appealed to the
            State Committee.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The county or State committee decision must incorporate, and be
            based upon, the results of the NRCS State Conservationist&apos;s
            review and subsequent determination.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='7207'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:780:-:780.12
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        780.12
      </num>
      <head>
        Appeals of penalties assessed under the Agricultural Foreign Investment
        Disclosure Act of 1978.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='780' sect='12' psec='' tq='N'>
              780.12
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Appeals of penalties assessed under the Agricultural Foreign
          Investment Disclosure Act of 1978.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Requests for appeals of penalties assessed under the Agricultural
            Foreign Investment Disclosure Act of 1978 must be addressed to:
            Administrator, 
            <PRTPAGE P='351' />
            Farm Service Agency, Stop 0572, 1400 Independence Avenue, SW.,
            Washington, DC 20250-0572.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Decisions in appeals under this section are not subject to
            reconsideration and are administratively final.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='7208'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:780:-:780.13
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        780.13
      </num>
      <head>
        Verbatim transcripts.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='780' sect='13' psec='' tq='N'>
              780.13
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Verbatim transcripts.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Appellants and their representatives are precluded from making any
            electronic recording of any portion of a hearing or other proceeding
            conducted in accordance with this part. Appellants interested in
            obtaining an official recording of a hearing or other proceeding may
            request a verbatim transcript in accordance with paragraph (b) of
            this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any party to an appeal or request for reconsideration under this
            part may request that a verbatim transcript be made of the hearing
            proceedings and that such transcript be made the official record of
            the hearing. The party requesting a verbatim transcript shall pay
            for the transcription service, provide a copy of the transcript to
            FSA free of charge, and allow any other party in the proceeding
            desiring to purchase a copy of the transcript to order it from the
            transcription service.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='7209'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:780:-:780.14
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        780.14
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='780' sect='14' psec='' tq='N'>
              780.14
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='7210'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:780:-:780.15
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        780.15
      </num>
      <head>
        Time limitations.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          70 FR 43266
        </aref>
        , July 27, 2005, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          71 FR 30574
        </aref>
        , May 30, 2006]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='780' sect='15' psec='' tq='N'>
              780.15
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Time limitations.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To the extent practicable, no later than 10 business days after an
            agency decision maker renders an adverse decision that affects a
            participant, FSA will provide the participant written notice of the
            adverse decision and available appeal rights.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A participant requesting an appealability review by the State
            Executive Director of an agency decision made at the county, area,
            district or State level that is otherwise determined by FSA not to
            be appealable must submit a written request for an appealability
            review to the State Executive Director that is received no later
            than 30 calendar days from the date a participant receives written
            notice of the decision.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A participant requesting reconsideration, mediation or appeal must
            submit a written request as instructed in the notice of decision
            that is received no later than 30 calendar days from the date a
            participant receives written notice of the decision. A participant
            that receives a determination made under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
                1400 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
             will be deemed to have consented to an extension of the time
            limitation for a final determination as provided in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
                1400 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
             if the participant requests mediation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notwithstanding the time limits in paragraphs (b) and (c) of this
            section, a request for an appealability review, reconsideration, or
            appeal may be accepted if, in the judgment of the reviewing
            authority with whom such request is filed, exceptional circumstances
            warrant such action. A participant does not have the right to seek
            an exception under this paragraph. FSA&apos;s refusal to accept an
            untimely request is not appealable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Decisions appealable under this part are final unless review
            options available under this part or 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='11' tq='N'>
                11
              </subref>
            </aref>
             are timely exercised.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whenever the final date for any requirement of this part falls on a
            Saturday, Sunday, Federal holiday, or other day on which the
            pertinent FSA office is not open for the transaction of business
            during normal working hours, the time for submission of a request
            will be extended to the close of business on the next working day.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The date when an adverse decision or other notice pursuant to these
            rules is deemed received is the earlier of physical delivery by
            hand, by facsimile with electronic confirmation of receipt, actual
            stamped record of receipt on a transmitted document, or 7 calendar
            days following deposit for delivery by regular mail.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            70 FR 43266
          </aref>
          , July 27, 2005, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            71 FR 30574
          </aref>
          , May 30, 2006]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='7211'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:780:-:780.16
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        780.16
      </num>
      <head>
        Implementation of final agency decisions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='780' sect='16' psec='' tq='N'>
              780.16
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Implementation of final agency decisions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          To the extent practicable, no later than 30 calendar days after an
          agency decision becomes a final administrative decision of USDA, FSA
          will implement the decision.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='7212'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:D:780:-:780.17
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        780.17
      </num>
      <head>
        Judicial review.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='780' sect='17' psec='' tq='N'>
              780.17
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Judicial review.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Decisions of the Administrator in appeals under this part from
            Agriculture Foreign Investment Disclosure 
            <PRTPAGE P='352' />
            Act penalties are administratively final decisions of USDA.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The decision of a State Executive Director or State Conservationist
            on equitable relief made under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='718' sect='307' psec='' tq='N'>
                718.307
              </subref>
               of this title
            </aref>
             is administratively final and also not subject to judicial review.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>