<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol10'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1413
    </extid>
    <num>
      1413
    </num>
    <head>
      COMMODITY INCENTIVE PAYMENT PROGRAMS
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='8788' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/8788.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 8788
            </subref>
             and 
            <subref title='7' sect='15' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/15.html'>
              15
            </subref>
          </aref>
           U.S.C. 714.
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 41965
          </aref>
          , July 20, 2010, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='12371'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1413:A:1413.101
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1413.101
      </num>
      <head>
        Applicability.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1413' sect='101' psec='' tq='N'>
              1413.101
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Applicability.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This subpart establishes the terms and conditions under which the
            Durum Wheat Quality Program (DWQP) as authorized by 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 1613 of
            </aref>
             the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008 (
            <aref target='_blank' title='Pub. L. 110-246' alt='Pub. L. 110-246' href='http://www.gpo.gov/fdsys/pkg/PLAW-110publ246/html/PLAW-110publ246.htm'>
              Pub. L. 110-246
            </aref>
            ) will be administered.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This program will operate only to the extent appropriated funding
            is available.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subject to available funding, eligible producers of durum wheat
            will be partially compensated for the cost of purchasing and
            applying fungicides to a crop of durum wheat to control Fusarium
            head blight on acres accurately certified as planted to durum wheat.
            “Available funding” requires that there be a specific appropriation
            for the program that applies to a particular crop for which the
            producer seeks compensation under this program.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12372'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1413:A:1413.102
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1413.102
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1413' sect='102' psec='' tq='N'>
              1413.102
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The following definitions apply to this subpart. The definitions in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            parts 
            <subref title='7' part='718' tq='N'>
              718
            </subref>
             and 
            <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
              1400 of this title
            </subref>
          </aref>
           also apply, except where they conflict with the definitions in this
          section.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Application period
          </E>
           means the dates established by the Deputy Administrator for Farm
          Programs for producers to apply for program benefits.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            CCC
          </E>
           means the Commodity Credit Corporation.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Crop year
          </E>
           means the calendar year in which the wheat was harvested or intended
          to be harvested. For example, a reference to the 2010 crop year of
          wheat means wheat that when planted was intended for harvest in
          calendar year 2010.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Durum wheat
          </E>
           means all varieties of white (amber) durum wheat as defined in the
          U.S. Standards for Wheat (
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR part 
            <subref title='7' part='810' tq='N'>
              810
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , subpart M) including, but not limited to, hard amber durum wheat and
          amber durum wheat.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Flowering stage
          </E>
           means the period of time during the wheat growth stage, after the
          head emergence has completed and prior to milk development in the
          kernel.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State committee, county committee or county office
          </E>
           means the respective FSA committee or office.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            United States
          </E>
           means all 50 States of the United States, the District of Columbia,
          the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and any other territory or possession
          of the United States.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            USDA
          </E>
           means the United States Department of Agriculture.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12373'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1413:A:1413.103
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1413.103
      </num>
      <head>
        Administration.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1413' sect='103' psec='' tq='N'>
              1413.103
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Administration.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             DWQP will be administered under the general supervision of the
            Executive Vice President, CCC (Administrator, Farm Service Agency
            (FSA)), or a designee, and will be carried out in the field by FSA
            State and county committees and FSA employees.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FSA representatives do not have authority to modify or waive any of
            the provisions of the regulations of this subpart, except as
            specified in paragraph (e) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State FSA committee will take any action required by the
            provisions of this subpart that the county FSA committee has not
            taken. The State FSA committee will also:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Correct, or require a county FSA committee to correct, any action
            taken by such county FSA committee that is 
            <PRTPAGE P='521' />
            not in compliance with the provisions of this subpart.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Require a county FSA committee to not take an action that is not in
            compliance with the provisions of this subpart.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No provision or delegation to a State or county FSA committee will
            preclude the Administrator, Deputy Administrator, or a designee from
            determining any question arising under the program in this subpart,
            or from reversing or modifying any determination made by a State or
            county FSA committee.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Deputy Administrator may authorize State and county FSA
            committees to waive or modify non-statutory program requirements of
            this subpart in cases where failure to meet such requirements does
            not adversely affect operation of the program in this subpart.
            Producers have no right to seek an exception under this provision.
            The Deputy Administrator&apos;s refusal to consider cases or
            circumstances or decision not to exercise this discretionary
            authority under this provision will not be considered an adverse
            decision and is not appealable.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12374'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1413:A:1413.104
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1413.104
      </num>
      <head>
        Eligibility.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1413' sect='104' psec='' tq='N'>
              1413.104
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Eligibility.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be considered eligible for DWQP payments, the person or entity
            must have a share in the treated wheat crop on those acres planted
            to durum wheat on which an eligible fungicide was applied, as
            certified on the application, have incurred the cost of acquiring
            and applying eligible fungicide, and meet the requirements in
            paragraph (b) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be eligible for benefits, a person or entity must be a:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Citizen of the United States;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             “Lawful alien” as defined in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1400' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
                1400.3
              </subref>
               of this chapter
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Partnership of citizens of the United States; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Corporation, limited liability corporation, or other farm
            organizational structure organized under State law.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A minor child is eligible to apply for DWQP payments if all the
            eligibility requirements of this subpart are met and the
            requirements in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
                1400 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
             that apply to minor children are met.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A person or entity determined to be a foreign person under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
                1400 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
             is not eligible to receive benefits under this subpart, unless that
            person provides land, capital, and a substantial amount of active
            personal labor in the production of crops on such farm.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State and local governments and their political subdivisions and
            related agencies are not eligible for DWQP payments.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be considered an eligible fungicide under this subpart, the
            fungicide must be:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Registered with the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, as
            required under the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide
            Act (FIFRA), unless exempt from FIFRA requirements;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In compliance with State pesticide regulations, if applicable, in
            the State in which benefits are being requested; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Applied specifically to control Fusarium head blight on acres
            certified as planted by the producer to durum wheat for the
            applicable crop year.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC will provide program benefits to reimburse eligible costs for a
            maximum of one fungicide treatment, including application cost,
            during the flowering stage, to a crop of durum wheat per crop year.
            Multiple or additional fungicide treatments, beyond a single
            treatment, to the same crop of wheat are not eligible for benefits.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12375'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1413:A:1413.105
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1413.105
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1413' sect='105' psec='' tq='N'>
              1413.105
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12376'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1413:A:1413.106
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1413.106
      </num>
      <head>
        Application process.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1413' sect='106' psec='' tq='N'>
              1413.106
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Application process.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To apply for DWQP payment, the producer must submit, to the FSA
            county office that maintains the producer&apos;s farm records for
            the agricultural operation, a completed application as specified in
            paragraph (c) of this section, including any supporting
            documentation required by FSA, and a report of acreage.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The producer must submit a completed application for payment and
            required supporting documentation to the administrative FSA county
            office during the relevant, for the crop, application period
            announced by FSA which will end no later than September 15 of 
            <PRTPAGE P='522' />
            the crop year in which the fungicide was applied to a crop of durum
            wheat.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A complete application includes all of the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An application form provided by FSA;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Certification of the total number and location of acres planted to
            durum wheat on which an eligible fungicide was applied specifically
            to control Fusarium head blight;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Certification of the date durum wheat, on which an eligible
            fungicide was applied specifically to control Fusarium head blight,
            was planted;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Certification of the type of eligible fungicide applied to acres
            certified as planted to durum wheat;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Certification of the date eligible fungicide was applied to acres
            certified as planted to durum wheat;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Documentation providing adequate proof, as determined by FSA, of
            the producer&apos;s actual cost of purchasing and applying eligible
            fungicide to acres certified as planted to durum wheat for one
            treatment; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any other documentation as determined by FSA to be necessary to
            make a determination of eligibility of the producer.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The producer requesting benefits under this program certifies the
            accuracy and truthfulness of the information provided in the
            application as well as any documentation filed with or in support of
            the application. All information provided is subject to verification
            by FSA.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Data furnished by the producer will be used to determine
            eligibility for program benefits. Furnishing the data is voluntary;
            however, without all required data program benefits will not be
            approved or provided.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12377'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1413:A:1413.107
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1413.107
      </num>
      <head>
        Availability of funds.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1413' sect='107' psec='' tq='N'>
              1413.107
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Availability of funds.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The 2008 Farm Bill authorizes up to $10 million to be appropriated
            for each of the 2009 through 2012 fiscal years for DWQP. Payments
            will not be made for claims for a particular crop year until after
            the application deadline, which is September 15 of that crop year,
            for the crop for which payment for the fungicide application is
            sought and only if funds are made available through an
            appropriation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the event that approval of all eligible applications for
            fungicide treatments for a particular crop would result in
            expenditures in excess of the amounts appropriated for that crop
            year, the FSA Deputy Administrator will prorate the funds by a
            national factor to reduce the total expected payments to the amount
            made available by the Secretary. FSA will prorate the payments in
            such manner as it determines appropriate and reasonable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Claims that are unpaid or paid at a reduced rate for a crop year
            for any reason will not be carried forward for payment under other
            funds for later crop years, unless provided for by law and approved
            by the Deputy Administrator. Such unpaid claims will be considered,
            as to any unpaid amount, void and nonpayable.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12378'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1413:A:1413.108
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1413.108
      </num>
      <head>
        Payment calculation.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1413' sect='108' psec='' tq='N'>
              1413.108
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Payment calculation.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subject to the availability of DWQP funds, the payment to an
            eligible producer will be the result of adding (adjusted for the
            producer&apos;s share of the crop):
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The lesser of:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The result of multiplying the number of acres certified by the
            producer as planted to durum wheat on which an eligible fungicide
            was applied, during the flowering stage, times the per acre national
            fungicide acquisition payment rate as set by the Deputy
            Administrator; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Fifty percent of the producer&apos;s actual cost of purchasing
            eligible fungicide for acres certified as planted to durum wheat and
            treated for the applicable crop year in a manner that would
            otherwise generate a payment under paragraph (a)(1)(i) of this
            section; plus
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The result of multiplying the number of acres certified as planted
            to durum wheat on which an eligible fungicide was applied during the
            flowering stage, times the State application per-acre payment rate
            set by the State committee, with such application payment not to
            exceed 50 percent of the actual application cost certified to by the
            producer.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The national fungicide acquisition payment rate set by the Deputy
            Administrator will be based on 50 percent of the national average
            cost of eligible fungicide (only including the cost 
            <PRTPAGE P='523' />
            of the chemical itself), applied to one acre of durum wheat for the
            applicable crop year.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State application payment rate set by the State committee will
            be based on 50 percent of the State average cost of applying an
            eligible fungicide to one acre of durum wheat for the applicable
            crop year.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12379'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1413:A:1413.109
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1413.109
      </num>
      <head>
        Refunds, joint and several liability.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1413' sect='109' psec='' tq='N'>
              1413.109
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Refunds, joint and several liability.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Excess payments, payments provided as the result of erroneous
            information provided by any person, or payments resulting from a
            failure to comply with any requirement or condition for payment in
            the application or this subpart, must be refunded to CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A refund required as specified in this section will be due with
            interest from the date of CCC disbursement and otherwise determined
            in accordance with paragraph (d) of this section and late payment
            charges as provided in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1403' tq='N'>
                1403 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Persons signing an application for payment as having an interest in
            an operation will be jointly and severally liable for any refund and
            related charges found to be due as specified in this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Interest will be applicable to any refunds required as specified in
            
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              parts 
              <subref title='7' part='792' tq='N'>
                792
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='1403' tq='N'>
                1403 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . Such interest will be charged at the rate that the U.S. Department
            of the Treasury charges CCC for funds, and will accrue from the date
            CCC made the erroneous payment to the date of repayment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC may waive the accrual of interest if it determines that the
            cause of the erroneous determination was not due to any action of
            the person, or was beyond the control of the person committing the
            violation. Any waiver is at the discretion of CCC alone.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12380'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1413:A:1413.110
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1413.110
      </num>
      <head>
        Misrepresentation and scheme or device.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1413' sect='110' psec='' tq='N'>
              1413.110
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Misrepresentation and scheme or device.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In addition to other penalties, sanctions, or remedies as may
            apply, a producer will be ineligible for payment through the DWQP if
            the producer is determined by CCC to have:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Adopted any scheme or device that tends to defeat the purpose of
            the program,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Made any fraudulent representation, or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Misrepresented any fact affecting a program determination.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any funds disbursed pursuant to this subpart to any producer
            engaged in a misrepresentation, scheme, or device, must be refunded
            with interest together with such other sums as may become due and
            all charges including interest will run from the date of
            disbursement of the CCC funds. Any producer engaged in acts
            prohibited by this section and any producer receiving payment as
            specified in this subpart will be jointly and severally liable with
            other persons or producers involved in such claim for payment for
            any refund due as specified in this section and for related charges.
            The remedies provided in this subpart will be in addition to other
            civil, criminal, or administrative remedies that may apply.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12381'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1413:A:1413.111
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1413.111
      </num>
      <head>
        Miscellaneous provisions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1413' sect='111' psec='' tq='N'>
              1413.111
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Miscellaneous provisions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Other interests.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any payment to any producer under this part will be made without
            regard to questions of title under State law, and without regard to
            any claim or lien against the commodity, or proceeds, in favor of
            the owner or any other creditor except agencies of the U.S.
            Government.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Assignments.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any producer entitled to any payment may assign any payment(s) in
            accordance with regulations governing the assignment of payments in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1404' tq='N'>
                1404 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Offsets.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC may offset or withhold any amount due to CCC from any benefit
            provided under this subpart in accordance with the provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1403' tq='N'>
                1403 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='792' tq='N'>
                792 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Violations of highly erodible land and wetland conservation
              provisions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='12' tq='N'>
                12 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
             apply to this subpart. That part sets out certain conservation
            requirements as a general condition for farm benefits.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Violations regarding controlled substances.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='718' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
                718.6
              </subref>
               of this title
            </aref>
            , which generally limit program payment eligibility for persons who
            have engaged in certain offenses with respect to controlled
            substances, will apply to this part.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12382'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1413:A:1413.112
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1413.112
      </num>
      <head>
        Appeals.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='524' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1413' sect='112' psec='' tq='N'>
              1413.112
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Appeals.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Appeals.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Appeal regulations set forth at 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              parts 
              <subref title='7' part='11' tq='N'>
                11
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='780' tq='N'>
                780 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
             apply to determinations made under this subpart.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Determinations not eligible for administrative review or appeal.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC determinations and policies that are not limited to a specific
            individual producer&apos;s application are not to be construed to be
            individual program eligibility determinations or adverse decisions
            and are, therefore, not subject to administrative review or appeal
            under 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='11' tq='N'>
                11
              </subref>
            </aref>
             or 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='780' tq='N'>
                780 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
             (but nothing in the regulations for this program will limit the
            ability of the National Appeals Division to decide its own
            jurisdiction under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='11' tq='N'>
                11
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ). Such determinations include, but are not limited to, application
            periods, deadlines, crop years, prices, general statutory or
            regulatory provisions that apply to similarly situated producers,
            national average payment prices, and payment factors established by
            CCC for DWQP for which this subpart applies or similar matters
            requiring CCC determinations.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12383'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1413:A:1413.113
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1413.113
      </num>
      <head>
        Deceased individuals or dissolved entities.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1413' sect='113' psec='' tq='N'>
              1413.113
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Deceased individuals or dissolved entities.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payment may be made for an eligible application on behalf of an
            eligible producer who is now a deceased individual or is a dissolved
            entity if a representative who currently has authority to enter into
            a contract on behalf of the producer signs the application for
            payment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Legal documents showing proof of authority to sign for the deceased
            individual or dissolved entity must be provided.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a producer is now a dissolved general partnership or joint
            venture, all members of the general partnership or joint venture at
            the time of dissolution or their duly authorized representatives
            must sign the application for payment.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12384'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1413:A:1413.114
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1413.114
      </num>
      <head>
        Records and inspections.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1413' sect='114' psec='' tq='N'>
              1413.114
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Records and inspections.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any producer receiving DWQP payments, or any other legal entity or
            person who provides information for the purposes of enabling a
            producer to receive a DWQP payment, must:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Maintain any books, records, and accounts supporting the
            information for 3 years following the end of the year during which
            the request for payment was submitted, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Allow authorized representatives of USDA and the U.S. Government
            Accountability Office, during regular business hours, to inspect,
            examine, and make copies of such books or records, and to enter the
            farm and to inspect and verify all applicable acreage in which the
            producer has an interest for the purpose of confirming the accuracy
            of information provided by or for the producer.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             [Reserved]
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>