<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol11'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709
    </extid>
    <num>
      1709
    </num>
    <head>
      ASSISTANCE TO HIGH ENERGY COST COMMUNITIES
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='5' sect='301' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/5/301.html'>
              5 U.S.C. 301
            </subref>
            , 
            <subref title='5' sect='7' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/5/7.html'>
              7
            </subref>
          </aref>
           U.S.C. 901 
          <E T='03'>
            et seq.
          </E>
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            70 FR 5351
          </aref>
          , Feb. 2, 2005, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='13468'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:A:1709.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.1
      </num>
      <head>
        Purpose.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Purpose.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The purpose of the Rural Utilities Service (RUS) Assistance to High
          Energy Cost Rural Communities Program is to help local communities
          meet their energy needs through direct loans and grants for energy
          facilities in qualifying extremely high energy cost communities,
          grants and loans to the Denali Commission for extremely high energy
          cost communities in Alaska, and grants to States to support revolving
          funds to finance more cost effective means of acquiring fuel in
          qualifying communities. This subpart sets forth definitions and
          requirements which are common to all grant and loan programs in this
          part administered by the RUS Electric Program under 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 19 of
          </aref>
           the Rural Electrification Act of 1936, as amended (RE Act) (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='918a' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/918a.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 918a
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ).
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13469'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:A:1709.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.2
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13470'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:A:1709.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Administrator
          </E>
           means the Administrator of the Rural Utilities Service (RUS), United
          States Department of Agriculture (USDA).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Agency
          </E>
           means the Rural Utilities Service (RUS), an agency of the United
          States Department of Agriculture (USDA), or a successor agency.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Census block
          </E>
           means the smallest geographic entity for which the U.S. Census Bureau
          collects and tabulates decennial census information and which are
          defined by boundaries shown on census maps.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Census designated place (CDP)
          </E>
           means a statistical entity recognized by the 
          <PRTPAGE P='65' />
          U.S. Census Bureau comprising a dense concentration of population that
          is not within an incorporated place but is locally identified by a
          name and which has boundaries defined on census maps.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Electric program
          </E>
           means the office within RUS, and its successor organization, that
          administers rural electrification programs authorized by the Rural
          Electrification Act of 1936 (RE Act) (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='901' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/901.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 901
            </subref>
          </aref>
          <E T='03'>
            et seq.
          </E>
          ) and such other programs so identified in USDA regulations.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Extremely high energy costs
          </E>
           means community average residential energy costs that are at least
          275 percent of one or more home energy cost benchmarks identified by
          RUS and based on the latest available information on national average
          residential energy expenditures as reported by the Energy Information
          Administration (EIA) of the United States Department of Energy.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Financial assistance
          </E>
           means a grant, loan, or grant-loan combination issued under this
          part.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Home energy
          </E>
           means any energy source or fuel used by a household for purposes
          other than transportation, including electricity, natural gas, fuel
          oil, kerosene, liquified petroleum gas (propane), other petroleum
          products, wood and other biomass fuels, coal, wind and solar energy.
          Fuels used for subsistence activities in remote rural areas are also
          included.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            High energy cost benchmarks
          </E>
           means the criteria established by RUS for eligibility as an extremely
          high energy cost community. Extremely high energy cost benchmarks are
          calculated as 275 percent of the relevant national average household
          energy benchmarks.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Indian Tribe
          </E>
           means a Federally recognized tribe as defined under 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 4 of
          </aref>
           the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='25' sect='450b' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/25/450b.html'>
              25 U.S.C. 450b
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ) to include “* * * any Indian tribe, band, nation, or other organized
          group or community, including any Alaska Native village or regional or
          village corporation as defined in or established pursuant to the
          Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='43' sect='1601' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/43/1601.html'>
              43 U.S.C. 1601
            </subref>
          </aref>
          <E T='03'>
            et seq.
          </E>
          ), that is recognized as eligible for the special programs and
          services provided by the United States to Indians because of their
          status as Indians.”
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Person
          </E>
           means any natural person, firm, corporation, association, or other
          legal entity, and includes Indian tribes and tribal entities.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State
          </E>
           means any of the several States of the United States, and, where
          provided by law, any Territory of the United States or other area
          authorized to receive the services and programs of the Rural Utilities
          Service or the Rural Electrification Act of 1936, as amended.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Target area
          </E>
           means the geographic area to be served by the grant.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Target community
          </E>
           means the unit or units of local government in which the target area
          is located.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13471'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:A:1709.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Allocation of available funds among programs.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Allocation of available funds among programs.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The Administrator, in his sole discretion, shall allocate available
          funds among the programs administered under this part and determine
          the grant application periods under each program. In making fund
          allocations for each fiscal year, the Administrator may consider the
          amount of available funds, the nature and amount of unfunded grant
          applications and prior awards, Agency resources, Agency priorities,
          and any other pertinent information.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13472'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:A:1709.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.5
      </num>
      <head>
        Determination of energy cost benchmarks.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Determination of energy cost benchmarks.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Administrator shall establish, using the most recent data
            available, and periodically revise, the home energy cost benchmarks
            and the high energy cost benchmarks used to determine community
            eligibility for high energy cost grant and loan programs and the
            Denali Commission high energy cost grants and loans. In setting
            these energy cost benchmarks, the Administrator shall review the
            latest available information on home energy costs published by the
            EIA. High energy cost benchmarks will be set at 275 percent of the
            applicable national average home energy cost benchmark as determined
            by the Administrator from the published EIA data. Eligibility
            benchmarks shall be published in each grant announcement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For use in determining eligibility for High Energy Cost Grants, the
            Administrator may establish benchmarks for national average annual
            household 
            <PRTPAGE P='66' />
            expenditures and for national average household per unit energy
            expenditures for major home energy sources or fuels, including, but
            not limited to, electricity, natural gas, fuel oil, kerosene,
            liquified petroleum gas (propane), other petroleum products, wood
            and other biomass fuels, coal, wind and solar energy.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13473'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:A:1709.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.6
      </num>
      <head>
        Appeals.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Appeals.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          An applicant may appeal a decision by the Assistant Administrator,
          Electric Program rejecting an application for failure to meet
          eligibility requirements. Applicants may not appeal rating panel
          scores or rankings. An appeal must be made, in writing to the
          Administrator, within 10 days after the applicant is notified of the
          determination to reject the application. Appeals must state the basis
          for the appeal and shall be submitted to the Administrator, Rural
          Utilities Service, U.S. Department of Agriculture, 1400 Independence
          Ave., SW., STOP 1500, Washington, DC 20250-1500. Thereafter, the
          Administrator will review the appeal to determine whether to sustain,
          reverse, or modify the original determination. The
          Administrator&apos;s determination shall be final. A written copy of
          the Administrator&apos;s decision will be furnished promptly to the
          applicant.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13474'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:A:1709.7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.7
      </num>
      <head>
        Applicant eligibility.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Applicant eligibility.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          An outstanding judgment obtained against an applicant by the United
          States in a Federal Court (other than in the United States Tax Court),
          which has been recorded, shall cause the applicant to be ineligible to
          receive a grant or loan under this part until the judgment is paid in
          full or otherwise satisfied. RUS financial assistance under this part
          may not be used to satisfy the judgment.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13475'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:A:1709.8
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.8
      </num>
      <head>
        Electronic submission.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.8
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Electronic submission.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Applicants may submit applications and reports electronically if so
          provided in the applicable grant announcement and grant agreements or
          if other regulations provide for electronic submission. Any electronic
          submissions must be in the form prescribed in the applicable grant
          announcement, grant agreement, or regulation.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13476'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:A:1709.9
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.9
      </num>
      <head>
        Grant awards and advance of funds.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.9
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Grant awards and advance of funds.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The grantee must execute a grant agreement that is acceptable to the
          Agency. The grantee must sign and return the grant agreement to the
          Agency, within the time specified, before any grant funds will be
          advanced.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13477'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:A:1709.10
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.10
      </num>
      <head>
        Ineligible grant purposes.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.10
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Ineligible grant purposes.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Grant funds under this part may not be used to:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Pay costs of preparing the application package for funding under
            programs in this part, or for any finders fees or incentives for
            persons or entities assisting in the preparation or submission of an
            application.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Fund political activities;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Pay any judgment or debt owed to the United States; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Pay construction costs of the project incurred prior to the date of
            grant award except as provided herein. Construction work should not
            be started and obligations for such work or materials should not be
            incurred before the grant is approved.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Applicants may request Agency approval for reimbursement of
            pre-award construction obligations if there are compelling reasons
            for proceeding with construction before grant approval. Such
            requests may be approved if the Agency determines that:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Compelling reasons, as determined by the Agency, exist for
            incurring obligations before grant approval;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The obligations will be incurred for authorized grant purposes;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All environmental requirements applicable to the Agency and the
            applicant have been met;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The applicant has the legal authority to incur the obligations at
            the time proposed, and payment of the debts will remove any basis
            for any mechanic&apos;s, material, or other liens that may attach to
            the grant financed property: and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The expenditure is incurred no more than 18 months before the date
            of the Administrator&apos;s approval of the grant award.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Agency may authorize payment of approved pre-award project
            construction obligations at the time of award approval. The
            applicant&apos;s request and the Agency&apos;s authorization 
            <PRTPAGE P='67' />
            for paying such obligations shall be in writing.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13478'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:A:1709.11
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.11
      </num>
      <head>
        Award conditions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.11
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Award conditions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          In addition to all other grant requirements, all approved applicants
          will be required to do the following:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Enter into a grant agreement with the Agency in form and substance
            acceptable to the Agency;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Request advances or reimbursements, as applicable, as provided in
            the grant agreement; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Maintain a financial management system that is acceptable to the
            Agency.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13479'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:A:1709.12
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.12
      </num>
      <head>
        Reporting requirements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='12' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.12
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Reporting requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          To support Agency monitoring of project performance and use of grant
          funds, Grantees shall file periodic reports, required under 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR part 
            <subref title='7' part='3015' tq='N'>
              3015
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , as provided in this part, and the grant agreement as follows:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A financial status report listing project expenditures by budget
            category in such form and at such times as provided in the grant
            agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Project performance reports in such form and at such intervals as
            provided in the grant agreement. The project performance report
            shall compare accomplishments to the objectives stated in the
            proposal and grant agreement. The project performance report should
            identify all completed tasks with supporting documentation. If the
            project schedule as approved in the grant agreement is not being
            met, the report should discuss the problems or delays that may
            affect completion of the project. Objectives for the next reporting
            period should be listed. Compliance with any special condition on
            the use of award funds should be discussed. Reports are due as
            provided in the grant agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A final project performance report with supporting documentation in
            such form and at the time specified in the grant agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Such other reports as the Agency determines are necessary to assure
            effective grant monitoring as part of the grant agreement or the
            grant announcement as a condition of the grant award or advances of
            funds.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13480'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:A:1709.13
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.13
      </num>
      <head>
        Grant administration.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='13' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.13
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Grant administration.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The authority to approve administrative actions is vested in the
          Administrator except as otherwise provided in the RUS delegations of
          authority. Administration of RUS grants is governed by the provisions
          of this subpart and subpart B of this part, the terms of the grant
          agreement and, as applicable, the provisions of 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR parts 
            <subref title='7' part='3015' tq='N'>
              3015, 3016
            </subref>
             and 
            <subref title='7' part='3017' tq='N'>
              3017
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , or their successors.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13481'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:A:1709.14
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.14
      </num>
      <head>
        Inspections.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='14' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.14
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Inspections.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The grantee will permit periodic inspection of the grant project
          operations by a representative of the Agency.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13482'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:A:1709.15
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.15
      </num>
      <head>
        Grant closeout.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='15' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.15
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Grant closeout.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Grant closeout is when all required work is completed, administrative
          actions relating to the completion of work and expenditure of funds
          have been accomplished, the final project report has been submitted
          and found acceptable by RUS and RUS accepts final expenditure
          information. No monitoring action by RUS of the grantee is required
          after grant closeout. However, grantees remain responsible in
          accordance with the terms of the grant agreement for compliance with
          conditions on property acquired or derived through grant funds.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13483'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:A:1709.16
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.16
      </num>
      <head>
        Performance reviews.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='16' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.16
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Performance reviews.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Each grant agreement shall include performance criteria and RUS will
          regularly evaluate the progress and performance of grantee according
          to such criteria. If the grantee does not comply with or does not meet
          the performance criteria set out in the grant agreement, the
          Administrator may require amendment of the grant agreement, or may
          suspend or terminate the grant pursuant to 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR 2015
          </aref>
          , subpart N.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13484'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:A:1709.17
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.17
      </num>
      <head>
        Environmental review.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='17' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.17
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Environmental review.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All grants made under this subpart are subject to the requirements
            of 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1794' tq='N'>
                1794
              </subref>
            </aref>
             or its successor.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Applicants must address environmental aspects of their projects in
            the grant application in sufficient detail to allow the Agency to
            categorize the project for purposes of compliance with environmental
            review requirements. 
            <PRTPAGE P='68' />
            The grant announcement will establish the form and content of the
            environmental information required for the application.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Projects that are selected for grant awards by the Administrator
            will be reviewed by the Agency under 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1794' tq='N'>
                1794
              </subref>
            </aref>
             prior to final award approval. The Agency may require the selected
            applicant to submit additional information, including an
            environmental report, environmental assessment, or environmental
            impact statement, as may be required, concerning the proposed
            project in order to complete the required reviews and to develop any
            project-specific conditions for the final grant agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13485'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:A:1709.18
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.18
      </num>
      <head>
        Civil rights.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='18' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.18
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Civil rights.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          This program will be administered in accordance with applicable
          Federal Civil Rights Law. All grants made under this subpart are
          subject to the requirements of title VI of the Civil Rights Act of
          1964, which prohibits discrimination on the basis of race, color or
          national origin. In addition, all grants made under this subpart are
          subject to the requirements of 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 504 of
          </aref>
           the Rehabilitation Act of 1973, as amended, which prohibits
          discrimination on the basis of disability; the requirements of the Age
          Discrimination Act of 1975, which prohibits discrimination on the
          basis of age; and title III of the Americans with Disabilities Act,
          which prohibits discrimination on the basis of disability by private
          entities in places of public accommodations. Grantees are required to
          comply with certain regulations on nondiscrimination in program
          services and benefits and on equal employment opportunity including 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR parts 
            <subref title='7' part='15' tq='N'>
              15
            </subref>
             and 
            <subref title='7' part='15b' tq='N'>
              15b
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; and 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            45 CFR part 
            <subref title='45' part='90' tq='N'>
              90
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , as applicable.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13486'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:A:1709.19
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.19
      </num>
      <head>
        Other USDA regulations.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='19' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.19
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Other USDA regulations.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The grant programs under this part are subject to the provisions of
          other departmental regulations, including but not limited to the
          following departmental regulations, or their successors, as
          applicable:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3015' tq='N'>
                3015
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , Uniform Federal Assistance Regulations;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3016' tq='N'>
                3016
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , Uniform Administrative Requirements for Grants and Cooperative
            Agreements to State and Local Governments;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3017' tq='N'>
                3017
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , Governmentwide Debarment and Suspension (Nonprocurement) and
            Governmentwide Requirements for Drug-Free Workplace (Grants);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3018' tq='N'>
                3018
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , New Restrictions on Lobbying;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3019' tq='N'>
                3019
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , Uniform Administrative Requirements for Grants and Agreements with
            Institutions of Higher Education, Hospitals and Other Non-profit
            Organizations; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3052' tq='N'>
                3052
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , Audits of States, Local Governments and Non-profit Organizations.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13487'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:A:1709.20
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.20
      </num>
      <head>
        Member delegate clause.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='20' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.20
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Member delegate clause.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Each grant agreement under this part shall provide that no member of
          Congress shall be admitted to any share or part of a grant program or
          any benefit that may arise there from, but this provision shall not be
          construed to bar as a contractor under a grant a publicly held
          corporation whose ownership might include a member of Congress.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13488'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:A:1709.21
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.21
      </num>
      <head>
        Audit requirements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='21' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.21
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Audit requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The grantee shall provide the Agency with an audit for each year,
          beginning with the year in which a portion of the financial assistance
          is expended, in accordance with the following:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the grantee is a for-profit entity, an RUS Electric or
            Telecommunication borrower or any other entity not covered by
            paragraph (b) of this section, the recipient shall provide an
            independent audit report in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1773' tq='N'>
                1773
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , “Policy on Audits of RUS Borrowers” and the grant agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the grantee is a State or local government, or a non-profit
            corporation (other than an RUS Electric or Telecommunication
            Borrower), the recipient shall provide an audit in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3052' tq='N'>
                3052
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13489'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:A:1709.22
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.22
      </num>
      <head>
        Project changes.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='22' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.22
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Project changes.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The Grantee shall obtain prior written approval from the Agency for
          any change to the scope or objectives of the approved grant project.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13490'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:A:1709.23-1709.99
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1709.23-1709.99
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='69' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='23-1709' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.23-1709
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .99
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13491'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:A:1709.100
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.100
      </num>
      <head>
        OMB control number.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='100' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.100
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          OMB control number.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The information collection requirements in this part are approved by
          the Office of Management and Budget and assigned OMB control number
          0572-0136.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13492'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:B:1709.101
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.101
      </num>
      <head>
        Purpose.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='101' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.101
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Purpose.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          This subpart establishes policies and procedures for the Rural
          Utilities Service (RUS) High Energy Cost Grant Program under 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 19(a)(1) of
          </aref>
           the Rural Electrification Act of 1936, as amended (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='918a' note='' psec='#a_1' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/918a.html#a_1'>
              7 U.S.C. 918a(a)(1)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ). The purpose of this grant program is to assure access to adequate
          and reliable energy services for persons in extremely high energy cost
          communities by providing financial assistance to acquire, construct,
          extend, upgrade, and otherwise improve energy generation,
          transmission, or distribution facilities serving the community.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13493'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:B:1709.102
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.102
      </num>
      <head>
        Policy.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='102' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.102
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Policy.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All high energy cost grants will be awarded competitively subject
            to the limited exceptions in 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR 
              <subref title='7' part='3015' sect='158' psec='#d' tq='N'>
                3015.158(d)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             RUS may give priority consideration to projects that benefit
            smaller rural communities, communities experiencing economic
            hardship, projects that extend service to households that lack
            reliable centralized or commercial energy services, and projects
            that correct imminent hazards to public safety, welfare, the
            environment or critical community energy facilities. RUS may also
            give priority to projects that are coordinated with State rural
            development initiatives or that serve a Federally-identified
            Empowerment Zone or Enterprise Community (EZ/EC) or a
            USDA-identified “Champion Community.” Priority consideration will be
            provided through the award of additional points under the project
            selection criteria as specified in the grant announcement.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13494'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:B:1709.103-1709.105
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1709.103-1709.105
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='103-1709' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.103-1709
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .105
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13495'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:B:1709.106
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.106
      </num>
      <head>
        Eligible applicants.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='106' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.106
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Eligible applicants.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Eligible applicants for grants to fund projects serving eligible
            extremely high energy cost communities include Persons, States,
            political subdivisions of States, and other entities organized under
            the laws of States.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Eligible applicants may be for-profit or non-profit business
            entities including but not limited to corporations, associations,
            partnerships, limited liability partnerships (LLPs), cooperatives,
            trusts, and sole proprietorships.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Eligible government applicants include State and local governments,
            and agencies and instrumentalities of States and local governments.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Indian tribes, other tribal entities, and Alaska Native
            Corporations are eligible applicants.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Individuals are also eligible applicants under this program,
            however the proposed grant project must provide community benefits
            and not be for the sole benefit of the individual applicant or an
            individual household.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             As a condition of eligibility, the applicant must demonstrate the
            capacity:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             to enter into a binding grant agreement with the Federal Government
            at the time of the award approval; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             to carry out the proposed grant project according to its terms.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13496'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:B:1709.107
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.107
      </num>
      <head>
        Eligible communities.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='107' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.107
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Eligible communities.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An eligible community under this program is one in which the
            average home energy costs exceed 275 percent of the national average
            under one or more high energy cost benchmarks established by RUS
            based on the latest available residential energy information from
            the Energy Information Administration (EIA) of the United States
            Department of Energy. RUS will update the national and high energy
            cost community benchmarks periodically to incorporate any changes in
            national home energy costs reported by EIA. RUS will publish the
            high energy cost community benchmark criteria in the grant
            announcement. Community eligibility will be determined by RUS at the
            
            <PRTPAGE P='70' />
            time of application based on the criteria published in the
            applicable grant announcement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Application must include information demonstrating that each
            community in the grant&apos;s proposed target area exceeds one or
            more of the RUS high energy cost community benchmarks to be eligible
            for assistance under this program. The smallest area that may be
            designated as a target area is a 2000 Census block
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The target community may include an extremely high cost to serve
            portion of a larger service area that does not otherwise meet the
            criteria, provided that the applicant can establish that the costs
            to serve the smaller target area exceed the benchmark.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In determining the community energy costs, applicants may include
            additional revenue sources that lower the rates or out of pocket
            consumer energy costs such as rate averaging, and other Federal,
            State, or private cost contributions or subsidies.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The applicant may propose a project that will serve high energy
            cost communities across a State or region, but where individual
            project beneficiaries will be selected at a later time. In such
            cases, to establish eligibility, the applicant must provide
            sufficient information in the application to determine that the
            proposed target area includes eligible high energy cost communities
            and proposed selection criteria to assure that grant funds are used
            to serve eligible communities.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13497'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:B:1709.108
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.108
      </num>
      <head>
        Supporting data for determining community eligibility.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='108' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.108
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Supporting data for determining community eligibility.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The application shall include the following:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Documentation of energy costs.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Documents or references to published or other sources for
            information or data on home energy expenditures or equivalent
            measures used to support eligibility, or where such information is
            unavailable or does not adequately reflect the actual cost of
            average home energy use in a local community, reasonable estimates
            of commercial energy costs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Served areas.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A comparison of the historical residential energy cost or
            expenditure information for the local commercial energy provider(s)
            serving the target community or target area with the benchmark
            criteria published by the Agency.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Engineering estimates.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Estimates based on engineering standards may be used in lieu of
            historical residential energy costs or expenditure information under
            the following circumstances:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Where historical community energy cost data are unavailable
            (unserved areas), incomplete or otherwise inadequate;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Where the target area is not connected to central station electric
            service to a degree comparable with other residential customers in
            the State or region.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Where historic energy costs do not reflect the costs of providing a
            necessary upgrade or replacement of energy infrastructure that would
            have the effect of raising costs above one or more of the Agency
            benchmarks.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Independent Agency review.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Information to support high energy cost eligibility is subject to
            independent review by the Agency. The Agency may reject applications
            that are not based on credible data sources or sound engineering
            estimates.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13498'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:B:1709.109
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.109
      </num>
      <head>
        Eligible projects.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='109' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.109
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Eligible projects.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Eligible projects are those that acquire, construct, extend, repair,
          upgrade or otherwise improve energy generation, transmission or
          distribution facilities serving communities with extremely high energy
          costs. All energy generation, transmission and distribution facilities
          and equipment used to provide or improve electricity, natural gas,
          home heating fuels, and other energy services to eligible communities
          are eligible. Projects providing or improving service to communities
          with extremely high energy costs through on-grid and off-grid
          renewable energy technologies, energy efficiency, and energy
          conservation projects and services are eligible. A grant project is
          eligible if it improves, or maintains energy services, or reduces the
          costs of providing energy services to eligible communities. Examples
          of eligible activities include, but are not limited to, the
          acquisition, construction, replacement, repair, or improvement of:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Electric generation, transmission, and distribution facilities,
            equipment, 
            <PRTPAGE P='71' />
            and services serving the eligible community;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Natural gas distribution or storage facilities and associated
            equipment and activities serving the eligible community;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Petroleum product storage and handling facilities serving
            residential or community use.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Renewable energy facilities used for on-grid or off-grid electric
            power generation, water or space heating, or process heating and
            power for the eligible community;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Backup up or emergency power generation or energy storage
            equipment, including distributed generation, to serve the eligible
            community; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Implementation of cost-effective energy efficiency, energy
            conservation measures that are part of the implementation of a
            coordinated demand management or energy conservation program for the
            eligible community, such as, for example, weatherization of
            residences and community facilities, or acquisition and installation
            of energy-efficient or energy saving appliances and devices .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13499'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:B:1709.110
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.110
      </num>
      <head>
        Use of grant funds.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='110' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.110
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Use of grant funds.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Project development costs.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Grants may be used to fund the costs and activities associated with
            the development of an eligible energy project. RUS will in no case
            approve the use of grant funds to be used solely or primarily for
            project development costs. Eligible project development costs must
            be reasonable and directly related to the project and may include
            the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Costs of conducting, or hiring a qualified consultant to conduct, a
            feasibility analysis of the proposed project to help establish the
            financial and technical sustainability of the project, provided that
            such costs do not exceed more than 10 percent of total project
            costs;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Design and engineering costs, including costs of environmental and
            cultural surveys and consulting services necessary to the project
            and associated environmental review, siting and permit approvals;
            and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Fees for legal and other professional services directly related to
            the project.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Construction costs.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Grant funds may be used for the reasonable costs of construction
            activities, including initial construction, installation, expansion,
            extension, repair, upgrades, and related activities, including the
            rental or lease of necessary equipment, to provide or improve energy
            generation, transmission, or distribution facilities or services;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Acquisitions and purchase.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Grant funds may be used for the acquisition of property, equipment,
            and materials, including the purchase of equipment, and materials,
            the acquisition or leasing of real or personal property, equipment,
            and vehicles associated with and necessary for project development,
            construction, and operation. Grant funds may be used for the
            acquisition of new or existing facilities or systems where such
            action is a cost-effective means to extend or maintain service to an
            eligible community or reduces the costs of such service for the
            primary benefit of community residents.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Grantee cost contributions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Grant funds may be applied as matching funds or cost contributions
            under Federal or other programs where the terms of those programs so
            allow use of other Federal funds.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13500'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:B:1709.111
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.111
      </num>
      <head>
        Limitations on use of grant funds.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='111' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.111
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Limitations on use of grant funds.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Planning and administrative costs.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Not more than 4 percent of each grant award may be used for the
            planning and administrative expenses of the applicant that are
            unrelated to the grant project.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Unproven technology.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Only projects that utilize technology with a proven operating
            history, and for which there is an established industry for the
            design, installation, and service (including spare parts) of the
            equipment, are eligible for funding. Energy projects utilizing
            experimental, developmental, or prototype technologies or technology
            demonstrations are not eligible for grant funds. The determination
            by RUS that a project relies on unproven technology shall be final.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13501'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:B:1709.112
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.112
      </num>
      <head>
        Ineligible grant purposes.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='112' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.112
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Ineligible grant purposes.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Grant funds may not be used for the costs of preparing the grant
            application, finders fees, fuel purchases, 
            <PRTPAGE P='72' />
            routine maintenance or other operating costs, or purchase of
            equipment, structures or real property not directly associated with
            providing energy services in the target community, or, except as
            provided in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='11' psec='#d' tq='N'>
                1709.11(d)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , project construction costs incurred prior to the date of the grant
            award.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In general, grant funds may not be used to support projects that
            primarily benefit areas outside of eligible target communities.
            However, grant funds may be used to finance an eligible target
            community&apos;s proportionate share of a larger energy project.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Grant funds may not be used to refinance or repay the
            applicant&apos;s outstanding loans or loan guarantees under the
            Rural Electrification Act of 1936, as amended.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13502'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:B:1709.113
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.113
      </num>
      <head>
        Limitations on grant awards.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='113' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.113
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Limitations on grant awards.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Administrator may establish minimum or maximum amount of funds
            that may be awarded in a single grant application within in any
            grant cycle in order to distribute available grant funds as broadly
            as possible. If the Administrator elects to impose a minimum or
            maximum grant amount, the limitations will be published in the grant
            announcement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Administrator may restrict eligible applicants to a single
            award of grant funds or to a monetary cap on grant awards within a
            grant cycle in order to assure that the available grant funds are
            distributed as broadly as possible. If the Administrator elects to
            impose a limit or cap on grant awards, the terms will be established
            in the grant announcement.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13503'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:B:1709.114
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.114
      </num>
      <head>
        Application process.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='114' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.114
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Application process.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The RUS will request applications for high energy cost grants on a
          competitive basis by publication of a grant announcement as a Notice
          of Funds Availability (NOFA) or Notice of Funding Opportunity. The
          grant announcement will establish the amount of funds available, the
          application package contents and additional requirements, the
          availability of application materials, high energy cost community
          eligibility benchmarks, selection criteria and weights, priority
          considerations, and deadlines and procedures for submitting
          applications.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13504'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:B:1709.115
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.115
      </num>
      <head>
        Availability of application materials.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='115' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.115
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Availability of application materials.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Application materials, including copies of the grant announcement and
          all required forms and certifications will be available by request
          from the Agency and by such other means as the Agency may determine.
          In addition, the Agency may make available an application guide and
          other materials that may be of assistance to prospective applicants.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13505'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:B:1709.116
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.116
      </num>
      <head>
        Application package.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='116' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.116
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Application package.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The requirements for the application package will be established in
          the grant announcement. A complete application package will consist of
          the standard application for federal assistance (SF-424 series), as
          applicable, a narrative project proposal prepared in accordance with
          the grant announcement, an RUS environmental profile, and such other
          supporting documentation, forms, and certifications as required in the
          grant announcement and this part.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13506'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:B:1709.117
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.117
      </num>
      <head>
        Application requirements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='117' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.117
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Application requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Required forms.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The forms required for application and where to obtain them will be
            specified in the announcement. All required forms must be completed,
            signed and submitted by a person authorized to submit the proposal
            on behalf of the applicant. For applications and forms that are
            submitted electronically, the application must be authenticated as
            provided in the grant announcement. In the case of grant
            applications submitted electronically, the applicant may be required
            to provide signed originals of required forms prior to and as a
            condition of the grant award.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Narrative proposal.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each application must include a narrative proposal describing the
            proposed project and addressing eligibility and selection criteria.
            The grant announcement will specify the contents, order, and format
            for the narrative proposal. The proposal must include all the
            required elements identified in this subsection. The grant
            announcement may establish additional required elements that 
            <PRTPAGE P='73' />
            must be addressed in the narrative project proposal.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Executive summary.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A summary of the proposal should briefly describe the project
            including target community, goals, tasks to be completed and other
            relevant information that provides a general overview of the
            project. The applicant must clearly state the amount of grant funds
            requested and identify any priority ratings for which the applicant
            believes it is qualified.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Applicant eligibility.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The narrative and supporting documentation must describe the
            applicant and establish its eligibility.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Community eligibility.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This section must describe the target area and communities to be
            served by the project and demonstrate eligibility. The applicant
            must clearly identify the:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Location and population of the areas to be served by the project;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Population of the local government division to which they belong;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Identity of local energy providers; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Sources of the high energy cost data and estimates used.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Project eligibility.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The narrative must describe the proposed project in sufficient
            detail to establish that it is an eligible project.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Project description.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The project description must:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_5_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Describe the project design, materials, and equipment in sufficient
            detail to support a finding of technical feasibility;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_5_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Identify the major tasks to be performed and a proposed timeline
            for completion of each task; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_5_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Identify the location of the project target area and the eligible
            extremely high energy cost communities to be served.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Project management.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The applicant must describe how and by whom the project will be
            managed during construction and operation. The description should
            address the applicant&apos;s organizational structure, key project
            personnel and the degree to which full time employees, affiliated
            entities or contractors will be utilized. The applicant must
            describe the identities, legal relationship, qualifications and
            experience of those persons that will perform project management
            functions. If the applicant proposes to use the equipment or design,
            construction and other services from non-affiliated entities, the
            applicant must describe how it plans to contract for such equipment
            or services.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Budget.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The budget narrative must present a detailed breakdown of all
            estimated costs and allocate these costs among the listed tasks in
            the work plan. All project costs, not just grant funds, must be
            accounted for in the budget. A pro forma operating budget for the
            first year of operations must also be included. The detailed budget
            description must be accompanied by SF-424A, “Budget
            Information—Non-Construction Programs,” or SF-424C “Budget
            Information—Construction Programs,” as applicable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Project goals and objectives.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The applicant must identify unambiguous measures for expected cost
            reduction, efficiencies or other improvements and the degree to
            which the incremental benefit will be enjoyed by residents of the
            eligible community. The description should specifically address how
            the project will provide or improve energy generation, transmission
            or distribution services in the target area. The project objectives
            and proposed evaluation measures will be the basis for project
            performance measures in the grant agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Performance measures.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The application must include specific criteria for measuring
            project performance. These proposed criteria will be used in
            establishing performance measures incorporated in the grant
            agreement in the event the proposal receives funding under this
            subpart. These suggested criteria are not binding on the Agency.
            Appropriate measures of project performance include expected
            reductions in home energy costs, avoided cost increases, enhanced
            reliability, new households served, or economic and social benefits
            from improvements in energy services.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Proposal evaluation and selection criteria.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The application must address individually and in narrative form
            each of the proposal evaluation and selection criteria referenced in
            the grant announcement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_11'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (11)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Rural development initiatives.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The proposal should describe whether and 
            <PRTPAGE P='74' />
            how the proposed project will support any State rural development
            initiatives. If the project is in support of a rural development
            initiative, the application should include confirming documentation
            from the appropriate rural development agency. The application must
            identify the extent to which the project is dependent upon or tied
            to other rural development initiatives, funding and approvals.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_12'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (12)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Environmental profile.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The application must include information about project
            characteristics and site specific conditions that may involve
            environmental, historic preservation and other resource issues. This
            information must be presented in sufficient detail so as to
            facilitate the Agency&apos;s identification of projects that may
            require additional environmental review under 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1794' tq='N'>
                1794
              </subref>
            </aref>
             before a grant award can be approved. The format and requirements
            for the environmental profile will be established in the grant
            announcement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_13'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (13)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Regulatory and other required project approvals.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The applicant must identify all regulatory or other approvals
            required by other Federal, State, local, tribal or private entities
            (including conditions precedent to financing) that are necessary to
            carry out the proposed project and an estimated schedule for
            obtaining the necessary permits and approvals.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13507'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:B:1709.118
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.118
      </num>
      <head>
        Submission of applications.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='118' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.118
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Submission of applications.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Unless otherwise provided in the grant announcement, a complete
          original application package and two copies must be submitted by the
          application deadline to RUS at the address specified in the applicable
          announcement. Instructions for submittal of applications
          electronically will be established in the grant announcement.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13508'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:B:1709.119
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.119
      </num>
      <head>
        Review of applications.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='119' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.119
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Review of applications.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             RUS will review each application package received to determine
            whether the applicant is eligible and whether the application is
            timely, complete, and responsive to the requirements set forth in
            the grant announcement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             RUS may, at its discretion, contact the applicant to clarify or
            supplement information in the application needed to determine
            eligibility, identifying information, and grant requests to allow
            for informed review. Failure of the applicant to provide such
            information in response to a written request by the Agency within
            the time frame established by the Agency may result in rejection of
            the application.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             After consideration of the information submitted, the Assistant
            Administrator, Electric Program will determine whether an applicant
            or project is eligible and whether an application is timely,
            complete, and responsive to the grant announcement and shall notify
            the applicant in writing. The Assistant Administrator&apos;s
            decision on eligibility may be appealed to the Administrator.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13509'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:B:1709.120
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.120
      </num>
      <head>
        Evaluation of applications.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='120' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.120
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Evaluation of applications.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Agency will establish one or more rating panels to review and
            rate the grant applications. The panels may include persons not
            employed by the Agency.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All timely and complete applications that meet the eligibility
            requirements will be referred to the rating panel. The rating panel
            will evaluate and rate all referred applications according to the
            evaluation criteria and weights established in the grant
            announcement. Panel members may make recommendations for conditions
            on grant awards to promote successful performance of the grant or to
            assure compliance with other Federal requirements.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             After the rating panel has evaluated and scored all proposals, in
            accordance with the point allocation specified in the grant
            announcement, the panel will prepare a list of all applications in
            rank order, together with funding level recommendations and
            recommendations for conditions, if any.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The list of ranked projects and rating panel recommendations will
            be forwarded to the Administrator for review and selection.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13510'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:B:1709.121
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.121
      </num>
      <head>
        Administrator&apos;s review and selection of grant awards.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='121' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.121
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Administrator&apos;s review and selection of grant awards.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The final decision to make an award is at the discretion of the
            Administrator. The Administrator shall make any selections of
            finalists for grant awards after consideration of the 
            <PRTPAGE P='75' />
            applications, the rankings, comments, and recommendations of the
            rating panel, and other pertinent information.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Based on consideration of the application materials, ranking panel
            ratings, comments, and recommendations, and other pertinent
            information, the Administrator may elect to award less than the full
            amount of grant requested by an applicant. Applicants will be
            notified of an offer of a reduced or partial award. If an applicant
            does not accept the Administrator&apos;s offer of a reduced or
            partial award, the Administrator may reject the application and
            offer an award to the next highest ranking project.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The projects selected by the Administrator will be funded in rank
            order to the extent of available funds.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the event an insufficient number of eligible applications are
            received in response to a published grant announcement and selected
            for funding to exhaust the funds available, the Administrator
            reserves the discretion to reopen the application period and to
            accept additional applications for consideration under the terms of
            the grant announcement. A notice regarding the reopening of an
            application period will be published in the 
            <E T='04'>
              Federal Register
            </E>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13511'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:B:1709.122
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.122
      </num>
      <head>
        Consideration of eligible grant applications under later grant
        announcements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='122' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.122
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Consideration of eligible grant applications under later grant
          announcements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          At the discretion of the Administrator, the grant announcement may
          provide that all eligible but unfunded proposals submitted under
          preceding competitive grant announcements may also be considered for
          funding. This option is provided to reduce the burden on applicants
          and the Agency. The grant announcement shall indicate how applicants
          may request reconsideration of previously submitted, but unfunded,
          applications and how they may supplement their applications.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13512'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:B:1709.123
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.123
      </num>
      <head>
        Evaluation criteria and weights.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='123' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.123
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Evaluation criteria and weights.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Establishing evaluation criteria and weights.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The grant announcement will establish the evaluation criteria and
            weights to be used in ranking the grant proposals submitted. Unless
            supplemented in the grant announcement, the criteria listed in this
            section will be used to evaluate proposals submitted under this
            program. Additional criteria may be included in the grant
            announcement. In establishing evaluation criteria and weights, the
            total points that may be awarded for project design and technical
            merit criteria shall not be less than 65 percent of the total
            available points, and the total points awarded for priority criteria
            shall not be more than 35 percent of the total available points. The
            distribution of points to be awarded per criterion will be
            identified in the grant announcement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Project design and technical merit.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In reviewing the grant proposal&apos;s project design and technical
            merit, reviewers will consider the soundness of the applicant&apos;s
            approach, the project&apos;s technical and financial feasibility,
            the adequacy of financial and other resources, the capabilities and
            experience of the applicant and its project management team, the
            project goals, and identified community needs and benefits. Points
            will be awarded under the following project elements:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Comprehensiveness and feasibility.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Reviewers will assess the technical and economic feasibility of the
            project and how well its goals and objectives address the challenges
            of the eligible communities. The panel will review the proposed
            design, construction, equipment and materials for the proposed
            energy facilities to determine technical feasibility. Reviewers may
            propose additional conditions on the grant award to assure that the
            project is technically sound. Budgets will be reviewed for
            completeness and the strength of non-Federal funding commitments.
            Points may not be awarded unless sufficient detail is provided to
            determine whether or not funds are being used for qualified
            purposes. Reviewers will consider the adequacy of the
            applicant&apos;s budget and resources to carry out the project as
            proposed. Reviewers will also evaluate how the applicant proposes to
            manage available resources such as grant funds, income generated
            from the facilities and any other financing sources to maintain and
            operate a financially viable project once the grant period has
            ended. Reviewers must make a finding of operational sustainability
            for any points to 
            <PRTPAGE P='76' />
            be awarded. Projects for which future grant funding is likely to be
            required in order to assure ongoing operations will not receive any
            points.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Demonstrated experience.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Reviewers will consider whether the applicant or its project team
            have demonstrated experience in successfully administering and
            carrying out projects that are comparable to that proposed in the
            application. The reviewers may assign a higher point score to
            proposals that develop the internal capacity to provide or improve
            energy services in the eligible communities over other proposals
            that rely extensively on temporary outside contractors.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Community needs.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Reviewers will consider the applicant&apos;s assessment of
            community energy needs to be addressed by the proposed project as
            well as the severity of physical and economic challenges affecting
            the target communities. In determining whether one proposal should
            receive more points than another under this criterion, reviewers
            will consider the relative burdens placed on the communities and
            individual households by extremely high energy costs, the hardships
            created by limited access to reliable and affordable energy services
            and the availability of other resources to support or supplement the
            proposed grant funding.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Project evaluation and performance measures.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Reviewers will consider the applicant&apos;s suggested project
            evaluation and performance criteria. Reviewers may award higher
            points to criteria that are quantifiable, directly relevant to
            project goals, and reflect serious consideration than to more
            subjective performance criteria that do not incorporate variables
            that reflect a reduction in energy cost or improvement in service.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Coordination with rural development initiatives.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Proposals that include documentation confirming coordination with
            State rural development initiatives may be credited points for this
            criterion.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Priority considerations.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subject to the limitation in paragraph (a) of this section,
            evaluation points may also be awarded for projects that advance
            identified priority interests identified in the grant announcement
            to assist the Agency in selecting among competing projects when the
            amount of funding requests exceed available funds. The grant
            announcement may incorporate all or some of the priority criteria
            listed below, and as discussed in paragraph (a) of this section, the
            grant announcement may supplement these criteria. The announcement
            will also specify the points that will be awarded to qualifying
            applications under these priority criteria.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Community economic hardship.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Economic hardship points may be awarded where the median household
            income for the target community is significantly below the State
            average or where the target community suffers from economic
            conditions that severely constrain its ability to provide or improve
            energy facilities serving the community. Applicants must describe in
            detail and document conditions creating severe community economic
            hardship in the proposal.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Rurality.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Priority consideration may be given to proposals that serve smaller
            rural communities. Applications will be scored based on the
            population of the largest incorporated cities, towns or villages or
            census designated places included within the grant&apos;s proposed
            target area as determined using the latest available population
            figures from the U.S. Census Bureau.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Unserved energy needs.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Points may be awarded to projects that extend or improve electric
            or other energy services to eligible communities or areas of
            eligible communities that do not have reliable centralized or
            commercial service.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Imminent hazard.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Additional points may be awarded for projects that correct a
            condition posing an imminent hazard to public safety, public
            welfare, the environment, or to a critical community or residential
            energy facility in immediate danger of failure because of a
            deteriorated condition, capacity limitation, or damage from a
            natural disaster or accident.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Cost sharing.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Projects that evidence significant commitments of funds,
            contributed property, equipment, or other in kind support for the
            project may be awarded additional 
            <PRTPAGE P='77' />
            points for this criterion where the aggregate value of these
            contributions exceed ten percent of total eligible project costs.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13513'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:B:1709.124
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.124
      </num>
      <head>
        Grant award procedures.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='124' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.124
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Grant award procedures.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Notification of applicants.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Agency will notify all applicants in writing whether they have
            been selected for a grant award. Applicants that have been selected
            as finalists for a competitive grant award will be notified in
            writing of their selection and advised that the Agency may request
            additional information in order to complete the required
            environmental review under 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR 1794
            </aref>
             and to meet other pre-award conditions.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Letter of conditions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Agency will notify each applicant selected as a finalist in
            writing setting out the amount of grant funds and the terms and
            conditions under which the grant will be made and requesting that
            the applicant indicate in writing its intent to accept these
            conditions.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Applicant&apos;s intent to meet conditions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon reviewing the conditions and requirements in the letter of
            conditions, the selected applicant must notify the agency in writing
            within the time period indicated, of its acceptance of the
            conditions, or if the proposed certain conditions cannot be met, the
            applicant must so advise the Agency and may propose alternate
            conditions. The Agency must concur with any changes proposed to the
            letter of conditions by the applicant before the application will be
            further processed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Grant agreement.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Agency and the grantee must sign a grant agreement acceptable
            to the Agency prior to the advance of funds.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13514'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:B:1709.125-1709.200
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1709.125-1709.200
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='125-1709' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.125-1709
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .200
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13515'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:C:1709.201
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.201
      </num>
      <head>
        Purpose.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='201' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.201
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Purpose.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          This subpart establishes policies and procedures for the Rural
          Utilities Service (RUS) State Bulk Fuel Revolving Fund Grants. The
          purpose of this grant program is to assist State entities in
          establishing and supporting a revolving fund to provide a more
          cost-effective means of purchasing fuel for communities where the fuel
          cannot be shipped by means of surface transportation.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13516'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:C:1709.202
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.202
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='202' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.202
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13517'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:C:1709.203
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.203
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='203' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.203
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          As used in this subpart, the following definitions apply:
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Eligible area
          </E>
           means any area that is primarily dependent on delivery of fuel by
          water or air for a significant part of the year and where fuel cannot
          be shipped routinely by means of surface transportation either because
          of absolute physical constraints or because surface transportation is
          not practical or is prohibitively expensive.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Fuel means
          </E>
           oil, diesel fuel, gasoline and other petroleum products, coal, and
          any other material that can be burned to make energy.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State entity
          </E>
           means a department, agency, or instrumentality of any State.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Surface transportation
          </E>
           means transportation by road, rail or pipeline.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13518'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:C:1709.204-1709.206
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1709.204-1709.206
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='204-1709' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.204-1709
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .206
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13519'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:C:1709.207
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.207
      </num>
      <head>
        Eligible applicants.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='207' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.207
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Eligible applicants.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Eligible applicants are restricted to State entities in existence as
          of November 9, 2000. Eligible State entities may partner with other
          entities, including other government agencies, in carrying out the
          programs funded by this program. Each applicant must demonstrate that
          it has the authority to enter into a binding agreement with the
          Federal Government to carry out the grant activities.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13520'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:C:1709.208
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.208
      </num>
      <head>
        Use of grant funds.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='208' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.208
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Use of grant funds.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Grant funds must be used to establish and support a revolving loan
          fund that facilitates cost effective fuel purchases for persons,
          communities, and businesses in eligible areas. Where a recipient State
          entity&apos;s existing program is authorized to fund multiple
          purposes, grant funds may only be used to the extent the recipient
          fund finances eligible activities.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13521'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:C:1709.209
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.209
      </num>
      <head>
        Limitations on use of grant funds.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='209' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.209
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Limitations on use of grant funds.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Not more than 4 percent of the grant award may be used for the
          planning 
          <PRTPAGE P='78' />
          and administrative expenses of the grantee.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13522'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:C:1709.210
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.210
      </num>
      <head>
        Application process.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='210' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.210
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Application process.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Applications.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Agency will solicit applications on a competitive basis by
            publication of a grant announcement establishing the amount of funds
            available, the maximum grant award, the required application
            materials and where to obtain them, the evaluation and selection
            criteria and weights, and application deadlines. Unless otherwise
            specified in the announcement, applicants must file an original
            application package and two copies. Where provided in the grant
            announcement, applicants may submit electronic applications.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Required forms.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The grant application will use the Standard Application for Federal
            Assistance (SF-424 series or its successor) and other forms as
            provided in the grant announcement. The required forms must be
            completed, signed and submitted by a person authorized to submit the
            proposal on behalf of the applicants. Where provided in the grant
            announcement, applicants may file electronic versions of the forms
            in compliance with the instructions in the grant announcement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Narrative proposal and required elements.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each grant application must include a narrative proposal describing
            the project and addressing the following elements. The form,
            contents, and order of the narrative proposal will be specified in
            the grant announcement. Additional elements may be published in the
            applicable grant announcement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Executive summary.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This summary of the proposal must identify the State entity
            applying for the grant and the key agency contact information
            (telephone and fax numbers, mailing address and e-mail address). The
            applicant must clearly state the amount requested in this section.
            It should briefly describe the program, including the estimated
            number of potential beneficiaries in eligible areas, their estimated
            fuel needs, the projects and activities to be financed through the
            revolving fund and how the projects and activities will improve the
            cost effectiveness of fuel procured.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Applicant eligibility.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The application must establish that the applicant is a State entity
            that was in existence as of November 9, 2000, and has the legal
            authority to enter into a financial assistance relationship with the
            Federal Government to carry out the grant activities.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Assessment of needs and potential beneficiaries.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The application must provide estimates of the number, location and
            population of potentially eligible areas in the State and their
            estimated fuel needs and costs. The section must also describe the
            criteria used to identify eligible areas, including the
            characteristics that make fuel deliveries by surface transport
            impossible or impracticable. The description of beneficiary
            communities should provide a detailed breakdown of the density
            profile of the area to be served by eligible projects. Indicate to
            what extent persons in eligible areas live outside of communities of
            2,500 persons or more, communities of 5,000 or more or outside of
            communities of 20,000 or more. All population estimates should be
            based on Census Bureau data where available. All representations
            should be supported with exhibits such as maps, summary tables and
            references to official information sources.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Project description.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The application must:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_4_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Describe the legal structure and staffing of the revolving fund
            proposal for fuel purchase support.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_4_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Identify the objectives of the project, the proposed criteria for
            establishing project funding eligibility and how the project is to
            be staffed, managed and financed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_4_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Describe how the potential beneficiaries will be informed of the
            availability of revolving fund benefits to them.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_4_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Explain how the proposed revolving fund program will help provide a
            more cost-effective means of meeting fuel supply needs in eligible
            areas, encourage the adoption of financially sustainable energy
            practices, the adequate planning and investment in bulk fuel
            facility operations and maintenance and cost-effective investments
            in energy efficiency.
            <PRTPAGE P='79' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_4_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the revolving fund program is not yet operational, a proposed
            implementation schedule and milestones should be provided.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Demonstrated experience.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The application shall describe past accomplishments and experiences
            that are relevant to determine whether the applicant is capable of
            administering the grant project.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Budget.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The application must include a pro forma operating budget for the
            proposed fund and a description of all funding sources. The level of
            detail must be sufficient for reviewers to determine that grant
            funds will be used only for eligible purposes and to determine the
            extent to which the program is entirely dependent on grant funding
            or whether it has financial support from the State or other sources.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Performance measures and project evaluation.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The application must provide unambiguous and quantifiable measures
            that will be used to evaluate the success and cost-effectiveness of
            the revolving fund in assuring adequate fuel supplies for eligible
            communities and for assessing the fuel supply projects financed. The
            grant announcement may establish additional required elements that
            must be addressed in the narrative proposal of the application
            package.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13523'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:C:1709.211
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.211
      </num>
      <head>
        Submission of applications.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='211' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.211
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Submission of applications.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Completed applications must be submitted to RUS at the address
          specified in the grant announcement on or before the deadline
          specified in the grant announcement. Instructions for submittal of
          applications electronically will be established in the grant
          announcement. Late applications will be rejected.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13524'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:C:1709.212
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.212
      </num>
      <head>
        Application review.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='212' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.212
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Application review.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The Agency will review all applications to determine whether the
          applicant is eligible and whether the application is timely, complete
          and sufficiently responsive to the requirements set forth in the grant
          announcement to allow for an informed review. Failure to address any
          of the required evaluation criteria or to submit all required forms
          will disqualify the proposal. The Agency reserves the right to contact
          the applicant to clarify information contained in the proposal to
          resolve issues related to eligibility and the grant request.
          Applications that are timely, complete, and responsive will be
          forwarded for further evaluation. Applications that are late,
          incomplete, or non-responsive will be rejected.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13525'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:C:1709.213
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.213
      </num>
      <head>
        Evaluation of applications.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='213' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.213
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Evaluation of applications.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Agency will establish one or more rating panels to review and
            rate the grant applications. The panels may include persons not
            employed by the Agency.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The rating panel will evaluate and rate all complete applications
            that meet the eligibility requirements according to the evaluation
            and selection criteria and weights established in the grant
            announcement. Panel members may make recommendations for conditions
            on grant awards to promote successful performance of the grant or to
            assure compliance with other Federal requirements.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             After all proposals have been evaluated and scored, the proposals,
            the rankings, recommendations, and comments of the rating panel will
            be forwarded to the Administrator.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13526'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:C:1709.214
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.214
      </num>
      <head>
        Administrator&apos;s review and selection of grant awards.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='214' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.214
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Administrator&apos;s review and selection of grant awards.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The final decision to make a grant award is at the discretion of
            the Administrator. The Administrator shall consider the
            applications, the ranking, comments, and recommendations of the
            rating panel, and any other pertinent information before making a
            decision about which, if any, applications to approve, the amount of
            funds awarded, and the order of approval. The Administrator reserves
            the right not to make any awards from the applications submitted.
            When the Administrator decides not to make any awards, the
            Administrator shall document in writing the reason for the decision.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Decisions on grant awards will be made by the Administrator after
            consideration of the applications, the rankings and recommendations
            of the rating panel. The Administrator may elect to award less than
            the full amount of grant requested by an applicant.
            <PRTPAGE P='80' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The applications selected by the Administrator will be funded in
            rank order to the extent of available funds.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13527'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:C:1709.215
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.215
      </num>
      <head>
        Consideration of unfunded applications under later grant announcements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='215' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.215
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Consideration of unfunded applications under later grant
          announcements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The grant announcement may provide that all eligible but unfunded
          proposals submitted under preceding announcements may also be
          considered for funding. The announcement shall describe whether and
          how prior applicants may request reconsideration and supplement their
          application material.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13528'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:C:1709.216
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.216
      </num>
      <head>
        Evaluation criteria and weights.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='216' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.216
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Evaluation criteria and weights.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Unless supplemented in the grant announcement, the criteria listed in
          this section will be used to evaluate proposals submitted under this
          program. The total points available and the distribution of points to
          be awarded per criterion will be identified in the grant announcement.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Program Design.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Reviewers will consider the financial viability of the
            applicant&apos;s revolving fund program design, the proposed
            criteria for establishing eligible projects and borrowers, and how
            the program will improve the cost effectiveness of bulk fuel
            purchases in eligible areas. Programs demonstrating a strong design
            and the ability to improve cost effectiveness will receive more
            points than applications that are less detailed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Assessment of needs.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Reviewers will award more points to programs that serve or give
            priority to assisting more costly areas than those that serve
            populations that suffer from less severe physical and economic
            challenges.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Program evaluation and performance measures.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Reviewers may award more points to performance measures that are
            relevant to the project objective and quantifiable than to
            performance measures that are more subjective and do not incorporate
            variables that reflect a reduction in fuel cost or improvement in
            service.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Demonstrated experience.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Applicants may be awarded points for relevant experience in
            administering revolving fund or other comparable programs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Rurality.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Reviewers may award more points to proposals that give priority in
            access to funds to communities with low population density or that
            are located in remote eligible areas than to proposals that serve
            eligible, but less remote and higher population density communities.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Cost sharing.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Although cost-sharing is not required under this program, projects
            that evidence significant funding or contributed property, equipment
            or other in kind support for the project may be awarded points for
            this criterion where the aggregate value of these contributions
            exceed 25 percent of the annual funding operations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Additional priority considerations.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The grant announcement may provide for additional points to be
            awarded to projects that advance identified Agency priority
            interests under this program.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13529'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:C:1709.217
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.217
      </num>
      <head>
        Grant award.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='217' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.217
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Grant award.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Notification of applicants.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Agency will notify all applicants in writing whether or not
            they have been selected for a grant award.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Letter of conditions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Agency will notify a selected applicant in writing, setting out
            the amount of grant approved and the conditions under which the
            grant will be made.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Applicant&apos;s intent to meet conditions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon reviewing the conditions and requirements in the letter of
            conditions, the selected applicant must complete, sign and return
            the Agency&apos;s “Letter of Intent to Meet Conditions,” or, if
            certain conditions cannot be met, the applicant may propose
            alternate conditions to the Agency. The Agency must concur with any
            changes proposed to the letter of conditions by the applicant before
            the application will be further processed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Grant agreement.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Agency and the grantee must execute a grant agreement
            acceptable to the Agency prior to the advance of funds.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13530'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:C:1709.218-1709.300
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1709.218-1709.300
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='218-1709' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.218-1709
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .300
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13531'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:G:1709.601
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1709.601
      </num>
      <head>
        Policy.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='601' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.601
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Policy.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          This subpart prescribes the policies of the Rural Utilities Service
          (RUS) when it is subsequently determined that the recipient of an
          Assistance to High Energy Cost Rural Communities program loan or grant
          was not eligible for all or part of the financial assistance received
          or that the assistance received was used for unauthorized purposes. It
          is the policy of the Agency that when assistance under this part has
          been received by an ineligible recipient or used for unauthorized
          purposes the Agency shall initiate appropriate actions to recover from
          the recipient the sum that is determined to be ineligible or used for
          unauthorized purposes, regardless of amount, unless any applicable
          statute of limitation has expired. The Agency shall make full use of
          available authority and procedures, including but not limited to those
          available under 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR part 
            <subref title='7' part='3015' tq='N'>
              3015
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , subpart N.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13532'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1709:G:1709.602-1709.999
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1709.602-1709.999
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1709' sect='602-1709' psec='' tq='N'>
              1709.602-1709
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .999
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>