<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol6'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:F:652
    </extid>
    <num>
      652
    </num>
    <head>
      TECHNICAL SERVICE PROVIDER ASSISTANCE
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='16' sect='3842' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/3842.html'>
              16 U.S.C. 3842
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            69 FR 69472
          </aref>
          , Nov. 29, 2004, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='6416'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:F:652:A:652.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        652.1
      </num>
      <head>
        Applicability.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='652' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              652.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Applicability.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The regulations in this part set forth the policies, procedures,
            and requirements related to delivery of technical assistance by
            individuals and entities other than the Department, hereinafter
            referred to as technical service providers (TSPs). The Food Security
            Act of 1985, requires the Secretary to deliver technical assistance
            to eligible participants for implementation of its Title XII
            Programs and the conservation activities in the Agricultural
            Management Assistance Program, 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='1524' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1524.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 1524
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , directly, through an agreement with a third party provider, or at
            the option of the producer through payment to the producer for an
            approved third party provider. This regulation defines how a
            participant acquires technical service from a third party TSP, sets
            forth a certification and decertification process, and establishes a
            method to make payments for technical services.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             TSPs may provide technical services to eligible participants in
            conservation planning, education and outreach, and assistance with
            design and implementation of conservation practices applied on
            private land, Indian land, or where allowed by conservation program
            rules on public land.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Chief may implement this part in any of the 50 States, District
            of Columbia, Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, Virgin Islands,
            American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Marianna
            Islands.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6417'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:F:652:A:652.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        652.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 6845
        </aref>
        , Feb. 12, 2010, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 48273
        </aref>
        , Aug. 10, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='652' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              652.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The following definitions apply to this part and all documents issued
          in accordance with this part, unless specified otherwise:
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Approved list
          </E>
           means the list of individuals, private sector entities, or public
          agencies certified by the Natural Resources Conservation Service
          (NRCS) to provide technical services to a participant.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Certification
          </E>
           means the action taken by NRCS to approve:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An individual as meeting the minimum NRCS criteria for providing
            technical service for conservation planning or a specific
            conservation practice or system.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An entity or public agency having an employee or employees that
            meet the minimum NRCS criteria for providing technical service for
            conservation planning or a specific conservation practice or system.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Chief
          </E>
           means the Chief of NRCS or designee.
          <PRTPAGE P='585' />
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Conservation activity plan
          </E>
           means the conservation practices associated with plan development as
          authorized under the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008 (2008
          Act).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Conservation plan
          </E>
           means a record of the client&apos;s decisions and supporting
          information for treatment of a land unit or water as a result of the
          planning process that meets the Field Office Technical Guide quality
          criteria for each natural resource (soil, water, air, plants, and
          animals), and takes into account economic and social considerations.
          The plan describes the schedule of operations and activities needed to
          solve identified natural resource problems and takes advantage of
          opportunities at a conservation management system level. The needs of
          the client, the resources, and Federal, State, and local requirements
          will be met.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Conservation practice
          </E>
           means a specified treatment, such as a structural or vegetative
          practice, or a land management practice that is planned and applied
          according to NRCS standards and specifications.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Contribution agreement
          </E>
           means the instrument used to acquire technical services under the
          authority of 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='6962a' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/6962a.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 6962a
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Cooperative agreement
          </E>
           means the same as defined in the Federal Grants and Cooperative
          Agreement Act, 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='31' sect='6301' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/31/6301.html'>
              31 U.S.C. 6301
            </subref>
          </aref>
           et seq.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Department
          </E>
           means the NRCS, the Farm Service Agency, or any other agency or
          instrumentality of the Department of Agriculture (USDA) that is
          assigned responsibility for all or a part of a conservation program
          subject to this part.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Eligible participant
          </E>
           means a producer, landowner, or entity that is participating in, or
          seeking to participate in, a conservation program covered by this rule
          in which the producer, landowner, or entity is otherwise eligible to
          participate.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Entity
          </E>
           means a corporation, joint stock company, association, cooperative,
          limited partnership, limited liability partnership, limited liability
          company, nonprofit organization, a member of a joint venture, or a
          member of a similar organization.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Indian land
          </E>
           means all lands held in trust by the United States for individual
          Indians or tribes, or all lands, titles to which are held by
          individual Indians or tribes, subject to Federal restrictions against
          alienation or encumbrance, or all lands which are subject to the
          rights of use, occupancy, and benefit of certain tribes. The term
          Indian land also includes land for which the title is held in fee
          status by Indian tribes and the United States Government-owned land
          under the Bureau of Indian Affairs jurisdiction.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Procurement contract
          </E>
           means the same as the term “contract” means under the Federal Grants
          and Cooperative Agreement Act, 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='31' sect='6301' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/31/6301.html'>
              31 U.S.C. 6301
            </subref>
          </aref>
          <E T='03'>
            et seq.
          </E>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Program contract
          </E>
           means the document that specifies the rights and obligations of any
          individual or entity that has been accepted for participation in a
          program authorized under Title XII of the Food Security Act of 1985,
          or the Agricultural Management Assistance Program, authorized under 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='1524' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1524.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 1524
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Public agency
          </E>
           means a unit or subdivision of Federal, State, local, or tribal
          government other than the Department.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Recommending organization
          </E>
           means a professional organization, association, licensing board, or
          similar organization with which NRCS has entered into an agreement to
          recommend qualified individuals for NRCS certification as TSPs for
          specific technical services.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Secretary
          </E>
           means the Secretary of the Department of Agriculture.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State Conservationist
          </E>
           means the NRCS employee authorized to direct and supervise NRCS
          activities in a State, Caribbean Area, or Pacific Basin Area.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Technical service
          </E>
           means the technical assistance provided by TSPs, including
          conservation planning; education and outreach; and the design,
          installation, and check-out of approved conservation practices.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Technical service contract
          </E>
           means a document that specifies the rights and obligations of an
          eligible participant to obtain technical services from a TSP where the
          eligible participant will not receive financial assistance for the
          implementation of the practice paid for in the technical service
          contract through 
          <PRTPAGE P='586' />
          participation in a Title XII conservation program or the Agricultural
          Management Assistance Program, 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='1524' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1524.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 1524
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Technical service provider
          </E>
           means an individual, entity, Indian Tribe, or public agency either:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Certified by NRCS and placed on the approved list to provide
            technical services to participants; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Selected by the Department to assist the Department in the
            implementation of conservation programs covered by this part through
            a procurement contract, contribution agreement, or cooperative
            agreement with the Department.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Written agreement
          </E>
           means the document that specifies the rights and obligations of any
          individual or entity that has been authorized by NRCS to receive
          conservation planning assistance without having a program contract.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 6845
          </aref>
          , Feb. 12, 2010, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 48273
          </aref>
          , Aug. 10, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6418'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:F:652:A:652.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        652.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Administration.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='652' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              652.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Administration.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             As provided in this part, the Department will provide technical
            assistance to participants directly, or at the option of the
            participant, through a TSP in accordance with the requirements of
            this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Chief of NRCS will direct and supervise the administration of
            the regulations in this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS will:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provide overall leadership and management for the development and
            administration of a TSP process;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Consult with the Farm Service Agency and other appropriate agencies
            and entities concerning the availability and utilization of TSPs and
            the implementation of technical service;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Establish policies, procedures, guidance, and criteria for
            certification, recertification, decertification, certification
            renewal, and implementation of the use of TSPs;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provide training to ensure that persons meet the certification
            criteria for certain technical expertise when there is a lack of
            training resources or market outside the agency for such technical
            expertise. However, any training provided by the Department will be
            limited to training about Department regulations, policies,
            procedures, processes, and business and technical tools unique to
            NRCS; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Establish a process for verifying information provided to NRCS
            under this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Department will not make payments under a program contract or
            written agreement with a participant for technical services provided
            by a TSP unless the TSP is certified by NRCS for the services
            provided and is identified on the approved list.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Department may enter into procurement contracts, contribution
            agreements, cooperative agreements, or other appropriate instruments
            to assist the Department in providing technical assistance when
            implementing conservation programs covered by this part. The
            Department will ensure that such instruments contain the
            qualification and performance criteria necessary to ensure quality
            implementation of the goals and objectives of these conservation
            programs; therefore, when the Department obtains assistance from a
            TSP in this manner, the TSP is authorized to provide technical
            services and receive payment even if such TSP is not certified in
            accordance with subpart B, nor identified on the approved list.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When a participant acquires technical services from a TSP, the
            Department is not a party to the agreement between the participant
            and the TSP. To ensure that quality implementation of the goals and
            objectives of the conservation programs are met, the TSP must be
            certified by NRCS in accordance with subpart B of this part and
            identified on the approved list. Upon request of NRCS, TSPs are
            required to submit copies of all transcripts, licensing, and
            certification documentation.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6419'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:F:652:A:652.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        652.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Technical service standards.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='652' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              652.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Technical service standards.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All technical services provided by TSPs must meet USDA standards
            and specifications as set forth in Departmental manuals, handbooks,
            guides, and other references for soils mapping and natural resources
            information, conservation planning, conservation practice
            application, and other areas of technical assistance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Department will only pay a participant for technical services
            provided in accordance with established 
            <PRTPAGE P='587' />
            NRCS standards, specifications, and requirements. The Department
            must approve all new technologies and innovative practices,
            including interim standards and specifications, prior to a TSP
            initiating technical services for those technologies and practices.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A TSP must assume responsibility in writing for the particular
            technical services provided. Technical services provided by the TSP
            must:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Comply with all applicable Federal, State, tribal, and local laws
            and requirements;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Meet applicable Department standards, specifications, and program
            requirements;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be consistent with the particular conservation program goals and
            objectives for which the program contract was entered into by the
            Department and the participant; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Incorporate alternatives that are both cost effective and
            appropriate to address the resource issues. Conservation
            alternatives will meet the objectives for the program and
            participant to whom assistance is provided.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             TSPs are responsible for the technical services provided, including
            any costs, damages, claims, liabilities, and judgments arising from
            past, present, and future negligent or wrongful acts or omissions of
            the TSP in connection with the technical service provided.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Department will not be in breach of any program contract or
            written agreement if it fails to implement conservation plans or
            practices or make payment for conservation plans or practices
            resulting from technical services that do not meet USDA standards
            and specifications or are not consistent with program requirements.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The participant is responsible for complying with the terms and
            conditions of the program contract or written agreement, which
            includes meeting USDA technical standards and specifications for any
            technical services provided by a TSP.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The TSP will report in the NRCS conservation accomplishment
            tracking system the appropriate data elements associated with the
            technical services provided to the Department or participant.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To the extent allowed under State or tribal law, TSPs may utilize
            the services of subcontractors to provide specific technical
            services or expertise needed by the TSP, provided that the
            subcontractors are certified by NRCS in accordance with this part
            for the particular technical services to be provided and the
            technical services are provided in terms of their Certification
            Agreement. Payments will not be made for any technical services
            provided by uncertified subcontractors, except when such technical
            services are provided under the provisions of a procurement
            contract, cooperative agreement, or contribution agreement with the
            NRCS.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6420'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:F:652:A:652.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        652.5
      </num>
      <head>
        Participant acquisition of technical services.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='652' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              652.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Participant acquisition of technical services.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Participants may obtain technical assistance directly from the
            Department or, when available, from a TSP.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To acquire technical assistance directly from the Department,
            participants should contact their local USDA Service Center.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To acquire technical services from a TSP, participants must:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Enter into and comply with a program contract or a written
            agreement prior to acquiring technical services; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Select a certified TSP from the approved list of TSPs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Department may approve written agreements for technical
            assistance prior to program participation based on available funding
            and natural resource priorities as identified by the State
            Conservationist.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The technical assistance indicated in paragraph (d) may include the
            development of conservation plans or activity plans suitable for
            subsequent incorporation into a program contract.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Department may make payment to eligible participants who have a
            technical service contract and utilize it for technical assistance
            from a TSP.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Department will identify in the particular program contract or
            written agreement the payment provisions for TSPs hired directly by
            the participant.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To obtain payment for technical services, participants must submit
            to the Department valid invoices, supporting documentation, and
            requests for payment. The Department will 
            <PRTPAGE P='588' />
            issue payment within 30 days of receiving these items. The
            Department may pay a participant for some or all of the costs
            associated with the technical services provided by a TSP hired by
            the participant, or upon receipt of an assignment of payment from
            the participant, make payment directly to the TSP.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Participants must authorize in writing to the Department the
            disclosure of their records on file with the Department that they
            wish to make available to specific TSPs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payments for technical services will be made only one time for the
            same technical service provided unless, as determined by the
            Department, the emergence of new technologies or major changes in
            the participant&apos;s farming or ranching operations necessitate
            the need for additional technical services.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Department will not make payment for activities or services
            that are customarily provided at no cost by a TSP to a participant
            as determined by the State Conservationist.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='l'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (l)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payment rates for technical services acquired by participants.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='l_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS will calculate TSP payment rates for technical services using
            national, regional, and locally determined price data.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='l_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Establishing TSP payment rates.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='l_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS will establish guidelines to analyze the local pricing
            information using a standardized method.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='l_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State Conservationist will establish TSP payment rates in each
            State for the various categories of technical services. The State
            Conservationist will determine the rates according to local NRCS
            cost data, procurement data, and market data.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='l_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             National Headquarters will review and approve State payment rates
            to ensure consistency where similar resource conditions and
            agricultural operations exist. Payment rates may vary to some degree
            between or within States due to differences in State laws, the cost
            of doing business, competition, and other variables.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='l_2_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             National Headquarters and State levels will review payment rates
            annually or more frequently, as needed, and adjust the rates based
            upon data from existing procurement contracts, Federal cost rates,
            and other appropriate sources.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='l_2_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS may adjust payment rates, as needed, on a case-by-case basis
            in response to unusual conditions or unforeseen circumstances in
            delivering technical services such as highly complex technical
            situations, emergency conditions, serious threats to human health or
            the environment, or major resource limitations. In these cases, NRCS
            will set a case-specific TSP payment rate based on the
            Department&apos;s determination of the scope, magnitude, and
            timeliness of the technical services needed.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6421'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:F:652:A:652.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        652.6
      </num>
      <head>
        Department delivery of technical services.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='652' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              652.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Department delivery of technical services.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Department may enter into a procurement contract, contribution
            agreement, cooperative agreement, or other appropriate instrument to
            assist the Department in providing technical assistance when
            implementing the conservation programs covered by this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Department may enter into a procurement contract, contribution
            agreement, cooperative agreement, or other appropriate instrument
            with TSPs to provide related technical assistance services that
            accelerate conservation program delivery. Related technical
            assistance services may include activities or services that
            facilitate the development, processing, or implementation of a
            program contract, such as recording conservation planning decisions
            and specifications.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS may enter into agreements with other agencies or with a
            non-Federal entity to provide technical services to eligible
            participants.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Department will ensure that such legal instruments contain
            qualification and performance criteria necessary to ensure quality
            implementation of these conservation programs. When the Department
            obtains assistance from a TSP through a procurement contract,
            contribution agreement, cooperative agreement, or other similar
            instrument, the TSP is authorized to provide technical services and
            receive payment even if such TSP is not certified in accordance with
            subpart B of this part nor identified on the approved list.
            <PRTPAGE P='589' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Department will implement procurement contracts, contribution
            agreements, cooperative agreements, and other appropriate
            instruments in accordance with applicable Federal acquisition or
            USDA Federal assistance rules and requirements for competency,
            quality, and selection, as appropriate. Any contract, contribution
            agreement, cooperative agreement, or other appropriate instrument
            entered into under this section will be for a minimum of one year,
            will not exceed 3 years in duration, and may be renewed upon mutual
            agreement of the parties.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A TSP may not receive payment twice for the same technical service,
            such as once from a participant through a program contract or
            written agreement and then again through a separate contract or
            agreement made directly with the Department.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Department will, to the extent practicable, ensure that the
            amounts paid for technical service under this part are consistent
            across conservation program areas, unless specific conservation
            program requirements include additional tasks.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6422'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:F:652:A:652.7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        652.7
      </num>
      <head>
        Quality assurance.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='652' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              652.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Quality assurance.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS will review, in consultation with the Farm Service Agency, as
            appropriate, the quality of the technical services provided by TSPs.
            As a requirement of certification, TSPs must develop and maintain
            documentation in accordance with Departmental manuals, handbooks,
            and technical guidance for the technical services provided, and
            provide this documentation to NRCS and the participant when the
            particular technical service is completed. NRCS may utilize
            information obtained through its quality assurance process,
            documentation submitted by the TSP, and other relevant information
            in determining how to improve the quality of technical service, as
            well as determining whether to decertify a TSP under subpart C of
            this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon discovery of a deficiency in the provision of technical
            service through its quality assurance process or other means, NRCS
            will, to the greatest extent practicable, send a notice to the TSP
            detailing the deficiency and requesting remedial action by the TSP.
            Failure by the TSP to promptly remedy the deficiency, or the
            occurrence of repeated deficiencies in providing technical services,
            may trigger the decertification process set forth in subpart C of
            this part. A failure by NRCS to identify a deficiency does not
            affect any action under the decertification process. TSPs are solely
            responsible for providing technical services that meet all NRCS
            standards and specifications.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6423'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:F:652:B:652.21
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        652.21
      </num>
      <head>
        Certification criteria and requirements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='652' sect='21' psec='' tq='N'>
              652.21
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Certification criteria and requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To qualify for certification an individual must:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Have the required technical training, education, and experience to
            perform the level of technical assistance for which certification is
            sought;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Meet any applicable professional or business licensing or similar
            qualification standards established by State or Tribal law;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Demonstrate, through documentation of training or experience,
            familiarity with NRCS guidelines, criteria, standards, and
            specifications as set forth in the applicable NRCS manuals,
            handbooks, field office technical guides, and supplements thereto
            for the planning and applying of specific conservation practices and
            management systems for which certification is sought; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Not be decertified in any State under subpart C of this part at the
            time of application for certification.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To qualify for certification an entity or public agency must be
            authorized to provide such services in the jurisdiction and have a
            certified individual providing, in accordance with this part,
            technical services on its behalf.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A technical service provider, as part of the certification by NRCS,
            must enter into a Certification Agreement with NRCS specifying the
            terms and conditions of the certification, including adherence to
            the requirements of this part, and acknowledging that failure to
            meet these requirements may result in ineligibility to receive
            payments from the Department, either directly or through the
            participant, for 
            <PRTPAGE P='590' />
            the technical services provided or may result in decertification.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS will certify Technical Service Providers for a time period
            specified by NRCS in the Certification Agreement, not to exceed 3
            years. Decertification and Renewal of Certification is administered
            in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='652' sect='26' psec='' tq='N'>
                652.26
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS may, pursuant to 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='31' sect='9701' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/31/9701.html'>
                31 U.S.C. 9701
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , establish and collect fees for the certification of technical
            service providers.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6424'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:F:652:B:652.22
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        652.22
      </num>
      <head>
        Certification process for individuals.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='652' sect='22' psec='' tq='N'>
              652.22
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Certification process for individuals.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In order to be considered for certification as a technical service
            provider, an individual must:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Submit an Application for Certification to NRCS in accordance with
            this section;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Request certification through a recommending organization pursuant
            to 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='652' sect='25' psec='' tq='N'>
                652.25
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Request certification through an application submitted by a
            private-sector entity or public agency pursuant to 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='652' sect='23' psec='' tq='N'>
                652.23
              </subref>
            </aref>
             or 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='652' sect='24' psec='' tq='N'>
                652.24
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , as appropriate.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The application must contain the documentation demonstrating that
            the individual meets all requirements of paragraph (a) of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='652' sect='21' psec='' tq='N'>
                652.21
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS will, within 60 days of receipt of an application, make a
            determination on the application submitted by an individual under
            paragraph (a)(1) of this section and in accordance with paragraph
            (a) of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='652' sect='21' psec='' tq='N'>
                652.21
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . If all requirements are met, NRCS will:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Enter into a Certification Agreement and certify the applicant as
            qualified to provide technical services for a specific practice,
            category, or categories of technical service;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Place the applicant on the list of approved technical service
            providers when certified; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Make available to the public the list of approved technical service
            providers by practice or category of technical services.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS may decertify an individual in accordance with the
            decertification process set forth in subpart C of this part.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6425'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:F:652:B:652.23
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        652.23
      </num>
      <head>
        Certification process for private-sector entities.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='652' sect='23' psec='' tq='N'>
              652.23
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Certification process for private-sector entities.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A private sector entity that applies for certification must
            identify, and provide supporting documentation, that it has the
            requisite professional and business licensure within the
            jurisdiction for which it seek certification, and that it employs at
            least one individual, authorized to act on its behalf that:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Has received certification on an individual basis in accordance
            with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='652' sect='22' psec='' tq='N'>
                652.22
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Seeks certification on an individual basis as part of the
            private-sector entity&apos;s certification and ensures that the
            requirements set forth in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='652' sect='21' psec='#a' tq='N'>
                652.21(a)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             are contained within the private-sector entity&apos;s application
            to support such certification.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS will determine pursuant to 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='652' sect='22' psec='' tq='N'>
                652.22
              </subref>
            </aref>
             whether the individual(s) identified in the private-sector
            entity&apos;s application meets the certification standards set
            forth in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='652' sect='21' psec='' tq='N'>
                652.21
              </subref>
            </aref>
             for the specific services the entity wishes to provide.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS will, within 60 days of receipt of an application, make a
            determination on the application submitted by an entity. If NRCS
            determines that all requirements for the private-sector entity and
            the identified individual(s) are met, NRCS will complete the actions
            described in paragraphs (c)(1) through (c)(3) of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='652' sect='22' psec='' tq='N'>
                652.22
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Certification Agreement entered into with the private-sector
            entity shall:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Identify the certified individuals who are authorized to perform
            technical services on behalf of and under the auspices of the
            entity&apos;s certification;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Require that the entity has, at all times, an individual who is a
            certified technical service provider authorized to act on the
            entity&apos;s behalf;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Require that the entity promptly provide an amended Certification
            Agreement to NRCS for approval when the list of certified
            individuals performing technical services under its auspices
            changes;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Require that responsibility for any work performed by non-certified
            individuals be assumed by a certified individual who is authorized
            to act on the entity&apos;s behalf; and
            <PRTPAGE P='591' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Require that the entity be legally responsible for the work
            performed by any individual working under the auspices of its
            certification.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS may, in accordance with the decertification process set forth
            in this part, decertify the private sector entity, the certified
            individual(s) acting under the auspices of its certification, or
            both the private sector entity and the certified individual(s)
            acting under the auspices of its certification.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6426'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:F:652:B:652.24
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        652.24
      </num>
      <head>
        Certification process for public agencies.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='652' sect='24' psec='' tq='N'>
              652.24
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Certification process for public agencies.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A public agency that applies for certification must identify, and
            provide supporting documentation, that it has the authority within
            the jurisdiction within which it seeks to provide technical services
            and an individual or individuals authorized to act on its behalf:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Has been certified as an individual in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='652' sect='22' psec='' tq='N'>
                652.22
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Seeks certification as an individual as part of the public
            agency&apos;s certification and sufficient information as set forth
            in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='652' sect='21' psec='#a' tq='N'>
                652.21(a)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             is contained within the public agency&apos;s application to support
            such certification.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS shall determine whether the individual identified in the
            public agency&apos;s application meets the certification standards
            set forth in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='652' sect='22' psec='' tq='N'>
                652.22
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS will, within 60 days of receipt of an application, make a
            determination on the application submitted by a public agency. If
            NRCS determines that all requirements for the public agency and the
            identified individual(s) are met, NRCS will perform the actions
            described in paragraph (c)(1) through (c)(3) of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='652' sect='22' psec='' tq='N'>
                652.22
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . The Certification Agreement entered into with the public agency
            shall:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Identify the certified individuals that are authorized to perform
            technical services on behalf of and under the auspices of the public
            agency&apos;s certification;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Require that the public agency have, at all times, an individual
            that is a certified technical service provider and is an authorized
            official of the public agency;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Require that the public agency promptly provide to NRCS for NRCS
            approval an amended Certification Agreement when the list of
            certified individuals performing technical services under its
            auspices changes;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Require that responsibility for any work performed by non-certified
            individuals be assumed by a certified individual that is authorized
            to act on the public agency&apos;s behalf; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Require that the public agency be legally responsible for the work
            performed by any individual working under the auspices of its
            certification.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS may, in accordance with the decertification process set forth
            in subpart C of this part, decertify the public agency, the
            certified individual(s) acting under its auspices, or both the
            public agency and the certified individual(s) acting under its
            auspices.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6427'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:F:652:B:652.25
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        652.25
      </num>
      <head>
        Alternative application process for individual certification.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='652' sect='25' psec='' tq='N'>
              652.25
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Alternative application process for individual certification.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS may enter into an agreement, including a memorandum of
            understanding or other appropriate instrument, with a recommending
            organization that NRCS determines has an adequate accreditation
            program in place to train, test, and evaluate candidates for
            competency in a particular area or areas of technical service
            delivery and whose accreditation program NRCS determines meets the
            certification criteria as set forth for the technical services to be
            provided.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Recommending organizations will, pursuant to an agreement entered
            into with NRCS:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Train, test, and evaluate candidates for competency in the area of
            technical service delivery;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Recommend to NRCS individuals who it determines meet the NRCS
            certification requirements of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='652' sect='21' psec='#a' tq='N'>
                652.21(a)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             for providing specific practices or categories of technical
            services;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Inform the recommended individuals that they must meet the
            requirements of this part, including entering into a Certification
            Agreement with NRCS, in order to provide technical services under
            this part;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Reassess individuals that request renewal of their certification
            pursuant to 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='652' sect='26' psec='' tq='N'>
                652.26
              </subref>
            </aref>
             through the recommendation of the organization; and
            <PRTPAGE P='592' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notify NRCS of any concerns or problems that may affect the
            organization&apos;s recommendation concerning the individual&apos;s
            certification, recertification, certification renewal, or technical
            service delivery.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Pursuant to an agreement with NRCS, a recommending organization may
            provide to the appropriate NRCS official a current list of
            individuals identified by the recommending organization as meeting
            NRCS criteria as set forth in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='652' sect='21' psec='#a' tq='N'>
                652.21(a)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             for specific practices or categories of technical service and
            recommend that the NRCS official certify these individuals as
            technical service providers in accordance with this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS will, within 60 days, make a determination on the
            recommendation for certification issued by the recommending
            organization. If NRCS determines that all requirements for
            certification are met by the recommended individual(s), NRCS will
            perform the actions described in paragraphs (c)(1) through (c)(3) of
            
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='652' sect='22' psec='' tq='N'>
                652.22
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS may terminate an agreement with a recommending organization if
            concerns or problems with its accreditation program, its
            recommendations for certification, or other requirements under the
            agreement arise.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6428'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:F:652:B:652.26
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        652.26
      </num>
      <head>
        Certification renewal.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='652' sect='26' psec='' tq='N'>
              652.26
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Certification renewal.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS certifications are in effect for a time period specified by
            NRCS in the Certification Agreement, not to exceed 3 years and
            automatically expire unless they are renewed for an additional time
            period in accordance with this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A technical service provider may request renewal of an NRCS
            certification by:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Submitting a complete certification renewal application to NRCS or
            through a private sector entity, a public agency, or a recommending
            organization to NRCS at least 60 days prior to expiration of the
            current certification;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Providing verification on the renewal form that the requirements of
            this part are met; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Agreeing to abide by the terms and conditions of a Certification
            Agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All certification renewals are in effect for a time period
            specified by NRCS in the Certification Agreement, not to exceed
            three years and before expiration, may be renewed for subsequent
            time period in accordance with this section.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6429'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:F:652:C:652.31
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        652.31
      </num>
      <head>
        Policy.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='652' sect='31' psec='' tq='N'>
              652.31
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Policy.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          In order to protect the public interest, it is the policy of NRCS to
          maintain certification of those technical service providers who act
          responsibly in the provision of technical service, including meeting
          NRCS standards and specifications when providing technical service to
          participants. This section, which provides for the decertification of
          technical service providers, is an appropriate means to implement this
          policy.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6430'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:F:652:C:652.32
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        652.32
      </num>
      <head>
        Causes for decertification.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='652' sect='32' psec='' tq='N'>
              652.32
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Causes for decertification.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          A State Conservationist, in whose State a technical service provider
          is certified to provide technical service, may decertify the technical
          service provider, in accordance with these provisions, if the
          technical service provider, or someone acting on behalf of the
          technical service provider:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Fails to meet NRCS standards and specifications in the provision of
            technical services;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Violates the terms of the Certification Agreement, including but
            not limited to, a demonstrated lack of understanding of, or an
            unwillingness or inability to implement, NRCS standards and
            specifications for a particular practice for which the technical
            service provider is certified, or the provision of technical
            services for which the technical service provider is not certified;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Engages in a scheme or device to defeat the purposes of this part,
            including, but not limited to, coercion, fraud, misrepresentation,
            or providing incorrect or misleading information; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Commits any other action of a serious or compelling nature as
            determined by NRCS that demonstrates the technical service
            provider&apos;s inability to fulfill the terms of the Certification
            Agreement or provide technical services under this part.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6431'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:F:652:C:652.33
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        652.33
      </num>
      <head>
        Notice of proposed decertification.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='593' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='652' sect='33' psec='' tq='N'>
              652.33
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Notice of proposed decertification.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The State Conservationist will send by certified mail, return receipt
          requested, to the technical service provider proposed for
          decertification a written Notice of Proposed Decertification, which
          will contain the cause(s) for decertification, as well as any
          documentation supporting decertification. In cases where a private
          sector entity or public agency is being notified of a proposed
          decertification, any certified individuals working under the auspices
          of such organization who are also being considered for decertification
          will receive a separate Notice of Decertification and will be afforded
          separate appeal rights following the process set forth below.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6432'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:F:652:C:652.34
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        652.34
      </num>
      <head>
        Opportunity to contest decertification.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='652' sect='34' psec='' tq='N'>
              652.34
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Opportunity to contest decertification.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          To contest decertification, the technical service provider must submit
          in writing to the State Conservationist, within 20 calendar days from
          the date of receipt of the Notice of Proposed Decertification, the
          reasons why the State Conservationist should not decertify, including
          any mitigating factors as well as any supporting documentation.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6433'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:F:652:C:652.35
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        652.35
      </num>
      <head>
        State Conservationist decision.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='652' sect='35' psec='' tq='N'>
              652.35
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          State Conservationist decision.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Within 40 calendar days from the date of the notice of proposed
          decertification, the State Conservationist will issue a written
          determination. If the State Conservationist decides to decertify, the
          decision will set forth the reasons for decertification, the period of
          decertification, and the scope of decertification. If the State
          Conservationist decides not to decertify the technical service
          provider, the technical service provider will be given written notice
          of that determination. The decertification determination will be based
          on an administrative record, which will be comprised of: the Notice of
          Proposed Decertification and supporting documents, and, if submitted,
          the technical service provider&apos;s written response and supporting
          documentation. Both a copy of the decision and administrative record
          will be sent promptly by certified mail, return receipt requested, to
          the technical service provider.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6434'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:F:652:C:652.36
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        652.36
      </num>
      <head>
        Appeal of decertification decisions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='652' sect='36' psec='' tq='N'>
              652.36
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Appeal of decertification decisions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Within 20 calendar days from the date of receipt of the State
            Conservationist&apos;s decertification determination, the technical
            service provider may appeal, in writing, to the Chief of NRCS. The
            written appeal must state the reasons for appeal and any arguments
            in support of those reasons. If the technical service provider fails
            to appeal, the decision of the State Conservationist is final.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Final decision. Within 30 calendar days of receipt of the technical
            service provider&apos;s written appeal, the Chief or his designee,
            will make a final determination, in writing, based upon the
            administrative record and any additional information submitted to
            the Chief by the technical service provider. The decision of the
            Chief, or his designee, is final and not subject to further
            administrative review. The Chief&apos;s determination will include
            the reasons for decertification, the period of decertification, and
            the scope of decertification.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6435'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:F:652:C:652.37
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        652.37
      </num>
      <head>
        Period of decertification.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='652' sect='37' psec='' tq='N'>
              652.37
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Period of decertification.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The period of decertification will not exceed three years in duration
          and will be decided by the decertifying official, either the State
          Conservationist or Chief, as applicable, based upon their weighing of
          all relevant facts and the seriousness of the reasons for
          decertification, mitigating factors, if any, and the following general
          guidelines:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For failures in the provision of technical service for which there
            are no mitigating factors, 
            <E T='03'>
              e.g.
            </E>
            , no remedial action by the technical service provider, a maximum
            period of three years decertification;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For repeated failures in the provision of technical assistance for
            which there are mitigating factors, 
            <E T='03'>
              e.g.
            </E>
            , the technical service provider has taken remedial action to the
            satisfaction of NRCS, a maximum period of one to two years
            decertification; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For a violation of Certification Agreement terms, 
            <E T='03'>
              e.g.
            </E>
            , failure to possess technical competency for a listed practice, a
            period of one year or less, if 
            <PRTPAGE P='594' />
            the technical service provider can master such competency within a
            year period.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6436'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:F:652:C:652.38
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        652.38
      </num>
      <head>
        Scope of decertification.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='652' sect='38' psec='' tq='N'>
              652.38
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Scope of decertification.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When the technical service provider is a private sector entity or
            public agency, the decertifying official may decertify the entire
            organization, including all the individuals identified as authorized
            to provide technical services under the auspices of such
            organization. The decertifying official may also limit the scope of
            decertification, for example, to one or more specifically named
            individuals identified as authorized to provide technical services
            under the organization&apos;s auspices or to an organizational
            element of such private sector entity or public agency. The scope of
            decertification will be set forth in the decertification
            determination and will be based upon the facts of each
            decertification action, including whether actions of particular
            individuals can be imputed to the larger organization.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In cases where specific individuals are decertified only, an entity
            or public agency must file within 10 calendar days an amended
            Certification Agreement removing the decertified individual(s) from
            the Certification Agreement. In addition, the entity or public
            agency must demonstrate that, to the satisfaction of the State
            Conservationist, the entity or public agency has taken affirmative
            steps to ensure that the circumstances resulting in decertification
            have been addressed.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6437'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:F:652:C:652.39
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        652.39
      </num>
      <head>
        Mitigating factors.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='652' sect='39' psec='' tq='N'>
              652.39
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Mitigating factors.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          In considering whether to decertify, the period of decertification,
          and scope of decertification, the deciding official will take into
          consideration any mitigating factors. Examples of mitigating factors
          include, but are not limited to the following:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The technical service provider worked, in a timely manner, to
            correct any deficiencies in the provision of technical service;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The technical service provider took the initiative to bring any
            deficiency in the provision of their technical services to the
            attention of NRCS and sought NRCS advice to remediate the situation;
            and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The technical service provider took affirmative steps to prevent
            any failures in the provision of technical services from occurring
            in the future.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6438'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:F:652:C:652.40
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        652.40
      </num>
      <head>
        Effect of decertification.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='652' sect='40' psec='' tq='N'>
              652.40
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Effect of decertification.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Department will not make payment under a program contract for
            the technical services of a decertified technical service provider
            that were provided during the period of decertification. Likewise,
            NRCS will not procure, or otherwise enter into an agreement for, the
            services of a decertified technical service provider during the
            period of decertification.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             National decertification list. NRCS shall maintain a current list
            of decertified technical service providers. NRCS shall remove
            decertified providers from the list of certified providers.
            Participants may not hire a decertified technical service provider.
            It is the participant&apos;s responsibility to check the decertified
            list before hiring a technical service provider. Decertification of
            a technical service provider in one State decertifies the technical
            service provider from providing technical services under current
            programs in all States, the Caribbean Area, and the Pacific Basin
            Area.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6439'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:F:652:C:652.41
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        652.41
      </num>
      <head>
        Effect of filing deadlines.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='652' sect='41' psec='' tq='N'>
              652.41
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Effect of filing deadlines.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          A technical service provider&apos;s failure to meet the filing
          deadlines under this subpart will result in the forfeiture of appeal
          rights. All filings must be received by NRCS no later than the close
          of business (5 p.m.) the last day of the filing period.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6440'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:F:652:C:652.42
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        652.42
      </num>
      <head>
        Recertification.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='652' sect='42' psec='' tq='N'>
              652.42
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Recertification.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          A decertified technical service provider may apply to be re-certified
          under the certification provisions of this part after the period of
          decertification has expired. A technical service provider may not
          utilize the certification renewal process in an attempt to be
          recertified after being decertified.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>