<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol4'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:B:253
    </extid>
    <num>
      253
    </num>
    <head>
      ADMINISTRATION OF THE FOOD DISTRIBUTION PROGRAM FOR HOUSEHOLDS ON INDIAN
      RESERVATIONS
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref target='_blank' href='http://frwebgate.access.gpo.gov/cgi-bin/getpage.cgi?dbname=95_statutes_at_large&amp;position=all&amp;page=958'>
            91 Stat. 958
          </aref>
           (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='2011-203' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/2011-203.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 2011-203
            </subref>
          </aref>
          6).
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            44 FR 35928
          </aref>
          , June 19, 1979, unless otherwise noted. Redesignated by Amdt. 1, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            47 FR 14137
          </aref>
          , Apr. 2, 1982.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='4852'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:B:253:-:253.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        253.1
      </num>
      <head>
        General purpose and scope.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='253' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              253.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General purpose and scope.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          This part describes the terms and conditions under which: commodities
          (available under 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='250' tq='N'>
              250 of this chapter
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ) may be distributed to households on or near all or any part of any
          Indian reservation, the program may be administered by capable Indian
          tribal organizations, and funds may be obtained from the Department
          for the costs incurred in administering the program. This part also
          provides for the concurrent operation of the Food Distribution Program
          and the Food Stamp Program on Indian reservations when such concurrent
          operation is requested by an ITO.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4853'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:B:253:-:253.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        253.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          44 FR 35928
        </aref>
        , June 19, 1979. Redesignated and amended by Amdt. 1, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          47 FR 14137
        </aref>
        , Apr. 2, 1982; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          59 FR 1449
        </aref>
        , Jan. 11, 1994; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          64 FR 73382
        </aref>
        , Dec. 30, 1999; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 4473
        </aref>
        , Jan. 28, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='253' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              253.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Disabled member
          </E>
           means a member of a household who:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Receives supplemental security income benefits under title XVI of
            the Social Security Act or disability or blindness payments under
            titles I, II, X, XIV, or XVI of the Social Security Act;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Receives federally- or State-administered supplemental benefits
            under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 1616(a) of
            </aref>
             the Social Security Act provided that the eligibility to receive
            the benefits is based upon the disability or blindness criteria used
            under title XVI of the Social Security Act;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Receives federally- or State-administered supplemental benefits
            under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 212(a) of
            </aref>
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 93-66' alt='Public Law 93-66' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d93:./list/bd/d93pl.lst:66%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 93-66
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Receives disability retirement benefits from a governmental agency
            because of a disability considered permanent under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 221(i) of
            </aref>
             the Social Security Act;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is a veteran with a service-connected or non-service-connected
            disability rated by the Veteran&apos;s Administration (VA) as total
            or paid as total by the VA under title 38 of the United States Code;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is a veteran considered by the VA to be in need of regular aid and
            attendance or permanently housebound under title 38 of the United
            States Code;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is a surviving spouse of a veteran and considered by the VA to be
            in need of regular aid and attendance or permanently housebound or a
            surviving child of a veteran and considered by the VA to be
            permanently incapable of self-support under title 38 of the United
            States Code;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is a surviving spouse or surviving child of a veteran and
            considered by the VA to be entitled to compensation 
            <PRTPAGE P='604' />
            for a service-connected death or pension benefits for a
            non-service-connected death under title 38 of the United States Code
            and has a disability considered permanent under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 221(i) of
            </aref>
             the Social Security Act. “Entitled” as used in this definition
            refers to those veterans&apos; surviving spouses and surviving
            children who are receiving the compensation or pension benefits
            stated or have been approved for such payments, but are not yet
            receiving them;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Receives an annuity payment under: 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              Section 2(a)(1)(iv) of
            </aref>
             the Railroad Retirement Act of 1974 and is determined to be
            eligible to receive Medicare by the Railroad Retirement Board; or 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 2(a)(1)(v) of
            </aref>
             the Railroad Retirement Act of 1974 and is determined to be
            disabled based upon the criteria used under title XVI of the Social
            Security Act; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is a recipient of interim assistance benefits pending the receipt
            of Supplemented Security Income, a recipient of disability related
            medical assistance under title XIX of the Social Security Act, or a
            recipient of disability-based State general assistance benefits
            provided that the eligibility to receive any of these benefits is
            based upon disability or blindness criteria established by the State
            agency, which are at least as stringent as those used under title
            XVI of the Social Security Act (as set forth at 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              20 CFR part 
              <subref title='20' part='416' tq='N'>
                416
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , subpart I, Determining Disability and Blindness as defined in
            Title XVI).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Elderly member
          </E>
           means a member of a household who is sixty years of age or older.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Exercises governmental jurisdiction
          </E>
           means the active exercise of the legislative, executive or judicial
          powers of government by an Indian tribal organization.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Food distribution program
          </E>
           means a food distribution program for households on Indian
          reservations operated pursuant to 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            sections 4(b) and 1304(a) of
          </aref>
          <aref target='_blank' title='Pub. L. 95-113' alt='Pub. L. 95-113' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d95:./list/bd/d95pl.lst:113%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Pub. L. 95-113
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Indian tribal household
          </E>
           means a household in which at least one household member is
          recognized as a tribal member by any Indian tribe, as defined in
          paragraph (d) of this section.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Indian tribal organization (ITO)
          </E>
           means: (1) The recognized governing body of any Indian tribe on a
          reservation; or (2) the tribally recognized intertribal organization
          which the recognized governing bodies of two or more Indian tribes on
          a reservation authorize to operate the Food Stamp Program or a Food
          Distribution Program on their behalf.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Indian tribe
          </E>
           means (1) any Indian tribe, Band, or other organized Indian group,
          for example, a Rancheria, Pueblo, or colony, and including any Alaska
          Native village or regional or village corporation (established
          pursuant to the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (
          <aref target='_blank' href='http://frwebgate.access.gpo.gov/cgi-bin/getpage.cgi?dbname=92_statutes_at_large&amp;position=all&amp;page=688'>
            85 Stat. 688
          </aref>
          )), and that is on a reservation and recognized as eligible for
          Federal programs and services provided to Indians because of their
          status as Indians; or (2) any Indian tribe or Band on a reservation
          holding a treaty with a State government.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Overissuance
          </E>
           means the dollar value of commodities issued to a household that
          exceeds the dollar value of commodities it was eligible to receive.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Reservation
          </E>
           means the geographically defined area or areas over which an ITO
          exercises governmental jurisdiction so long as such area or areas are
          legally recognized by the Federal or a State government as being set
          aside for the use of Indians.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State
          </E>
           means any one of the fifty States, the District of Columbia, and the
          reservation of an Indian tribe whose ITO meets the requirements of the
          Food Stamp Act of 1977 for participation as a State agency.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State agency
          </E>
           means:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The agency of State government, including the local offices
            thereof, which enters into an agreement with FNS for the
            distribution of commodities on all or part of an Indian reservation,
            and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The ITO of any Indian tribe, determined by the Department to be
            capable of effectively administering a Food Distribution Program,
            which enters into an agreement with FNS for the distribution of
            commodities on all or part of an Indian reservation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Urban place
          </E>
           means a town or city with a population of 10,000 or more.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            44 FR 35928
          </aref>
          , June 19, 1979. Redesignated and amended by Amdt. 1, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            47 FR 14137
          </aref>
          , Apr. 2, 1982; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            59 FR 1449
          </aref>
          , Jan. 11, 1994; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            64 FR 73382
          </aref>
          , Dec. 30, 1999; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 4473
          </aref>
          , Jan. 28, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4854'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:B:253:-:253.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        253.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Availability of commodities.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          44 FR 35928
        </aref>
        , June 19, 1979. Redesignated by Amdt. 1, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          47 FR 14137
        </aref>
        , Apr. 2, 1982, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          65 FR 47833
        </aref>
        , Aug. 4, 2000]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='605' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='253' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              253.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Availability of commodities.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Conditions for distribution.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In jurisdictions where the Food Stamp Program is in operation,
            there shall be no distribution of commodities to households under
            the authority of any law, except that distribution may be made (1)
            on a temporary basis under programs authorized by law to meet
            disaster relief needs, (2) for the purpose of the Commodity
            Supplemental Food Program, and (3) whenever a request for concurrent
            or separate Food Distribution Program on a reservation is made by an
            ITO.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Concurrent or separate food program operation.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Distribution of commodities, with or without the Food Stamp
            Program, shall be made whenever an ITO submits to FNS a completed
            application for the Food Distribution Program on all or part of a
            reservation and the application is approved by FNS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as provided in paragraph (b)(2) of this section, when the
            Food Distribution Program is operating on all or part of a
            reservation, all eligible households within those boundaries may
            participate in the Food Distribution Program, or, if the ITO has
            elected concurrent operation of the Food Stamp Program, may elect to
            participate in either program, without regard to whether the
            household is an Indian tribal household.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS may determine, based on the number of non-Indian tribal
            households located on all or part of a reservation, that concurrent
            operation is necessary. When such a determination has been made all
            households residing in such areas may apply to participate in either
            the Food Stamp or the Food Distribution Program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Household distribution.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Commodities acquired under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 416 of
            </aref>
             the Agricultural Act of 1949, as amended; 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 32 of
            </aref>
             Pub. L. 320, 74th Congress, as amended; 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 709 of
            </aref>
             the Food and Agricultural Act of 1963, as amended; and 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 4(a) of
            </aref>
             the Agriculture and Consumer Protection Act of 1973, as amended, by
            
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 1304 of
            </aref>
             the Food and Agriculture Act of 1977, may be made available under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='250' tq='N'>
                250 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
             for distribution to households in accordance with the provisions of
            that part and the additional provisions and requirements of this
            part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Food distribution program benefits.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Households eligible under this part shall receive a monthly food
            package based on the number of household members. The food package
            offered to each household shall consist of a quantity and variety of
            commodities made available by the Department to provide eligible
            households with an opportunity to obtain a more nutritious diet and
            shall represent an acceptable nutritional alternative to Food Stamp
            Program benefits. The food package offered to each household by the
            State agency shall contain a variety of foods from each of the food
            groups in the Food Distribution Program on Indian Reservations
            Monthly Distribution Guide Rates by Household Size—Vegetables,
            Fruit, Bread-Cereal-Rice-Pasta, Meat-Poultry-Fish-Dry
            Beans-Eggs-Nuts, Milk-Yogurt-Cheese, and Fats-Oils-Sweets. FNS shall
            periodically notify State agencies of the kinds of commodities it
            proposes to make available based, insofar as practicable, on the
            preferences of eligible households as determined by the State
            agency. In the event one or more of the proposed commodities cannot
            be delivered, the Department shall arrange for delivery of a similar
            commodity within the same food group.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            44 FR 35928
          </aref>
          , June 19, 1979. Redesignated by Amdt. 1, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            47 FR 14137
          </aref>
          , Apr. 2, 1982, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            65 FR 47833
          </aref>
          , Aug. 4, 2000]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4855'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:B:253:-:253.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        253.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Administration.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          44 FR 35928
        </aref>
        , June 19, 1979, as amended by Amdt. 163, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          45 FR 14006
        </aref>
        , Mar. 4, 1980. Redesignated and amended by Amdt. 1, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          47 FR 14137
        </aref>
        , Apr. 2, 1982]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='253' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              253.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Administration.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Federal administration.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Within the Department of Agriculture, the Food and Nutrition
            Service (FNS) shall be responsible for the Food Distribution
            Program. FNS shall have the power to determine the amount of any
            claim and to settle and adjust any claim.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              State agency administration.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If FNS determines that the ITO is capable of effective and
            efficient administration, the ITO shall administer the Food
            Distribution Program on all or part of the reservation. If FNS
            determines that the ITO is not capable of effective and efficient
            administration of the Food Distribution Program, the appropriate
            agency of the State government shall be responsible for the Food
            Distribution Program on all or part of 
            <PRTPAGE P='606' />
            the Indian reservation. In addition, the appropriate agency of the
            State government may administer the Program on behalf of an
            otherwise capable tribe if agreed to in writing by both parties.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the case where the Indian reservation boundaries cross State
            lines, the ITO and appropriate State agencies may jointly request
            FNS approval that a single State agency administer the Food
            Distribution Program on all or part of the Indian reservation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An agency of State government responsible for administering the
            Food Distribution Program may contract Program functions to an ITO.
            These functions include, but are not limited to, outreach,
            preparation of bilingual materials, commodity issuance,
            determination of food preferences of households, publicizing uses of
            commodities, and transportation and on-site delivery services. The
            State agency may also use the ITO in prescreening translations,
            interpretive services and other noncertification functions. The
            State agency shall not contract responsibility for certification
            activities such as interviews or eligibility determinations with an
            ITO that has been determined incapable of administering the Food
            Distribution Program. In all cases the State agency shall retain
            full responsibility for program administration.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Qualification as a reservation.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The appropriate ITO of an established Indian reservation will
            qualify for participation under the provisions of this part, when
            that ITO files an application which demonstrates the status of an
            area as an established reservation, unless FNS determines that such
            area(s) does not qualify as a reservation as that term is defined in
            these regulations. For purposes of this part, established
            reservation means the geographically defined area(s) currently
            recognized and established by Federal or State treaty or by Federal
            statute whereby such geographically defined area(s) is set aside for
            the use of Indians. Where such established areas exist, the
            appropriate ITO is presumed to exercise governmental jurisdiction,
            unless otherwise determined by FNS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The appropriate ITO for other areas, in order to qualify as
            reservations for the provisions of this part, must show to FNS:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             That the ITO exercises governmental jurisdiction over a geographic
            area(s) which enjoys legal recognition from the Federal or a State
            government and is set aside for the use of Indians;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A clear and precise description of the boundaries of such
            geographic area(s).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Application by an ITO.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any ITO which desires to participate in the Food Distribution
            Program shall file an application with the FNS Regional Office
            serving the State or States in which the reservation is located. The
            ITO shall specify if it is requesting the Food Distribution Program
            alone or concurrently with the Food Stamp Program. The ITO shall
            also specify whether it wants either or both programs on all or part
            of the reservation, and if on part, shall describe the geographic
            boundaries of the relevant part(s). Additionally, if the ITO wishes
            to serve areas near the reservation, the ITO shall describe the
            geographic boundaries of the near area(s) for FNS review and
            approval. Any urban place inside a reservation can be served by the
            Food Distribution Program. Any urban place outside reservation
            boundaries may not be served. However, an ITO or State agency can
            request the Department to change those limitations with
            justification. The ITO application shall also provide other
            information requested by FNS, including but not limited to, that the
            ITO serves an established reservation or a reservation otherwise
            qualified as described in paragraph (c) of this section. Properly
            addressed applications shall be acknowledged by the FNS Regional
            Office in writing within five working days of receipt.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Tribal capability.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In determining whether the ITO on a given reservation is
            potentially capable of effectively and efficiently administering a
            Food Distribution Program, allowing for fulfillment of that
            potential through training and technical assistance, FNS shall
            consult with other sources, such as the BIA, and shall consider the
            ITO&apos;s experience, if any, in operating other government
            programs 
            <PRTPAGE P='607' />
            and its management and fiscal capabilities. Other factors for
            evaluation include, but are not limited to, the ITO&apos;s ability
            to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Order and properly store commodities,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Certify eligible households,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Arrange for physical issuance of commodities,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Keep appropriate records and submit required reports,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_1_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Budget and account for administrative funds,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_1_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Determine the food preferences of households, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_1_vii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Conduct on-site reviews of certification and distribution
            procedures and practices.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Food and Nutrition Service (FNS) shall make a determination of
            potential Indian Tribal Organization (ITO) capability within 30 days
            of receipt of a completed application for the Food Distribution
            Program. FNS shall promptly advise ITOs of the need for additional
            information if an incomplete application is received.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS shall, if requested by an ITO which has been determined by FNS
            to be potentially capable of administering a Food Distribution
            Program, provide the ITO&apos;s designees with appropriate training
            and technical assistance to prepare the ITO to take over program
            administration. In determining what training and technical
            assistance are necessary, FNS shall consult with the ITO and other
            sources, such as the BIA.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            44 FR 35928
          </aref>
          , June 19, 1979, as amended by Amdt. 163, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            45 FR 14006
          </aref>
          , Mar. 4, 1980. Redesignated and amended by Amdt. 1, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            47 FR 14137
          </aref>
          , Apr. 2, 1982]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4856'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:B:253:-:253.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        253.5
      </num>
      <head>
        State agency requirements.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          44 FR 35928
        </aref>
        , June 19, 1979, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          47 FR 746
        </aref>
        , Jan. 7, 1982. Redesignated and amended by Amdt. 1, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          47 FR 14137
        </aref>
        , Apr, 2, 1982; Amdt. 2, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          47 FR 19665
        </aref>
        , May 7, 1982; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          48 FR 29123
        </aref>
        , June 24, 1983; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          62 FR 53731
        </aref>
        , Oct. 16, 1997; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          64 FR 73383
        </aref>
        , Dec. 30, 1999; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          65 FR 47833
        </aref>
        , Aug. 4, 2000]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='253' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              253.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          State agency requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Plan of operation.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency that assumes responsibility for the Food
            Distribution Program shall submit a plan of operation for approval
            by FNS. Approval of the plan shall be a prerequisite to the donation
            of commodities available for use by households under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='250' tq='N'>
                250 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . The approved plan shall be considered permanent, with amendments
            to be added as changes in State agency administration or management
            of the program, as described in the plan, are made, or at the
            request of FNS. No amendment to the plan of operation of any State
            agency shall be effective without prior approval of FNS, and FNS may
            require amendment of any plan as a condition of continuing approval.
            If the agency is not an ITO, the appropriate agency of the State
            government shall also:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Consult in good faith with the ITO on the reservation where the
            appropriate agency of the State government is responsible for
            administering the Food Distribution Program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A State agency which is not an ITO shall submit its plan of
            operation, budget and any substantive subsequent amendments to the
            ITO for comment at least 45 days prior to submission of the plan,
            budget or amendment to FNS. Comments by the ITO shall be attached to
            the plan, budget or amendment which is submitted to FNS. This
            paragraph does not apply to amendments required by FNS under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='253' sect='7' psec='#a_1' tq='N'>
                253.7(a)(1)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The plan of operation shall describe the manner in which
            commodities will be distributed, including, but not limited to, the
            storage and distribution facilities to be used, the procedures to
            assure ongoing consultation with the ITO where the appropriate
            agency of the State government administers the Program, the method
            by which the food preferences of households shall be determined, the
            manner in which the State agency plans to supervise the Food
            Distribution Program, and plans by which the State agency will
            control dual participation. The plan shall also include by reference
            or otherwise the following assurances:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No household on any Indian reservation shall be permitted to
            participate simultaneously in the Food Stamp Program and the Food
            Distribution Program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The value of the commodities provided to any eligible household
            shall not be considered income or resources for any purposes under
            any Federal, State, or local laws, including, but not limited to,
            laws relating to taxation, welfare, and public assistance programs;
            and no State agency shall decrease any assistance otherwise provided
            to a household because of the receipt of commodities.
            <PRTPAGE P='608' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The distribution of commodities shall not be used as a means for
            furthering the political interest of any individual or party.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             There shall be no discrimination in the certification of applicant
            households or in the distribution of commodities because of sex,
            race, color, age, political beliefs, religion, handicap or national
            origin.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Households shall not be required to make any payments in money,
            materials or services for, or in connection with, the receipt of
            commodities; and they shall not be solicited in connection with the
            receipt of commodities for voluntary cash contributions for any
            purpose.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Adequate personnel, including supervisory personnel, to review the
            Food Distribution Program shall be provided to ensure compliance
            with the requirements of this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_vii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Use of disclosure of information obtained from food distribution
            applicant households, exclusively for the Food Distribution Program,
            shall be restricted to persons directly connected with the
            administration or enforcement of the provisions of the Food
            Distribution Programs as defined in this part of this subchapter,
            the Food Stamp Act or regulations, or with other Federal or
            federally aided, means-tested assistance programs such as title IV-A
            (TANF), XIX (Medicaid), or XVI (SSI), or with general assistance
            programs that are subject to the joint processing requirements
            specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='273' sect='2' psec='#j_2' tq='N'>
                273.2(j)(2)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Operating manuals.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall maintain ongoing consultation with the ITO
            in developing the State agency&apos;s written internal policies,
            instructions, and forms which are necessary to carry out the Food
            Distribution Program and shall submit them to FNS for approval prior
            to their use. The State agency shall file any comments or
            recommendations offered by the ITO, for review by FNS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Staffing.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Personnel used in the certification process shall be employed in
            accordance with (1) the current standards for a Merit System of
            Personnel Administration or any standards later prescribed by the
            Office of Personnel Management under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 208 of
            </aref>
             the Intergovernmental Personnel Act of 1970 or (2) when
            appropriate, the ITO&apos;s personnel system if it incorporates the
            basic elements of a merit system.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Bilingual requirements.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall provide bilingual staff, certification
            forms, including the application form and certification notices as
            specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='253' sect='7' psec='#a_2' tq='N'>
                253.7(a)(2) and (b)(3)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , respectively, and any form developed by the State agency for
            reporting changes in household composition and income, pursuant to 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='253' sect='7' psec='#c' tq='N'>
                253.7(c)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , and outreach materials, when either an estimated 100 or more low
            income households or the majority of low-income households on the
            reservation are a single language minority. Single-language minority
            refers to households which speak the same non-English language and
            which do not contain adults(s) fluent in English as a second
            language. If the non-English language is spoken but not written, the
            State agency shall provide bilingual staff, if required, but not
            bilingual material.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall ensure that offices serving reservations
            subject to the criteria in paragraph (d)(1) of this section provide
            sufficient bilingual staff for the timely processing of non-English
            speaking applicants.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall develop estimates of the numbers of
            low-income, single-language minority households by using census data
            (including the Census Bureau&apos;s Current Population Report:
            Population Estimates and Projections, Series P-25, No. 627) and
            knowledge of the reservation. Local Bureau of Census offices,
            Community Services Administration offices, Community Action
            agencies, Bureau of Indian Affairs, Indian Health Services, planning
            agencies, the ITO and school officials may be important sources of
            information in determining the need for bilingual services.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Outreach and referral.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall inform potentially eligible households of
            the availability of the Food Distribution Program. The State agency
            shall develop and distribute printed information in the appropriate
            languages about the Program and eligibility requirements. Outreach
            material shall contain information about a household&apos;s right to
            file an application on the same date it contacts 
            <PRTPAGE P='609' />
            the certification office. The State agency shall be sufficiently
            familiar with general eligibility requirements for the Supplemental
            Food Program for Women, Infants and Children (WIC) or the Commodity
            Supplemental Food Program, if available to reservation residents,
            the Supplemental Security Income Program (SSI), and appropriate
            public and general assistance programs, to identify those applicants
            whose households contain persons who may be eligible for these
            programs, to inform the applicants of their potential eligibility,
            and to provide the applicants with the addresses and telephone
            numbers for these programs. For example, the State agency should
            provide information on the WIC program to applicants whose
            households contain pregnant women, nursing or postpartum women, or
            children up to the fifth birthday.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Training requirements.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall institute a training program for all
            personnel who are assigned responsibility for the certification of
            applicant households, for fair hearing officers, for field
            supervisors who review local Food Distribution Programs, for those
            involved in outreach and those responsibile for ordering, storing,
            and distributing commodities.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State agency training programs shall cover eligibility criteria,
            certification procedures, commodity ordering, storage and
            distribution practices, household rights and responsibilities and
            other job-related responsibilities. The content of the training
            material shall be reviewed and revised periodically to correct
            deficiencies in program operations or reflect changes in policy and
            procedures.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS shall review the effectiveness of State agency training based
            on information obtained from field reviews, administrative analyses
            and other sources.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Nutrition education.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall publicize how commodities may be used to
            contribute to a nutritious diet and how commodities may be properly
            stored by means of visual displays, and printed material. The State
            agency shall encourage appropriate organizations, county extension
            home economists, expanded Food and Nutrition Program aides, and
            qualified volunteers to provide food and nutrition information,
            menus, or cooking demonstrations, as appropriate for participating
            households. The State agency shall encourage the dissemination of
            food and nutrition information designed to improve the nutrition of
            households on reservations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Records and reports.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall keep records and submit reports and other
            information as required by FNS. Records required under this part
            shall be retained for a period of three years from the date of the
            submission of the annual financial status report, SF-269; except
            that, if any litigation, claim or audit is started before the
            expiration of the three year period, the records shall be retained
            until all litigation, claims or audit findings involving the records
            have been resolved.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Monitoring.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In accordance with its responsibility for efficient and effective
            program administration the State agency shall monitor and review its
            operations under this part to ensure compliance with the provisions
            of this part and with any applicable instructions of FNS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall review program operations at least annually,
            document program deficiencies and establish and implement specific
            plans of corrective action for deficiencies noted.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Reviews of operations shall include, but not be limited to,
            certification of households, determination of food preferences,
            distribution of commodities, fair hearing procedures, commodity
            inventories and timeliness and accuracy of reports to FNS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Program reviews and corrective action plans shall be available to
            FNS upon request.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Investigations and complaints.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall promptly investigate complaints received of
            irregularities in the handling, distribution, receipt or use of
            commodities, other than use of commodities by eligible households in
            the preparation of meals for home consumption, and shall take
            appropriate action to correct any irregularities. The State agency
            shall also promptly investigate complaints of irregularities
            relating to certification procedures or the delivery of services and
            shall take appropriate action to 
            <PRTPAGE P='610' />
            correct any irregularities or noncompliance with provisions relating
            to certification procedures, provision of services or household
            rights. The State agency shall document each investigation and
            action in sufficient detail to allow for FNS review of all State
            agency actions and information. The Department shall make
            investigations at the request of the State agency and ITO or when
            the Department determines an investigation is necessary.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Sanctions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the State agency fails to comply with the provisions of this
            part or its plan of operation, FNS may:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='k_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Take action against any State agency under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='253' sect='11' psec='#g' tq='N'>
                253.11(g)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             with respect to administrative funds available from FNS for use by
            the State agency or (2) disqualify the State agency from further
            distribution of commodities to households. Disqualification of the
            State agency shall not prevent FNS or the Department from taking
            other actions, including prosecution under applicable Federal
            statutes, when deemed necessary. Reinstatement shall be contingent
            upon approval by FNS of the State agency&apos;s plan for corrective
            action or determination by FNS that the State agency has complied
            with any other requirements for reinstatement which FNS may set
            forth. These provisions apply to all State agencies, regardless of
            whether the Program is administered by an agency of the State
            government or an ITO. If the ITO is disqualified as a State agency,
            an appropriate agency of State government shall administer the Food
            Distribution Program on the reservation. If an agency of State
            government is disqualified as the State agency for the Food
            Distribution Program on the reservation, the ITO may request in
            writing a capability determination for program administration in
            accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='253' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
                253.4
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='l'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (l)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Appeals.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='l_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The agency of the State government or an ITO may appeal an initial
            determination by FNS on:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='l_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whether or not the reservation definition is met;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='l_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The capability of an ITO to administer the Food Distribution
            Program;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='l_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Sanctions taken under paragraph (k) of this section or 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='253' sect='11' psec='#g' tq='N'>
                253.11(g)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='l_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Federal matching percentage level of administrative funding
            made available by FNS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='l_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             At the time FNS advises the State agency or ITO of its
            determination, FNS shall also advise the State agency or ITO of its
            right to appeal and, except for appeals of funding determinations,
            shall advise the State agency or ITO of its right to request either
            a meeting to present its position in person or a review of the
            record. On appeals of funding determinations, FNS shall advise the
            State agency or ITO that it may indicate if it wishes a meeting,
            however, FNS need schedule a meeting only if FNS determines a
            meeting is warranted to reach a proper adjudication of the matter.
            Otherwise, FNS shall review supportive information submitted by the
            State agency or ITO in paragraph (l)(3)(ii) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='l_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Procedure—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='l_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Time limit.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any State agency or ITO that wants to appeal an initial FNS
            determination under paragraph (l) of this section must notify the
            Administrator of FNS, in writing, within 15 days from the date of
            the determination. If the appeal concerns either paragraph (l)(1)
            (i) or (ii) of this section, the implementation timeframes as
            specified in paragraph (m) of this section and the timeframe for
            determining an ITO&apos;s capability as specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='253' sect='4' psec='#e_2' tq='N'>
                253.4(e)(2)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             are suspended from the date the appeal is requested to the date of
            the final determination.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='l_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Acknowledgment.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Within five days of receipt by the Administrator, of FNS, of a
            request for review, FNS shall provide the State agency or ITO with a
            written acknowledgment of the request by certified mail, return
            receipt requested. The acknowledgment shall include the name and
            address of the official designated by the Administrator, FNS, to
            review the appeal. The acknowledgment shall also notify the State
            agency or ITO that within ten days of receipt of the acknowledgment,
            the State agency or ITO shall submit written information in support
            of its position.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='l_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Scheduling a meeting.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the Administrator, FNS, grants a meeting FNS shall advise the
            State agency or ITO of the time, date and location of the 
            <PRTPAGE P='611' />
            meeting by certified mail, return receipt requested at least ten
            days in advance of the meeting. FNS shall schedule and conduct the
            meeting and make a decision within 60 days of the receipt of the
            information submitted in response to paragraph (l)(3)(ii) of this
            section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='l_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Review.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If no meeting is conducted the official designated by the
            Administrator, FNS, shall review information presented by a State
            agency or ITO which requests a review and shall make a final
            determination in writing within 45 days of the receipt of the State
            agency&apos;s or ITO&apos;s information submitted in response to
            paragraph (l)(3)(ii) of this section setting forth in full the
            reasons for the determination.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='l_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Final decision.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The official&apos;s decision after a meeting or a review shall be
            final.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='m'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (m)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Implementation.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall implement changes required by amendments to
            these regulations in accordance with schedules specified in the
            amendment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='m_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Amendment 2.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If an ITO currently participates in, but does not administer, the
            Food Distribution Program on Indian Reservations:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_1_ii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS shall determine tribal eligibility and capability to administer
            the Food Distribution Program on Indian Reservations within 60 days
            of receipt of a completed application. If an incomplete application
            is received, FNS shall within 15 days, notify the ITO of what
            additional information is required. The processing time for the
            capability determination shall start from the date the additional
            information is received by FNS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_1_ii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon FNS&apos; determination that the ITO will administer the Food
            Distribution Program on Indian Reservations, FNS shall expeditiously
            plan for and provide needed training and technical assistance to
            facilitate timely commencement of tribal administrative
            responsibilities. The ITO shall have 120 days from FNS&apos;
            determination in paragraph (m)(1)(i)(A) of this section to submit
            and have approved a plan of operation, operating manuals, and to
            commence program operations under the regulations as specified in
            this part. Extensions may be granted by FNS to ITOs if good cause is
            shown.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_1_ii_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If FNS determines that an ITO is not capable of administering the
            Food Distribution Program on Indian Reservations, FNS shall direct
            the State to continue program operations and submit a new plan of
            operation and to commence program operations under the regulations
            as specified in this part within 120 days from FNS&apos;
            determination in paragraph (m)(1)(i)(A) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If an ITO currently administers the Food Distribution Program on
            Indian Reservations, the timeframes specified in paragraph (m)(1)(i)
            of this section apply except that:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_1_ii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS shall determine tribal eligibility and capability to administer
            the Food Distribution Program on Indian Reservations within 30 days
            of receipt of a completed application.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_1_ii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If FNS determines that the ITO will not administer the Food
            Distribution Program on Indian Reservations, FNS shall direct the
            ITO to continue program operations until the State government can
            commence program operations. The State government shall have 120
            days from FNS&apos; determination in paragraph (m)(1)(i)(A) of this
            section to submit and have approved a plan of operation and to
            commence program operations under the regulations as specified in
            this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If an ITO does not currently participate in a Food Distribution
            Program on Indian Reservations, the timeframes in paragraph
            (m)(1)(i) of this section apply except that if FNS determines that
            an ITO cannot administer the program, FNS shall direct the State to
            submit a plan of operation and to commence program operations under
            the regulations as specified in this part within 180 days from the
            determination.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Extensions to the above implementation timeframe (except for those
            timeframes set forth in paragraphs (m)(1) (i)(A) and (ii)(A) of this
            section) may be granted by FNS to ITOs or State government agencies
            if there is compelling justification involving circumstances which
            were not reasonably foreseeable and which are not the fault of the
            ITO or the State agency and 
            <PRTPAGE P='612' />
            which circumstances present extraordinary problems that would render
            earlier implementation impossible.
          </text>
        </P>
        <APPRO>
          (Approved by the Office of Management and Budget under control number
          0584-0071)
        </APPRO>
        <SECAUTH>
          (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='44' sect='3506' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/44/3506.html'>
              44 U.S.C. 3506
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; E.O. 12372, July 14, 1982, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            47 FR 30959
          </aref>
          , 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            sec. 401(b) of
          </aref>
           the Intergovernmental Cooperation Act of 1968, 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='31' sect='6506' note='' psec='#c' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/31/6506.html#c'>
              31 U.S.C. 6506(c)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          )
        </SECAUTH>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            44 FR 35928
          </aref>
          , June 19, 1979, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            47 FR 746
          </aref>
          , Jan. 7, 1982. Redesignated and amended by Amdt. 1, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            47 FR 14137
          </aref>
          , Apr, 2, 1982; Amdt. 2, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            47 FR 19665
          </aref>
          , May 7, 1982; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            48 FR 29123
          </aref>
          , June 24, 1983; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            62 FR 53731
          </aref>
          , Oct. 16, 1997; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            64 FR 73383
          </aref>
          , Dec. 30, 1999; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            65 FR 47833
          </aref>
          , Aug. 4, 2000]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4857'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:B:253:-:253.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        253.6
      </num>
      <head>
        Eligibility of households.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          44 FR 35928
        </aref>
        , June 19, 1979. Redesignated by Amdt. 1, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          47 FR 14137
        </aref>
        , Apr. 2, 1982, and amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          59 FR 1449
        </aref>
        , Jan. 11, 1994; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          64 FR 73383
        </aref>
        , Dec. 30, 1999; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          65 FR 47833
        </aref>
        , Aug. 4, 2000; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 4473
        </aref>
        ; Jan. 28, 2010; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          76 FR 18865
        </aref>
        , Apr. 6, 2011]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='253' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              253.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Eligibility of households.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Household concept.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall determine eligibility for the Food
            Distribution Program on a household basis. Household means any of
            the following individuals or groups of individuals, provided that
            such individuals or groups are not boarders or residents of an
            institution and provided that separate household or boarder status
            shall not be granted to a spouse of a member of the household, or to
            children under 18 years of age under the parental control of a
            member of the household.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An individual living alone.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An individual living with others, but customarily purchasing food
            and preparing meals for home consumption separate and apart from the
            others.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A group of individuals living together for whom food is customarily
            purchased in common and for whom meals are prepared together for
            home consumption.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Nonhousehold members.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The following individuals residing with a household shall not be
            considered household members in determining the household&apos;s
            eligibility. Nonhousehold members specified in paragraphs (a)(2) (i)
            and (v) who are otherwise eligible may participate in the Program as
            separate households.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Roomers.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Individuals to whom a household furnishes lodging, but not meals,
            for compensation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
            <head>
              SSI recipients in “cash-out” States.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Recipients of SSI benefits who reside in a State designated by the
            Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare to have specifically
            included the value of the coupon allotment in its State supplemental
            payments. These persons are not eligible for Food Distribution
            Program benefits.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Disqualified individuals.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Individuals disqualified from the Food Stamp Program for fraud, as
            set forth in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='273' sect='16' psec='' tq='N'>
                273.16
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Illegal residents.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Individuals who are not legal residents of the United States. While
            U.S. citizenship is not required for participation in the Food
            Distribution Program, persons receiving food distribution benefits
            must be lawfully living in the United States.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Others.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Other individuals who share living quarters with the household but
            who do not customarily purchase food and prepare meals with the
            household. For example, if the applicant household shares living
            quarters with another family to save on rent, but does not purchase
            and prepare food together with that family, the members of the other
            family are not members of the applicant household.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Authorized representatives.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The head of the household, spouse, or any other responsible member
            of the household may designate an authorized representative to act
            on behalf of the household in making application for commodities
            and/or obtaining commodities as provided in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='253' sect='7' psec='#a_10_i' tq='N'>
                253.7(a)(10)(i)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='253' sect='7' psec='#a_10_ii' tq='N'>
                253.7(a)(10)(ii)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             respectively.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Residency or citizenship.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All households residing on a reservation on which the FDPIR
            operates shall be eligible to apply for program benefits on that
            reservation regardless of whether they include an Indian member. All
            Indian tribal households as defined in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='253' sect='2' psec='#c' tq='N'>
                253.2(c)
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
             which reside in near areas established under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='253' sect='4' psec='#d' tq='N'>
                253.4(d)
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
             shall be eligible to apply for program benefits. The ITO or State
            agency shall serve all income-eligible applicant households residing
            on reservations who apply for benefits, and all income-eligible
            applicant Indian tribal households residing in near areas. The ITO
            or State agency administering the program in a near area shall, for
            purposes of determining program eligibility, accept documentation
            from a household member&apos;s tribe of origin as proof of tribal
            membership. Residency shall not mean domicile nor shall the State
            agency impose any durational residency requirement. However, persons
            on the reservation 
            <PRTPAGE P='613' />
            solely for vacations shall not be considered residents. No household
            may participate in the Food Stamp Program or in the Food
            Distribution Program in more than one geographical area at the same
            time.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No person shall participate in the Food Distribution Program on an
            Indian reservation unless the person is legally a resident of the
            United States. A further discussion of “legal residency” is provided
            in paragraph (a)(2)(iv) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Income and resource eligibility standards of public assistance,
              supplemental security income, and certain general assistance
              households.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Households in which all members are included in a federally aided
            public assistance or supplemental security income grant, except as
            provided for in paragraph (a)(2)(ii) of this section, shall, if
            otherwise eligible under this part, be determined to be eligible to
            participate in the Food Distribution Program while receiving such
            grants without regard to the income and resources of the household
            members.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If FNS determines that a State or local general assistance program
            applies criteria of need the same as or similar to, those applied
            under any of the federally aided public assistance programs,
            households in which all members are included in such a general
            assistance grant, shall, if otherwise eligible under this part, be
            determined to be eligible to participate in the Food Distribution
            Program while receiving such grants without regard to the income and
            resources of household members.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Resource eligibility standards—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Uniform household standards for nonassistance households.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall apply uniform national resource standards of
            eligibility to all applicant households, except those in which all
            members are recipients of federally aided public assistance,
            supplemental security income, or certain general assistance program
            benefits as provided in paragraph (c)(2) of this section. The
            household&apos;s maximum allowable resources shall not exceed the
            limits established for the Supplemental Nutrition Assistance
            Program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Resources.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In determining the resources of a household, only cash on hand,
            money in checking or savings accounts, savings certificates, stocks,
            or bonds, or other readily negotiable and accessible certificates or
            instruments shall be counted; except that the following resources
            shall be entirely excluded:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The cash value of life insurance policies and the first $1,500 of
            the equity value of one bona fide pre-paid funeral agreement per
            household member. The equity value of a pre-paid funeral agreement
            is the value that can be legally converted to cash by the household
            member. For example, an individual has a $1,200 pre-paid funeral
            agreement with a funeral home. The conditions of the agreement allow
            the household to cancel the agreement and receive a refund of the
            $1,200 minus a service fee of $50. The equity value of the pre-paid
            funeral agreement is $1,150.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The value of funds held in retirement accounts described in 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              sections 401(a), 403(a), 403(b), 408, 408A, 457(b), and 501(c)(18)
              of
            </aref>
             the Internal Revenue Code of 1986; the value of funds held in a
            Federal Thrift Savings Plan account as described in 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='5' sect='8439' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/5/8439.html'>
                5 U.S.C. 8439
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ; and any other retirement program or account for which a resource
            exclusion is allowed under the Supplemental Nutrition Assistance
            Program (SNAP).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any governmental payments which are designated for the restoration
            of a home damaged in a disaster, if the household is subject to a
            legal sanction if the funds are not used as intended, for example
            payments made by the Department of Housing and Urban Development
            through the individual and family grant program of disaster loans or
            grants made by the Small Business Administration.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Resources, such as those of students or self-employed persons,
            which have been prorated as income. The treatment of self-employment
            income is explained in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='253' sect='7' psec='#b_1_iii' tq='N'>
                253.7(b)(1)(iii)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Resources which are excluded by express provision of Federal
            statute. The following is the current listing of resources excluded
            by Federal statute:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='d_2_v_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payment received under the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act
            (Pub. L. 92-203, 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 21(a)
            </aref>
             or the Sac and Fox Indian claims agreement 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Pub. L. 94-189' alt='Pub. L. 94-189' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d94:./list/bd/d94pl.lst:189%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Pub. L. 94-189
            </aref>
            );
            <PRTPAGE P='614' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='d_2_v_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payments received by certain Indian tribal members under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Pub. L. 94-114' alt='Pub. L. 94-114' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d94:./list/bd/d94pl.lst:114%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Pub. L. 94-114
            </aref>
            , 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 6
            </aref>
            , regarding submarginal land held in trust by the United States;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='d_2_v_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payments received by certain Indian tribal members under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Pub. L. 94-540' alt='Pub. L. 94-540' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d94:./list/bd/d94pl.lst:540%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Pub. L. 94-540
            </aref>
             regarding the Grand River Bank of Ottawa Indians;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='d_2_v_D'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (D)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Reimbursements from the Uniform Relocation Assistance and Real
            Property Acquistion Policy Act of 1970 (Pub. L. 91-646, 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 216
            </aref>
            );
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='d_2_v_E'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (E)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Earned income tax credits received before January 1, 1980, as a
            result of 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Pub. L. 95-600' alt='Pub. L. 95-600' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d95:./list/bd/d95pl.lst:600%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Pub. L. 95-600
            </aref>
            , the Revenue Act of 1978.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The value of funds held in a qualified education savings program
            described in 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 529 of
            </aref>
             Internal Revenue Code of 1986 or in a Coverdell education savings
            account under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 530 of
            </aref>
             that Code, and any other education savings program or account for
            which a resource exclusion is allowed under SNAP.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Jointly owned resources.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Resources owned jointly by separate households shall be prorated
            between or among those households unless the applicant can
            demonstrate that such resources are inaccessible to it because
            access to the value of the resource is dependent upon the agreement
            of a joint owner who refuses to comply.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Resources of disqualified members.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Resources of individuals disqualified from participation in the
            Food Stamp Program for fraud shall continue to count in their
            entirety to the remaining household members when determining the
            household&apos;s eligibility for the Food Distribution Program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Income—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Income eligibility standards for nonassistance households.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='3'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall apply uniform national income eligibility
            standards for the Food Distribution Program except for households in
            which all members are recipients of public assistance, supplemental
            security income except as provided for in paragraph (a)(2)(ii) of
            this section, paragraph (c) of this section, or certain general
            assistance program payments as provided in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='283' sect='6' psec='#c' tq='N'>
                283.6(c)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . The income eligibility standards shall be the applicable SNAP net
            monthly income eligibility standards for the appropriate area,
            increased by the amount of the applicable SNAP standard deduction
            for that area.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='e_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The income eligibility standards for the Food Distribution Program
            shall be adjusted each October 1, as necessary, to reflect changes
            in the Food Stamp Program income eligibility limits and standard
            deductions.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Definition of income.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Household income shall mean all income from whatever source,
            excluding only items specified in paragraph (e)(3) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Earned income shall include:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_ii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All wages and salaries of an employee.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_ii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The total gross income from a self-employment enterprise, including
            the net profit from the sale of any capital goods or equipment
            related to the business. Ownership of rental property shall be
            considered a self-employment enterprise. Payments from a roomer and
            returns on rental property shall be considered self-employment
            income.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_ii_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Training allowances from vocational and rehabilitative programs
            recognized by Federal, State or local governments, such as the Work
            Incentive Program, and programs authorized by the Job Training
            Partnership Act, to the extent they are not a reimbursement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Unearned income shall include, but not be limited to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_ii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Assistance payments from Federal or Federally aided public
            assistance programs, such as Supplemental Security Income (SSI) or
            Temporary Assistance for Needy Families (TANF), General Assistance
            (GA) programs, or other assistance programs based on need.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_ii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Annuities; pensions; retirement; veteran&apos;s or disability
            benefits; worker&apos;s or unemployment compensation; old-age,
            survivors, or social security benefits; strike benefits; foster care
            payments for children or adults.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_ii_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Support or alimony payments made directly to the household from
            nonhousehold members.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_ii_D'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (D)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Scholarships, education grants, fellowships, deferred payment loans
            for education, veteran&apos;s education benefit and the like in
            excess of amounts excluded under paragraph (e)(3)(iii) of this
            section.
            <PRTPAGE P='615' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_ii_E'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (E)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payments from Government-sponsored programs, dividends, interest,
            royalties, and all other direct money payments from any source which
            can be construed to be a gain or benefit.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_ii_F'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (F)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The earned or unearned income of an individual disqualified from
            participation in the Food Stamp Program for fraud shall continue to
            be counted as income, less the pro rata share for the disqualified
            member. Procedures for calculating this pro rata share are described
            in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='253' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
                253.7
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Income shall not include the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_iii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Monies withheld from an assistance payment, earned income or other
            income source, or monies received from any income source which are
            voluntarily or involuntarily returned to repay a prior overpayment
            received from that income source.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_iii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Child support payments received by TANF recipients which must be
            transferred to the agency administering title IV-D of the Social
            Security Act of 1935, as amended, to maintain TANF eligibility.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Income exclusions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Only the following items shall be excluded from household income
            and no other income shall be disregarded:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any gain or benefit which is not in the form of money payable
            directly to the household, including:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_3_iii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
            <head>
              In-kind income.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Nonmonetary or in-kind benefits, such as meals, clothing, public
            housing, or produce from a garden.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_3_iii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Vendor payments.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A payment made in money on behalf of a household shall be
            considered a vendor payment whenever a person or organization
            outside of the household uses its own funds to make a direct payment
            to either the household&apos;s creditors or a person or organization
            providing a service to the household. For example, if a relative,
            who is not a household member, pays out of its own resources the
            household&apos;s rent directly to the landlord, the payment is
            considered a vendor payment and is not counted as income to the
            household. Also, payments specified by a court order or other
            written support or alimony agreement to go directly to a third party
            rather than the household and support payments which are paid to a
            third party are excluded as vendor payments. Wages garnished or
            diverted by employers, or money deducted or otherwise diverted from
            a household&apos;s public assistance grant by a State for purposes
            such as managing the household&apos;s expenses, shall not be
            considered a vendor payment, since the person or organization making
            the payment is using money payable to the household rather than its
            own funds.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any income in the certification period which is received too
            infrequently or irregularly to be reasonably anticipated, but not in
            excess of $30 in a quarter.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Education loans on which payment is deferred, grants scholarships,
            fellowships, veterans&apos; educational benefits, and the like to
            the extent that they are used for tuition and mandatory school fees.
            Mandatory fees are those charged to all students or those charged to
            all students within a certain curriculum. For example, uniforms, lab
            fees, or equipment charged to all students to enroll in a chemistry
            course would be excluded. However, transportation, supplies, and
            textbook expenses are not uniformly charged to all students and,
            therefore, would not be excluded as mandatory fees.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_3_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All loans, including loans from private individuals as well as
            commercial institutions, other than education loans on which
            repayment is deferred.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_3_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Reimbursements for past or future expenses to the extent they do
            not exceed actual expenses. For example, reimbursements of flat
            allowances for job or training related expenses such as travel per
            diem, uniforms, and transportation to and from the job or training
            site are excluded as income.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_3_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Monies received and used for care and maintenance of a third party
            beneficiary who is not a household member.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_3_vii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The earned income (as defined in paragraph (e)(2)(i) of this
            section) of children who are members of the household, who are
            students at least half time and who have not attained their
            eighteenth birthday. The exclusion shall continue to apply during
            temporary interruptions in school attendance due to semester or
            vaction breaks, provided the child&apos;s enrollment 
            <PRTPAGE P='616' />
            will resume following the break. Individuals are considered children
            for purposes of this provision if they are under the parental
            control of another household member.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_3_viii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (viii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Money received in the form of a nonrecurring lump sum payment,
            including but not limited to, income tax refunds, rebates, or
            credits; retroactive lump-sum social security, SSI, public
            assistance, railroad retirement benefits or other payments, or
            retroactive lump-sum insurance settlements; refunds of security
            deposits on rental properties or utilities or lump-sum payments
            arising from land interests held in trust for, or by, a tribe. These
            payments shall be counted as resources in the month received unless
            specifically excluded from consideration as a resource by other
            Federal law.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_3_ix'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ix)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The cost of producing self-employment income. The procedures for
            computing the cost of producing self-employment income are described
            in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='253' sect='7' psec='#b_1_iii' tq='N'>
                253.7(b)(1)(iii)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_3_x'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (x)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any income that is specifically excluded by any other Federal
            statute from consideration as income. The following Federal statutes
            provide such an exclusion.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_3_x_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Reimbursements from the Uniform Relocation Assistance and Real
            Property Acquisition Policy Act of 1970 (Pub. L. 91-646, 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 216
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_3_x_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payments received under the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act
            (Pub. L. 92-203, 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 21(a)
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_3_x_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any payment to volunteers under Title II (RSVP, foster
            grandparents, and others) and title III (SCORE and ACE) of the
            Domestic Volunteer Services Act of 1973 (
            <aref target='_blank' title='Pub. L. 93-113' alt='Pub. L. 93-113' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d93:./list/bd/d93pl.lst:113%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Pub. L. 93-113
            </aref>
            ), as amended. Payments under title I (VISTA) to volunteers shall be
            excluded for those individuals receiving federally donated
            commodities, food stamps, or public assistance at the time they
            joined the title I program, except that households which are
            receiving an income exclusion for a VISTA or other title I
            subsistence allowance at the time of implementation of these rules
            shall continue to receive an income exclusion for VISTA for the
            length of their volunteer contract in effect at the time of
            implementation of these rules. Temporary interruptions in food
            distribution shall not alter the exclusion once an initial
            determination has been made. New applicants who are not receiving
            federally donated commodities, food stamps or public assistance at
            the time they joined VISTA shall have these volunteer payments
            included as earned income.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_3_x_D'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (D)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Income derived from certain submarginal land of the United States
            which is held in trust for certain Indian tribes (
            <aref target='_blank' title='Pub. L. 94-114' alt='Pub. L. 94-114' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d94:./list/bd/d94pl.lst:114%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Pub. L. 94-114
            </aref>
            , 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 6
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_3_x_E'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (E)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payments received by certain Indian tribal members under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Pub. L. 94-540' alt='Pub. L. 94-540' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d94:./list/bd/d94pl.lst:540%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Pub. L. 94-540
            </aref>
             regarding the Grand River Band of Ottawa Indians.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_3_xi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (xi)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Combat pay.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Combat pay is defined as additional payment that is received by or
            from a member of the United States Armed Forces deployed to a combat
            zone, if the additional pay is the result of deployment to or
            service in a combat zone, and was not received immediately prior to
            serving in a combat zone.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Income deductions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Households with earned income, as defined in paragraph (e)(2)(i) of
            this section, shall be allowed a deduction of twenty percent of
            their earned income. Earned income excluded under paragraph (e)(3)
            of this section shall not be considered earned income for the
            purpose of computing this deduction.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Households shall also receive a deduction for the actual costs for
            the care of a child or other dependent when necessary for a
            household member to accept or continue employment or attend training
            or pursue education which is preparatory to employment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Households will receive a deduction for legally required child
            support payments paid by a household member to or for a nonhousehold
            member, including payments made to a third party on behalf of the
            nonhousehold member (vendor payments). The State agency must allow a
            deduction for amounts paid towards overdue child support
            (arrearages). Alimony payments made to or for a nonhousehold member
            cannot be included in the child support deduction.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Households will receive a deduction for the full amount of the
            Medicare Part B medical insurance premium that is withheld from the
            Federal retirement or disability payment of a household member or is
            paid by a 
            <PRTPAGE P='617' />
            household member directly to Medicare. This income deduction is not
            allowed in situations where the premium is paid by the State on
            behalf of the Medicare beneficiary or where household members are
            not Medicare beneficiaries because they receive their health care
            through the Indian Health Service.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            44 FR 35928
          </aref>
          , June 19, 1979. Redesignated by Amdt. 1, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            47 FR 14137
          </aref>
          , Apr. 2, 1982, and amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            59 FR 1449
          </aref>
          , Jan. 11, 1994; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            64 FR 73383
          </aref>
          , Dec. 30, 1999; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            65 FR 47833
          </aref>
          , Aug. 4, 2000; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 4473
          </aref>
          ; Jan. 28, 2010; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 18865
          </aref>
          , Apr. 6, 2011]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4858'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:B:253:-:253.7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        253.7
      </num>
      <head>
        Certification of households.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          44 FR 35928
        </aref>
        , June 19, 1979, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          47 FR 746
        </aref>
        , Jan. 7, 1982. Redesignated and amended by Amdt. 1, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          47 FR 14137
        </aref>
        , Apr. 2, 1982; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          64 FR 73383
        </aref>
        , Dec. 30, 1999; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          65 FR 47833
        </aref>
        , Aug. 4, 2000; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 4473
        </aref>
        , Jan. 28, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='253' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              253.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Certification of households.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Application processing—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General purpose.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The application process includes filing and completing an
            application form, being interviewed, and having certain information
            verified. The State agency shall act promptly on all applications.
            Expedited service shall be available to household in immediate need.
            When the State agency is other than the ITO, the ITO, when
            appropriate, may receive copies of certification and/or termination
            notices to the extent requested or agreed upon by the household.
            State agencies and ITOs may develop formalized mechanisms to ensure
            ITO receipt of notices.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Food Distribution Program application form.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall use an application form acceptable to FNS.
            The State agency shall consult with the ITO in developing the
            application form. The State agency shall make application forms
            readily accessible to potentially eligible households and those
            groups or organizations involved in outreach efforts. The State
            agency shall also provide an application form to anyone who requests
            the form. State agencies which elect joint PA or GA/Food
            Distribution Program procedures shall follow the requirements of
            paragraph (g) of this section for the application form. State
            agencies may also use an abbreviated recertification form.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Filing an application.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Households must file an application for the Food Distribution
            Program by submitting the form to a certification office in person,
            through an authorized representative or by mail. The State agency
            shall document the date the application was received. Each household
            has the right to file an application form the same day it contacts
            the certification office during office hours on the reservation
            where the household resides. The household shall be advised that it
            does not have to be interviewed before filing the application and
            may file an incomplete application form as long as the application
            contains the applicant&apos;s name and address and is signed by a
            responsible member of the household or the household&apos;s
            authorized representative.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Household cooperation.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To determine eligibility, the application form must be completed
            and signed, the household or its authorized representative must be
            interviewed, and certain information on the application must be
            verified. If the household refuses to cooperate with the State
            agency in completing this process, the application shall be denied
            upon a determination of refusal. For a determination of refusal to
            be made, the household must be able to cooperate, but clearly
            demonstrate that it will not take actions that it can take and that
            are required to complete the application process. For example, to be
            denied for refusal to cooperate, a household must refuse to be
            interviewed and not merely fail to appear for the interview. If
            there is any question as to whether the household has merely failed
            to cooperate, as opposed to refused to cooperate, the household
            shall not be denied solely for this reason. The household shall also
            be determined ineligible if it refuses to cooperate in any
            subsequent review of its eligibility. Once denied or terminated for
            refusal to cooperate, the household may reapply but shall not be
            determined eligible until it cooperates.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Interviews.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All applicant households, including those submitting applications
            by mail, shall have an interview with a qualified eligibility worker
            prior to initial certification and all recertifications. At State
            agency discretion, applicants may be interviewed by telephone or in
            the home. No household shall be interviewed by telephone for any two
            consecutive certifications without a face-to-face interview. State
            agencies must attempt to schedule home visits in advance. Home
            visits cannot extend required processing standards set forth in
            paragraphs (a)(7) 
            <PRTPAGE P='618' />
            and (a)(9) of this section. The individual interviewed may be the
            head of household, spouse, any other responsible member of the
            household or an authorized representative. The household, if it
            wishes, may be accompanied to the interview by anyone of its choice.
            The interviewer shall not only review the information that appears
            on the application, but shall explore and resolve with the household
            unclear and incomplete information. Households shall be advised of
            their rights and responsibilities during the interview. The
            interview shall be conducted as an official and confidential
            discussion of household circumstances. The applicant&apos;s right to
            privacy shall be protected during the interview. Facilities shall be
            adequate to preserve the privacy and confidentiality of the
            interview.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Verification.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Verification is the use of third party information or documentation
            to establish the accuracy of statements on the application in order
            to determine eligibility or ineligibility of the household.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Mandatory verification.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_6_i_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (A)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Gross non-exempt income.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency must obtain verification of each household&apos;s
            gross non-exempt income prior to certification. Households certified
            under the expedited service processing standards at paragraph (a)(9)
            of this section are not subject to this requirement. Income does not
            need to be verified to the exact dollar amount unless the
            household&apos;s eligibility would be affected, since Food
            Distribution Program benefits are not reduced as income rises. If
            the eligibility worker is unable to verify the household&apos;s
            income, the worker must determine an amount to be used for
            certification purposes based on the best available information.
            Reasons for inability to verify income include failure of the person
            or organization providing the income to cooperate with the household
            and the State agency, or lack of other sources of verification.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_6_i_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Legal obligation and actual child support payments.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency must obtain verification of the household&apos;s
            legal obligation to pay child support, the amount of the obligation,
            and the monthly amount of child support the household actually pays.
            Documentation that verifies the household&apos;s legal obligation to
            pay child support, such as a court order, cannot be used to verify
            the household&apos;s actual monthly child support payments.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_6_i_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Medicare Part B medical insurance premium.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency must obtain verification of the household&apos;s
            payment of the Medicare Part B medical insurance premium.
            Documentation of this expense could include:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          (
          <E T='03'>
            1
          </E>
          ) A copy of the current year Social Security benefit statement
          (SSA-4926-SM), or a similar statement provided to Railroad Retirement
          Board and Civil Service Retirement beneficiaries, which identifies the
          amount of the Medicare Part B premium withheld each month; or
        </P>
        <P>
          (
          <E T='03'>
            2
          </E>
          ) A receipt for Medicare Part B premium payments paid directly to
          Medicare by the household.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_6_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Verification of questionable information.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Eligibility criteria other than income, including residency on or
            near the reservation, shall be verified prior to certification only
            if they are questionable. To be considered questionable, the
            information on the application must be inconsistent with statements
            by the applicant, inconsistent with other information on the
            application or previous applications, or inconsistent with other
            information received by the State agency. However, due to the
            difficulty in verifying whether a group of individuals is a
            household, State agencies shall generally accept the
            household&apos;s statement regarding food preparation and
            consumption.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_6_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Responsibility for obtaining verification.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The household has primary responsibility for providing documentary
            evidence or an acceptable collateral contact to support its income
            statements and to resolve any questionable information. However, the
            State agency shall assist the household in obtaining the needed
            verification. The State agency shall accept any reasonable
            documentary evidence provided by the household and shall be
            primarily concerned with how adequately the verification proves the
            statements on the application. The State agency shall also accept
            verification from collateral contacts so long as the collateral
            contacts can provide accurate third party verification. The State 
            <PRTPAGE P='619' />
            agency shall rely on the household to provide the name of the
            collateral contact. The State agency is not required to use a
            collateral contact designated by the household if the collateral
            contact cannot be expected to provide accurate third party
            verification. If the collateral contact designated by the household
            is unacceptable to the State agency, the State agency shall ask the
            household to designate another collateral contact, and the State
            agency shall document the casefile as to the reason the collateral
            contact was rejected and an alternate was requested. The State
            agency shall use collateral contacts, rather than documentary
            evidence, for verification if such verification is acceptable, and
            would result in better service to the household. For example, the
            household may be able to obtain a wage stub from the employer, but
            the State agency could call the employer the same day to provide the
            verification of income. Home visits shall be used as verification
            only if documentary evidence and collateral contacts cannot be
            obtained, and the State agency attempts to schedule the visit in
            advance with the household.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_6_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Documentation.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Casefiles must be documented to support a determination of
            eligibility or denial. Documentation shall be in sufficient detail
            to permit a reviewer to determine the reasonableness and accuracy of
            the determination.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_6_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Verification for recertification.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             At recertification, the State agency shall verify a change in
            income if the source has changed or the amount has changed by more
            than $50 per month since the last time the income was verified.
            State agencies may verify income which is unchanged or has changed
            by $50 per month or less, provided verification is, at a minimum,
            required when information is questionable as defined in paragraph
            (a)(6)(ii) of this section. All other changes reported at the time
            of recertification shall be subject to the same verification
            procedures as apply at initial certification. Unchanged information,
            other than income, shall not be verified at recertification unless
            the information is questionable as defined in paragraph (a)(6)(ii)
            of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Processing standards.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall provide eligible households that complete
            the initial application process an opportunity to participate as
            soon as possible, but not later than seven calendar days excluding
            weekends and holidays after the application was filed. An
            application is filed the day the State agency receives an
            application containing the applicant&apos;s name and address and
            which is signed by either a responsible member of the household or
            the household&apos;s authorized representative.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Delays in processing.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the State agency cannot determine a household&apos;s eligibility
            within seven calendar days excluding weekends and holidays of the
            date the application was filed due to lack of verification as
            required in paragraph (a)(6) of this section, the State agency shall
            authorize the distribution of commodities to the household for one
            month pending verification. In order to certify the household
            pending verification, the information on the application form must
            be complete and indicate that the household will likely be eligible.
            No further distribution of commodities shall be made without
            completing the eligibility determination.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Expedited service.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall provide an opportunity to obtain commodities
            within one calendar day excluding weekends and holidays after the
            date the application was filed for those households with no income
            in the current month and also for those households which, in the
            judgment of the certifying agency, would likely be eligible and
            would otherwise suffer a hardship. The basis for this determination
            shall be recorded in the casefile. State agencies shall provide same
            day service, if possible, to households eligible for expedited
            service which would likely suffer a hardship if required to return
            to the office the next day. Warehouses or other distribution points
            need not be open during all certification hours to meet this need.
            However, accessibility to federally donated commodities by
            appropriate certification or other personnel should be established
            for households in immediate need. When State agencies can
            demonstrate a need, FNS may approve other expedited timeframes based
            on 
            <PRTPAGE P='620' />
            circumstances such as distance to warehouses or other distribution
            points. To expedite the certification of households in immediate
            need the State agency shall postpone the verification required under
            paragraph (a)(6) of this section. However, the State agency shall
            verify the household&apos;s identity and address through a
            collateral contact or readily available documentary evidence. If
            possible, the household&apos;s income statements should be verified
            at the same time. The State agency shall complete the verification
            for households certified on an expedited basis prior to the
            distribution of commodities to the household for any subsequent
            month.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Authorized representatives.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The head of the household, spouse, or any other responsible member
            of the household may designate an authorized representative to act
            on behalf of the household in one or all of the following
            capacities:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_10_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Making application for commodities.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When the head of the household or the spouse cannot make
            application, another household member may apply or an adult
            nonhousehold member may be designated in writing as the authorized
            representative for that purpose. The head of the household or the
            spouse should prepare or review the application whenever possible,
            even though another household member or the authorized
            representative will actually be interviewed. Adults who are
            nonhousehold members may be designated as authorized representatives
            for certification purposes only if they are sufficiently aware of
            relevant household circumstances.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_10_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Obtaining commodities.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An authorized representative of the household may be designated to
            obtain commodities. Designation shall be made at the time the
            application is completed except that the household may be permitted
            to designate an emergency authorized representative in the event
            that illness or other unforeseen circumstances prevent the household
            from otherwise obtaining commodities. Designation of an emergency
            authorized representative must be made in writing by a responsible
            member of the household. State agencies may distribute commodities
            to household members or authorized representatives presenting an
            identification card or other appropriate identification that
            satisfactorily identifies the member obtaining commodities.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Eligibility determinations—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Determining income.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='3'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall take into account the income already
            received by the household during the certification period and any
            anticipated income the household and the State agency are reasonably
            certain will be received during the remainder of the certification
            period. If the amount of income that is anticipated is uncertain,
            that portion of the household&apos;s income that is uncertain shall
            not be counted by the State agency. For example, a household
            anticipating income from a new source, such as a new job or recently
            applied for public assistance benefits, may be uncertain as to the
            timing and amount of the initial payment. These monies shall not be
            anticipated by the State agency unless there is reasonable certainty
            concerning the month in which the payment will be received and in
            what amount. If the exact amount of the income is not known, that
            portion of it which can be anticipated with reasonable certainty
            shall be considered as income. In cases where the receipt of income
            is reasonably certain but the monthly amount may fluctuate, and the
            household&apos;s income is close to the income eligibility limit the
            State agency may elect to average income provided that such
            averaging does not disadvantage the household. Such averaging shall
            be based on income that is anticipated to be available to the
            household during the certification period. The State agency shall
            use income received in the past 30 days as an indicator of future
            income during the certification period unless changes in income have
            occurred or can be anticipated.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Income anticipated during the certification period shall be counted
            as income only in the month it is expected to be received, unless
            the income is averaged.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='b_1_iii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Self-employment income which represents a household&apos;s annual
            support including the net profit from the sale of any capital goods
            or equipment related to the business shall be 
            <PRTPAGE P='621' />
            annualized over a 12-month period, even if the income is received in
            only a short period of time. For example, self-employment income
            received by farmers shall be averaged over a 12-month period if the
            income represents the farmer&apos;s annual support.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='b_1_iii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Self-employment income which represents only a part of a
            household&apos;s annual support, including the net profit from the
            sale of any capital goods or equipment related to the business,
            shall be averaged over the period of time the income is intended to
            cover. For example, self-employed vendors who work only in the
            summer and supplement their income from other sources during the
            balance of the year shall have their self-employment income averaged
            over the summer months rather than a 12-month period.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='b_1_iii_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For the period of time over which self-employment income is
            determined, the State agency shall add all gross self-employment
            income, exclude the cost of producing the self-employment income and
            divide the net self-employment income by the number of months over
            which the income will be averaged. The allowable costs of producing
            self-employment income include but are not limited to, the
            identifiable costs of labor, stock, raw materials, seed and
            fertilizer, interest paid to purchase income producing property,
            insurance premiums, and taxes paid on income producing property.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='b_1_iii_D'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (D)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In determining net self-employment income, payments on the
            principal of the purchase price of income-producing real estate and
            capital assets, equipment, machinery, and other durable goods, net
            losses from previous periods, Federal, State, and local income
            taxes, money set aside for retirement purposes, and other
            work-related personal expenses (such as transportation to and from
            work) will not be allowable costs of doing business.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The monthly net self-employment income shall be added to any other
            earned income received by the household. The total monthly earned
            income, less the 20 percent earned income deduction, shall then be
            added to all monthly unearned income received by the household.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Allowable costs for dependent care shall be subtracted from the
            household&apos;s total monthly income to determine net monthly
            income.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The total net monthly income shall be compared to the income
            eligibility standard for the appropriate household size to determine
            the household&apos;s eligibility.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Certification periods.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall establish definite periods of time within
            which households shall be eligible to receive benefits. Further
            eligibility shall be established upon a recertification based upon a
            newly completed application, an interview, and such verification as
            required by paragraph (a)(6)(v) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Certification periods shall conform to calendar months. The first
            month in the certification period of initial applicants shall be the
            month in which eligibility is determined. For example, if a
            household submits an application in late January and the household
            is determined eligible on the fifth working day which falls in
            February, a six-month certification period would include February
            through July. Upon recertification, the certification period will
            begin with the month following the last month of the previous
            certification period.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A household shall be assigned a certification period for as long a
            period as the household&apos;s circumstances are expected to remain
            sufficiently stable such that the household is expected to continue
            to meet the program&apos;s eligibility standards.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In no event may a certification period exceed 12 months, except
            that households in which all adult members are elderly and/or
            disabled may be certified for up to 24 months. Households assigned
            certification periods that are longer than 12 months must be
            contacted by the State agency at least once every 12 months to
            determine if the household wishes to continue to participate in the
            program and whether there are any changes in household circumstances
            that would warrant a redetermination of eligibility or a change in
            benefit level. The State agency may use any method it chooses for
            this contact, including a face-to-face interview, telephone call or
            a home visit. Contact 
            <PRTPAGE P='622' />
            with the household&apos;s authorized representative would not
            satisfy this requirement; the State agency must contact a household
            member. The case file must document the contact with the household
            and include the date of contact, method of contact, name of person
            contacted, whether the household wishes to continue to participate,
            and whether changes in household circumstances would warrant a
            redetermination of eligibility or a change in benefit level.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Certification notices—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Notice of eligibility.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If an application is approved, the State agency shall provide the
            household a written notice of eligibility and the beginning and
            ending dates of the certification period. Households certified on an
            expedited basis shall be advised that the subsequent month&apos;s
            eligibility will depend upon completion of the postponed
            verification.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Notice of denial.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the application is denied, the State agency shall provide the
            household written notice explaining the basis for the denial, the
            household&apos;s right to request a fair hearing, and the telephone
            number and address of the person to contact for additional
            information. If there is an individual or organization available
            which provides free legal representation, the notice shall also
            advise the household of the availability of the service.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Notice of adverse action.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='b_3_iii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Prior to any action to reduce or terminate a household&apos;s
            benefits within the certification period, except for households
            voluntarily switching program participation from the Food
            Distribution Program to the Food Stamp Program, State agencies shall
            provide the household timely and adequate advance notice before the
            adverse action is taken. The notice must be issued within 10 days of
            determining that an adverse action is warranted. The adverse action
            must take effect with the next scheduled distribution of commodities
            that follows the expiration of the advance notice period, unless the
            household requests a fair hearing.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='b_3_iii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In State agencies that have elected joint public assistance or
            general assistance and Food Distribution processing, the notice of
            adverse action shall be considered timely if the advance notice
            period conforms to that period of time defined by the State agency
            as an adequate notice period for its public or general assistance
            caseload, provided that the period includes at least 10 days from
            the date the notice is mailed to the date upon which the action
            becomes effective. In circumstances other than joint processing, the
            advance notice shall be considered timely if the advance notice
            period includes at least 10 days from the date the notice is issued
            to the date upon which the action becomes effective.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='b_3_iii_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The notice of adverse action must include the following in easily
            understandable language:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          (
          <E T='03'>
            1
          </E>
          ) The reason for the adverse action;
        </P>
        <P>
          (
          <E T='03'>
            2
          </E>
          ) The date the adverse action will take effect;
        </P>
        <P>
          (
          <E T='03'>
            3
          </E>
          ) The household&apos;s right to request a fair hearing and continue to
          receive benefits pending the outcome of the fair hearing;
        </P>
        <P>
          (
          <E T='03'>
            4
          </E>
          ) The date by which the household must request the fair hearing;
        </P>
        <P>
          (
          <E T='03'>
            5
          </E>
          ) The liability of the household for any overissuances received while
          awaiting the outcome of the fair hearing, if the fair hearing
          official&apos;s decision is adverse to the household;
        </P>
        <P>
          (
          <E T='03'>
            6
          </E>
          ) The telephone number and address of someone to contact for
          additional information; and
        </P>
        <P>
          (
          <E T='03'>
            7
          </E>
          ) The telephone number and address of an individual or organization
          that provides free legal representation, if available.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='b_3_iii_D'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (D)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall continue distribution of commodities to the
            household after the end of the adverse notice period if the
            household requests a fair hearing during the advance notice period.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='b_3_iii_E'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (E)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the State agency determines that a household received more USDA
            commodities than it was entitled to receive, it must establish a
            claim against the household in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='253' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
                253.9
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . The initial demand letter for repayment must be provided to the
            household at the same time the notice of adverse action is issued.
            It may be combined with the notice of adverse action.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Reporting changes.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Certified households are required to report 
            <PRTPAGE P='623' />
            changes in household composition and income which would necessitate
            a change in the determination of eligibility. To facilitate
            reporting changes in income each certified household shall be
            advised at the time of certification what the maximum monthly income
            limit, as defined in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='253' sect='6' psec='#e_1' tq='N'>
                253.6(e)(1)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , is for its size household, and shall be required to report any
            change in income that goes above that limit to the certification
            office within ten days after the change becomes known to the
            household. Households must also report within 10 calendar days when
            countable resources, which are identified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='253' sect='6' psec='#d_2' tq='N'>
                253.6(d)(2)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , exceed the maximum allowable limits as described at 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='253' sect='6' psec='#d_1' tq='N'>
                253.6(d)(1)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . The State agency shall develop the procedures for when and how
            changes in household circumstances are reported. Changes reported
            over the telephone or in person shall be acted on in the same manner
            as those reported in writing.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the State agency determines that the household is no longer
            eligible or reduces the amount of commodities due the household
            because the household has lost a member or members, the State agency
            shall provide the household with a notice of adverse action not
            later than ten days after the change is reported. If the reported
            change increases the amount of commodities due the household, the
            household shall be notified that the increase shall be effective not
            later than the month following the date the change was reported.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Recertification.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall develop a procedure for notifying the
            household prior to or shortly after the end of its certification
            period that the household must reapply and be recertified for
            continued participation. Households shall also be notified of the
            date upon which termination from participation will be effective
            should the household fail to reapply before the expiration of the
            certification period.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall approve or deny a household&apos;s
            application for recertification and notify the household of that
            determination prior to the expiration of the household&apos;s
            current certification period. Households applying for
            recertification in the last month of the current certification
            period must be provided an opportunity to obtain commodity
            distribution on an uninterrupted basis.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall continue distribution of commodities to the
            household denied at the point of recertification if the household
            timely requests a fair hearing.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Controls for dual participation—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Prohibition on dual participation.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No household shall be allowed to participate simultaneously in the
            Food Stamp Program and Food Distribution Program. The State agency
            shall inform each applicant household of this prohibition and shall
            develop a method to detect dual participation. The method developed
            by the State agency shall, at a minimum, employ lists of currently
            certified households provided by and provided to the appropriate
            food stamp agency on a monthly basis. The State agency may also
            employ computer checks, address checks and telephone calls to
            prevent dual participation. The State agency shall coordinate with
            the appropriate food stamp agency or agencies in developing controls
            for dual participation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Choice of programs.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Households eligible for either the Food Stamp Program or Food
            Distribution Program on reservations on which both programs are
            available may elect to participate in either program. Such
            households may elect to participate in one program, and subsequently
            elect the other at the end of the certification period. Households
            may also elect to switch from one program to the other program
            within a certification period only by terminating their
            participation, and notifying the State agency of their intention to
            switch programs. Households certified in either the Food
            Distribution or Food Stamp Program on the first day of the month can
            only receive benefits in the program for which they are currently
            certified during that month. At the point the household elects to
            change programs the household should notify the State agency of its
            intent to switch programs, and should file an application for the
            program in which it wishes to participate. Households voluntarily
            withdrawing from one program with the intent of switching to the
            other shall have their 
            <PRTPAGE P='624' />
            eligibility terminated for the program in which they are currently
            certified on the last day of the month in which the household
            notifies the State agency of its intent to change programs.
            Entitlement in the program for which a household is now filing an
            application, if all eligibility criteria are met, would begin in the
            month following the month of termination in the previous program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Treatment of disqualified household members.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The following are not eligible to participate in the Food
            Distribution Program:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Household members disqualified from the Food Distribution Program
            for an intentional program violation under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='253' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
                253.8
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . These household members may participate, if otherwise eligible, in
            the Food Distribution Program once the period of disqualification
            has ended.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Household members disqualified from the Food Stamp Program for an
            intentional program violation under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='273' sect='16' psec='' tq='N'>
                273.16
              </subref>
               of this chapter
            </aref>
            . These household members may participate, if otherwise eligible, in
            the Food Distribution Program once the period of disqualification
            under the Food Stamp Program has ended. The State agency must, in
            cooperation with the appropriate food stamp agency, develop a
            procedure that ensures that these household members are identified.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Households disqualified from the Food Distribution Program for
            failure to pay an overissuance claim. The circumstances under which
            a disqualification is allowed for such failure are specified in FNS
            Handbook 501.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             During the time a household member is disqualified, the eligibility
            and food distribution benefits of any remaining household members
            will be determined as follows:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Resources.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The resources of the disqualified member will continue to count in
            their entirety to the remaining household members.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Income.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A pro rata share of the income of the disqualified member will be
            counted as income to the remaining members. This pro rata share is
            calculated by dividing the disqualified member&apos;s earned (less
            the 20 percent earned income deduction) and unearned income evenly
            among all household members, including the disqualified member. All
            but the disqualified member&apos;s share is counted as income to the
            remaining household members.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Eligibility and benefits.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The disqualified member will not be included when determining the
            household&apos;s size for purposes of assigning food distribution
            benefits to the household or for purposes of comparing the
            household&apos;s net monthly income with the income eligibility
            standards.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Joint processing PA/GA.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State agencies which are responsible for and administer both the
            Food Distribution and public assistance (PA) or general assistance
            (GA) programs on Indian reservations may allow a household to apply
            for the Food Distribution Program at the same time the household
            applies for PA or GA benefits. However, while PA households are
            categorically eligible, GA households except for those households in
            GA programs which have been determined by FNS to have criteria of
            need the same as, or similiar to those under federally aided public
            assistance programs as provided for in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='253' sect='6' psec='#c_2' tq='N'>
                253.6(c)(2)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             shall have their eligibility for commodities based solely on Food
            Distribution eligibility criteria. All criteria provided in this
            paragraph (f), are applicable to State agencies which administer
            both the Food Distribution and assistance programs and which elect
            joint processing. Under joint processing, the State agency shall use
            joint application forms that contain all the information needed to
            determine eligibility for commodities or shall attach a form for the
            other needed information.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall process all applications for PA or GA as
            applications for the Food Distribution Program as well, unless the
            household clearly indicates on a space on the application that the
            household does not want commodities. The State agency shall conduct
            a single interview for PA or GA and Food Distribution Program
            eligibility, unless the State agency is unable to do so within the
            Food Distribution Program processing standards specified in
            paragraphs (a)(7) and (a)(9)of this section. In such cases the State
            agency shall provide separate certification for PA or GA and Food
            Distribution Program eligibility.
            <PRTPAGE P='625' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency may verify those factors of eligibility which must
            be verified for PA or GA, under PA or GA rules, but must follow the
            Food Distribution Program rules for all other factors.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             PA households have the same reporting requirements as any other
            food distribution household. PA households which report a change in
            circumstances to the PA worker shall be considered to have reported
            the change for food distribution purposes. All of the requirements
            pertaining to reporting changes for PA households shall be applied
            to GA households in project areas where GA and food distribution
            cases are processed jointly.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency must follow all Food Distribution Program
            timeliness rules for certification of households for the Food
            Distribution Program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Fair hearing—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Availability of hearings.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall provide a fair hearing to any household
            aggrieved by any action of the State agency which affects the
            participation of the household in the Food Distribution Program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Timely action on hearings—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Time frames for the State agency.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency must conduct the hearing, arrive at a decision,
            and notify the household of the decision within 60 days of receipt
            of a request for a fair hearing. The fair hearing decision may
            result in a change in the household&apos;s eligibility or the amount
            of commodities issued to the household based on household size. The
            State agency must implement these changes to be effective for the
            next scheduled distribution of commodities following the date of the
            fair hearing decision. If the commodities are normally made
            available to the household within a specific period of time (for
            example, from the first day of the month through the tenth day of
            the month), the effective date of the disqualification will be the
            first day of that period.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Household requests for postponement.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The household may request and is entitled to receive, a
            postponement of the scheduled hearing. The postponement shall not
            exceed 30 days and, the time limit for action on the decision may be
            extended for as many days as the hearing is postponed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Notification of right to request hearing.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             At the time of application, each household shall be informed of its
            right to a hearing, of the method by which a hearing may be
            requested, and that its case may be presented by a household member
            or a representative, such as a legal counsel, a relative, a friend
            or other spokesperson. If there is an individual or organization
            available which provides free legal representation, the household
            shall also be informed of the availability of that service. Hearing
            procedures shall be published by the State agency and made available
            to any interested party.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Time period for requesting hearing.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A household shall be allowed to request a hearing on any action by
            the State agency which occurred in the prior 90 days or which
            affects current benefits.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Request for hearing.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A request for a hearing is any clear expression, oral or written,
            by the household or its representative to the State agency that it
            wishes to present its case to a higher authority. The freedom to
            make such a request shall not be limited or interfered with in any
            way. Upon request, the State agency shall make available without
            charge the specific materials necessary for a household or its
            representative to determine whether a hearing should be requested or
            to prepare for a hearing.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Denial or dismissal of request for hearing.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall not deny or dismiss a request for a hearing
            unless:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_6_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The request is not received within the time period specified in
            paragraph (g)(4) of this section;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_6_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The request is withdrawn in writing by the household or its
            representative; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_6_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The household or its representative fails, without good cause, to
            appear at the scheduled hearing.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Notification of time and place of hearing.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The time, date and place of the hearing shall be convenient to the
            household. At least 15 days prior to the hearing, advance written
            notice shall be provided to all parties involved to permit adequate
            preparation of the case. The notice shall:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_7_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Advise the household or its representative of the name, address,
            and 
            <PRTPAGE P='626' />
            the phone number of the person to notify in the event it is not
            possible for the household to attend the scheduled hearing.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_7_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Specify that the State agency will dismiss the hearing request if
            the household or its representative fails to appear for the hearing
            without good cause.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_7_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Include the State agency hearing procedures and any other
            information that would provide the household with an understanding
            of the proceedings, and that would contribute to the effective
            presentation of the household&apos;s case.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_7_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Explain that the household or representative may examine the
            casefile prior to the hearing.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Hearing official.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Hearings shall be conducted by an impartial official(s), designated
            by the State agency, who does not have any personal interest or
            involvement in the case and who was not directly involved in the
            initial determination of the action which is being contested. The
            hearing official shall:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_8_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Administer oaths or affirmations if required by the State;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_8_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Ensure that all relevant issues are considered;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_8_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Request, receive and make part of the record all evidence
            determined necessary to decide the issues being raised;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_8_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Regulate the conduct and course of the hearing consistent with due
            process to ensure an orderly hearing; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_8_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Render a hearing decision in the name of the State agency, in
            accordance with paragraph (g)(11) of this section, which will
            resolve the dispute.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Attendance at hearing.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The hearing shall be attended by a representative of the State
            agency which initiated the action being contested and by the
            household and/or its representative. The hearing may also be
            attended by friends or relatives of the household upon household
            consent.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Conduct of hearing.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The household may not be familiar with the rules of order and it
            may be necessary to make particular efforts to arrive at the facts
            of the case in a manner that makes the household feel most at ease.
            The household or its representative must be given adequate
            opportunity to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_10_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Examine all documents and records to be used at the hearing at a
            reasonable time before the date of the hearing, as well as during
            the hearing. The contents of the casefile, including the application
            forms and documents of verification used by the State agency shall
            be made available, provided the confidential information is
            protected from release. The State agency shall provide a free copy
            of the relevant portions of the casefile if requested by the
            household or its representative. Confidential information that is
            protected from release and other documents or records which the
            household will not otherwise have an opportunity to contest or
            challenge shall not be introduced at the hearing or affect the
            hearing official&apos;s decision.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_10_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Present the case or have it presented by a legal counsel or other
            person.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_10_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bring witnesses.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_10_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Advance arguments without undue interference.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_10_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Question or refute any testimony or evidence, including an
            opportunity to confront and cross-examine adverse witnesses.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_10_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Submit evidence to establish all pertinent facts and circumstances
            in the case.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_11'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (11)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Hearing decisions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_11_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Decisions of the hearing officials shall comply with Federal law or
            regulations and shall be based on the hearing record. The verbatim
            transcript or recording of testimony and exhibits or an official
            report containing the substance of what transpired at the hearing,
            together with all papers and requests filed in the proceeding, shall
            constitute the exclusive record for a final decision by the hearing
            official.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_11_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A decision by the hearing official shall be binding on the State
            agency and shall summarize the facts of the case, specify the
            reasons for the decision and identify the supporting evidence and
            the pertinent FNS regulations. The decision shall become a part of
            the record.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_11_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Within 10 days of the date the fair hearing decision is issued, the
            State agency must issue a notice to the household advising it of the
            decision.
            <PRTPAGE P='627' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='h_11_iii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the decision upheld the adverse action by the State agency, the
            notice must advise the household of the right to pursue judicial
            review.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='h_11_iii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the decision upheld a disqualification, the notice must also
            include the reason for the decision, the date the disqualification
            will take effect, and the duration of the disqualification (that is,
            12 months; 24 months; or permanent). The State agency must also
            advise any remaining household members if the household&apos;s
            benefits will change, or if the household is no longer eligible as a
            result of the disqualification.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_11_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency must revise the demand letter for repayment issued
            previously to the household to include the value of all overissued
            commodities provided to the household during the appeal process,
            unless the fair hearing decision specifically requires the
            cancellation of the claim. The State agency must also advise the
            household that collection action on the claim will continue, in
            accordance with FNS Handbook 501, unless suspension is warranted.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_12'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (12)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Agency conferences.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_12_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall offer agency conferences to households which
            request an immediate resolution by a higher authority of a denial of
            eligibility for food distribution benefits. The State agency may
            also offer agency conferences to households adversely affected by
            any agency action. The State agency shall advise households that use
            of an agency conference is optional and that such use shall in no
            way delay or replace the fair hearing process. The agency
            conferences may be attended by the eligibility worker responsible
            for the agency action, and shall be attended by an eligibility
            supevisor and/or the agency director, as well as the household
            and/or its representative. An agency conference may lead to an
            informal resolution of the dispute. However, a fair hearing must
            still be held if requested by the household.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_12_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An agency conference for households requesting an immediate
            resolution by a higher authority of an eligibility issue shall be
            scheduled within four working days of the request unless the
            household requests that it be scheduled later or states that it does
            not wish to have an agency conference.
          </text>
        </P>
        <APPRO>
          (Approved by the Office of Management and Budget under control number
          0584-0071)
        </APPRO>
        <SECAUTH>
          (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='44' sect='3506' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/44/3506.html'>
              44 U.S.C. 3506
            </subref>
          </aref>
          )
        </SECAUTH>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            44 FR 35928
          </aref>
          , June 19, 1979, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            47 FR 746
          </aref>
          , Jan. 7, 1982. Redesignated and amended by Amdt. 1, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            47 FR 14137
          </aref>
          , Apr. 2, 1982; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            64 FR 73383
          </aref>
          , Dec. 30, 1999; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            65 FR 47833
          </aref>
          , Aug. 4, 2000; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 4473
          </aref>
          , Jan. 28, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4859'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:B:253:-:253.8
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        253.8
      </num>
      <head>
        Administrative disqualification procedures for intentional program
        violation.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          64 FR 73384
        </aref>
        , Dec. 30, 1999]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='253' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              253.8
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Administrative disqualification procedures for intentional program
          violation.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              What is an intentional program violation?
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An intentional program violation is considered to have occurred
            when a household member knowingly, willingly, and with deceitful
            intent:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Makes a false or misleading statement, or misrepresents, conceals,
            or withholds facts in order to obtain Food Distribution Program
            benefits which the household is not entitled to receive; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Commits any act that violates a Federal statute or regulation
            relating to the acquisition or use of Food Distribution Program
            commodities.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              What are the disqualification penalties for an intentional program
              violation?
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Household members determined by the State agency to have committed
            an intentional program violation will be ineligible to participate
            in the program:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For a period of 12 months for the first violation;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For a period of 24 months for the second violation; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Permanently for the third violation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Who can be disqualified?
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Only the household member determined to have committed the
            intentional program violation can be disqualified. However, the
            disqualification may affect the eligibility of the household as a
            whole, as addressed under paragraphs (e)(5) and (h) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Can the disqualification be appealed?
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Household members determined by the State agency to have committed
            an intentional program violation may appeal the disqualification, as
            provided under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='253' sect='7' psec='#h_1' tq='N'>
                253.7(h)(1)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              What are the State agency&apos;s responsibilities?
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each State agency must 
            <PRTPAGE P='628' />
            implement administrative disqualification procedures for intentional
            program violations that conform to this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency must inform households in writing of the
            disqualification penalties for intentional program violations each
            time they apply for benefits, including recertifications. This
            notice must also advise households that an intentional program
            violation may be referred to authorities for prosecution.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency must attempt to substantiate all suspected cases
            of intentional program violation. An intentional program violation
            is considered to be substantiated when the State agency has clear
            and convincing evidence demonstrating that a household member
            committed one or more acts of intentional program violation, as
            defined in paragraph (a) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Within 10 days of substantiating that a household member has
            committed an intentional program violation, the State agency must
            provide the household member with a notice of disqualification, as
            described in paragraph (f) of this section. A notice must still be
            issued in instances where the household member is not currently
            eligible or participating in the program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency must advise any remaining household members if the
            household&apos;s benefits will change or if the household will no
            longer be eligible as a result of the disqualification.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency must provide the household member to be
            disqualified with an opportunity to appeal the disqualification
            through a fair hearing, as required by 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='253' sect='7' psec='#h' tq='N'>
                253.7(h)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency must refer all substantiated cases of intentional
            program violations to Tribal, Federal, State, or local authorities
            for prosecution under applicable statutes. However, a State agency
            that has conferred with its legal counsel and prosecutors to
            determine the criteria for acceptance for possible prosecution is
            not required to refer cases that do not meet the prosecutors&apos;
            criteria.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency must establish claims, and pursue collection as
            appropriate, on all substantiated cases of intentional program
            violation in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='253' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
                253.9
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              What are the requirements for the notice of disqualification?
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Within 10 days of substantiating the intentional program violation,
            the State agency must issue to the household member a notice of
            disqualification. The notice must allow an advance notice period of
            at least 10 days. The disqualification must begin with the next
            scheduled distribution of commodities that follows the expiration of
            the advance notice period, unless the household member requests a
            fair hearing. A notice must still be issued in instances where the
            household member is not currently eligible or participating in the
            program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The notice must conform to the requirements of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='253' sect='7' psec='#b_3_iii_C' tq='N'>
                253.7(b)(3)(iii)(C)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             for notices of adverse action.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              What are the appeal procedures for administrative
              disqualifications?—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Appeal rights.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The household member has the right to request a fair hearing to
            appeal the disqualification in accordance with the procedures at 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='253' sect='7' psec='#h' tq='N'>
                253.7(h)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Notification of hearing.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency must provide the household member with a
            notification of the time and place of the fair hearing as described
            in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='253' sect='7' psec='#h_7' tq='N'>
                253.7(h)(7)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . The notice must also include:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A warning that if the household member fails to appear at the
            hearing, the hearing decision will be based solely on the
            information provided by the State agency; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A statement that the hearing does not prevent the Tribal, Federal,
            State, or local government from prosecuting the household member in
            a civil or criminal court action, or from collecting any
            overissuance(s).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
            <head>
              What are the procedures for applying disqualification penalties?
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the household member did not request a fair hearing, the
            disqualification must begin with the next scheduled distribution of
            commodities that follows the expiration of the advance notice period
            of the notice of adverse action. If the commodities are normally
            made available to the household within a specific period of time
            (for example, from the first day of the month through the tenth day
            of the month), the effective date of the disqualification will be
            the first day of that period. The State agency must apply the
            disqualification 
            <PRTPAGE P='629' />
            period (that is, 12 months, 24 months, or permanent) specified in
            the notice of disqualification. The State agency must advise any
            remaining household members if the household&apos;s benefits will
            change or if the household is no longer eligible as a result of the
            disqualification.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the household member requested a fair hearing and the
            disqualification was upheld by the fair hearing official, the
            disqualification must begin with the next scheduled distribution of
            commodities that follows the date the hearing decision is issued. If
            the commodities are normally made available to the household within
            a specific period of time (for example, from the first day of the
            month through the tenth day of the month), the effective date of the
            disqualification will be the first day of that period. The State
            agency must apply the disqualification period (that is, 12 months,
            24 months, or permanent) specified in the notice of
            disqualification. No further administrative appeal procedure exists
            after an adverse fair hearing decision. The decision by a fair
            hearing official is binding on the State agency. The household
            member, however, may seek relief in a court having appropriate
            jurisdiction. As provided under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='253' sect='7' psec='#h_11_iii_B' tq='N'>
                253.7(h)(11)(iii)(B)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , the State agency must advise any remaining household members if
            the household&apos;s benefits will change, or if the household is no
            longer eligible as a result of the disqualification.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Once a disqualification has begun, it must continue uninterrupted
            for the duration of the penalty period (that is, 12 months; 24
            months; or permanent). Changes in the eligibility of the
            disqualified household member&apos;s household will not interrupt or
            shorten the disqualification period.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The same act of intentional program violation continued over a
            period of time will not be separated so that more than one penalty
            can be imposed. For example, a household intentionally fails to
            report that a household member left the household, resulting in an
            overissuance of benefits for 5 months. Although the violation
            occurred over a period of 5 months, only one penalty will apply to
            this single act of intentional program violation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the case was referred for Tribal, Federal, State, or local
            prosecution and the court of appropriate jurisdiction imposed a
            disqualification penalty, the State agency must follow the court
            order.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            64 FR 73384
          </aref>
          , Dec. 30, 1999]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4860'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:B:253:-:253.9
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        253.9
      </num>
      <head>
        Claims against households.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          64 FR 73385
        </aref>
        , Dec. 30, 1999]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='253' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
              253.9
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Claims against households.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              What are the procedures for establishing a claim against a
              household for an overissuance?
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency must establish a claim against any household that
            has received more Food Distribution Program commodities than it was
            entitled to receive.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The procedures for establishing and collecting claims against
            households are specified in FNS Handbook 501, The Food Distribution
            Program on Indian Reservations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Who is responsible for repaying a household overissuance claim?
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All adult household members are jointly and separately liable for
            the repayment of the value of any overissuance of Food Distribution
            Program benefits to the household.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Responsibility for repayment continues even in instances where the
            household becomes ineligible or is not participating in the program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            64 FR 73385
          </aref>
          , Dec. 30, 1999]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4861'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:B:253:-:253.10
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        253.10
      </num>
      <head>
        Commodity control, storage and distribution.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          44 FR 35928
        </aref>
        , June 19, 1979, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          47 FR 746
        </aref>
        , Jan. 7, 1982. Redesignated by Amdt. 1, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          47 FR 14137
        </aref>
        , Apr. 2, 1982, and further redesignated at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          64 FR 73384
        </aref>
        , Dec. 30, 1999.]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='253' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
              253.10
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Commodity control, storage and distribution.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Control and accountability.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall be responsible for the issuance of
            commodities to households and the control of and accountability for
            the commodities upon its acceptance of the commodities at time and
            place of delivery.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Commodity inventories.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall, in cooperation with the FNS Regional
            office, develop an appropriate procedure for determining and
            monitoring the level of commodity inventories at central commodity
            storage facilities and at each local distribution point. The State
            agency shall maintain the inventories at proper levels taking into
            consideration, among other factors, household preferences and the
            historical and projected volume of distribution at each site. The
            procedures shall provide that commodity inventories at each central 
            <PRTPAGE P='630' />
            storage facility and each local distribution point are not in
            excess, but are adequate for, an uninterrupted distribution of
            commodities.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Storage facilities and practices.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall as a minimum ensure that:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Adequate and appropriate storage facilities are maintained. The
            facilities shall be clean and neat and safe-guarded against theft,
            damage, insects, rodents and other pests.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Department recommended dunnage, stacking and ventilation methods
            are followed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Commodities are stacked in a manner which facilitates an accurate
            inventory.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Commodities are issued on a first-in, first-out basis.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Commodities held in storage for a protracted period of time are
            reinspected prior to issuance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Out-of-condition commodities are disposed of in accordance with
            Department approved methods.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notification is provided to certified households of the location of
            distribution sites and days and hours of distribution.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An adequate supply of commodities which are available from the
            Department is on hand at all distribution sites.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Sufficient distribution sites, either stationary or mobile, are
            geographically located or routed in relation to population density
            of eligible households.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Days and hours of distribution are sufficient for caseload size and
            convenience.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_11'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (11)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Households are advised they may refuse any commodity not desired,
            even if the commodities are prepackaged by household size.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_12'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (12)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Emergency issuance of commodities will be made to households
            certified for expedited service in accordance with the provisions of
            
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='253' sect='7' psec='#a_9' tq='N'>
                253.7(a)(9)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_13'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (13)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Eligible households or authorized representatives are identified
            prior to the issuance of commodities.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_14'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (14)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Authorized signatures are obtained for commodities issued and the
            issue date recorded.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_15'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (15)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Posters are conspicuously displayed advising program participants
            to accept only those commodities, and in such quantities, as will be
            consumed by them.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_16'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (16)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Complete and current records are kept of all commodities received,
            issued, transferred, and on hand and of any inventory overages,
            shortages, and losses.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_17'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (17)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A list of commodities offered by the Department is displayed at
            distribution sites so that households may indicate preferences for
            future orders.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Distribution.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall distribute commodities only to households
            eligible to receive them under this part. If the State agency uses
            any other agency, administration, bureau, service or similar
            organization to effect or assist in the certification of households
            or distribution of commodities, the State agency shall impose upon
            such organization responsibility for determining that households to
            whom commodities are distributed are eligible under this part. The
            State agency shall not delegate to any such organization its
            responsibilities to the Department for overall management and
            control of the Food Distribution Program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Improper distribution or loss of or damage of commodities.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State agencies shall take action to obtain restitution in
            connection with claims arising in their favor for improper
            distribution, use or loss, or damage of commodities in accordance
            with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='250' sect='13' psec='' tq='N'>
                250.13
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='250' sect='15' psec='' tq='N'>
                250.15
              </subref>
               of this chapter
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Damaged or out-of-condition commodities.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall immediately notify the appropriate Food and
            Nutrition Service Regional Office (FNSRO) if any commodities are
            found to be damaged or out-of-condition at the time of arrival, or
            at any subsequent time, whether due to latent defects or any other
            reason. FNSRO shall advise the State agency of the appropriate
            action to be taken with regard to such commodities. If the
            commodities are declared unfit for human consumption in accordance
            with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='250' sect='13' psec='#f' tq='N'>
                250.13(f)
              </subref>
               of this chapter
            </aref>
            , they shall be disposed of as provided for under that section. When
            out-of-condition commodities do not create a hazard to other food at
            the same location, they shall not be disposed of until FNSRO or the
            responsible commodity contractor approves. 
            <PRTPAGE P='631' />
            When circumstances require prior disposal of a commodity, the
            quantity and manner of disposition shall be reported to the
            appropriate FNSRO. If any damaged or out-of-condition commodities
            are inadvertently issued to a household and are rejected or returned
            by the household because the commodities were unsound at the time of
            issuance and not because the household failed to provide proper
            storage, care or handling, the State agency shall replace the
            damaged or out-of-condition commodities with the same or similar
            kind of commodities which are sound and in good condition. The State
            agency shall account for such replacements on its monthly inventory
            report.
          </text>
        </P>
        <APPRO>
          (Approved by the Office of Management and Budget under control number
          0584-0071)
        </APPRO>
        <SECAUTH>
          (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='44' sect='3506' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/44/3506.html'>
              44 U.S.C. 3506
            </subref>
          </aref>
          )
        </SECAUTH>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            44 FR 35928
          </aref>
          , June 19, 1979, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            47 FR 746
          </aref>
          , Jan. 7, 1982. Redesignated by Amdt. 1, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            47 FR 14137
          </aref>
          , Apr. 2, 1982, and further redesignated at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            64 FR 73384
          </aref>
          , Dec. 30, 1999.]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4862'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:II:B:253:-:253.11
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        253.11
      </num>
      <head>
        Administrative funds.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          44 FR 35928
        </aref>
        , June 19, 1979, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          47 FR 746
        </aref>
        , Jan. 7, 1982. Redesignated and amended by Amdt. 1, 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          47 FR 14137
        </aref>
        , Apr. 2, 1982, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          62 FR 53731
        </aref>
        , Oct. 16, 1997. Redesignated at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          64 FR 73385
        </aref>
        , Dec. 30, 1999, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          77 FR 50907
        </aref>
        , Aug. 23, 2012]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='253' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
              253.11
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Administrative funds.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Allocation of administrative funds to FNS Regional Offices.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each fiscal year, after enactment of a program appropriation for
            the full fiscal year and apportionment of funds by the Office of
            Management and Budget, administrative funds will be allocated to
            each FNS Regional Office for further allocation to State agencies.
            To the extent practicable, administrative funds will be allocated to
            FNS Regional Offices in the following manner:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             65 percent of all administrative funds available nationally will be
            allocated to each FNS Regional Office in proportion to its share of
            the total number of participants nationally, averaged over the three
            previous fiscal years; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             35 percent of all administrative funds available nationally will be
            allocated to each FNS Regional Office in proportion to its share of
            the total current number of State agencies administering the program
            nationally.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Allocation of administrative funds to State agencies.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Prior to receiving administrative funds, State agencies must submit
            a proposed budget reflecting planned administrative costs to the
            appropriate FNS Regional Office for approval. Planned administrative
            costs must be allowable under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='277' tq='N'>
                277 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . To the extent that funding levels permit, the FNS Regional Office
            allocates to each State agency administrative funds necessary to
            cover 75 percent of approved administrative costs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              State agency matching requirement.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State agencies must match administrative funds allocated to them as
            follows:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Unless Federal administrative funding is approved at a rate higher
            than 75 percent of approved administrative costs, in accordance with
            paragraph (c)(2) of this section, each State agency must contribute
            25 percent of its total approved administrative costs. Cash or
            non-cash contributions, including third party in-kind contributions,
            and the value of services rendered by volunteers, may be used to
            meet the State agency matching requirement. In accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='277' tq='N'>
                277 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , such contributions must:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be verifiable;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Not be contributed for another federally-assisted program, unless
            authorized by Federal legislation;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be necessary and reasonable to accomplish program objectives;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be allowable under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              Part 
              <subref title='7' part='277' tq='N'>
                277 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Not be paid by the Federal Government under another assistance
            agreement unless authorized under the other agreement and its
            subject laws and regulations; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be included in the approved budget.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency may request a waiver to reduce its matching
            requirement below 25 percent of approved administrative costs. In
            its proposed budget, the State agency must submit compelling
            justification to the appropriate FNS Regional Office that it is
            unable to meet the 25 percent matching requirement and that
            additional administrative funds are necessary for the effective
            operation of the program. The FNS Regional Office may, at its
            discretion, approve a reduction of the matching requirement and
            provide additional administrative funds to cover more than 75
            percent of approved administrative costs to a State agency that
            provides compelling justification. 
            <PRTPAGE P='632' />
            In its compelling justification submission, the State agency must
            include a summary statement and recent financial documents, in
            accordance with FNS instructions. Compelling justification may
            include but is not limited to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The need for additional administrative funding for startup costs
            during the first year of program operation; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The need to prevent a reduction in the level of necessary and
            reasonable program services provided.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Use of funds by State agencies.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any funds received under this section shall be used only for costs
            that are allowable under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='277' tq='N'>
                277 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , and that are incurred in operating the food distribution program.
            Such funds may not be used to pay costs that are, or may be, paid
            with funds provided from other Federal sources.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Application for funds.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any State agency administering a Food Distribution Program that
            desires to receive administrative funds under this section shall
            submit form SF-424, “Application for Federal Assistance,” to the
            appropriate FNS Regional Office at least three months prior to the
            beginning of a Federal fiscal year. The application shall include
            budget information, reflecting by category of expenditure the State
            agency&apos;s best estimate of the total amount to be expended in
            the administration of the program during the fiscal year. FNS may
            require that detailed information be submitted by the State agency
            to support or explain the total estimated amounts shown for each
            budget cost category. As required by 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3015' tq='N'>
                3015
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , Subpart V, agencies of State government shall submit the
            application for Federal assistance to the State clearinghouse before
            submitting it to the FNSRO. ITOs shall not be subject to this
            requirement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Approval of the application by FNS shall be a prerequisite to the
            payment of any funds to State agencies.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Availability of funds.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS shall review and evaluate the budget information submitted by
            the State agency in relationship to the State agency&apos;s plan of
            operation and any other factors which may be relevant to FNS&apos;
            determination as to whether the estimated expenditures itemized by
            budget category are reasonable and justified. FNS shall give written
            notification to the State agency of (i) its approval or disapproval
            of any or all of the itemized expenditures, (ii) the amount of funds
            which will be made available, and (iii) the period for which funds
            are available.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS shall review and evaluate applications submitted by State
            agencies for administrative funds available under this section in
            the following order of priority and shall give preference in making
            payments of funds under this section in the same order of priority:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Applications from State agencies which desire to continue a Food
            Distribution Program now in operation,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Applications from State agencies, in the order received, which FNS
            determines are immediately capable of effectively and efficiently
            administering the Program, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Applications from other States agencies, in the order received.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Method of payment to State agencies.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payments are made to State agencies through a Letter of Credit or
            an advance by Treasury check. The Letter of Credit funding method
            shall be used by FNS except when the advances to be made within a 12
            month period are estimated to be less than $120,000. However, FNS
            may, at its option, reimburse a State agency by Treasury check
            regardless of the amount in response to a valid claim submitted by
            the State agency.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Letter of Credit funding method shall be done in conjunction
            with Treasury Department procedures, Treasury Circular No. 1075 and
            through an appropriate Treasury Regional Disbursing Office (RDO).
            The Standard Form 183, “Request for Payment on Letter of Credit and
            Status of Funds Report,” shall be correctly prepared and certified
            by a duly appointed official of the State for requesting payment
            from an RDO.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The advance by Treasury check method shall be done by use of the
            Standard Form 270, “Request for Advance or Reimbursement,” and
            procedures associated with its use. State agencies receiving
            payments under this method may request payments before cash outlays
            are made.
            <PRTPAGE P='633' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any State agency receiving payment under the Letter of Credit
            method or the advance by Treasury check method shall have in place
            and in operation, a financial management system which meets the
            standards for fund control and accountability prescribed in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='277' tq='N'>
                277 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , as amended. The State agency shall demonstrate on a continuing
            basis its willingness and ability to have and to function within
            procedures that will minimize the time lapse between the transfer of
            funds and its disbursement to meet obligations. For any State agency
            which does not meet the requirement of this paragraph, the
            reimbursement by Treasury check method shall be the preferred method
            for FNS to make payments to that State agency.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Accounting for funds.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each State agency which receives administrative funds under this
            section shall establish and maintain an effective system of fiscal
            control and accounting procedures. Expenditures and accountability
            of such funds shall be in accordance with the appropriate provisions
            of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='277' tq='N'>
                277
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . The accounting procedures maintained by the State agency shall be
            such as to accurately reflect the receipt, expenditure and current
            balance of funds provided by FNS and to facilitate the prompt
            preparation of reports required by FNS. The accounting procedures
            shall also provide for segregation of costs specifically
            identifiable to the Food Distribution Program from any other costs
            incurred by the State agency. Any budget revisions by a State agency
            which require the transfer of funds from an approved cost category
            to another shall be in accordance with the budget revision
            procedures set forth in OMB Circular No. A-102, Attachment K, and
            shall be approved by FNS prior to any transfer of funds.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Return, reduction, and reallocation of funds.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FNS may require State agencies to return prior to the end of the
            fiscal year any or all unobligated funds received under this
            section, and may reduce the amount it has apportioned or agreed to
            pay to any State agency if FNS determines that:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency is not administering the Food Distribution Program
            in accordance with its plan of operation approved by FNS and the
            provisions of this part, or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The amount of funds which the State agency requested from FNS is in
            excess of actual need, based on reports of expenditures and current
            projections of Program needs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Circumstances or conditions justify the return reallocation or
            transfer of funds to accomplish the purpose of this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall return to FNS within 90 days following the
            close of each Federal fiscal year any funds received under this
            section which are unobligated at that time.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Records, reports, audits.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency shall:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='j_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Keep such accounts and records as may be necessary to enable FNS to
            determine whether there has been compliance with this section, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='j_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Adhere to the retention and custodial requirements for records set
            forth in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='277' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
                277.4
              </subref>
               of this chapter
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State agency receiving funds either through a Treasury RDO
            Letter of Credit system or Treasury check shall submit quarterly
            reports to FNS on Form SF-269, “Financial Status Report,” by the
            30th day after close of the reporting quarter and shall submit such
            other reports as may be required by FNS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The appropriate provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='277' tq='N'>
                277
              </subref>
            </aref>
             are adaptable to this section for additional guidance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <APPRO>
          (Approved by the Office of Management and Budget under control number
          0584-0071)
        </APPRO>
        <SECAUTH>
          (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='44' sect='3506' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/44/3506.html'>
              44 U.S.C. 3506
            </subref>
          </aref>
          )
        </SECAUTH>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            44 FR 35928
          </aref>
          , June 19, 1979, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            47 FR 746
          </aref>
          , Jan. 7, 1982. Redesignated and amended by Amdt. 1, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            47 FR 14137
          </aref>
          , Apr. 2, 1982, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            62 FR 53731
          </aref>
          , Oct. 16, 1997. Redesignated at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            64 FR 73385
          </aref>
          , Dec. 30, 1999, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            77 FR 50907
          </aref>
          , Aug. 23, 2012]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>