<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol10'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1465
    </extid>
    <num>
      1465
    </num>
    <head>
      AGRICULTURAL MANAGEMENT ASSISTANCE
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='1524' note='' psec='#b' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1524.html#b'>
              7 U.S.C. 1524(b)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            74 FR 64595
          </aref>
          , Dec. 8, 2009, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='12917'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1465:A:1465.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1465.1
      </num>
      <head>
        Purposes and applicability.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1465' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              1465.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Purposes and applicability.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Through the Agricultural Management Assistance program (AMA), the
          Natural Resources Conservation Service (NRCS) provides financial
          assistance funds annually to producers in 16 statutorily designated
          States to: Construct or improve water management structures or
          irrigation structures; plant trees to form windbreaks or to improve
          water quality; and mitigate risk through production diversification or
          resource conservation practices including soil erosion control,
          integrated pest management, or the transition to organic farming. AMA
          is applicable in Connecticut, Delaware, Hawaii, Maine, Maryland,
          Massachusetts, Nevada, New Hampshire, New Jersey, New York,
          Pennsylvania, Rhode Island, Utah, Vermont, West Virginia, and Wyoming.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12918'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1465:A:1465.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1465.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Administration.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1465' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              1465.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Administration.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Administration and implementation of AMA&apos;s conservation
            provisions for the Commodity Credit Corporation (CCC) is assigned to
            NRCS, using the funds, facilities, and authorities of the CCC.
            Accordingly, where NRCS is mentioned in this part, it also refers to
            the CCC&apos;s funds, facilities, and authorities, where applicable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS will:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provide overall management and implementation leadership for AMA;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Establish policies, procedures, priorities, and guidance for
            implementation;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Establish payment limits;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Determine eligible practices;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Develop and approve AMA plans of operation and contracts with
            selected participants;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provide technical leadership for implementation, quality assurance,
            and evaluation of performance;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Make AMA allocation and contract funding decisions; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Issue payments for completed conservation practices.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No delegation in this part to lower organizational levels will
            preclude the Chief of NRCS from determining any issues arising under
            this part or from reversing or modifying any determination made
            under this part.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12919'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1465:A:1465.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1465.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1465' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              1465.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The following definitions apply to this part and all documents used in
          accordance with this part, unless specified otherwise:
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Agricultural land
          </E>
           means cropland, grassland, rangeland, pasture, and other agricultural
          land on which agricultural or forest-related products or livestock are
          produced. Other agricultural lands may include cropped woodland,
          marshes, incidental areas included in the agricultural operation, and
          other types of agricultural land used for production of livestock.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Agricultural operation
          </E>
           means a parcel or parcels of land whether contiguous or
          noncontiguous, which the producer is listed as the operator or
          owner/operator in the Farm Service Agency (FSA) record system, which
          is under the effective control of the producer at the 
          <PRTPAGE P='783' />
          time the producer applies for a contract, and which is operated by the
          producer with equipment, labor, management and production, forestry,
          or cultivation practices that are substantially separate from other
          operations.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            AMA plan of operations (APO)
          </E>
           means the document that identifies the location and timing of
          conservation practices that the participant agrees to implement on
          eligible land in order to address the resource concerns and program
          purposes. The APO is part of the AMA contract.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Applicant
          </E>
           means a person, legal entity, joint operation, or Indian Tribe that
          has an interest in an agricultural operation, as defined in 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR part 
            <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
              1400
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , who has requested in writing to participate in AMA.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Beginning farmer or rancher
          </E>
           means a person or legal entity who:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Has not operated a farm or ranch, or who has operated a farm or
            ranch for not more than 10 consecutive years. This requirement
            applies to all members of an entity who will materially and
            substantially participate in the operation of the farm or ranch.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the case of a contract with an individual, individually, or with
            the immediate family, material and substantial participation
            requires that the individual provide substantial day-to-day labor
            and management of the farm or ranch consistent with the practices in
            the county or State where the farm or ranch is located.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the case of a contract with an entity or joint operation, all
            members must materially and substantially participate in the
            operation of the farm or ranch. Material and substantial
            participation requires that each of the members provide some amount
            of the management, or labor and management necessary for day-to-day
            activities, such that if each of the members did not provide these
            inputs, operation of the farm or ranch would be seriously impaired.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Chief
          </E>
           means the Chief of NRCS, United States Department of Agriculture
          (USDA), or designee.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Conservation district
          </E>
           means any district or unit of State, Tribal, or local government
          formed under State, Tribal, or territorial law for the express purpose
          of developing and carrying out a local soil and water conservation
          program. Such district or unit of government may be referred to as a
          “conservation district,” “soil conservation district,” “soil and water
          conservation district,” “resource conservation district,” “natural
          resource district,” “land conservation committee,” or similar name.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Conservation practice
          </E>
           means one or more conservation improvements and activities, including
          structural practices, land management practices, vegetative practices,
          forest management, and other improvements that achieve program
          purposes.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Contract
          </E>
           means a legal document that specifies the rights and obligations of
          any participant accepted into the program. An AMA contract is an
          agreement for the transfer of assistance from USDA to the participant
          to share in the costs of applying conservation practices.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Designated conservationist
          </E>
           means an NRCS employee whom the State Conservationist has designated
          as responsible for AMA administration in a specific area.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Historically underserved producer
          </E>
           means an eligible person, joint operation, or legal entity who is a
          beginning farmer or rancher, socially disadvantaged farmer or rancher,
          limited resource farmer or rancher, or nonindustrial private forest
          landowner who meets the beginning, socially disadvantaged, or limited
          resource qualifications set forth in this section.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Indian Tribe
          </E>
           means any Indian Tribe, band, nation, or other organized group or
          community, including any Alaska Native village, or regional or village
          corporation as defined in or established pursuant to the Alaska Native
          Claims Settlement Act (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='43' sect='1601' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/43/1601.html'>
              43 U.S.C. 1601
            </subref>
          </aref>
          <E T='03'>
            et seq.
          </E>
          ) that is eligible for the special programs and services provided by
          the United States to Indians because of their status as Indians.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Indian land
          </E>
           is an inclusive term describing all lands held in trust by the United
          States for individual Indians or Tribes, or all lands, titles to which
          are held by individual Indians or Tribes, subject to Federal
          restrictions against alienation or encumbrance, or all lands which are
          subject to the rights of use, occupancy, and benefit of certain 
          <PRTPAGE P='784' />
          Tribes. For purposes of this part, the term Indian land also includes
          land for which the title is held in fee status by Indian Tribes and
          the United States Government-owned land under the Bureau of Indian
          Affairs (BIA) jurisdiction.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Joint operation
          </E>
           means, as defined in 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR part 
            <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
              1400
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , a general partnership, joint venture, or other similar business
          arrangement in which the members are jointly and severally liable for
          the obligations of the organization.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Legal entity
          </E>
           means, as defined in 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR part 
            <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
              1400
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , an entity created under Federal or State law that: (1) Owns land or
          an agricultural commodity, product, or livestock; or (2) produces an
          agricultural commodity, product, or livestock.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Lifespan
          </E>
           means the period of time in which a conservation practice should be
          operated and maintained and used for the intended purpose.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Limited resource farmer or rancher
          </E>
           means:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A person with direct or indirect gross farm sales of not more than
            $155,200 in each of the previous 2 years (adjusted for inflation
            using the Prices Paid by Farmer Index as compiled by the National
            Agricultural Statistics Service), and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Has a total household income at or below the national poverty level
            for a family of four, or less than 50 percent of county median
            household income in each of the previous 2 years (to be determined
            annually using Commerce Department data).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Liquidated damages
          </E>
           means a sum of money stipulated in the AMA contract that the
          participant agrees to pay NRCS if the participant fails to adequately
          complete the terms of the contract. The sum represents an estimate of
          the technical assistance expenses incurred to service the contract and
          reflects the difficulties of proof of loss and the inconvenience or
          non-feasibility of otherwise obtaining an adequate remedy.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Livestock
          </E>
           means all animals produced on farms and ranches, as determined by the
          Chief.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Natural Resources Conservation Service
          </E>
           is an agency of USDA which has responsibility for administering AMA
          using the funds, facilities, and authorities of the CCC.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Nonindustrial private forest land
          </E>
           means rural land that has existing tree cover or is suitable for
          growing trees and is owned by any nonindustrial private individual,
          group, association, corporation, Indian Tribe, or other private legal
          entity that has definitive decision-making authority over the land.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Operation and maintenance
          </E>
           means work performed by the participant to keep the applied
          conservation practice functioning for the intended purpose during the
          conservation practice lifespan. Operation includes the administration,
          management, and performance of non-maintenance actions needed to keep
          the completed practice safe and functioning as intended. Maintenance
          includes work to prevent deterioration of the practice, repairing
          damage, or replacement of the practice to its original condition if
          one or more components fail.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Operation and maintenance (O&amp;M) agreement
          </E>
           means the document that, in conjunction with the APO, specifies the
          operation and maintenance responsibilities of the participants for
          conservation practices installed with AMA assistance.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Participant
          </E>
           means a person, legal entity, joint operation, or Indian Tribe that
          is receiving payment or is responsible for implementing the terms and
          conditions of an AMA contract.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Payment
          </E>
           means the financial assistance provided to the participant based on
          the estimated costs incurred in performing or implementing
          conservation practices, including costs for planning, design,
          materials, equipment, installation, labor, maintenance, management, or
          training, as well as the estimated income foregone by the producer for
          the designated conservation practices.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Person
          </E>
           means, as defined in 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR part 
            <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
              1400
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , an individual, natural person and does not include a legal entity.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Producer
          </E>
           means a person, legal entity, joint operation, or Indian Tribe that
          has an interest in the agricultural operation, according to 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR part 
            <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
              1400
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , or who is engaged in agricultural production or forestry management.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Resource concern
          </E>
           means a specific natural resource problem that represents a
          significant concern in a State 
          <PRTPAGE P='785' />
          or region and is likely to be addressed successfully through the
          implementation of the conservation practices by participants.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Secretary
          </E>
           means the Secretary of USDA.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Socially disadvantaged farmer or rancher
          </E>
           means a farmer or rancher who has been subjected to racial or ethnic
          prejudices because of their identity as a member of a group without
          regard to their individual qualities.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State Conservationist
          </E>
           means the NRCS employee authorized to direct and supervise NRCS
          activities in a State, Caribbean Area, or Pacific Islands Area.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Structural practice
          </E>
           means a conservation practice, including a vegetative practice, that
          involves establishing, constructing, or installing a site-specific
          measure to conserve and protect a resource from degradation, or
          improve soil, water, air, or related natural resources in the most
          cost-effective manner. Examples include, but are not limited to,
          animal waste management facilities, terraces, grassed waterways,
          tailwater pits, livestock water developments, contour grass strips,
          filterstrips, critical area plantings, tree plantings, establishment
          or improvement of wildlife habitat, and capping of abandoned wells.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Technical assistance
          </E>
           means technical expertise, information, and tools necessary for the
          conservation of natural resources on land active in agricultural,
          forestry, or related uses. The term includes the following:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Technical services provided directly to farmers, ranchers, and
            other eligible entities, such as conservation planning, technical
            consultation, and assistance with design and implementation of
            conservation practices; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Technical infrastructure, including activities, processes, tools,
            and agency functions needed to support delivery of technical
            services, such as technical standards, resource inventories,
            training, data, technology, monitoring, and effects analyses.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Technical Service Provider
          </E>
           (TSP) means an individual, private-sector entity, or public agency
          certified by NRCS to provide technical services to program
          participants or in lieu of, or on behalf of NRCS.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12920'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1465:A:1465.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1465.4
      </num>
      <head>
        National priorities.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1465' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              1465.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          National priorities.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Chief, with advice from State Conservationists, will identify
            national priorities to achieve the conservation objectives of AMA.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             National priorities will be used to guide annual funding
            allocations to States. (c) State Conservationists will use national
            priorities in conjunction with State and local priorities to
            prioritize and select AMA applications for funding.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS will undertake periodic reviews of the national priorities and
            the effects of program delivery at the State and local levels to
            adapt the program to address emerging resource issues.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12921'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1465:A:1465.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1465.5
      </num>
      <head>
        Program requirements.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          74 FR 64595
        </aref>
        , Dec. 8, 2009, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          76 FR 19684
        </aref>
        , Apr. 8, 2011]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1465' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              1465.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Program requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Participation in AMA is voluntary. The participant, in cooperation
            with the local conservation district, applies for practice
            installation for the agricultural operation. NRCS provides payments
            through contracts to apply needed conservation practices within a
            time schedule specified in the APO.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Chief determines the funds available for financial assistance
            according to the purpose and projected cost for which the financial
            assistance is provided in a fiscal year. The Chief allocates the
            funds available to carry out AMA in consideration of national
            priorities established under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1465' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
                1465.4
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be eligible to participate in AMA, an applicant must:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Own or operate an agricultural operation within an applicable
            State, as listed in 1465.1;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provide NRCS with written evidence of ownership or legal control
            for the life of the proposed contract, including the O&amp;M
            agreement. An exception may be made by the Chief:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the case of land allotted by the BIA, Tribal land, or other
            instances in which the Chief determines that there is sufficient
            assurance of control; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the applicant is a tenant of the land involved in agricultural
            production, the applicant will provide NRCS with the written
            concurrence of the landowner in order to apply a structural
            practice(s);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Submit an application form NRCS-CPA-1200;
            <PRTPAGE P='786' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Agree to provide all information to NRCS determined to be necessary
            to assess the merits of a proposed project and to monitor contract
            compliance;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provide a list of all members of the legal entity and embedded
            entities along with members&apos; tax identification numbers and
            percentage interest in the entity. Where applicable, American
            Indians, Alaska Natives, and Pacific Islanders may use another
            unique identification number for each individual eligible for
            payment;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             With regard to contracts with Indian Tribes or Indians represented
            by the BIA, payments if a BIA or Tribal official certify in writing
            that no one individual, directly or indirectly, will receive more
            than the payment limitation. The Tribal entity must also provide,
            annually, a listing of individuals and payments made by social
            security or tax identification number or other unique identification
            number, during the previous year for calculation of overall payment
            limitations. The BIA or Tribal entity must also provide, at the
            request of NRCS, proof of payments made to the person or legal
            entity that incurred costs or sacrificed income related to
            conservation practice implementation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Supply other information, as required by NRCS, to determine payment
            eligibility as established by 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
                1400
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , Adjusted Gross Income;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             With regard to any participant that utilizes a unique
            identification number as an alternative to a tax identification
            number, the participant will utilize only that identifier for any
            and all other AMA contracts to which the participant is a party.
            Violators will be considered to have provided fraudulent
            representation and be subject to full penalties of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1465' sect='25' psec='' tq='N'>
                1465.25
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             States, political subdivisions, and entities thereof will not be
            persons eligible for payment. Any cooperative association of
            producers that markets commodities for producers will not be
            considered to be a person eligible for payment;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be in compliance with the terms of all other USDA-administered
            conservation program agreements to which the participant is a party;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_11'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (11)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Develop and agree to comply with an APO and O&amp;M agreement, as
            described in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1465' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
                1465.3
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_12'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (12)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Comply with applicable registration and reporting requirements of
            the Federal Funding Accountability and Transparency Act of 2006 (
            <aref target='_blank' title='Pub. L. 109-282' alt='Pub. L. 109-282' href='http://www.gpo.gov/fdsys/pkg/PLAW-109publ282/html/PLAW-109publ282.htm'>
              Pub. L. 109-282
            </aref>
            , as amended), and 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              2 CFR parts 
              <subref title='2' part='25' tq='N'>
                25
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='2' part='170' tq='N'>
                170
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land may only be considered for enrollment in AMA if NRCS
            determines that the land is:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Privately owned land;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Publicly owned land where:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The land is a working component of the participant&apos;s
            agricultural and forestry operation; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The participant has control of the land for the term of the
            contract; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The conservation practices to be implemented on the public land are
            necessary and will contribute to an improvement in the identified
            resource concern; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The land is Indian land.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            74 FR 64595
          </aref>
          , Dec. 8, 2009, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 19684
          </aref>
          , Apr. 8, 2011]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12922'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1465:A:1465.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1465.6
      </num>
      <head>
        AMA plan of operations.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1465' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              1465.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          AMA plan of operations.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All conservation practices in the APO must be approved by NRCS and
            developed and carried out in accordance with the applicable NRCS
            technical guidance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The participant is responsible for implementing the APO.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The APO must include:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A description of the participant&apos;s specific conservation and
            environmental objectives to be achieved;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To the extent practicable, the quantitative or qualitative goals
            for achieving the participant&apos;s conservation and environmental
            objectives;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A description of one or more conservation practices in the
            conservation system, including conservation planning, design, or
            installation activities to be implemented to achieve the
            conservation and environmental objectives;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A description of the schedule for implementing the conservation
            practices, including timing, sequence, operation, and maintenance;
            and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Information that will enable evaluation of the effectiveness of the
            plan in achieving the environmental objectives.
            <PRTPAGE P='787' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An APO may be modified in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1465' sect='24' psec='' tq='N'>
                1465.24
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12923'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1465:A:1465.7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1465.7
      </num>
      <head>
        Conservation practices.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1465' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              1465.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Conservation practices.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State Conservationist will determine the conservation practices
            eligible for AMA payments. To be considered eligible conservation
            practices, the practices must meet the purposes of the AMA as set
            out in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1465' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
                1465.1
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . A list of eligible practices will be available to the public.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The APO includes the schedule of operations, activities, and
            payment rates of the practices needed to solve identified natural
            resource concerns.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12924'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1465:A:1465.8
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1465.8
      </num>
      <head>
        Technical services provided by qualified personnel not affiliated with
        USDA.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1465' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              1465.8
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Technical services provided by qualified personnel not affiliated with
          USDA.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS may use the services of qualified TSPs in performing its
            responsibilities for technical assistance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Participants may use technical services from qualified personnel of
            other Federal, State, local agencies, Indian Tribes, or individuals
            who are certified as TSPs by NRCS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Technical services provided by qualified personnel not affiliated
            with USDA may include, but are not limited to: conservation
            planning; conservation practice survey, layout, design,
            installation, and certification; and information, education, and
            training for producers, and related technical services as defined in
            
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='652' tq='N'>
                652
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS retains approval authority of work done by non-NRCS personnel
            for the purpose of approving AMA payments.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12925'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1465:B:1465.20
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1465.20
      </num>
      <head>
        Applications for participation and selecting applications for
        contracting.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1465' sect='20' psec='' tq='N'>
              1465.20
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Applications for participation and selecting applications for
          contracting.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any producer who has eligible land may submit an application for
            participation in AMA at a USDA service center. Producers who are
            members of a joint operation will file a single application for the
            joint operation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS will accept applications throughout the year. The State
            Conservationist will distribute information on the availability of
            assistance, national priorities, and the State-specific goals.
            Information will be provided that explains the process to request
            assistance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State Conservationist will develop ranking criteria and a
            ranking process to select applications, taking into account
            national, State, Tribal, and local priorities.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State Conservationist, or designated conservationist, using a
            locally-led process will evaluate, rank, and select applications for
            contracting based on the State-developed ranking criteria and
            ranking process.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State Conservationist, or designated conservationist, will work
            with the applicant to collect the information necessary to evaluate
            the application using the ranking criteria.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12926'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1465:B:1465.21
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1465.21
      </num>
      <head>
        Contract requirements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1465' sect='21' psec='' tq='N'>
              1465.21
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Contract requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In order for a participant to receive payments, the participant
            will enter into a contract agreeing to implement one or more
            eligible conservation practices. Costs for technical services may be
            included in the contract.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An AMA contract will:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Encompass all portions of an agricultural operation receiving AMA
            assistance;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Have a minimum duration of one year after completion of the last
            practice, but not more than 10 years;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Incorporate all provisions required by law or statute, including
            participant requirements to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Not conduct any practices on the agricultural operation that would
            tend to defeat the purposes of the contract according to 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1465' sect='25' psec='' tq='N'>
                1465.25
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Refund any AMA payments received with interest, and forfeit any
            future payments under AMA, on the violation of a term or condition
            of the contract, consistent with the provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1465' sect='25' psec='' tq='N'>
                1465.25
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Refund all AMA payments received on the transfer of the right and
            interest of the producer in land subject to the contract, unless the
            transferee of the right and interest agrees to assume all
            obligations, including operation and maintenance of the AMA
            contract&apos;s conservation practices, consistent with the
            provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1465' sect='24' psec='' tq='N'>
                1465.24
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Supply information as required by NRCS to determine compliance with
            the contract and requirements of AMA.
            <PRTPAGE P='788' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Specify the participant&apos;s requirements for operation and
            maintenance of the applied conservation practices consistent with
            the provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1465' sect='22' psec='' tq='N'>
                1465.22
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Specify any other provision determined necessary or appropriate by
            NRCS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The participant must apply the practice(s) according to the
            schedule set out in the APO.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12927'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1465:B:1465.22
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1465.22
      </num>
      <head>
        Conservation practice operation and maintenance.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1465' sect='22' psec='' tq='N'>
              1465.22
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Conservation practice operation and maintenance.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The contract will incorporate the O&amp;M agreement that addresses
            the operation and maintenance of the conservation practices applied
            under the contract.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS expects the participant to operate and maintain each
            conservation practice installed under the contract for its intended
            purpose for the conservation practice lifespan as specified in the
            O&amp;M agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS may periodically inspect the conservation practice(s) during
            the contract duration to ensure that operation and maintenance
            requirements are being carried out, and that the conservation
            practice is fulfilling its intended objectives.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Conservation practices installed before the contract execution, but
            included in the contract to obtain the environmental benefits agreed
            upon, must be operated and maintained as specified in the contract
            and O&amp;M agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If NRCS finds during the contract that a participant is not
            operating and maintaining practices in an appropriate manner, NRCS
            may terminate and request a refund of payments made for that
            conservation practice under the contract.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the event a conservation practice fails through no fault of the
            participant, the State Conservationist may issue payments to
            re-establish the conservation practice, at the rates established in
            accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1465' sect='23' psec='' tq='N'>
                1465.23
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , provided such payments do not exceed the payment limitation
            requirements as set forth in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1465' sect='23' psec='' tq='N'>
                1465.23
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12928'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1465:B:1465.23
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1465.23
      </num>
      <head>
        Payments.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1465' sect='23' psec='' tq='N'>
              1465.23
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Payments.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Federal share of payments to a participant will be:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Up to 75 percent of the estimated incurred cost or 100 percent of
            the estimated income foregone of an eligible practice, except as
            provided in (a)(2) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the case of historically underserved producers, the payment rate
            will be the applicable rate and an additional rate that is not less
            than 25 percent above the applicable rate, provided that this
            increase does not exceed 90 percent of the estimated incurred costs
            or estimated income foregone.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In no instance will the total financial contributions for an
            eligible practice from other sources exceed 100 percent of the
            estimated incurred cost of the practice.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Participants may contribute their portion of the estimated costs of
            practices through in-kind contributions, including labor and
            materials, providing the materials contributed meet the NRCS
            standard and specifications for the practice being installed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payments for practices applied prior to application or contract
            approval—
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payments will not be made to a participant for a conservation
            practice that was applied prior to application for the program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payments will not be made to a participant for a conservation
            practice that was initiated or implemented prior to contract
            approval, unless the participant obtained a waiver from the State
            Conservationist, or designated conservationist, prior to practice
            implementation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The total amount of payments paid to a person or legal entity under
            this part may not exceed $50,000 for any fiscal year.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For purposes of applying the payment limitations provided for in
            this section, NRCS will use the provisions in 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
                1400
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , Payment Limitation and Payment Eligibility.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A participant will not be eligible for payments for conservation
            practices on eligible land if the participant receives payments or
            other benefits for the same practice on the same land under any
            other conservation program administered by USDA.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The participant and NRCS must certify that a conservation practice
            is 
            <PRTPAGE P='789' />
            completed in accordance with the contract before NRCS will approve
            any payment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subject to fund availability, the payment rates for conservation
            practices scheduled after the year of contract obligation may be
            adjusted to reflect increased costs.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12929'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1465:B:1465.24
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1465.24
      </num>
      <head>
        Contract modifications, extensions, and transfers of land.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1465' sect='24' psec='' tq='N'>
              1465.24
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Contract modifications, extensions, and transfers of land.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The participant and NRCS may modify a contract if both parties
            agree to the contract modification, the APO is revised in accordance
            with NRCS requirements, and the designated conservationist approves
            the modified contract.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             It is the participant&apos;s responsibility to notify NRCS when he
            or she either anticipates the voluntary or involuntary loss of
            control of the land.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The participant and NRCS may mutually agree to transfer a contract
            to another party.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To receive an AMA payment, the transferee must be determined by
            NRCS to be eligible to participate in AMA and will assume full
            responsibility under the contract, including the O&amp;M agreement
            for those conservation practices already installed and those
            conservation practices to be installed as a condition of the
            contract.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             With respect to any and all payment owed to participants who wish
            to transfer ownership or control of land subject to a contract, the
            division of payment will be determined by the original party and the
            party&apos;s successor. In the event of a dispute or claim on the
            distribution of payments, NRCS may withhold payments without the
            accrual of interest pending a settlement or adjudication on the
            rights to the funds.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS may require a participant to refund all or a portion of any
            assistance earned under AMA if the participant sells or loses
            control of the land under an AMA contract, and the successor in
            interest is not eligible or refuses to accept future payments to
            participate in the AMA or refuses to assume responsibility under the
            contract.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The contract participants will be jointly and severally responsible
            for refunding the payments with applicable interest pursuant to
            paragraph (d) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12930'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1465:B:1465.25
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1465.25
      </num>
      <head>
        Contract violations and termination.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1465' sect='25' psec='' tq='N'>
              1465.25
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Contract violations and termination.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If NRCS determines that a participant is in violation of the terms
            of a contract, O&amp;M agreement, or other documents incorporated
            into the contract, NRCS will give the participant notice and 60
            days, unless otherwise determined by the State Conservationist, to
            correct the violation and comply with the terms of the contract and
            attachments thereto. If a participant continues in violation, the
            State Conservationist may terminate the AMA contract.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notwithstanding the provisions of (a) of this section, a contract
            termination will be effective immediately upon a determination by
            the State Conservationist that the participant has submitted false
            information or filed a false claim, or engaged in any act, scheme,
            or device for which a finding of ineligibility for payments is
            permitted under the provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1465' sect='35' psec='' tq='N'>
                1465.35
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , or in a case in which the actions of the party involved are deemed
            to be sufficiently purposeful or negligent to warrant a termination
            without delay.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If NRCS terminates a contract, the participant will forfeit all
            rights to future payments under the contract and refund all or part
            of the payments received, plus interest. Participants violating AMA
            contracts may be determined ineligible for future NRCS-administered
            conservation program funding.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State Conservationist may require only a partial refund of the
            payments received if the State Conservationist determines that a
            previously installed conservation practice can function
            independently and is not affected by the violation or the absence of
            other conservation practices that would have been installed under
            the contract.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If NRCS terminates a contract due to breach of contract, or the
            participant voluntarily terminates the contract before any
            contractual payments have been made, the participant will forfeit
            all rights for further payments under the contract and will pay such
            liquidated damages as prescribed 
            <PRTPAGE P='790' />
            in the contract. The State Conservationist will have the option to
            waive the liquidated damages depending upon the circumstances of the
            case.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When making all contract termination decisions, NRCS may reduce the
            amount of money owed by the participant by a proportion that
            reflects the good faith effort of the participant to comply with the
            contract or the existence of hardships beyond the participant&apos;s
            control that have prevented compliance with the contract. If the
            participant claims hardship, that claim must be well documented and
            cannot have existed when the applicant applied for participation in
            the program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The participant may voluntarily terminate a contract if NRCS agrees
            based on NRCS&apos; determination that termination is in the public
            interest.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In carrying out NRCS&apos; role in this section, NRCS may consult
            with the local conservation district.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12931'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1465:C:1465.30
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1465.30
      </num>
      <head>
        Appeals.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1465' sect='30' psec='' tq='N'>
              1465.30
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Appeals.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A participant may obtain administrative review of an adverse
            decision under AMA in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR parts 
              <subref title='7' part='11' tq='N'>
                11
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='614' tq='N'>
                614
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , except as provided in paragraph (b) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The following decisions are not appealable:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payment rates, payment limits;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Funding allocations;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Eligible conservation practices; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Other matters of general applicability, including:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_4_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Technical standards and formulas;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_4_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Denial of assistance due to lack of funds or authority; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_4_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Science-based formulas and criteria.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12932'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1465:C:1465.31
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1465.31
      </num>
      <head>
        Compliance with regulatory measures.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1465' sect='31' psec='' tq='N'>
              1465.31
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Compliance with regulatory measures.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Participants who carry out conservation practices will be responsible
          for obtaining the authorities, rights, easements, permits, or other
          approvals necessary for the implementation, operation, and maintenance
          of the conservation practices in keeping with applicable laws and
          regulations. Participants will be responsible for compliance with all
          laws and for all effects or actions resulting from the
          participant&apos;s performance under the contract.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12933'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1465:C:1465.32
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1465.32
      </num>
      <head>
        Access to operating unit.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1465' sect='32' psec='' tq='N'>
              1465.32
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Access to operating unit.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Any authorized NRCS representative will have the right to enter an
          operating unit or tract for the purpose of determining eligibility and
          for ascertaining the accuracy of any representations related to
          contracts and performance. Access will include the right to provide
          technical assistance; determine eligibility; inspect any work
          undertaken under the contracts, including the APO and O&amp;M
          agreement; and collect information necessary to evaluate the
          conservation practice performance as specified in the contracts. The
          NRCS representative will make an effort to contact the participant
          prior to exercising this provision.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12934'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1465:C:1465.33
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1465.33
      </num>
      <head>
        Equitable relief.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1465' sect='33' psec='' tq='N'>
              1465.33
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Equitable relief.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a participant relied upon the advice or action of any authorized
            NRCS representative and did not know, or have reason to know, that
            the action or advice was improper or erroneous, the participant may
            be eligible for equitable relief under 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='635' tq='N'>
                635
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 
              <subref title='7' part='635' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
                635.3
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . The financial or technical liability for any action by a
            participant that was taken based on the advice of an NRCS certified
            TSP is the responsibility of the certified TSP and will not be
            assumed by NRCS when NRCS authorizes payment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a participant has been found in violation of a provision of the
            AMA contract or any document incorporated by reference through
            failure to comply fully with that provision, the participant may be
            eligible for equitable relief under 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='635' tq='N'>
                635
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 
              <subref title='7' part='635' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
                635.4
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12935'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1465:C:1465.34
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1465.34
      </num>
      <head>
        Offsets and assignments.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1465' sect='34' psec='' tq='N'>
              1465.34
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Offsets and assignments.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as provided in paragraph (b) of this section, any payment or
            portion thereof to any participant will be made without regard to
            questions of Title under State law and without regard to any claim
            or lien against the crop, or proceeds thereof, in favor of the owner
            or any other creditor except agencies of the United States
            Government. The regulations governing offsets and withholdings found
            at 7 CFR 
            <PRTPAGE P='791' />
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1403' tq='N'>
                1403
              </subref>
            </aref>
             will be applicable to contract payments.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             AMA participants may assign any payments in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1404' tq='N'>
                1404
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12936'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1465:C:1465.35
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1465.35
      </num>
      <head>
        Misrepresentation and scheme or device.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1465' sect='35' psec='' tq='N'>
              1465.35
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Misrepresentation and scheme or device.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A participant who is determined to have erroneously represented any
            fact affecting an AMA determination made in accordance with this
            part will not be entitled to contract payments and must refund to
            NRCS all payments plus interest, as determined in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1403' tq='N'>
                1403
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A participant will refund to NRCS all payments, plus interest, as
            determined by NRCS with respect to all NRCS contracts to which they
            are a party if they are determined to have knowingly:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Adopted any scheme or device that tends to defeat the purpose of
            AMA;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Made any fraudulent representation;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Adopted any scheme or device for the purpose of depriving any
            tenant or sharecropper of the payments to which such person would
            otherwise be entitled under the program; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Misrepresented any fact affecting an AMA determination.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Where paragraph (a) or (b) of this section applies, the
            participant&apos;s interest in all contracts will be terminated. In
            accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1465' sect='25' psec='#c' tq='N'>
                1465.25(c)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , NRCS may determine the producer ineligible for future funding from
            any NRCS conservation programs.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12937'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1465:C:1465.36
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1465.36
      </num>
      <head>
        Environmental services credits for conservation improvements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1465' sect='36' psec='' tq='N'>
              1465.36
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Environmental services credits for conservation improvements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          NRCS recognizes that environmental benefits will be achieved by
          implementing conservation practices funded through AMA, and that
          environmental credits may be gained as a result of implementing
          activities compatible with the purposes of an AMA contract. NRCS
          asserts no direct or indirect interest on these credits. However, NRCS
          retains the authority to ensure that operation and maintenance
          requirements for AMA-funded improvements are met, consistent with 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1465' sect='21' psec='' tq='N'>
              1465.21
            </subref>
          </aref>
           and 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1465' sect='22' psec='' tq='N'>
              1465.22
            </subref>
          </aref>
          . Where activities may impact the land under an AMA contract,
          participants are highly encouraged to request an operation and
          maintenance compatibility determination prior to entering into any
          credit agreements. The AMA conservation program contract may be
          modified in accordance with policies outlined in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1465' sect='24' psec='' tq='N'>
              1465.24
            </subref>
          </aref>
           provided the modifications meet AMA purposes and are in compliance
          with this part.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>