<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol10'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1450
    </extid>
    <num>
      1450
    </num>
    <head>
      BIOMASS CROP ASSISTANCE PROGRAM (BCAP)
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='8111' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/8111.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 8111
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 66234
          </aref>
          , October 27, 2010, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='12846'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1450:A:1450.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1450.1
      </num>
      <head>
        Administration.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 66234
        </aref>
        , October 27, 2010, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          76 FR 56951
        </aref>
        , Sept. 15, 2011]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1450' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              1450.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Administration.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The regulations in this part are administered under the general
            supervision and direction of the Executive Vice President, Commodity
            Credit Corporation (CCC), or a designee. In the field, the
            regulations in this part will be implemented by the Farm Service
            Agency (FSA) State and county committees (“State committees” and
            “county committees,” respectively).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State executive directors, county executive directors, and State
            and county committees do not have the authority to modify or waive
            any of the provisions in this part unless specifically authorized by
            the FSA Deputy Administrator for Farm Program (Deputy
            Administrator).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State committee may take any action authorized or required by
            this part to be taken by the county committee, but which has not
            been taken by such committee, such as:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Correct or require a county committee to correct any action taken
            by such county committee that is not in accordance with this part;
            or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Require a county committee to withhold taking any action that is
            not in accordance with this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No delegation of authority to a State or county committee will
            preclude the Executive Vice President, CCC, or a designee, from
            determining any question arising under this part or from reversing
            or modifying any determination made by a State or county committee.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Data furnished by participants will be used to determine
            eligibility for program benefits. Furnishing the data is voluntary;
            however, the failure to provide data could result in program
            benefits being withheld or denied.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subject to the availability of funds and all other eligibility
            provisions of this part, this part provides the terms, conditions
            and requirements of BCAP. In the event that CCC determines that
            available funds are insufficient to accommodate the demand for
            establishment and annual payments as well as all potential
            applications for matching payments for collection, harvest, storage,
            and transportation of eligible material, without any advance notice
            other than that stated here, CCC may prioritize the expenditure of
            program funds in favor of funding for the selection of BCAP project
            areas and the establishment and annual payments related to those
            project areas, and may make such other priorities in approvals that
            will, in the determination of the Deputy Administrator, advance the
            purposes of BCAP.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 66234
          </aref>
          , October 27, 2010, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 56951
          </aref>
          , Sept. 15, 2011]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12847'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1450:A:1450.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1450.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 66234
        </aref>
        , October 27, 2010, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          76 FR 56951
        </aref>
        , Sept. 15, 2011]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1450' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              1450.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The definitions in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='718' tq='N'>
                718 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
             apply to this part and all documents issued in accordance with this
            part, except as otherwise provided in this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The following definitions apply to this part:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Advanced biofuel
          </E>
           means fuel derived from renewable biomass other than corn kernel
          starch, including biofuels derived from cellulose, hemicellulose, or
          lignin; biofuels derived from sugar and starch (other than ethanol
          derived from corn kernel starch); biofuel derived from waste material,
          including crop residue, other vegetative waste material, animal waste,
          food waste, and yard waste; diesel-equivalent fuel derived from
          renewable biomass including vegetable oil and animal fat; biogas
          (including landfill gas and sewage waste treatment gas) produced
          through the conversion of organic matter from renewable biomass; and
          butanol or other alcohols produced through the conversion of organic
          matter from renewable biomass; and other fuel derived from cellulosic
          biomass.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Agricultural land
          </E>
           means cropland, grassland, pastureland, rangeland, hayland, and other
          land on which food, fiber, or other agricultural products are produced
          or capable of being produced.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Animal waste
          </E>
           means the organic animal waste of animal operations such as confined
          beef or dairy, poultry, or swine operations including manure,
          contaminated runoff, milking house waste, dead poultry, bedding, and
          spilled feed. Depending on the poultry system, animal waste can also
          include litter, wash-flush water, and waste feed.
          <PRTPAGE P='747' />
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Annual payment
          </E>
           means the annual payment specified in the BCAP contract for BCAP
          project areas that is issued to a participant for placing eligible
          land in BCAP.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Beginning farmer or rancher
          </E>
           means, as determined by CCC, a person or entity who:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Has not been a farm or ranch operator or owner for more than 10
            years,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Materially and substantially participates in the operation of the
            farm or ranch, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If an entity, is an entity in which at least 50 percent of the
            members or stockholders of the entity meet the first two
            requirements of this definition.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Biobased product
          </E>
           means a product determined by CCC to be a commercial or industrial
          product (other than food or feed) that is:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Composed, in whole or in significant part, of biological products,
            including renewable domestic agricultural materials and forestry
            materials; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An intermediate ingredient or feedstock.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Bioenergy
          </E>
           means renewable energy produced from organic matter. Organic matter
          may be used directly as a fuel, be processed into liquids and gases,
          or be a residual of processing and conversion.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Biofuel
          </E>
           means a fuel derived from renewable biomass.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Biomass conversion facility
          </E>
           means a facility that converts or proposes to convert renewable
          biomass into heat, power, biobased products, or advanced biofuels.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Conservation district
          </E>
           is as defined in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='1410' tq='N'>
              1410 of this chapter
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Conservation plan
          </E>
           means a schedule and record of the participant&apos;s decisions and
          supporting information for treatment of a unit of land or water, and
          includes a schedule of operations, activities, and estimated
          expenditures for eligible crops and the collection or harvesting of
          eligible material, as appropriate, and addresses natural resource
          concerns including the sustainable harvesting of biomass, when
          appropriate, by addressing the site-specific needs of the landowner.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Contract acreage
          </E>
           means eligible land that is covered by a BCAP contract between the
          producer and CCC.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Delivery
          </E>
           means the point of delivery of an eligible crop or eligible material,
          as determined by the CCC.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Deputy Administrator
          </E>
           means the FSA Deputy Administrator for Farm Programs, or a designee.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Dry ton
          </E>
           means one U.S. ton measuring 2,000 pounds. One dry ton is the amount
          of renewable biomass that would weigh one U.S. ton at zero percent
          moisture content.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Eligible crop
          </E>
           means a crop of renewable biomass as defined in this section
          excluding:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any crop that is eligible to receive payments under Title I,
            “Commodity Programs,” of the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of
            2008 (
            <aref target='_blank' title='Pub. L. 110-246' alt='Pub. L. 110-246' href='http://www.gpo.gov/fdsys/pkg/PLAW-110publ246/html/PLAW-110publ246.htm'>
              Pub. L. 110-246
            </aref>
            ) or an amendment made by that title, including, but not limited to,
            barley, corn, grain sorghum, oats, rice, or wheat; honey; mohair;
            certain oilseeds such as canola, crambe, flaxseed, mustard seed,
            rapeseed, safflower seed, soybeans, sesame seed, and sunflower
            seeds; peanuts; pulse crops such as small chickpeas, lentils, and
            dry peas; dairy products; sugar; wool; and cotton boll fiber; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any plant that CCC has determined to be either a noxious weed or an
            invasive species. With respect to noxious weeds and invasive
            species, a list of such plants will be available in the FSA county
            office.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Eligible material
          </E>
           is renewable biomass as defined in this section excluding:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Material that is whole grain from any crop that is eligible to
            receive payments under Title I of the Food, Conservation, and Energy
            Act of 2008 or an amendment made by that title, including, but not
            limited to, barley, corn, grain sorghum, oats, rice, or wheat;
            honey; or material that is mohair; certain oilseeds such as canola,
            crambe, flaxseed, mustard seed, rapeseed, safflower seed, soybeans,
            sesame seed, and sunflower seeds; peanuts; pulse crops such as small
            chickpeas, lentils, and dry peas; dairy products; sugar; wool; and
            cotton boll fiber;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Animal waste and by-products of animal waste including fats, oils,
            greases, and manure;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Food waste and yard waste; and
            <PRTPAGE P='748' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Algae.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Eligible material owner,
          </E>
           for purposes of the matching payment, means a person or entity having
          the right to collect or harvest eligible material, who has the risk of
          loss in the material that is delivered to an eligible facility and who
          has directly or by agent delivered or intends to deliver the eligible
          material to a qualified biomass conversion facility, including:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For eligible material harvested or collected from private lands,
            including cropland, the owner of the land, the operator or producer
            conducting farming operations on the land, or any other person
            designated by the owner of the land; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For eligible material harvested or collected from public lands, a
            person having the right to harvest or collect eligible material
            pursuant to a contract or permit with the US Forest Service or other
            appropriate Federal agency, such as a timber sale contract,
            stewardship contract or agreement, service contract or permit, or
            related applicable Federal land permit or contract, and who has
            submitted a copy of the permit or contract authorizing such
            collection to CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Equivalent plan
          </E>
           means a plan approved by a State or other State agency or government
          entity that is similar to and serves the same purpose as a forest
          stewardship plan and has similar goals, objectives, and terms. These
          plans generally address natural resource concerns including the
          sustainable harvesting of biomass, when appropriate, by addressing the
          site-specific needs of the landowner.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Establishment payment
          </E>
           means the payment made by CCC to assist program participants in
          establishing the practices required for non-woody perennial crops and
          woody perennial crops, as specified in a producer contract under the
          project portion of BCAP.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Food waste
          </E>
           means, as determined by CCC, a material composed primarily of food
          items, or originating from food items, or compounds from domestic,
          municipal, food service operations, or commercial sources, including
          food processing wastes, residues, or scraps.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Forest stewardship plan
          </E>
           means a long-term, comprehensive, multi-resource forest management
          plan that is prepared by a professional resource manager and approved
          by the State Forester or equivalent State official. Forest stewardship
          plans address the following resource elements wherever present, in a
          manner that is compatible with landowner objectives concerning:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Soil and water;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Biological diversity;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Range;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Aesthetic quality;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Recreation;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Timber;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Fish and wildlife;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Threatened and endangered species;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Forest health;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Archeological, cultural and historic sites;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_11'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (11)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Wetlands;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_12'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (12)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Fire; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_13'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (13)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Carbon cycle.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Higher-value product
          </E>
           means an existing market product that is comprised principally of an
          eligible material or materials and, in some distinct local regions, as
          determined by the CCC, has an existing market as of October 27, 2010.
          Higher-value products may include, but are not limited to, products
          such as mulch, fiberboard, nursery media, lumber, or paper.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Highly erodible land
          </E>
           means land as determined as specified in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='12' tq='N'>
              12 of this title
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Indian tribe
          </E>
           has the same meaning as in 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='25' sect='450b' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/25/450b.html'>
              25 U.S.C. 450b
            </subref>
          </aref>
           (
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 4 of
          </aref>
           the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Institution of higher education
          </E>
           has the same meaning as in 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='20' sect='1002' note='' psec='#a' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/20/1002.html#a'>
              20 U.S.C. 1002(a)
            </subref>
          </aref>
           (
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 102(a) of
          </aref>
           the Higher Education Act of 1965).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Intermediate ingredient or feedstock
          </E>
           means an ingredient or compound made in whole or in significant part
          from biological products, including renewable agricultural material
          (including plant, animal, and marine material), or forestry material
          that is subsequently used to make a more complex compound or product.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Legal entity
          </E>
           has the same meaning as in the regulations in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1400' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              1400.3
            </subref>
             of this chapter
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Matching payments
          </E>
           means those CCC payments provided for eligible material delivered to
          a qualified biomass conversion facility.
          <PRTPAGE P='749' />
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Native sod
          </E>
           means land:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             On which the plant cover is composed principally of native grasses,
            grasslike plants, forbs, or shrubs suitable for grazing and
            browsing; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             That had never been tilled for the production of an annual crop as
            of June 18, 2008.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Nonindustrial private forest land
          </E>
           means, as defined in 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='16' sect='2103a' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/2103a.html'>
              16 U.S.C. 2103a
            </subref>
          </aref>
           (the Cooperative Forestry Assistance Act of 1978, as amended), rural
          lands with existing tree cover, or suitable for growing trees, where
          the land is owned by any private individual, group, association,
          corporation, Indian tribe, or other private legal entity.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Offer
          </E>
           means, unless otherwise indicated, the per-acre rental payment
          requested by the owner or operator in such owner&apos;s or
          operator&apos;s request to participate in the establishment payment
          and annual payment component of BCAP.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Operator
          </E>
           means a person who is in general control of the land enrolled in
          BCAP, as determined by CCC.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Participant
          </E>
           means a person who is participating in BCAP—either as a person who
          has applied for and is eligible to receive payments, has a BCAP
          contract, or is a project sponsor.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Payment period
          </E>
           means a contract period of either up to 5 years for annual and
          non-woody perennial crops, or up to 15 years for woody perennial
          crops, during which the participant receives an annual payment under
          the establishment payment and annual payment component of BCAP.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Person
          </E>
           has the same meaning as in the regulations in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1400' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              1400.3
            </subref>
             of this chapter
          </aref>
          . In addition, for BCAP, the term “producer” means either an owner or
          operator of BCAP project acreage that is physically located in a BCAP
          project area, or a producer of an eligible crop produced on that
          acreage.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Producer
          </E>
           means, with respect to subpart B of this part, a person who had the
          risk of loss in the production of the material that is the subject of
          the BCAP payment; and with respect to subpart C of this part, an owner
          or operator of contract acreage that is physically located within a
          BCAP project area or a producer of an eligible crop produced on that
          acreage and who has the risk of loss in the relevant crop at the
          relevant period of time or who will have the risk of loss in crops
          required to be produced.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Project area
          </E>
           means a geographic area with specified boundaries submitted by a
          project sponsor and approved by CCC under the establishment payment
          and annual payment component of BCAP.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Project sponsor
          </E>
           means a group of producers or a biomass conversion facility who
          proposes a project area.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Qualified biomass conversion facility
          </E>
           means a biomass conversion facility that meets all the requirements
          for BCAP qualification, and whose facility representatives enter into
          a BCAP agreement with CCC.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Renewable biomass
          </E>
           means:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Appropriate materials, pre-commercial thinnings, or invasive
            species from National Forest System land and U.S. Department of the
            Interior, Bureau of Land Management land that:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Are by-products of preventive treatments that are removed to reduce
            hazardous fuels, to reduce or contain disease or insect infestation,
            or to restore ecosystem health;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Would not otherwise be used for higher-value products; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Are harvested in accordance with applicable law and land management
            plans and the requirements for old-growth maintenance, restoration,
            and management direction of 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='16' sect='6512' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/6512.html'>
                16 U.S.C. 6512
              </subref>
            </aref>
             (specifically, 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              sections 102(e)(2), (3), and (4) of
            </aref>
             the Healthy Forests Restoration Act of 2003 and large-tree
            retention provisions of subsection (f)); or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any organic matter that is available on a renewable or recurring
            basis from non-Federal land or land belonging to an Indian or Indian
            Tribe that is held in trust by the United States or subject to a
            restriction against alienation imposed by the United States,
            including:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Renewable plant material, including:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_iii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Feed grains;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_iii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Other agricultural commodities;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_iii_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Other plants and trees; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_iii_D'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (D)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Algae;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Waste material, including:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_ii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Crop residue;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_ii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Other vegetative waste material (including wood waste and wood
            residues);
            <PRTPAGE P='750' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_ii_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Animal waste and byproducts (including fats, oils, greases, and
            manure); and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_ii_D'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (D)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Food waste and yard waste.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Socially disadvantaged farmer or rancher
          </E>
           means, unless other classes of persons are approved by CCC in
          writing, a farmer or rancher who is a member of a group whose members
          have been subject to racial or ethnic prejudice because of their
          identity as members of a group without regard to their individual
          qualities. Groups include:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             American Indians or Alaskan Natives;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Asians or Asian Americans;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Blacks or African Americans;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Native Hawaiians or other Pacific Islanders; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Hispanics.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Technical assistance
          </E>
           means assistance in determining the eligibility of land and practices
          for BCAP, implementing and certifying practices, ensuring contract
          performance, and providing annual rental rate surveys. The technical
          assistance provided in connection with BCAP to owners or operators, as
          approved by CCC, includes, but is not limited to: Technical expertise,
          information, and tools necessary for the conservation of natural
          resources on land; technical services provided directly to farmers,
          ranchers, and other eligible entities, such as conservation planning,
          technical consultation, and assistance with design and implementation
          of eligible practices; and technical infrastructure, including
          activities, processes, tools, and functions needed to support delivery
          of technical services, such as technical standards, resource
          inventories, training, data, technology, monitoring, and effects
          analyses.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Tribal government
          </E>
           means any Indian tribe, band, nation, or other organized group, or
          community, including pueblos, rancherias, colonies and any Alaska
          Native Village, or regional or village corporation as defined in or
          established pursuant to 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='43' sect='1601-162' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/43/1601-162.html'>
              43 U.S.C. 1601-162
            </subref>
          </aref>
          9h (the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act), that is recognized as
          eligible for the special programs and services provided by the United
          States to Indians because of their status as Indians.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Violation
          </E>
           means an act by the participant, either intentional or unintentional,
          that would cause the participant to no longer be eligible to receive
          or retain all or a portion of BCAP payments.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Yard waste
          </E>
           means any renewable biomass generated from municipal or residential
          land, such as urban forestry materials, construction or demolition
          materials, trimmings from grasses and trees, or biomass removed due to
          invasive species or weather-related disaster, that can be separated
          from and has low potential (such as contamination with plastics,
          metals, chemicals, or other toxic compounds that cannot be removed)
          for the generation of toxic byproducts resulting from conversion, and
          that otherwise cannot be recycled for other purposes (such as
          post-consumer waste paper).
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 66234
          </aref>
          , October 27, 2010, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 56951
          </aref>
          , Sept. 15, 2011]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12848'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1450:A:1450.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1450.3
      </num>
      <head>
        General.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1450' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              1450.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The objectives of BCAP are to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Support the establishment and production of eligible crops for
            conversion to bioenergy and biobased products in selected project
            areas; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Assist agricultural and forest landowners and operators with
            matching payments to support the collection, harvest, storage, and
            transportation costs of eligible material for use in a biomass
            conversion facility.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A participant must implement and adhere to a conservation plan,
            forest stewardship plan, or equivalent plan prepared in accordance
            with BCAP guidelines, as established and determined by CCC. A
            conservation plan, forest stewardship plan, or equivalent plan for
            contract acreage must be implemented by a participant and must be
            approved by the conservation district in which the lands are
            located, or, in the case of Federal lands, the appropriate approval
            authority of jurisdiction. If the conservation district declines to
            review the conservation plan, forest stewardship plan, or equivalent
            plan, the provider of technical assistance may take such further
            action as is needed to account for lack of such review.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Agricultural and forest landowners and operators must comply with
            any applicable existing conservation plan, forest stewardship plan,
            or 
            <PRTPAGE P='751' />
            equivalent plan and all other applicable laws, regulations, or
            Executive Orders for any removal of eligible material for use in a
            biomass conversion facility to receive matching payments.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as otherwise provided in this part, a participant may
            receive, in addition to any payments under this part, financial
            assistance, rental or easement payments, tax benefits, or other
            payments from a State or a private organization in return for
            enrolling lands in BCAP, without any commensurate reduction in BCAP
            payments.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12849'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1450:A:1450.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1450.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Violations.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1450' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              1450.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Violations.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a participant fails to carry out the terms and conditions of a
            BCAP contract, CCC may terminate the BCAP contract.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the BCAP contract is terminated by CCC in accordance with this
            paragraph:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The participant will forfeit all rights to further payments under
            the contract and must refund all payments previously received, plus
            interest; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The participant must pay liquidated damages to CCC in an amount as
            specified in the contract.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC may reduce a demand for a refund under this section to the
            extent CCC determines that such relief would be appropriate and
            would not deter the accomplishment of the purposes of BCAP.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12850'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1450:A:1450.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1450.5
      </num>
      <head>
        Performance based on advice or action of USDA.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 66234
        </aref>
        , October 27, 2010, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          76 FR 56951
        </aref>
        , Sept. 15, 2011]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1450' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              1450.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Performance based on advice or action of USDA.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='718' sect='303' psec='' tq='N'>
                718.303
              </subref>
               of this title
            </aref>
             relating to performance based on the action or advice of an
            authorized representative of USDA apply to this part, and may be
            considered as a basis to provide relief to persons subject to
            sanctions under this part to the extent that relief is otherwise
            permitted by this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             [Reserved]
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 66234
          </aref>
          , October 27, 2010, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 56951
          </aref>
          , Sept. 15, 2011]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12851'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1450:A:1450.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1450.6
      </num>
      <head>
        Access to land.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1450' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              1450.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Access to land.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For purposes related to this program, the participant must upon
            request provide any representative of USDA, or designee thereof,
            with access to land that is:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The subject of an application for a contract under this part; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Under contract or otherwise subject to this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For land identified in paragraph (a) of this section, the
            participant must provide such representatives or designees with
            access to examine records for the land to determine land
            classification, eligibility, or for other purposes, and to determine
            whether the participant is in compliance with the terms and
            conditions of the BCAP contract.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12852'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1450:A:1450.7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1450.7
      </num>
      <head>
        Division of payments and provisions about tenants and sharecroppers.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1450' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              1450.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Division of payments and provisions about tenants and sharecroppers.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payments received under this part will be divided as specified in
            the applicable contract. CCC may refuse to enter into a contract
            when there is a disagreement among persons or legal entities seeking
            enrollment as to a person&apos;s or legal entity&apos;s eligibility
            to participate in the contract as a tenant or sharecropper, and
            there is insufficient evidence, as determined by CCC, to indicate
            whether the person or legal entity seeking participation as a tenant
            or sharecropper has an interest in the acreage offered for
            enrollment in the BCAP.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC may remove an operator or tenant from a BCAP contract when:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The operator or tenant requests in writing to be removed from the
            BCAP contract;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The operator or tenant files for bankruptcy and the trustee or
            debtor in possession fails to affirm the contract, to the extent
            permitted by applicable bankruptcy laws;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The operator or tenant dies during the contract period and the
            administrator of the estate fails to succeed to the contract within
            a period of time determined appropriate by CCC; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A court of competent jurisdiction orders the removal of the
            operator or tenant from the BCAP contract and such order is received
            by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Tenants who fail to maintain tenancy on the acreage under contract
            for any reason may be removed from a contract by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12853'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1450:A:1450.8
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1450.8
      </num>
      <head>
        Payments not subject to claims.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='752' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1450' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              1450.8
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Payments not subject to claims.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subject to 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1403' tq='N'>
                1403 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , any payment or portion of the payment due any person or legal
            entity under this part will be allowed without regard to questions
            of title under State law, and without regard to any claim or lien in
            favor of any creditor, except agencies of the U.S. Government.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             [Reserved]
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12854'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1450:A:1450.9
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1450.9
      </num>
      <head>
        Assignments.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1450' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
              1450.9
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Assignments.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Participants may assign the right to receive cash payments under
            BCAP, in whole or in part, as provided in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1404' tq='N'>
                1404 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             [Reserved]
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12855'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1450:A:1450.10
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1450.10
      </num>
      <head>
        Appeals.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1450' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
              1450.10
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Appeals.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as provided in paragraph (b) of this section, a person or
            legal entity applying for participation may appeal or request
            reconsideration of an adverse determination in accordance with the
            administrative appeal regulations at 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              parts 
              <subref title='7' part='11' tq='N'>
                11
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='780' tq='N'>
                780 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Determinations by the Natural Resources Conservation Service may be
            appealed in accordance with procedures established under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='614' tq='N'>
                614 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
             or otherwise established by the Natural Resources Conservation
            Service.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12856'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1450:A:1450.11
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1450.11
      </num>
      <head>
        Scheme or device.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1450' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
              1450.11
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Scheme or device.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If CCC determines that a person or legal entity has employed a
            scheme or device to defeat the purposes of this part, or any part,
            of any USDA program, payment otherwise due or paid such person or
            legal entity during the applicable period may be required to be
            refunded, with interest calculated from the date of disbursement of
            the funds by CCC, as determined appropriate by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A scheme or device includes, but is not limited to, coercion,
            fraud, misrepresentation, depriving any other person or legal entity
            of any payments, or obtaining a payment that otherwise would not be
            payable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A new owner or operator or tenant of land subject to this part who
            succeeds to the contract responsibilities must report in writing to
            CCC any interest of any kind in the land subject to this part that
            is retained by a previous participant. Such interest may include a
            present, future, or conditional interest, reversionary interest, or
            any option, future or present, on such land, and any interest of any
            lender in such land where the lender has, will, or can legally
            obtain, a right of occupancy to such land or an interest in the
            equity in such land other than an interest in the appreciation in
            the value of such land occurring after the loan was made. Failure to
            fully disclose such interest will be considered a scheme or device
            under this section.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12857'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1450:A:1450.12
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1450.12
      </num>
      <head>
        Filing of false claims.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1450' sect='12' psec='' tq='N'>
              1450.12
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Filing of false claims.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If CCC determines that any participant has knowingly supplied false
            information or has knowingly filed a false claim, such participant
            will be ineligible for payments under this part with respect to the
            fiscal year in which the false information or claim was filed and
            the contract may be terminated, in which case CCC may demand a full
            refund of all prior payments.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             False information or false claims include, but are not limited to,
            claims for payment for practices that do not comply with the
            conservation plan, forest stewardship plan, or equivalent plan. Any
            amounts paid under these circumstances must be refunded to CCC,
            together with interest as determined by CCC, and any amounts
            otherwise due the participant will be withheld.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The remedies provided for in this section will be in addition to
            any other remedy available to CCC and in addition to any criminal
            penalty or any other remedy available to the United States.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12858'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1450:A:1450.13
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1450.13
      </num>
      <head>
        Miscellaneous.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1450' sect='13' psec='' tq='N'>
              1450.13
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Miscellaneous.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as otherwise provided in this part, in the case of death,
            incompetency, or disappearance of any participant, any payments due
            under this part may be paid to the participant&apos;s successor(s)
            in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='707' tq='N'>
                707 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Unless otherwise specified in this part, payments under this part
            will be subject to the compliance requirements of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='12' tq='N'>
                12 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
             concerning highly erodible land and wetland conservation and
            payments.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any remedies permitted CCC under this part will be in addition to 
            <PRTPAGE P='753' />
            any other remedy, including, but not limited to, criminal remedies
            or actions for damages in favor of CCC, or the United States as may
            be permitted by law.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Absent a scheme or device to defeat the purposes of BCAP, when an
            owner loses control of BCAP acreage enrolled under subpart C of this
            part due to foreclosure and the new owner chooses not to continue
            the contract in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1450' sect='215' psec='' tq='N'>
                1450.215
              </subref>
            </aref>
             refunds will not be required from any participant on the contract
            to the extent that the Deputy Administrator determines that
            forgiving such repayment is appropriate in order to provide fair and
            equitable treatment.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12859'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1450:B:1450.100
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1450.100
      </num>
      <head>
        General.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1450' sect='100' psec='' tq='N'>
              1450.100
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A person or legal entity with the right to collect or harvest
            eligible material for the sale and delivery of such eligible
            material to a qualified biomass conversion facility, may be eligible
            for payment under the provisions of this subpart.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             [Reserved]
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12860'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1450:B:1450.101
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1450.101
      </num>
      <head>
        Qualified biomass conversion facility.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1450' sect='101' psec='' tq='N'>
              1450.101
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Qualified biomass conversion facility.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be considered a qualified biomass conversion facility, a biomass
            conversion facility must enter into an agreement with CCC and must:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Meet all applicable regulatory and permitting requirements by
            applicable Federal, State, or local authorities;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Agree in writing to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Maintain accurate records of all eligible material purchases and
            related documents regardless of whether matching payments will be
            sought by the seller; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Make available at one place and at all reasonable times for
            examination by representatives of USDA, all books, papers, records,
            contracts, scale tickets, settlement sheets, invoices, written price
            quotations, or other documents related to BCAP for not less than 3
            years after the date that eligible material was delivered to the
            qualified biomass conversion facility;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Clearly indicate the actual tonnage delivered on the scale ticket
            or equivalent to be provided to the eligible material owner;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Calculate a total dry ton weight equivalent of the actual tonnage
            delivered and provide that measurement to the eligible material
            owner;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Use commercial weight scales that are certified for accuracy by
            applicable State or local authorities and accurate moisture
            measurement equipment to determine the dry ton weight equivalent of
            actual tonnage delivered;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Pay fair market value for eligible material regardless of whether
            the seller has applied for or receives a matching payment authorized
            by this subpart.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For a qualified biomass conversion facility, CCC can:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Periodically inform the public that payments may be available for
            deliveries of eligible material to such qualified biomass conversion
            facility;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Maintain a listing of qualified biomass conversion facilities for
            general public access and distribution that may include general
            information about the facility and its eligible material needs; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Suspend, terminate, or take other actions as appropriate when CCC
            determines a qualified biomass conversion facility fails to comply
            with the agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12861'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1450:B:1450.102
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1450.102
      </num>
      <head>
        Eligible material owner.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 66234
        </aref>
        , October 27, 2010, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          76 FR 56951
        </aref>
        , Sept. 15, 2011]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1450' sect='102' psec='' tq='N'>
              1450.102
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Eligible material owner.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In order to be eligible for a payment under this subpart, a person
            or legal entity must:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be a producer of an eligible crop that is produced on contract
            acreage authorized by subpart C of this part; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Have the right to collect or harvest eligible material and such
            person may only receive payment if the risk of loss for the material
            transferred to that person occurred prior to the time the payment is
            made that will be used to determine the matching payment that is
            requested under this subpart; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Certify that the eligible material for which a payment may be
            issued according to 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1450' sect='106' psec='' tq='N'>
                1450.106
              </subref>
            </aref>
             has been harvested according to a conservation plan, forest
            stewardship plan, or equivalent plan, and, if woody eligible
            material collected and harvested on land other than contract
            acreage, are byproducts 
            <PRTPAGE P='754' />
            of preventative treatments that are removed to reduce hazardous
            fuels, to reduce or contain disease or insect infestation, or to
            restore ecosystem health.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A qualified biomass conversion facility that meets the requirements
            of paragraph (a) of this section may be considered an eligible
            material owner if it otherwise meets the definition in this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 66234
          </aref>
          , October 27, 2010, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 56951
          </aref>
          , Sept. 15, 2011]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12862'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1450:B:1450.103
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1450.103
      </num>
      <head>
        Eligible material that qualifies for payment.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1450' sect='103' psec='' tq='N'>
              1450.103
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Eligible material that qualifies for payment.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except for paragraph (b) of this section, in order to qualify, as
            determined by CCC, for a payment under this subpart:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Eligible material must be renewable biomass that, at a minimum,
            meets the definition in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1450' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
                1450.2
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and is listed on the official Web site for BCAP as an eligible
            material at 
            <E T='03'>
              http://www.fsa.usda.gov/energy;
            </E>
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Eligible material must be collected or harvested by the eligible
            material owner:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Directly from:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_i_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             National Forest System land, Bureau of Land Management land;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_i_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Non-Federal land; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_i_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land belonging to an Indian or Indian tribe that is held in trust
            by the United States or subject to a restriction against alienation
            imposed by the United States;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Consistent with a conservation plan, forest stewardship plan, or
            plan that CCC determined to be an equivalent plan, that provides the
            following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_ii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The purpose of the harvest of the eligible material;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_ii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The expected volume of the harvest;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_ii_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The total number of acres to be harvested;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_ii_D'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (D)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The name of the eligible material owner(s); and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_2_ii_E'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (E)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any additional information, as determined by CCC; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Consistent with Executive Order 13112, “Invasive Species. ”
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Woody eligible material produced on land other than contract
            acreage must be:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Byproducts of preventative treatments that are removed to reduce
            hazardous fuels, to reduce or contain disease or insect infestation,
            or to restore ecosystem health; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If harvested from Federal lands then done so in accordance with the
            requirements for old-growth maintenance, restoration, and management
            direction provided by 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='16' sect='6512' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/6512.html'>
                16 U.S.C. 6512
              </subref>
            </aref>
             for Federal lands; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Eligible material must be delivered to a qualified biomass
            conversion facility (as specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1450' sect='101' psec='' tq='N'>
                1450.101
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and other provisions of these regulations).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notwithstanding paragraph (a) of this section, payments under this
            subpart are not authorized for:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any eligible material delivered before October 27, 2010;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any eligible material for which payment from a biomass conversion
            facility was received before the application for payment under this
            subpart is received and approved by the FSA county office, as
            specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1450' sect='104' psec='' tq='N'>
                1450.104
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any woody eligible material collected or harvested outside contract
            acreage that would otherwise be used for higher-value products; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any otherwise eligible material collected or harvested outside
            contract acreage that, after delivery to a biomass conversion
            facility, its campus, or its affiliated facilities, must be
            separated from an eligible material used for a higher-value market
            product in order to be used for heat, power, biobased products, or
            advanced biofuels.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12863'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1450:B:1450.104
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1450.104
      </num>
      <head>
        Signup.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1450' sect='104' psec='' tq='N'>
              1450.104
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Signup.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Applications for participation and requests for payments under this
            subpart will be accepted on a continuous basis.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An eligible material owner must apply to participate in the
            matching payments component of BCAP before payment for the eligible
            material is received from a qualified biomass conversion facility.
            The application must be submitted to the FSA county office and
            approved by CCC before any payment is made by the qualified biomass
            conversion facility for the eligible material.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Applications must include the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Based on information obtained from contracts, agreements, or
            binding letters of intent:
            <PRTPAGE P='755' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An estimate of the total dry tons of eligible material expected to
            be sold to the qualified biomass conversion facility;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The type(s) of eligible material that is expected to be sold;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The name of the qualified biomass conversion facility that will
            purchase the eligible material;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The expected, fair market, per dry ton payment rate the owner plans
            to receive for the delivery of the eligible material; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The date or dates the eligible material is expected to be delivered
            to the qualified biomass conversion facility.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A new or amended conservation plan, forest stewardship plan, or
            equivalent plan, as specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1450' sect='103' psec='' tq='N'>
                1450.103
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Eligible material owners who deliver eligible material to more than
            one qualified biomass conversion facility must submit separate
            applications for each facility to which eligible material will be
            delivered.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             After delivery, eligible material owners must notify CCC and
            request the payment. Payments will be disbursed only after delivery
            is verified by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Information that must be submitted to CCC in order to request
            payments includes settlement, summary, or other acceptable data that
            provide:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Total actual tonnage delivered and a total dry weight tonnage
            equivalent amount determined by the qualified biomass conversion
            facility using standard moisture determinations applicable to the
            eligible material;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Total payment received, including the per dry-ton payment rate(s)
            matched with actual and dry weight tonnage delivered; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The qualified biomass conversion facility&apos;s certification as
            to the authenticity of the information.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12864'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1450:B:1450.105
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1450.105
      </num>
      <head>
        Obligations of participant.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1450' sect='105' psec='' tq='N'>
              1450.105
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Obligations of participant.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All participants whose payment application was approved must agree
            to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Carry out and certify compliance with the terms and conditions of
            the payment application including adherence to a conservation plan,
            forest stewardship plan, or equivalent plan, as appropriate; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be jointly and severally responsible, if the participant has a
            share of the payment greater than zero, with other contract
            participants for compliance with the provisions of such contract and
            the provisions of this part, and for any refunds or payment
            adjustments that may be required for violations of any of the terms
            and conditions of the BCAP contract and this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             [Reserved]
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12865'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1450:B:1450.106
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1450.106
      </num>
      <head>
        Payments.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1450' sect='106' psec='' tq='N'>
              1450.106
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Payments.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payments under this subpart will be for a term not to exceed 2
            years beginning the date that CCC issues the first payment, under
            this subpart to the participant and for each participant runs from
            the date that the participant receives a matching payment from CCC
            even though the participant may over time change facilities. The
            Deputy Administrator may further limit the period to reflect
            participation in BCAP for any time prior to October 27, 2010 as the
            Deputy Administrator deems appropriate. In addition, where ownership
            of a source of material has changed, or where it is deemed that
            other circumstances warrant, the Deputy Administrator may apply the
            time limit applicable to a person or entity or to another person or
            entity to assure that the 2-year limit is not avoided by private
            arrangement or other circumstance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payments under this subpart will be paid at a rate of $1 for each
            $1 per dry ton provided by the qualified biomass conversion facility
            for the market-based sale of eligible material in an amount up to
            $45 per dry ton.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12866'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1450:C:1450.200
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1450.200
      </num>
      <head>
        General.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1450' sect='200' psec='' tq='N'>
              1450.200
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             As provided in this subpart, establishment payments and annual
            payments may be provided by CCC to producers of eligible crops
            within a project area.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             [Reserved]
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12867'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1450:C:1450.201
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1450.201
      </num>
      <head>
        Project area proposal submission requirements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1450' sect='201' psec='' tq='N'>
              1450.201
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Project area proposal submission requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be considered for selection as a project area, a project sponsor
            must 
            <PRTPAGE P='756' />
            submit a proposal to CCC that includes, at a minimum:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A description of the sources of renewable biomass, eligible land,
            and eligible crops that may be enrolled within the proposed project
            area;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A letter of commitment from a biomass conversion facility stating
            that the facility will use, for BCAP purposes, eligible crops
            intended to be produced in the proposed project area;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Information demonstrating that the biomass conversion facility will
            have sufficient equity available to operate if the facility is not
            operational at the time the project area proposal is submitted; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Other information that gives CCC a reasonable assurance that the
            biomass conversion facility will be in operation in a timely manner
            so that it will utilize the eligible crops, as determined by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The project area description required in paragraph (a) of this
            section needs to specify geographic boundaries and be described in
            definite terms such as acres, watershed boundaries, mapped longitude
            and latitude coordinates, or counties.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The project area needs to be physically located near a biomass
            conversion facility or facilities, as determined by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Project area proposals may limit the nature and types of eligible
            crops to be established within a project area.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12868'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1450:C:1450.202
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1450.202
      </num>
      <head>
        Project area selection criteria.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1450' sect='202' psec='' tq='N'>
              1450.202
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Project area selection criteria.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In selecting project areas, CCC will consider:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The dry tons of the eligible crops proposed to be produced in the
            proposed project area and the probability that such crops will be
            used for BCAP purposes;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The dry tons of renewable biomass projected to be available from
            sources other than the eligible crops grown on contract acres;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The anticipated economic impact in the proposed project area;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The opportunity for producers and local investors to participate in
            the ownership of the biomass conversion facility in the proposed
            project area;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The participation rate by beginning or socially disadvantaged
            farmers or ranchers;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The impact on soil, water, and related resources;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The variety in biomass production approaches within a project area,
            including agronomic conditions, harvest and postharvest practices,
            and monoculture and polyculture crop mixes;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The range of eligible crops among project areas; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any other additional criteria, as determined by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             [Reserved]
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12869'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1450:C:1450.203
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1450.203
      </num>
      <head>
        Eligible persons and legal entities.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1450' sect='203' psec='' tq='N'>
              1450.203
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Eligible persons and legal entities.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In order to be eligible to enter into a BCAP contract for this
            subpart, a person or legal entity must be an owner, operator, or
            tenant of eligible land within a project area, as defined in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1450' sect='204' psec='' tq='N'>
                1450.204
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and be the person or entity with the ability to perform under the
            terms of the contract.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             [Reserved]
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12870'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1450:C:1450.204
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1450.204
      </num>
      <head>
        Eligible land.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1450' sect='204' psec='' tq='N'>
              1450.204
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Eligible land.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For the purposes of this subpart, eligible land must be physically
            and legally capable of producing an eligible crop and must be:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Agricultural land; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Nonindustrial private forest land.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For the purposes of this subpart, eligible land is not:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Federal- or State-owned land, including land owned by local
            governments or municipalities;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land that is native sod;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land enrolled in the Conservation Reserve Program operated under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1410' tq='N'>
                1410 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land enrolled in the Wetlands Reserve Program operated under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1467' tq='N'>
                1467 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land enrolled in the Grassland Reserve Program operated under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1415' tq='N'>
                1415 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12871'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1450:C:1450.205
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1450.205
      </num>
      <head>
        Duration of contracts.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1450' sect='205' psec='' tq='N'>
              1450.205
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Duration of contracts.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Contracts under this subpart will be for a term of up to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             5 years for annual and non-woody perennial crops; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             15 years for woody perennial crops.
            <PRTPAGE P='757' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The establishment time period may vary due to: Type of crop,
            agronomic conditions (for example, establishment time frame, winter
            hardiness), and other factors.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12872'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1450:C:1450.206
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1450.206
      </num>
      <head>
        Obligations of participant.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 66234
        </aref>
        , October 27, 2010, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          76 FR 56951
        </aref>
        , Sept. 15, 2011]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1450' sect='206' psec='' tq='N'>
              1450.206
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Obligations of participant.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All participants subject to a BCAP contract must:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Carry out the terms and conditions of the contract;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Make available to CCC or to an institution of higher education or
            other entity designated by CCC, such information as CCC determines
            to be appropriate to promote the production of eligible crops and
            the development of renewable biomass conversion technology;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Comply with the highly erodible land and wetland conservation
            requirements of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='12' tq='N'>
                12 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Implement a:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_4_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Conservation plan,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_4_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Forest stewardship plan, or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_4_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Equivalent plan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Implement the conservation plan, forest stewardship plan, or
            equivalent plan which is part of such contract, in accordance with
            the schedule of dates included in such conservation plan, forest
            stewardship plan, or equivalent plan, unless CCC determines that the
            participant cannot fully implement the conservation plan, forest
            stewardship plan, or equivalent plan for reasons beyond the
            producer&apos;s control and CCC and the participant agree to a
            modified plan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Demonstrate compliance with the conservation plan, forest
            stewardship plan, or equivalent plan through required
            self-certification subject to compliance spot checks, as determined
            by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Establish temporary vegetative cover either within the timeframes
            required by the conservation plan, forest stewardship plan, or
            equivalent plan or as determined by the Deputy Administrator, if the
            eligible crops cannot be timely established; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the participant has a share of the payment greater than zero, be
            jointly and severally responsible with the other contract
            participants for compliance with the provisions of such contract and
            the provisions of this part, and for any refunds or payment
            adjustments that may be required for violations of any of the terms
            and conditions of the contract and this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payments may cease and producers may be subject to contract
            termination for failure to establish eligible crops.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A contract will not be terminated for failure by the participant to
            establish an approved cover on the land if, as determined by CCC:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The failure to plant or establish such cover was due to a natural
            disaster such as excessive rainfall, flooding, or drought; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The participant establishes the approved cover as soon as
            practicable after the wet or drought conditions that prevented the
            establishment of such cover subside.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 66234
          </aref>
          , October 27, 2010, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 56951
          </aref>
          , Sept. 15, 2011]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12873'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1450:C:1450.207
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1450.207
      </num>
      <head>
        Conservation plan, forest stewardship plan, or equivalent plan.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1450' sect='207' psec='' tq='N'>
              1450.207
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Conservation plan, forest stewardship plan, or equivalent plan.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The producer must implement a conservation plan, forest stewardship
            plan, or equivalent plan that complies with CCC guidelines and is
            approved by the appropriate conservation district for the land to be
            entered in BCAP. If the conservation district declines to review the
            conservation plan, forest stewardship plan, or equivalent plan, or
            disapproves the conservation plan, forest stewardship plan, or
            equivalent plan, such approval may be waived by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The practices and management activities included in a conservation
            plan, forest stewardship plan, or equivalent plan, and agreed to by
            the producer, must be implemented in a cost-effective manner that
            meets BCAP purposes as determined by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If applicable, a tree planting plan must be developed and included
            in the conservation plan, forest stewardship plan, or equivalent
            plan. Such tree planting plan may allow a reasonable time to
            complete plantings, as determined by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each conservation plan, forest stewardship plan, or equivalent
            plan, and any revision of the plan, will be subject to approval by
            CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12874'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1450:C:1450.208
      </extid>
      <num st='0'>
        1450.208
      </num>
      <head>
        Eligible practices.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='758' />
        <SECTNO>
          1450.208
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Eligible practices.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Eligible practices are those practices specified in the
            conservation plan, forest stewardship plan, or equivalent plan that
            meet all standards needed to cost-effectively establish:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Annual crops;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Non-woody perennial crops; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Woody perennial crops.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             [Reserved]
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12875'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1450:C:1450.209
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1450.209
      </num>
      <head>
        Signup.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1450' sect='209' psec='' tq='N'>
              1450.209
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Signup.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Offers for contracts may be submitted on a continuous basis to CCC
            as determined by the Deputy Administrator.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             [Reserved]
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12876'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1450:C:1450.210
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1450.210
      </num>
      <head>
        Acceptability of offers.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1450' sect='210' psec='' tq='N'>
              1450.210
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Acceptability of offers.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Acceptance or rejection of any contract offered will be at the sole
            discretion of CCC, and offers may be rejected for any reason as
            determined appropriate to accomplish the purposes of BCAP.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An offer to enroll land in BCAP will be irrevocable for such period
            as is determined and announced by CCC. The producer will be liable
            to CCC for liquidated damages if the applicant revokes an offer
            during the period in which the offer is irrevocable as determined by
            CCC. CCC may waive payment of such liquidated damages if CCC
            determines that the assessment of such damages, in a particular
            case, is not in the best interest of CCC and BCAP.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12877'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1450:C:1450.211
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1450.211
      </num>
      <head>
        BCAP contract.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1450' sect='211' psec='' tq='N'>
              1450.211
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          BCAP contract.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In order to enroll land in BCAP, the participant must enter into a
            contract with CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The contract is comprised of:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The terms and conditions for participation in BCAP;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The conservation plan, forest stewardship plan, or equivalent plan;
            and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any other materials or agreements determined necessary by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In order to enter into a contract, the producer must submit an
            offer to participate as specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1450' sect='209' psec='' tq='N'>
                1450.209
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The contract must, within the dates established by CCC, be signed
            by:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The producer; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The owners of the eligible land to be placed in the BCAP and other
            eligible participants, if applicable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Deputy Administrator is authorized to approve contracts on
            behalf of CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC will honor contracts even in the event that a project area
            biomass conversion facility does not become fully or partially
            operational.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Contracts may be terminated by CCC before the full term of the
            contract has expired if:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The owner loses control of or transfers all or part of the acreage
            under contract and the new owner does not wish to continue the
            contract;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The participant voluntarily requests in writing to terminate the
            contract and obtains the approval of CCC according to terms and
            conditions as determined by CCC;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The participant is not in compliance with the terms and conditions
            of the contract;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The BCAP practice fails or is not established after a certain time
            period, as determined CCC, and the cost of restoring or establishing
            the practice outweighs the benefits received from the restoration or
            establishment;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The contract was approved based on erroneous eligibility
            determinations; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC determines that such a termination is needed in the public
            interest.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as allowed and approved by CCC where the new owner of land
            enrolled in BCAP is a Federal agency that agrees to abide by the
            terms and conditions of the terminated contract, the participant in
            a contract that has been terminated must refund all or part of the
            payments made with respect to the contract plus interest, as
            determined by CCC, and must pay liquidated damages as provided for
            in the contract and this part. CCC may permit the amount(s) to be
            repaid to be reduced to the extent that such a reduction will not
            impair the purposes of BCAP. Further, a refund of all payments need
            not be required from a participant who is otherwise in full
            compliance with the contract when the land is purchased by or for
            the United States, as determined appropriate by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12878'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1450:C:1450.212
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1450.212
      </num>
      <head>
        Establishment payments.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='759' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1450' sect='212' psec='' tq='N'>
              1450.212
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Establishment payments.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Establishment payments will be made available upon a determination
            by CCC that an eligible practice, or an identifiable portion of a
            practice, has been established in compliance with the appropriate
            standards and specifications.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as otherwise provided for in this part, such payments will
            be made only for the cost-effective establishment or installation of
            an eligible practice, as determined by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as provided in paragraph (d) of this section, such payments
            will not be made to the same owner or operator on the same acreage
            for any eligible practices that have been previously established, or
            for which such owner or operator has received establishment
            assistance from any Federal agency.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Establishment payments may be authorized for the replacement or
            restoration of practices on land for which assistance has been
            previously allowed under BCAP, only if the failure of the original
            practice was due to reasons beyond the control of the participant,
            as agreed to by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In addition, CCC may make partial payments when the participant
            completes identifiable components of the contract. CCC may make
            supplemental establishment payments, if necessary.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12879'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1450:C:1450.213
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1450.213
      </num>
      <head>
        Levels and rates for establishment payments.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1450' sect='213' psec='' tq='N'>
              1450.213
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Levels and rates for establishment payments.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC will pay not more than 75 percent of the actual or average cost
            (whichever is lower) of establishing non-woody perennial crops and
            woody perennial crops specified in the conservation plan, forest
            stewardship plan, or equivalent plan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The average cost of performing a practice may be determined by CCC
            based on recommendations from the State Technical Committee. Such
            cost may be the average cost in a State, a county, or a part of a
            State or county, as determined by CCC. This means that the
            calculated 75 percent of the average cost may represent less than 75
            percent of the actual cost for an individual participant.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as otherwise provided for in this part, a participant may
            receive, in addition to any payment under this part, establishment
            assistance, rental payments, or tax benefits from a State or a
            private organization in return for enrolling lands in BCAP without a
            commensurate reduction in BCAP establishment payments.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12880'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1450:C:1450.214
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1450.214
      </num>
      <head>
        Annual payments.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1450' sect='214' psec='' tq='N'>
              1450.214
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Annual payments.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Annual payments will be made in such amount and in accordance with
            such time schedule as may be agreed upon and specified in the BCAP
            contract.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Based on the regulations in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='42' psec='' tq='N'>
                1410.42
              </subref>
               of this chapter
            </aref>
             and as determined by CCC, annual payments include a payment based
            on all or a percentage of:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A weighted average soil rental rate for cropland;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The applicable marginal pastureland rental rate for all other land
            except for nonindustrial private forest land;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For forest land, the average county rental rate for cropland as
            adjusted for forest land productivity for nonindustrial private
            forest land; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any incentive payment as determined by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The annual payment will be divided among the participants on a
            single contract as agreed to in such contract, as determined by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A participant that has an established eligible crop and is
            therefore not eligible for establishment payments under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1450' sect='212' psec='' tq='N'>
                1450.212
              </subref>
            </aref>
             may be eligible for annual payments under the provisions of this
            section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the case of a contract succession, annual payments will be
            divided between the predecessor and the successor participants as
            agreed to among the participants and approved by CCC. If there is no
            agreement among the participants, annual payments will be divided in
            such manner deemed appropriate by the Deputy Administrator and such
            distribution may be prorated based on the actual days of ownership
            of the property by each party.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Annual payments will be reduced, as determined by CCC:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             By a percentage of the sum of the sale price and payments under
            subpart B of this part for the crop collected or harvested from the
            contract acreage as follows:
            <PRTPAGE P='760' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             By 1 percent if the eligible crop is delivered to a biomass
            conversion facility for conversion to cellulosic biofuels as defined
            by 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              40 CFR 
              <subref title='40' part='80' sect='1401' psec='' tq='N'>
                80.1401
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             By 10 percent if the eligible crop is delivered to a biomass
            conversion facility for conversion to advanced biofuels;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             By 25 percent if the eligible crop is delivered to a biomass
            conversion facility for conversion to heat, power, or biobased
            products;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             By 100 percent if the eligible crop is used for a purpose other
            than conversion to heat, power, biobased products, or advanced
            biofuels;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the producer violates a term of the contract; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In other circumstances deemed necessary or appropriate to carry out
            BCAP.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12881'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1450:C:1450.215
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1450.215
      </num>
      <head>
        Transfer of land.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1450' sect='215' psec='' tq='N'>
              1450.215
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Transfer of land.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a new owner or operator purchases or obtains the right and
            interest in, or right to occupancy of, land subject to a BCAP
            contract, such new owner or operator, upon the approval of CCC, may
            become a participant to a new BCAP contract with CCC for the
            transferred land.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For the transferred land, if the new owner or operator becomes a
            successor to the existing BCAP contract, the new owner or operator
            will assume all obligations of the BCAP contract of the previous
            participant.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the new owner or operator is approved as a successor to a BCAP
            contract with CCC, then, except as otherwise determined by the
            Deputy Administrator:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Establishment payments will be made to the past or present
            participant who established the practice; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Annual payments to be paid during the fiscal year when the land was
            transferred will be divided between the new participant and the
            previous participant in the manner specified in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1450' sect='214' psec='#c' tq='N'>
                1450.214(c)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a participant transfers all or part of the right and interest
            in, or right to occupancy of, land subject to a BCAP contract and
            the new owner or operator does not become a successor to such
            contract within 60 days of such transfer, or such other time as CCC
            determines to be appropriate, such contract will be terminated with
            respect to the affected portion of such land, and the original
            participant:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Forfeits all rights to any future payments for that acreage;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Must refund all previous payments received under the contract by
            the participant or prior participants, plus interest, except as
            otherwise specified by CCC. The provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1450' sect='211' psec='#g' tq='N'>
                1450.211(g)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             will apply.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Federal agencies acquiring property, by foreclosure or otherwise,
            that contains BCAP contract acreage cannot be a party to the
            contract by succession. However, through an addendum to the
            contract, if the current operator of the property is one of the
            contract participants, the contract may remain in effect and, as
            permitted by CCC, such operator may continue to receive payments
            under such contract if CCC determines that such allowance is in the
            public interest and:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The property is maintained in accordance with the terms of the
            contract;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Such operator continues to be the operator of the property; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Ownership of the property remains with such Federal agency.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>