<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol7'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:B:718
    </extid>
    <num>
      718
    </num>
    <head>
      PROVISIONS APPLICABLE TO MULTIPLE PROGRAMS
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='1311' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1311.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 1311
            </subref>
          </aref>
          <E T='03'>
            et seq.,
          </E>
           1501 
          <E T='03'>
            et seq.,
          </E>
           1921 
          <E T='03'>
            et seq.,
          </E>
           7201 
          <E T='03'>
            et seq.,
          </E>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='15' sect='714b' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/15/714b.html'>
              15 U.S.C. 714b
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <PRTPAGE P='27' />
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            61 FR 37552
          </aref>
          , July 18, 1996, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='6568'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:B:718:A:718.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        718.1
      </num>
      <head>
        Applicability.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          72 FR 63284
        </aref>
        , Nov. 8, 2007]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='718' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              718.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Applicability.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This part:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is applicable to all programs set forth in chapters VII and XIV of
            this title which are administered by the Farm Service Agency (FSA),
            except that only 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='718' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
                718.6
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='718' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
                718.11
              </subref>
            </aref>
             are applicable to 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              parts 
              <subref title='7' part='761' tq='N'>
                761
              </subref>
            </aref>
             through 774 of this chapter;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Governs how FSA monitors marketing quotas, allotments, base acres
            and acreage reports. The regulations affected are those that
            establish procedures for measuring allotments and program eligible
            acreage, and determining program compliance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For all programs, except for those administered under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              parts 
              <subref title='7' part='761' tq='N'>
                761
              </subref>
            </aref>
             through 774 of this chapter:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The provisions of this part will be administered under the general
            supervision of the Administrator, FSA, and carried out in the field
            by State and county FSA committees (State and county committees);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State and county committees, and representatives and employees
            thereof, do not have authority to modify or waive any regulations in
            this part;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No provisions or delegation herein to a State or county committee
            will preclude the Administrator, FSA, or a designee, from
            determining any question arising under the program or from reversing
            or modifying any determination made by a State or county committee;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Deputy Administrator, FSA, may authorize State and county
            committees to waive or modify deadlines and other requirements in
            cases where lateness or failure to meet such other requirements does
            not adversely affect the operation of the program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The programs under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              parts 
              <subref title='7' part='761' tq='N'>
                761
              </subref>
            </aref>
             through 774 will be administered according to the part, or parts,
            applicable to the specific program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            72 FR 63284
          </aref>
          , Nov. 8, 2007]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6569'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:B:718:A:718.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        718.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          68 FR 16172
        </aref>
        , Apr. 3, 2003; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          69 FR 250
        </aref>
        , Jan. 5, 2004]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='718' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              718.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Except as provided in individual parts of chapters VII and XIV of this
          title, the following terms shall be as defined herein:
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Administrative variance
          </E>
           (AV) means the amount by which the determined acreage of tobacco may
          exceed the effective allotment and be considered in compliance with
          program regulations.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Allotment
          </E>
           means an acreage for a commodity allocated to a farm in accordance
          with the Agricultural Adjustment Act of 1938, as amended.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Allotment crop
          </E>
           means any tobacco crop for which acreage allotments are established
          pursuant to 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='723' tq='N'>
              723 of this chapter
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Barley
          </E>
           means barley that follows the standard planting and harvesting
          practice of barley for the area in which the barley is grown.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Base acres
          </E>
           means the quantity of acres established according to 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='1413' tq='N'>
              1413 of this title
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            CCC
          </E>
           means the Commodity Credit Corporation.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Combination
          </E>
           means consolidation of two or more farms or parts of farms, having
          the same operator, into one farm.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Common ownership unit
          </E>
           means a distinguishable parcel of land consisting of one or more
          tracts of land with the same owners, as determined by FSA.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Constitution
          </E>
           means the make-up of the farm before any change is made because of
          change in ownership or operation.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Controlled substances
          </E>
           means the term set forth in 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            21 CFR part 
            <subref title='21' part='1308' tq='N'>
              1308
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Corn
          </E>
           means field corn or sterile high-sugar corn that follows the standard
          planting and harvesting practices for corn for the area in which the
          corn is grown. Popcorn, corn nuts, blue corn, sweet corn, and corn
          varieties grown for decoration uses are not corn.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            County
          </E>
           means the county or parish of a state. For Alaska, Puerto Rico and
          the Virgin Islands, a county shall be an area designated by the State
          committee with the concurrence of the Deputy Administrator.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            County committee
          </E>
           means the FSA county committee.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Crop reporting date
          </E>
           means the latest date the Administrator, FSA will allow the farm
          operator, owner, or their 
          <PRTPAGE P='28' />
          agent to submit a crop acreage report in order for the report to be
          considered timely.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Cropland.
          </E>
           (a) Means land which the county committee determines meets any of the
          following conditions:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is currently being tilled for the production of a crop for harvest.
            Land which is seeded by drilling, broadcast or other no-till
            planting practices shall be considered tilled for cropland
            definition purposes;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is not currently tilled, but it can be established that such land
            has been tilled in a prior year and is suitable for crop production;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is currently devoted to a one-row or two-row shelter belt planting,
            orchard, or vineyard;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is in terraces that, were cropped in the past, even though they are
            no longer capable of being cropped;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is in sod waterways or filter strips planted to a perennial cover;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is preserved as cropland in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1410' tq='N'>
                1410 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is land that has newly been broken out for purposes of being
            planted to a crop that the producer intends to, and is capable of,
            carrying through to harvest, using tillage and cultural practices
            that are consistent with normal practices in the area; provided
            further that, in the event that such practices are not utilized
            other than for reasons beyond the producer&apos;s control, the
            cropland determination shall be void retroactive to the time at
            which the land was broken out.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land classified as cropland shall be removed from such
            classification upon a determination by the county committee that the
            land is:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No longer used for agricultural production;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No longer suitable for production of crops;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subject to a restrictive easement or contract that prohibits its
            use for the production of crops unless otherwise authorized by the
            regulation of this chapter;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No longer preserved as cropland in accordance with the provisions
            of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1410' tq='N'>
                1410 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and does not meet the conditions in paragraphs (a)(1) through
            (a)(6) of this definition; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Converted to ponds, tanks or trees other than those trees planted
            in compliance with a Conservation Reserve Program contract executed
            pursuant to 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1410' tq='N'>
                1410 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , or trees that are used in one-or two-row shelterbelt plantings, or
            are part of an orchard or vineyard.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Current year
          </E>
           means the year for which allotments, quotas, acreages, and bases, or
          other program determinations are established for that program. For
          controlled substance violations, the current year is the year of the
          actual conviction.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Deputy Administrator
          </E>
           means Deputy Administrator for Farm Programs, Farm Service Agency,
          U.S. Department of Agriculture or their designee.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Determination
          </E>
           means a decision issued by a State, county or area FSA committee or
          its employees that affects a participant&apos;s status in a program
          administered by FSA.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Determined acreage
          </E>
           means that acreage established by a representative of the Farm
          Service Agency by use of official acreage, digitizing or planimetering
          areas on the photograph or other photographic image, or computations
          from scaled dimensions or ground measurements.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Direct and counter-cyclical program (DCP) cropland
          </E>
           means land that currently meets the definition of cropland, land that
          was devoted to cropland at the time it was enrolled in a production
          flexibility contract in accordance with 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='1413' tq='N'>
              1413 of this title
            </subref>
          </aref>
           and continues to be used for agricultural purposes, or land that met
          the definition of cropland on or after April, 4, 1996, and continues
          to be used for agricultural purposes and not for nonagricultural
          commercial or industrial use.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Division
          </E>
           means the division of a farm into two or more farms or parts of
          farms.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Entity
          </E>
           means a corporation, joint stock company, association limited
          partnership, irrevocable trust, estate, charitable organization, or
          other similar organization including any such organization
          participating in the farming operation as a partner in a general
          partnership, a participant in a joint venture, a grantor of a
          revocable trust, or as a participant in a similar organization.
          <PRTPAGE P='29' />
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Extra Long Staple (ELS) Cotton
          </E>
           means cotton that follows the standard planting and harvesting
          practices of the area in which the cotton is grown, and meets all of
          the following conditions:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             American-Pima, Sea Island, Sealand, all other varieties of the
            Barbandense species of cotton and any hybrid thereof, and any other
            variety of cotton in which 1 or more of these varieties is
            predominant; and,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The acreage is grown in a county designated as an ELS county by the
            Secretary; and,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The production from the acreage is ginned on a roller-type gin.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Family member
          </E>
           means an individual to whom a person is related as spouse, lineal
          ancestor, lineal descendant, or sibling, including:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Great grandparent;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Grandparent;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Parent;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Child, including a legally adopted child;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Grandchild
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Great grandchildren;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Sibling of the family member in the farming operation; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Spouse of a person listed in paragraphs (1) through (7) of this
            definition.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Farm
          </E>
           means a tract, or tracts, of land that are considered to be a
          separate operation under the terms of this part provided further that
          where multiple tracts are to be treated as one farm, the tracts must
          have the same operator and must also have the same owner except that
          tracts of land having different owners may be combined if all owners
          agree to the treatment of the multiple tracts as one farm for these
          purposes.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Farm inspection
          </E>
           means an inspection by an authorized FSA representative using aerial
          or ground compliance to determine the extent of producer adherence to
          program requirements.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Farm number
          </E>
           means a number assigned to a farm by the county committee for the
          purpose of identification.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Farmland
          </E>
           means the sum of the DCP cropland, forest, acreage planted to an
          eligible crop acreage as specified in 1437.3 of this title and other
          land on the farm.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Field
          </E>
           means a part of a farm which is separated from the balance of the
          farm by permanent boundaries such as fences, permanent waterways,
          woodlands, and croplines in cases where farming practices make it
          probable that such cropline is not subject to change, or other similar
          features.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            GIS
          </E>
           means Geographic Information System or a system that stores,
          analyzes, and manipulates spatial or geographically referenced data.
          GIS computes distances and acres using stored data and calculations.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            GPS
          </E>
           means Global Positioning System or a positioning system using
          satellites that continuously transmit coded information. The
          information transmitted from the satellites is interpreted by GPS
          receivers to precisely identify locations on earth by measuring
          distance from the satellites.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Grain sorghum
          </E>
           means grain sorghum of a feed grain or dual purpose variety
          (including any cross that, at all stages of growth, having
          characteristics of a feed grain or dual purpose variety) that follows
          the standard planting and harvesting practice for grain sorghum for
          the area in which the grain sorghum was planted. Sweet sorghum is not
          considered a grain sorghum.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Ground measurement
          </E>
           means the distance between 2 points on the ground, obtained by actual
          use of a chain tape, GPS with a minimum accuracy level as determined
          by the Deputy Administrator, or other measuring device.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Joint operation
          </E>
           means a general partnership, joint venture, or other similar business
          organization.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Landlord
          </E>
           means one who rents or leases farmland to another.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Measurement service
          </E>
           means a measurement of acreage or farm-stored commodities performed
          by a representative of FSA and paid for by the producer requesting the
          measurement.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Measurement service after planting
          </E>
           means determining a crop or designated acreage after planting but
          before the farm operator files a report of acreage for the crop.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Measurement service guarantee
          </E>
           means a guarantee provided when a producer requests and pays for an
          authorized FSA representative to measure acreage for FSA and CCC
          program participation unless the producer takes action to adjust the
          measured acreage. If the producer has taken no such action, and 
          <PRTPAGE P='30' />
          the measured acreage is later discovered to be incorrect, the acreage
          determined pursuant to the measurement service will be used for
          program purposes for that program year.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Minor child
          </E>
           means an individual who is under 18 years of age. State court
          proceedings conferring majority on an individual under 18 years of age
          will not change such an individual&apos;s status as a minor.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Nonagricultural commercial or industrial use
          </E>
           means land that is no longer suitable for producing annual or
          perennial crops, including conserving uses, or forestry products.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Normal planting period
          </E>
           means that period during which the crop is normally planted in the
          county, or area within the county, with the expectation of producing a
          normal crop.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Normal row width
          </E>
           means the normal distance between rows of the crop in the field, but
          not less than 30 inches for all crops.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Oats
          </E>
           means oats that follows the standard planting and harvesting practice
          of oats for the area in which the oats are grown.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Operator
          </E>
           means an individual, entity, or joint operation who is determined by
          the FSA county committee to be in control of the farming operations on
          the farm.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Owner
          </E>
           means one who has legal ownership of farmland, including:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any agency of the Federal Government, however, such agency shall
            not be eligible to receive any payment pursuant to such contract;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             One who is buying farmland under a contract for deed;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             One who has a life-estate in the property; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For purposes of enrolling a farm in a program authorized by
            chapters VII and XIV of this title:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             One who has purchased a farm in a foreclosure proceeding; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_4_i_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The redemption period has not passed; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_4_i_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The original owner has not redeemed the property.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_4_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             One who meets the provisions of paragraph (d)(1)(i) of this
            definition shall be entitled to receive benefits in accordance with
            an agency program only to the extent the owner complies with all
            program requirements.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             One who is an heir to property but cannot provide legal
            documentation to confirm ownership of the property, if such heir
            certifies to the ownership of the property and the certification is
            considered acceptable, as determined by the Deputy Administrator.
            Upon a false or inaccurate certification the Deputy Administrator
            may impose liability on the certifying party for additional cost
            that results—however such a certification may be taken by the Deputy
            Administrator as a bar to other claims where there has been a
            failure of other persons claiming an interest in the property to act
            promptly to protect or declare their interest or where the current
            public records do not accurately set out the current ownership of
            the farm.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Partial reconstitution
          </E>
           means a reconstitution that is made effective in the current year for
          some crops, but is not made effective in the current year for other
          crops. This results in the same farm having two or more farm numbers
          in one crop year.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Participant
          </E>
           means one who participates in, or receives payments or benefits in
          accordance with any of the programs administered by FSA.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Pasture
          </E>
           means land that is used to, or has the potential to, produce food for
          grazing animals.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Person
          </E>
           means an individual, or an individual participating as a member of a
          joint operation or similar operation, a corporation, joint stock
          company, association, limited stock company, limited partnership,
          irrevocable trust, revocable trust together with the grantor of the
          trust, estate, or charitable organization including any entity
          participating in the farming operation as a partner in a general
          partnership, a participant in a joint venture, a grantor of a
          revocable trust, or a participant in a similar entity, or a State,
          political subdivision or agency thereof. To be considered a separate
          person for the purpose of this part, the individual or other legal
          entity must:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Have a separate and distinct interest in the land or the crop
            involved;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Exercise separate responsibility for such interest; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be responsible for the cost of farming related to such interest
            from a 
            <PRTPAGE P='31' />
            fund or account separate from that of any other individual or
            entity.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Producer
          </E>
           means an owner, operator, landlord, tenant, or sharecropper, who
          shares in the risk of producing a crop and who is entitled to share in
          the crop available for marketing from the farm, or would have shared
          had the crop been produced. A producer includes a grower of hybrid
          seed.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Quota
          </E>
           means the pounds allocated to a farm for a commodity in accordance
          with the Agricultural Adjustment Act of 1938, as amended.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Random inspection
          </E>
           means an examination of a farm by an authorized representative of FSA
          selected as a part of an impartial sample to determine the adherence
          to program requirements.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Reconstitution
          </E>
           means a change in the land constituting a farm as a result of
          combination or division.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Reported acreage
          </E>
           means the acreage reported by the farm operator, farm owner, farm
          producer, or their agent on a Form prescribed by the FSA.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Required inspection
          </E>
           means an examination by an authorized representative of FSA of a farm
          specifically selected by application of prescribed rules to determine
          adherence to program requirements or to verify the farm
          operator&apos;s, farm owner&apos;s, farm producer, or agent&apos;s
          report.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Rice
          </E>
           means rice that follows the standard planting and harvesting
          practices of the area excluding sweet, glutinous, or candy rice such
          as Mochi Gomi.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Secretary
          </E>
           means the Secretary of Agriculture of the United States, or a
          designee.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Sharecropper
          </E>
           means one who performs work in connection with the production of a
          crop under the supervision of the operator and who receives a share of
          such crop for its labor.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Skip-row or strip-crop planting
          </E>
           means a cultural practice in which strips or rows of the crop are
          alternated with strips of idle land or another crop.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Staking and referencing
          </E>
           means determining an acreage before planting by:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Measuring or computing a delineated area from ground measurements
            and documenting the area measured; and, (2) Staking and referencing
            the area on the ground.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Standard deduction
          </E>
           means an acreage that is excluded from the gross acreage in a field
          because such acreage is considered as being used for farm equipment
          turn-areas. Such acreage is established by application of a prescribed
          percentage of the area planted to the crop in lieu of measuring the
          turn area.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State
          </E>
           means each of the 50 States, the District of Columbia, the
          Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, the Virgin Islands of the United
          States, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana
          Islands, or the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Subdivision
          </E>
           means a part of a field that is separated from the balance of the
          field by temporary boundary, such as a cropline which could be easily
          moved or will likely disappear.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Tenant
          </E>
           means:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             One who rents land from another in consideration of the payment of
            a specified amount of cash or amount of a commodity; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             One (other than a sharecropper) who rents land from another person
            in consideration of the payment of a share of the crops or proceeds
            therefrom.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Tolerance
          </E>
           means a prescribed amount within which the reported acreage and/or
          production may differ from the determined acreage and/or production
          and still be considered as correctly reported.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Tract
          </E>
           means a unit of contiguous land under one ownership, which is
          operated as a farm, or part of a farm.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Tract combination
          </E>
           means the combining of two or more tracts if the tracts have common
          ownership and are contiguous.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Tract division
          </E>
           means the dividing of a tract into two or more tracts because of a
          change in ownership or operation.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Turn-area
          </E>
           means the area across the ends of crop rows which is used for
          operating equipment necessary to the production of a row crop (also
          called turn row, headland, or end row).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Upland cotton
          </E>
           means planted and stub cotton that is not considered extra long
          staple cotton, and that follows the standard planting and harvesting
          practices of the area and is produced from other than pure strain
          varieties of the Barbadense species, any hybrid thereof, or any other
          variety of cotton in which 
          <PRTPAGE P='32' />
          one or more of these varieties predominate. For program purposes,
          brown lint cotton is considered upland cotton.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Wheat
          </E>
           means wheat for feed or dual purpose variety that follows the
          standard planting and harvesting practice of wheat for the area in
          which the wheat is grown.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            68 FR 16172
          </aref>
          , Apr. 3, 2003; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            69 FR 250
          </aref>
          , Jan. 5, 2004]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6570'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:B:718:A:718.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        718.3
      </num>
      <head>
        State committee responsibilities.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='718' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              718.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          State committee responsibilities.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State committee shall, with respect to county committees:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Take any action required of the county committee, which the county
            committee fails to take in accordance with this part;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Correct or require the county committee to correct any action taken
            by such committee, which is not in accordance with this part;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Require the county committee to withhold taking any action which is
            not in accordance with this part;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Review county office rates for producer services to determine
            equity between counties;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Determine, based on cost effectiveness, which counties will use
            aerial compliance methods and which counties will use ground
            measurement compliance methods; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Adjust the per acre rate for acreage in excess of 25 acres to
            reflect the actual cost involved when performing measurement service
            from aerial slides or digital images.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State committee shall submit to the Deputy Administrator
            requests to deviate from deductions prescribed in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='718' sect='108' psec='' tq='N'>
                718.108
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , or the error amount or percentage for refunds of redetermination
            costs as prescribed in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='718' sect='111' psec='' tq='N'>
                718.111
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6571'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:B:718:A:718.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        718.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Authority for farm entry and providing information.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='718' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              718.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Authority for farm entry and providing information.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This section applies to all farms that have a tobacco allotment or
            quota under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='723' tq='N'>
                723 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and all farms that are currently participating in programs
            administered by FSA.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A representative of FSA may enter any farm that participates in an
            FSA or CCC program in order to conduct a farm inspection as defined
            in this part. A program participant may request that the FSA
            representative present written authorization for the farm inspection
            before granting access to the farm. If a farm inspection is not
            allowed within 30 days of written authorization:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All FSA and CCC program benefits for that farm shall be denied;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The person preventing the farm inspection shall pay all costs
            associated with the farm inspection;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The entire crop production on the farm will be considered to be in
            excess of the quota established for the farm; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For tobacco, the farm operator must furnish proof of disposition
            of:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_4_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All tobacco which is in addition to the production shown on the
            marketing card issued with respect to such farm; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_4_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No credit will be given for disposing of excess tobacco other than
            that identified by a marketing card unless disposed of in the
            presence of FSA in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='718' sect='109' psec='' tq='N'>
                718.109
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a program participant refuses to furnish reports or data
            necessary to determine benefits in accordance with paragraph (a) of
            this section, or FSA determines that the report or data was
            erroneously provided through the lack of good faith, all program
            benefits relating to the report or data requested will be denied.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6572'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:B:718:A:718.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        718.5
      </num>
      <head>
        Rule of fractions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='718' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              718.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Rule of fractions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Fractions shall be rounded after completion of the entire
            associated computation. All mathematical calculations shall be
            carried to two decimal places beyond the number of decimal places
            required by the regulations governing each program. In rounding,
            fractional digits of 49 or less beyond the required number of
            decimal places shall be dropped; if the fractional digits beyond the
            required number of decimal places are 50 or more, the figure at the
            last required decimal place shall be increased by “1” as follows:
          </text>
        </P>
        <table class='gpotable' CDEF='s50,r50,10' COLS='3' OPTS='L2,tp0,i1'>
          <caption />
          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th>
                Required decimal
              </th>
              <th>
                Computation
              </th>
              <th>
                Result
              </th>
            </tr>
          </thead>
          <tfoot />
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Whole numbers
              </td>
              <td>
                6.49 (or less)
                <LI>
                  6.50 (or more)
                </LI>
              </td>
              <td>
                6
                <LI>
                  7
                </LI>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Tenths
              </td>
              <td>
                7.649 (or less)
                <LI>
                  7.650 (or more)
                </LI>
              </td>
              <td>
                7.6
                <LI>
                  7.7
                </LI>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Hundredths
              </td>
              <td>
                8.8449 (or less)
                <LI>
                  8.8450 (or more)
                </LI>
              </td>
              <td>
                8.84
                <LI>
                  8.85
                </LI>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Thousandths
              </td>
              <td>
                9.63449 (or less)
                <LI>
                  9.63450 (or more)
                </LI>
              </td>
              <td>
                9.634
                <LI>
                  9.635
                </LI>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                0 thousandths
              </td>
              <td>
                10.993149 (or less)
                <LI>
                  10.993150 (or more)
                </LI>
              </td>
              <td>
                10.9931
                <LI>
                  10.9932
                </LI>
              </td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The acreage of each field or subdivision computed for tobacco and
            CCC disaster assistance programs shall be recorded in acres and
            hundredths of an acre, dropping all thousandths of an acre. The
            acreage of each field or subdivision computed for crops, except
            tobacco, shall be recorded in acres and tenths of an acre, rounding
            all hundredths of an acre to the nearest tenth.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6573'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:B:718:A:718.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        718.6
      </num>
      <head>
        Controlled substance.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          72 FR 63284
        </aref>
        , Nov. 8, 2007]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='718' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              718.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Controlled substance.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The following terms apply to this section:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              USDA benefit
            </E>
             means the issuance of any grant, contract, loan, or payment by
            appropriated funds of the United States.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Person
            </E>
             means an individual.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any person convicted
            under Federal or State law of:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Planting, cultivating, growing, producing, harvesting, or storing a
            controlled substance in any crop year is ineligible during the crop
            year of conviction and the four succeeding crop years, for any of
            the following USDA benefits:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any payments or benefits under the Direct and Counter Cyclical
            Program (DCP) in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1412' tq='N'>
                1412 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any payments or benefits for losses to trees, crops, or livestock
            covered under disaster programs administered by FSA;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any price support loan available in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1421' tq='N'>
                1421 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any price support or payment made under the Commodity Credit
            Corporation Charter Act;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A farm storage facility loan made under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 4(h) of
            </aref>
             the Commodity Credit Corporation Charter Act or any other Act;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Crop Insurance under the Federal Crop Insurance Act;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_vii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A loan made or guaranteed under the Consolidated Farm and Rural
            Development Act or any other law administered by FSA&apos;s Farm
            Loan Programs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Possession or trafficking of a controlled substance, is ineligible
            for any or all USDA benefits:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             At the discretion of the court,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To the extent and for a period of time the court determines.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a person denied benefits under this section is a shareholder,
            beneficiary, or member of an entity or joint operation, benefits for
            which the entity or joint operation is eligible will be reduced, for
            the appropriate period, by a percentage equal to the total interest
            of the shareholder, beneficiary, or member.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            72 FR 63284
          </aref>
          , Nov. 8, 2007]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6574'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:B:718:A:718.7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        718.7
      </num>
      <head>
        Furnishing maps.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='718' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              718.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Furnishing maps.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          A reasonable number, as determined by FSA, of reproductions of
          photographs, mosaics and maps shall be available to the owner of a
          farm insurance companies reinsured by the Federal Crop Insurance
          Corporation (FCIC), private party contractors performing their
          official duties on behalf of FSA, CCC, and other USDA agencies. To all
          others, reproductions shall be made available at the rate FSA
          determines will cover the cost of making such items available.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6575'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:B:718:A:718.8
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        718.8
      </num>
      <head>
        Administrative county.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='718' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              718.8
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Administrative county.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If all land on the farm is physically located in one county, the
            farm shall be administratively located in such county. If there is
            no FSA office in the county or the county offices have been
            consolidated, the farm shall be administratively located in the
            contiguous county most convenient for the farm operator.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the land on the farm is located in more than one county, the
            farm shall be administratively located in either of such counties as
            the county committees and the farm operator agree. If no agreement
            can be reached, the farm shall be administratively located in the
            county where the principal dwelling is situated, or where the major
            portion of the farm is located if there is no dwelling.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State committee shall submit all requests to deviate from
            regulations specified in this section to the Deputy Administrator.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6576'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:B:718:A:718.9
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        718.9
      </num>
      <head>
        Signature requirements.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          68 FR 16172
        </aref>
        , Apr. 3, 2003; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          69 FR 250
        </aref>
        , Jan. 5, 2004]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='34' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='718' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
              718.9
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Signature requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When a program authorized by this chapter or Chapter XIV of this
            title requires the signature of a producer; landowner; landlord; or
            tenant, a husband or wife may sign all such FSA or CCC documents on
            behalf of the other spouse, unless such other spouse has provided
            written notification to FSA and CCC that such action is not
            authorized. The notification must be provided to FSA with respect to
            each farm.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except a husband or wife may not sign a document on behalf of a
            spouse with respect to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Program document required to be executed in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='3' tq='N'>
                3 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Easements entered into under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1410' tq='N'>
                1410 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Power of attorney;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Such other program documents as determined by FSA or CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An individual; duly authorized officer of a corporation; duly
            authorized partner of a partnership; executor or administrator of an
            estate; trustee of a trust; guardian; or conservator may delegate to
            another the authority to act on their behalf with respect to FSA and
            CCC programs administered by USDA service center agencies by
            execution of a Power of Attorney, or such other form as approved by
            the Deputy Administrator. FSA and CCC may, at their discretion,
            allow the delegations of authority by other individuals through use
            of the Power of Attorney or such other form as approved by the
            Deputy Administrator.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notwithstanding another provision of this regulation or any other
            FSA or CCC regulation in this title, a parent may execute documents
            on behalf of a minor child unless prohibited by a statute or court
            order.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notwithstanding any other provision in this title, an authorized
            agent of the Bureau of Indian Affairs (BIA) of the United States
            Department of Interior may sign as agent for landowners with
            properties affiliated with or under the management or trust of the
            BIA. For collection purposes, such payments will be considered as
            being made to the persons who are the beneficiaries of the payment
            or may, alternatively, be considered as an obligation of all persons
            on the farm in general. In the event of a need for a refund or other
            claim may be collected, among other means, by other monies due such
            persons or the farm.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            68 FR 16172
          </aref>
          , Apr. 3, 2003; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            69 FR 250
          </aref>
          , Jan. 5, 2004]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6577'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:B:718:A:718.10
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        718.10
      </num>
      <head>
        Time limitations.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='718' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
              718.10
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Time limitations.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Whenever the final date prescribed in any of the regulations in this
          title for the performance of any act falls on a Saturday, Sunday,
          national holiday, State holiday on which the office of the county or
          State Farm Service Agency committee having primary cognizance of the
          action required to be taken is closed, or any other day on which the
          cognizant office is not open for the transaction of business during
          normal working hours, the time for taking required action shall be
          extended to the close of business on the next working day. Or in case
          the action required to be taken may be performed by mailing, the
          action shall be considered to be taken within the prescribed period if
          the mailing is postmarked by midnight of such next working day. Where
          the action required to be taken is with a prescribed number of days
          after the mailing of notice, the day of mailing shall be excluded in
          computing such period of time.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6578'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:B:718:A:718.11
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        718.11
      </num>
      <head>
        Disqualification due to Federal crop insurance violation.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          72 FR 63284
        </aref>
        , Nov. 8, 2007]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='718' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
              718.11
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Disqualification due to Federal crop insurance violation.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              Section 515(h) of
            </aref>
             the Federal Crop Insurance Act (FCIA) provides that a person who
            willfully and intentionally provides false or inaccurate information
            to the Federal Crop Insurance Corporation (FCIC) or to an approved
            insurance provider with respect to a policy or plan of FCIC
            insurance, after notice and an opportunity for a hearing on the
            record, will be subject to one or more of the sanctions described in
            
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 515(h)(3)
            </aref>
            . In 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 515(h)(3)
            </aref>
            , the FCIA specifies that in the case of a violation committed by a
            producer, the producer may be disqualified for a period of up to 5
            years from receiving any monetary or non-monetary benefit under a
            number of programs. The list includes, but is not limited to,
            benefits under:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The FCIA.
            <PRTPAGE P='35' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Agricultural Market Transition Act (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='7201' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/7201.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 7201
              </subref>
            </aref>
            <E T='03'>
              et seq.
            </E>
            ), including the Noninsured Crop Disaster Assistance Program under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 196 of
            </aref>
             that Act (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='7333' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/7333.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 7333
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Agricultural Act of 1949 (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='1421' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1421.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 1421
              </subref>
            </aref>
            <E T='03'>
              et seq.
            </E>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Commodity Credit Corporation Charter Act (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='15' sect='714' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/15/714.html'>
                15 U.S.C. 714
              </subref>
            </aref>
            <E T='03'>
              et seq.
            </E>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Agricultural Adjustment Act of 1938 (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='1281' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1281.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 1281
              </subref>
            </aref>
            <E T='03'>
              et seq.
            </E>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Title XII of the Food Security Act of 1985 (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='16' sect='3801' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/3801.html'>
                16 U.S.C. 3801
              </subref>
            </aref>
            <E T='03'>
              et seq.
            </E>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='1921' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1921.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 1921
              </subref>
            </aref>
            <E T='03'>
              et seq.
            </E>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any law that provides assistance to a producer of an agricultural
            commodity affected by a crop loss or a decline in prices of
            agricultural commodities.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Violation determinations are made by FCIC. However, upon notice
            from FCIC to FSA that a producer has been found to have committed a
            violation to which paragraph (a) of this section applies, that
            person will be ineligible for payments under the programs specified
            in paragraph (a) of this section that are funded by FSA for the same
            period of time for which, as determined by FCIC, the producer will
            be ineligible for crop insurance benefits of the kind referred to in
            paragraph (a)(1) of this section. Appeals of the determination of
            ineligibility will be administered under the rules set by FCIC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Other sanctions may also apply.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            72 FR 63284
          </aref>
          , Nov. 8, 2007]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6579'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:B:718:B:718.101
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        718.101
      </num>
      <head>
        Measurements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='718' sect='101' psec='' tq='N'>
              718.101
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Measurements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Measurement services include, but are not limited to, measuring
            land and crop areas, quantities of farm-stored commodities, and
            appraising the yields of crops in the field when required for
            program administration purposes. The county committee shall provide
            measurement service if the producer requests such service and pays
            the cost, except that service shall not be provided to determine
            total acreage or production of a crop when the request is made:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             After the established final reporting date for the applicable crop,
            unless a late filed report is accepted as provided in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='718' sect='103' psec='' tq='N'>
                718.103
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             After the farm operator has furnished production evidence when
            required for program administration purposes except as provided in
            this subpart; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In connection with a late-filed report of acreage, unless there is
            evidence of the crop&apos;s existence in the field and use made of
            the crop, or the lack of the crop due to a disaster condition
            affecting the crop.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The acreage requested to be measured by staking and referencing
            shall not exceed the effective farm allotment for marketing quota
            crops or acreage of a crop that is limited to a specific number of
            acres to meet any program requirement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When a producer requests, pays for, and receives written notice
            that measurement services have been furnished, the measured acreage
            shall be guaranteed to be correct and used for all program purposes
            for the current year even though an error is later discovered in the
            measurement thereof, if the producer has taken action with an
            economic significance based on the measurement service, and the
            entire crop required for the farm was measured. If the producer has
            not taken action with an economic significance based on the
            measurement service, the producer shall be notified in writing that
            an error was discovered and the nature and extent of such error. In
            such cases, the corrected acreage will be used for determining
            program compliance for the current year.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When a measurement service reveals acreage in excess of the
            permitted acreage and the allowable tolerance as defined in this
            part, the producer must destroy the excess acreage and pay for FSA
            to verify destruction, in order to keep the measurement service
            guarantee.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6580'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:B:718:B:718.102
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        718.102
      </num>
      <head>
        Acreage reports.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          68 FR 16176
        </aref>
        , Apr. 3, 2003, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          71 FR 13741
        </aref>
        , Mar. 17, 2006]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='718' sect='102' psec='' tq='N'>
              718.102
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Acreage reports.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In order to be eligible for benefits, participants in the programs
            specified in paragraphs (b)(1) through (b)(6) of 
            <PRTPAGE P='36' />
            this section must annually submit accurate information as required
            by these provisions.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Participants in the programs governed by 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1412' tq='N'>
                1412 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
             must report the acreage of fruits and vegetables planted for
            harvest on a farm enrolled in such program;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Participants in the programs governed by 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              parts 
              <subref title='7' part='1421' tq='N'>
                1421
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='1427' tq='N'>
                1427 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
             must report the acreage planted to a commodity for harvest for
            which a marketing assistance loan or loan deficiency payment is
            requested;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Participants in the programs governed by 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1410' tq='N'>
                1410 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
             must report the use of land enrolled in such programs;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All participants in the programs governed by 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1437' tq='N'>
                1437 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
             must report all acreage in the county of the eligible crop in which
            the producer has a share;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Participants in the programs governed by 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='723' tq='N'>
                723 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1464' tq='N'>
                1464 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
             must report the acreage planted to tobacco by kind on all farms
            that have an effective allotment or quota greater than zero;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All participants in the programs governed by 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              parts 
              <subref title='7' part='1412' tq='N'>
                1412, 1421
              </subref>
              , and 
              <subref title='7' part='1427' tq='N'>
                1427 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
             must report the use of all cropland on the farm.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All producers requesting to report acreage as prevented planted or
            failed must provide documentation to FSA where the farm is
            administered that meets the provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='718' sect='103' psec='' tq='N'>
                718.103
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The reports required under paragraph (a) of this section shall be
            timely filed by the farm operator, farm owner, producer of the crop
            on the farm, or a duly authorized representative with the county
            committee by the final reporting date applicable to the crop as
            established by the county committee and State committee.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            68 FR 16176
          </aref>
          , Apr. 3, 2003, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            71 FR 13741
          </aref>
          , Mar. 17, 2006]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6581'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:B:718:B:718.103
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        718.103
      </num>
      <head>
        Prevented planted and failed acreage.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          71 FR 13741
        </aref>
        , Mar. 17, 2006]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='718' sect='103' psec='' tq='N'>
              718.103
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Prevented planted and failed acreage.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Prevented planting is the inability to plant an eligible crop with
            proper equipment during the planting period as a result of an
            eligible cause of loss, as determined by CCC. The eligible cause of
            loss that prevented the planting must have:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Occurred after a previous planting period for the crop;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Occurred before the final planting date for the crop in the
            applicable crop year or, in the case of multiple plantings, the
            harvest date of the first planting in the applicable planting
            period, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Similarly affected other producers in the area, as determined by
            CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be approved by FSA as prevented planted acreage:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The acreage must have been reported within 15 calendar days after
            the latter of
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The occurrence of prevented planting, or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The end of the planting period;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The acreage must have been prevented from being planted as the
            result of a natural disaster and not a management decision; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The prevented planted acreage report must be acted on by the COC.
            The COC will deny the acreage report if it is not satisfied with the
            documentation provided.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To receive prevented planted credit for acreage:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The producer must show there was the intent to plant the acreage by
            providing documentation of field preparation, seed purchase and any
            other information that shows the acreage could have been planted and
            harvested under normal weather conditions, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The producer must show that the amount of the prevented planted
            acreage credit is consistent with prior years&apos; planting history
            for the farm.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Eligible prevented planting acreage will be determined on the basis
            of the producer&apos;s intent to plant the crop acreage and
            possession of, or access to, resources to plant, grow, and harvest
            the crop, as applicable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Prevented planting acreage credit is not provided on acreage that
            had either a previous or subsequent crop planted on the acreage,
            unless the COC determines that all of the following conditions are
            met:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             There is an established practice of planting two or more crops for
            harvest on the same acreage in the same crop year;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Both crops could have reached maturity if each planting was
            harvested or would have been harvested;
            <PRTPAGE P='37' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Both the initial and subsequent planted crops were planted or
            prevented-planted within the normal planting period for that crop;
            and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Both the initial and subsequent planted crops meet all other
            eligibility provisions of this part including good farming
            practices.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Prevented planted acreage credit will not be given to crops where
            the prevented-planted acreage was affected by drought, unless:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             On the final planting date for non-irrigated acreage, the area that
            is prevented from being planted has insufficient soil moisture for
            germination of seed and progress toward crop maturity because of a
            prolonged period of dry weather, as determined by CCC; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Prolonged precipitation deficiencies exceeded the D2 level as
            determined using the U.S. Drought Monitor; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Verifiable information is collected from sources whose business or
            purpose it is to record weather conditions, as determined by CCC,
            and including but not limited to the local weather reporting
            stations of the U.S. National Weather Service.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Prevented planted acreage credit under this part shall apply to
            irrigated crops where the acreage was prevented from being planted
            due to a lack of water resulting from drought conditions or
            contamination by saltwater intrusion of an irrigation supply
            resulting from drought conditions if there was not a reasonable
            probability of having adequate water to carry out an irrigation
            practice.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Acreage ineligible for prevented planting coverage includes, but is
            not limited to acreage:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Which planting history or conservation plans indicate would remain
            fallow for crop rotation purposes;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Used for conservation purposes or intended to be or considered to
            have been left unplanted under any program administered by USDA,
            including the Conservation Reserve and Wetland Reserve Programs; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Not planted because of a management decision.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Failed acreage is acreage that was planted with the proper
            equipment during the planting period but failed as a result of an
            eligible cause of loss, as determined by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be approved by CCC as failed acreage the acreage must have been
            reported as failed acreage before disposition of the crop, and the
            acreage must have been planted under normal conditions but failed as
            the result of a natural disaster and not a management decision.
            Producers who file a failed acreage report must have the request
            acted on by the COC. The COC will deny the acreage report if it is
            not satisfied with the documentation provided.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To receive failed acreage credit the producer must show all of the
            following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='k_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             That the acreage was planted under normal conditions using the
            proper equipment with the intent to harvest the acreage.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='k_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provide documentation that the crop was planted using farming
            practices consistent for the crop and area, but could not be brought
            to harvest because of disaster-related conditions.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='l'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (l)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The eligible cause for failed acreage must have:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='l_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Occurred after the crop was planted, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='l_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Before the normal harvest date for the crop in the applicable crop
            year or in the case of multiple plantings, the harvest date of the
            first planting in the applicable planting period, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='l_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Other producers in the area were similarly affected as determined
            by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='m'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (m)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Eligible failed acreage will be determined on the basis of the
            producer planting the crop under normal conditions with the
            expectation to take the crop to harvest.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='n'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (n)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Acreage ineligible for failed acreage credit includes, but is not
            limited to acreage:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='n_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Which was planted using methods that could not be considered normal
            for the area and without the expectation of harvest;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='n_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Used for conservation purposes or intended to be or considered to
            have been un-harvested under any program administered by USDA,
            including the Conservation Reserve and Wetland Reserve Programs; and
            <PRTPAGE P='38' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='n_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             That failed because of a management decision.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            71 FR 13741
          </aref>
          , Mar. 17, 2006]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6582'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:B:718:B:718.104
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        718.104
      </num>
      <head>
        Late-filed and revised acreage reports.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          71 FR 13742
        </aref>
        , Mar. 17, 2006]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='718' sect='104' psec='' tq='N'>
              718.104
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Late-filed and revised acreage reports.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Late-filed acreage reports may be accepted after the final
            reporting date, and be considered timely filed, if both of the
            following apply:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The crop or identifiable crop residue is in the field, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The acreage has not already been determined by FSA.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The farm operator filing a report late shall pay the cost of a farm
            inspection unless FSA determines that failure to report in a timely
            manner was beyond the producer&apos;s control.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Revised acreage reports may be filed with respect to 2005 and
            subsequent years to change the acreage reported if:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The acreage has not already been determined by FSA; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Actual crop or residue is present in the field.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Revised reports shall be filed and accepted:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             At any time for all crops if the crop or residue still exists in
            the field for inspection to verify the existence and use made of the
            crop, the lack of the crop, or a disaster condition affecting the
            crop; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the producer was in compliance with all other program
            requirements at the reporting date.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            71 FR 13742
          </aref>
          , Mar. 17, 2006]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6583'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:B:718:B:718.105
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        718.105
      </num>
      <head>
        Tolerances, variances, and adjustments.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='718' sect='105' psec='' tq='N'>
              718.105
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Tolerances, variances, and adjustments.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Tolerance is the amount by which the determined acreage for a crop
            may differ from the reported acreage or allotment for the crop and
            still be considered in compliance with program requirements under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='718' sect='102' psec='#b_1' tq='N'>
                718.102(b)(1), (b)(3) and (b)(5)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Tolerance rules apply to those fields for which a staking and
            referencing was performed but such acreage was not planted according
            to those measurements or when a measurement service is not requested
            for acreage destroyed to meet program requirements.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Tolerance rules do not apply to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Program requirements of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='718' sect='102' psec='#b_2' tq='N'>
                718.102(b)(2), (b)(4) and (b)(6)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Official fields when the entire field is devoted to one crop;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Those fields for which staking and referencing was performed and
            such acreage was planted according to those measurements; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The adjusted acreage for farms using measurement after planting
            which have a determined acreage greater than the marketing quota
            crop allotment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An administrative variance is applicable to all allotment crop
            acreages. Allotment crop acreages as determined in accordance with
            this part shall be deemed in compliance with the effective farm
            allotment or program requirement when the determined acreage does
            not exceed the effective farm allotment by more than an
            administrative variance determined as follows:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For all kinds of tobacco subject to marketing quotas, except dark
            air-cured and fire-cured the larger of 0.1 acre or 2 percent of the
            allotment; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For dark air-cured and fire-cured tobacco, an acreage based on the
            effective acreage allotment as provided in the table as follows:
          </text>
        </P>
        <table class='gpotable' CDEF='s50,15' COLS='2' OPTS='L2,tp0,i1'>
          <caption />
          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th>
                Effective acreage allotment is within this range
              </th>
              <th>
                Administrative variance
              </th>
            </tr>
          </thead>
          <tfoot />
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                0.01 to 0.99
              </td>
              <td>
                0.01
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                1.00 to 1.49
              </td>
              <td>
                0.02
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                1.50 to 1.99
              </td>
              <td>
                0.03
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                2.00 to 2.49
              </td>
              <td>
                0.04
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                2.50 to 2.99
              </td>
              <td>
                0.05
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                3.00 to 3.49
              </td>
              <td>
                0.06
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                3.50 to 3.99
              </td>
              <td>
                0.07
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                4.00 to 4.49
              </td>
              <td>
                0.08
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                4.50 and up
              </td>
              <td>
                0.09
              </td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A tolerance applies to tobacco, other than flue-cured or burley, if
            the measured acreage exceeds the allotment by more than the
            administrative variance but by not more than the tolerance. Such
            excess acreage of tobacco may be adjusted to the effective farm
            acreage allotment to avoid marketing quota penalties or receive
            price support.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the acreage report for a crop is outside the tolerance for that
            crop:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FSA may consider the requirements of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='718' sect='102' psec='#b_1' tq='N'>
                718.102 (b)(1), (b)(3) and (b)(5)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             not to have been met, and;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Participants may be ineligible for all or a portion of payments or
            benefits 
            <PRTPAGE P='39' />
            subject to the requirements of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='718' sect='102' psec='#b_1' tq='N'>
                718.102 (b)(1), (b)(3) and (b)(5)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6584'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:B:718:B:718.106
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        718.106
      </num>
      <head>
        Non-compliance and fraudulent acreage reports.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='718' sect='106' psec='' tq='N'>
              718.106
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Non-compliance and fraudulent acreage reports.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Participants that knowingly and willfully provide false or inaccurate
          acreage reports may be ineligible for some or all payments or benefits
          subject to the requirements of 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='718' sect='102' psec='#b_1' tq='N'>
              718.102 (b)(1), (b)(3) and (b)(5)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          :
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The county committee determines that the acreage report filed
            according to 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='718' sect='102' psec='#b_1' tq='N'>
                718.102 (b)(1), (b)(3) and (b)(5)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             is inaccurate, and;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A good-faith effort to accurately report the acreage was not made
            because the report was knowingly and willfully falsified.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6585'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:B:718:B:718.107
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        718.107
      </num>
      <head>
        Acreages.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='718' sect='107' psec='' tq='N'>
              718.107
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Acreages.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If an acreage has been established by FSA for an area delineated on
            an aerial photograph or within a GIS, such acreage will be
            recognized by the county committee as the acreage for the area until
            such time as the boundaries of such area are changed. When
            boundaries not visible on the aerial photograph are established from
            data furnished by the producer, such acreage shall not be recognized
            as official acreage until an authorized representative of FSA
            verifies the boundaries.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Measurements of any row crop shall extend beyond the planted area
            by the larger of 15 inches or one-half the distance between the
            rows.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The entire acreage of a field or subdivision of a field devoted to
            a crop shall be considered as devoted to the crop subject to a
            deduction or adjustment except as otherwise provided in this part.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6586'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:B:718:B:718.108
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        718.108
      </num>
      <head>
        Measuring acreage including skip row acreage.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='718' sect='108' psec='' tq='N'>
              718.108
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Measuring acreage including skip row acreage.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When one crop is alternating with another crop, whether or not both
            crops have the same growing season, only the acreage that is
            actually planted to the crop being measured will be considered to be
            acreage devoted to the measured crop.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subject to the provisions of this paragraph and section, whether
            planted in a skip row pattern or without a pattern of skipped rows,
            the entire acreage of the field or subdivision may be considered as
            devoted to the crop only where the distance between the rows, for
            all rows, is 40 inches or less. If there is a skip that creates idle
            land wider than 40 inches, or if the distance between any rows is
            more than 40 inches, then the area planted to the crop shall be
            considered to be that area which would represent the smaller of; a
            40 inch width between rows, or the normal row spacing in the field
            for all other rows in the field—those that are not more than 40
            inches apart. The allowance for individual rows would be made based
            on the smaller of actual spacing between those rows or the normal
            spacing in the field. For example, if the crop is planted in single,
            wide rows that are 48 inches apart, only 20 inches to either side of
            each row (for a total of 40 inches between the two rows) could, at a
            maximum, be considered as devoted as the crop and normal spacing in
            the field would control. Half the normal distance between rows will
            also be allowed beyond the outside planted rows not to exceed 20
            inches and will reflect normal spacing in the field.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In making calculations under this section, further reductions may
            be made in the acreage considered planted if it is determined that
            the acreage is more sparsely planted than normal using reasonable
            and customary full production planting techniques.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Deputy Administrator has the discretionary authority to allow
            row allowances other than those specified in this section in those
            instances in which crops are normally planted with spacings greater
            or less than 40 inches, such as in case of tobacco, or where other
            circumstances are present which the Deputy Administrator finds
            justifies that allowance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Paragraphs (a) through (d) of this section shall apply with respect
            to the 2003 and subsequent crops. For preceding crops, the rules in
            effect on January 1, 2002, shall apply.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6587'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:B:718:B:718.109
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        718.109
      </num>
      <head>
        Deductions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='718' sect='109' psec='' tq='N'>
              718.109
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Deductions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any contiguous area which is not devoted to the crop being measured
            and which is not part of a skip-row pattern under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='718' sect='108' psec='' tq='N'>
                718.108
              </subref>
            </aref>
             shall be deducted from the acreage of the crop if such area 
            <PRTPAGE P='40' />
            meets the following minimum national standards or requirements:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A minimum width of 30 inches;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For tobacco—three-hundredths (.03) acre. Turn areas, terraces,
            permanent irrigation and drainage ditches, sod waterways,
            non-cropland, and subdivision boundaries each of which is at least
            30 inches in width may be combined to meet the 0.03-acre minimum
            requirement; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For all other crops and land uses—one-tenth (.10) acre. Turn areas,
            terraces, permanent irrigation and drainage ditches, sod waterways,
            non-cropland, and subdivision boundaries each of which is at least
            30 inches in width and each of which contain 0.1 acre or more may be
            combined to meet any larger minimum prescribed for a State in
            accordance with this subpart.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the area not devoted to the crop is located within the planted
            area, the part of any perimeter area that is more than 217.8 feet
            (33 links) in width will be considered to be an internal deduction
            if the standard deduction is used.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A standard deduction of 3 percent of the area devoted to a row crop
            and zero percent of the area devoted to a close-sown crop may be
            used in lieu of measuring the acreage of turn areas.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6588'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:B:718:B:718.110
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        718.110
      </num>
      <head>
        Adjustments.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='718' sect='110' psec='' tq='N'>
              718.110
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Adjustments.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The farm operator or other interested producer having excess
            tobacco acreage (other than flue-cured or burley) may adjust an
            acreage of the crop in order to avoid a marketing quota penalty if
            such person:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notifies the county committee of such election within 15 calendar
            days after the date of mailing of notice of excess acreage by the
            county committee; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Pays the cost of a farm inspection to determine the adjusted
            acreage prior to the date the farm visit is made.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The farm operator may adjust an acreage of tobacco (except
            flue-cured and burley) by disposing of such excess tobacco prior to
            the marketing of any of the same kind of tobacco from the farm. The
            disposition shall be witnessed by a representative of FSA and may
            take place before, during, or after the harvesting of the same kind
            of tobacco grown on the farm. However, no credit will be allowed
            toward the disposition of excess acreage after the tobacco is
            harvested but prior to marketing, unless the county committee
            determines that such tobacco is representative of the entire crop
            from the farm of the kind of tobacco involved.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6589'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:B:718:B:718.111
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        718.111
      </num>
      <head>
        Notice of measured acreage.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='718' sect='111' psec='' tq='N'>
              718.111
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Notice of measured acreage.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Notice of measured acreage shall be provided by FSA and mailed to the
          farm operator. This notice shall constitute notice to all parties who
          have ownership, leasehold interest, or other, in such farm.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6590'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:B:718:B:718.112
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        718.112
      </num>
      <head>
        Redetermination.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='718' sect='112' psec='' tq='N'>
              718.112
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Redetermination.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A redetermination of crop acreage, appraised yield, or farm-stored
            production for a farm may be initiated by the county committee,
            State committee, or Deputy Administrator at any time.
            Redetermination may be requested by a producer with an interest in
            the farm if they pay the cost of the redetermination. The request
            must be submitted to FSA within 15 calendar days after the date of
            the notice described in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='718' sect='110' psec='' tq='N'>
                718.110
              </subref>
               or 
              <subref title='7' part='718' sect='111' psec='' tq='N'>
                718.111
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , or within 5 calendar days after the initial appraisal of the yield
            of a crop, or before the farm-stored production is removed from
            storage. A redetermination shall be undertaken in the manner
            prescribed by the Deputy Administrator. A redetermination shall be
            used in lieu of any prior determination.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The county committee shall refund the payment of the cost for a
            redetermination when, because of an error in the initial
            determination:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The appraised yield is changed by at least the larger of:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Five percent or 5 pounds for cotton;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Five percent or 1 bushel for wheat, barley, oats, and rye; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Five percent or 2 bushels for corn and grain sorghum; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The farm stored production is changed by at least the smaller of 3
            percent or 600 bushels; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The acreage of the crop is:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Changed by at least the larger of 3 percent or 0.5 acre; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Considered to be within program requirements.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6591'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:B:718:C:718.201
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        718.201
      </num>
      <head>
        Farm constitution.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='718' sect='201' psec='' tq='N'>
              718.201
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Farm constitution.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In order to implement agency programs and monitor farmer compliance
            with regulations, the agency must have records on what land is being
            farmed by a particular producer. This is accomplished by a
            determination of what land or groups of land ‘constitute’ an
            individual unit or farm. Land, which has been properly constituted
            under prior regulations, shall remain so constituted until a
            reconstitution is required under paragraph (c) of this section. The
            constitution and identification of land as a farm for the first time
            and the subsequent reconstitution of a farm made hereafter, shall
            include all land operated by an individual entity or joint operation
            as a single farming unit except that it shall not include:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land under separate ownership unless the owners agree in writing
            and the labor, equipment, accounting system, and management are
            operated in common by the operator but separate from other tracts;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land under a lease agreement of less than 1 year duration;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land in different counties when the tobacco allotments or quotas
            established for the land involved cannot be transferred from one
            county to another county by lease, sale, or owner. However, this
            paragraph shall not apply if:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All of the land is contiguous;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The land is located in counties that are contiguous in the same
            State if:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='a_3_ii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A burley or flue-cured tobacco quota is established for one or more
            of the tracts; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='a_3_ii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The county committee determines that the tracts will be operated as
            a single farming unit as set forth in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='718' sect='202' psec='' tq='N'>
                718.202
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Because of a change in operation, tracts or parts of tracts will be
            divided from the parent farm that currently has land in more than
            one county, and there is no change in operation and ownership of the
            remainder of the farm, or if there is a change in ownership, the new
            owner agrees in writing to the constitution of the farm.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Federally-owned land;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State-owned wildlife lands unless the former owner has possession
            of the land under a leasing agreement; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land constituting a farm which is declared ineligible to be
            enrolled in a program under the regulations governing the program;
            and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For acreage base crops, land located in counties that are not
            contiguous. However, this paragraph shall not apply if:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_7_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Counties are divided by a river;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_7_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Counties do not touch because of a correction line adjustment; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_7_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The land is within 20 miles, by road, of other land that will be a
            part of the farming unit.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If all land on the farm is physically located in one county, the
            farm shall be administratively located in such county. If there is
            no FSA office in the county or the county offices have been
            consolidated, the farm shall be administratively located in the
            contiguous county most convenient for the farm operator.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the land on the farm is located in more than one county, the
            farm shall be administratively located in either of such counties as
            the county committees and the farm operator agree. If no agreement
            can be reached, the farm shall be administratively located in the
            county where the principal dwelling is situated, or where the major
            portion of the farm is located if there is no dwelling.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A reconstitution of a farm either by division or by combination
            shall be required whenever:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A change has occurred in the operation of the land after the last
            constitution or reconstitution and as a result of such change the
            farm does not meet the conditions for constitution of a farm as set
            forth in paragraph (a) of this section except that no reconstitution
            shall be made if the county committee determines that the primary
            purpose of the change in operation is to establish eligibility to
            transfer allotments subject to sale or lease, or increase amount of
            program benefits received;
            <PRTPAGE P='42' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The farm was not properly constituted the previous time;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An owner requests in writing that the land no longer be included in
            a farm composed of tracts under separate ownership;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The county committee determines that the farm was reconstituted on
            the basis of false information;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The county committee determines that tracts included in a farm are
            not being operated as a single farming unit.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Reconstitution shall not be approved if the county committee
            determines that the primary purpose of the reconstitution is to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Circumvent the provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='12' tq='N'>
                12 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Circumvent any other chapter of this title.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6592'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:B:718:C:718.202
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        718.202
      </num>
      <head>
        Determining the land constituting a farm.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='718' sect='202' psec='' tq='N'>
              718.202
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Determining the land constituting a farm.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In determining the constitution of a farm, consideration shall be
            given to provisions such as ownership and operation. For purposes of
            this part, the following rules shall be applicable to determining
            what land is to be included in a farm.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A minor shall be considered to be the same owner or operator as the
            parent, court-appointed guardian, or other person responsible for
            the minor child, unless the parent or guardian has no interest in
            the minor&apos;s farm or production from the farm, and the minor:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is a producer on a farm;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Maintains a separate household from the parent or guardian;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Personally carries out the farming activities; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Maintains a separate accounting for the farming operation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A minor shall not be considered to be the same owner or operator as
            the parent or court-appointed guardian if the minor&apos;s interest
            in the farming operation results from being the beneficiary of an
            irrevocable trust and ownership of the property is vested in the
            trust or the minor.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A life estate tenant shall be considered to be the owner of the
            property for their life.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A trust shall be considered to be an owner with the beneficiary of
            the trust; except a trust can be considered a separate owner or
            operator from the beneficiary, if the trust:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Has a separate and distinct interest in the land or crop involved;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Exercises separate responsibility for the separate and distinct
            interest; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Maintains funds and accounts separate from that of any other
            individual or entity for the interest.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The county committee shall require specific proof of ownership.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land owned by different persons of an immediate family living in
            the same household and operated as a single farming unit shall be
            considered as being under the same ownership in determining a farm.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All land operated as a single unit and owned and operated by a
            parent corporation and subsidiary corporations of which the parent
            corporation owns more than 50 percent of the value of the
            outstanding stock, or where the parent is owned and operated by
            subsidiary corporations, shall be constituted as one farm.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6593'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:B:718:C:718.203
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        718.203
      </num>
      <head>
        County committee action to reconstitute a farm.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='718' sect='203' psec='' tq='N'>
              718.203
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          County committee action to reconstitute a farm.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Action to reconstitute a farm may be initiated by the county
          committee, the farm owner, or the operator with the concurrence of the
          owner of the farm. Any request for a farm reconstitution shall be
          filed with the county committee.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6594'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:B:718:C:718.204
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        718.204
      </num>
      <head>
        Reconstitution of allotments, quotas, and bases.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='718' sect='204' psec='' tq='N'>
              718.204
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Reconstitution of allotments, quotas, and bases.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Farms shall be reconstituted in accordance with this subpart when
            it is determined that the land areas are not properly constituted
            and, to the extent practicable, shall be based on the facts and
            conditions existing at the time the change requiring the
            reconstitution occurred.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Reconstitutions of farms subject to a direct and counter-cyclical
            program contract in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1413' tq='N'>
                1413 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
             will be effective for the current year if initiated on or before
            August 1 or prior to the issuance of DCP payments for the farm or
            farms being reconstituted.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For tobacco farms, a reconstitution will be effective for the
            current 
            <PRTPAGE P='43' />
            year for each crop for which the reconstitution is initiated before
            the planting of such crop begins or would have begun.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph (c) of this section, a
            reconstitution may be effective for the current year if the county
            committee determines, and the State committee concurs, that the
            purpose of the request for reconstitution is not to perpetrate a
            scheme or device designed to evade the requirements governing
            programs found in this title.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6595'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:B:718:C:718.205
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        718.205
      </num>
      <head>
        Substantive change in farming operation, and changes in related legal
        entities.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='718' sect='205' psec='' tq='N'>
              718.205
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Substantive change in farming operation, and changes in related legal
          entities.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land that is properly constituted as a farm shall not be
            reconstituted if:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The reconstitution request is based upon the formation of a newly
            established legal entity which owns or operates the farm or any part
            of the farm and the county committee determines there is not a
            substantive change in the farming operation;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The county committee determines that the primary purpose of the
            request for reconstitution is to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Obtain additional benefits under one or more commodity programs;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Avoid damages or penalties under a contract or statute;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Correct an erroneous acreage report; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Circumvent any other program provisions. In addition, no farm shall
            remain as constituted when the county committee determines that a
            substantive change in the farming operation has occurred which would
            require a reconstitution, except as otherwise approved by the State
            committee with the concurrence of the Deputy Administrator.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In determining whether a substantive change has occurred with
            respect to a farming operation, the county committee shall consider
            factors such as the composition of the legal entities having an
            interest in the farming operation with respect to management,
            financing, and accounting. The county committee shall also consider
            the use of land, labor, and equipment available to the farming
            operations and any other relevant factors that bear on the
            determination.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Unless otherwise approved by the State committee with the
            concurrence of the Deputy Administrator, when the county committee
            determines that a corporation, trust, or other legal entity is
            formed primarily for the purpose of obtaining additional benefits
            under the commodity programs of this title, the farm shall remain as
            constituted, or shall be reconstituted, as applicable, when the farm
            is owned or operated by:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A corporation having more than 50 percent of the stock owned by
            members of the same family living in the same household;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Corporations having more than 50 percent of the stock owned by
            stockholders common to more than one corporation; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Trusts in which the beneficiaries and trustees are family members
            living in the same household.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Application of the provisions of paragraph (c) of this section
            shall not limit or affect the application of paragraphs (a) and (b)
            of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6596'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:B:718:C:718.206
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        718.206
      </num>
      <head>
        Determining farms, tracts, allotments, quotas, and bases when
        reconstitution is made by division.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='718' sect='206' psec='' tq='N'>
              718.206
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Determining farms, tracts, allotments, quotas, and bases when
          reconstitution is made by division.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The methods for dividing farms, tracts, allotments, quotas, and
            bases in order of precedence, when applicable, are estate,
            designation by landowner, contribution, cropland, DCP cropland,
            default, and history. The proper method shall be determined on a
            crop by crop basis.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The estate method is the pro-rata distribution of allotments,
            quotas, and bases for a parent farm among the heirs in settling an
            estate. If the estate sells a tract of land before the farm is
            divided among the heirs, the allotments, quotas, and bases for that
            tract shall be determined according to paragraphs (c) through (h) of
            this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Allotments, quotas, and bases shall be divided in accordance with a
            will, but only if the county committee determines that the terms of
            the will are such that a division can reasonably be made by the
            estate method.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If there is no will or the county committee determines that the
            terms of a will are not clear as to the division of allotments,
            quotas, and bases, such allotments, quotas, and bases shall be
            apportioned in the manner agreed to in 
            <PRTPAGE P='44' />
            writing by all interested heirs or devisees who acquire an interest
            in the property for which such allotments, quotas, and bases have
            been established. An agreement by the administrator or executor
            shall not be accepted in lieu of an agreement by the heirs or
            devisees.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If allotments, quotas, and bases are not apportioned in accordance
            with the provisions of paragraphs (b)(2) or (b)(3) of this section,
            the allotments, quotas, and bases shall be divided pursuant to
            paragraphs (d) through (h) of this section, as applicable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the ownership of a tract of land is transferred from a parent
            farm, the transferring owner may request that the county committee
            divide the allotments, quotas, and bases, including historical
            acreage that has been double cropped, between the parent farm and
            the transferred tract, or between the various tracts if the entire
            farm is sold to two or more purchasers, in a manner designated by
            the owner of the parent farm subject to the conditions set forth in
            paragraph (c)(3) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the county committee determines that allotments, quotas, and
            bases cannot be divided in the manner designated by the owner
            because of the conditions set forth in paragraph (c)(3) of this
            section, the owner shall be notified and permitted to revise the
            designation so as to meet the conditions in paragraph (c)(3) of this
            section. If the owner does not furnish a revised designation of
            allotments, quotas, and bases within a reasonable time after such
            notification, or if the revised designation does not meet the
            conditions of paragraph (c)(3) of this section, the county committee
            will divide the allotments, quotas, and bases in a pro-rata manner
            in accordance with paragraphs (d) through (h) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A landowner may designate a manner in which allotments, quotas, and
            bases are divided according to this paragraph.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The transferring owner and transferee shall file a signed written
            memorandum of understanding of the designation with the county
            committee before any CCC or FSA prescribed form, letter or contract
            providing an allotment, base or quota is issued and before a
            subsequent transfer of ownership of the land. The landowner shall
            designate the allotments, quotas, and bases that shall be
            permanently reduced when the sum of the allotments, quotas, and
            bases exceeds the cropland for the farm.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Where the part of the farm from which the ownership is being
            transferred was owned for a period of less than 3 years, the
            designation by landowner method shall not be available with respect
            to the transfer unless the county committee determines that the
            primary purpose of the ownership transfer was other than to retain
            or to sell allotments, quotas, or bases. In the absence of such a
            determination, and if the farm contains land which has been owned
            for less than 3 years, that part of the farm which has been owned
            for less than 3 years shall be considered as a separate farm and the
            allotments, quotas, or bases, shall be assigned to that part in
            accordance with paragraphs (d) through (h) of this section. Such
            apportionment shall be made prior to any designation of allotments,
            quotas, and bases with respect to the part that has been owned for 3
            years or more.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The designation by landowner method is not applicable to crop
            allotments or quotas which are restricted to transfer within the
            county by lease, sale, or by owner, when the land on which the farm
            is located is in two or more counties.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The designation by landowner method may be applied at the
            owner&apos;s request to land owned by any Indian Tribal Council
            which is leased to two or more producers for the production of any
            crop of a commodity for which an allotment, quota, or base has been
            established. If the land is leased to two or more producers, an
            Indian Tribal Council may request that the county committee divide
            the allotments, quotas, and bases between the applicable tracts in
            the manner designated by the Council. The use of this method shall
            not be subject to the conditions of paragraph (c)(3) of this
            section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The contribution method is the pro-rata distribution of a parent
            farm&apos;s allotments and quotas to each tract as the tract
            contributed to the allotments and quotas at the time of combination 
            <PRTPAGE P='45' />
            and may be used when the provisions of paragraphs (b) and (c) of
            this section do not apply.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The county committee determines and the State committee or a
            representative thereof concurs, that the use of the contribution
            method would not result in an equitable distribution of allotments
            and quotas, considering available land, cultural operations, and
            changes in type of farming.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The cropland method is the pro-rata distribution of allotments and
            quotas to separate tracts proportionately to the tract&apos;s
            contribution to the cropland for the parent tract. This method shall
            be used if paragraphs (b) through (d) of this section do not apply
            unless the county committee determines that division by the history
            method would result in more representative allotments and quotas
            than the cropland method, taking into consideration the operation
            normally carried out on each tract for the commodities produced on
            the farm.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The history method is the pro-rata distribution of allotments and
            quotas to separate tracts on the basis of the operation normally
            carried out on each tract of the parent farm. The county committee
            may use the history method of dividing allotments and quotas when
            it:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Determines that this method would result in a more accurate
            pro-rata distribution of allotments and quotas based on actual
            contribution of the tract to the totals of the parent farm than the
            cropland method would; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Obtains written consent of all owners to use the history method.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The county committee may waive the requirement for written consent
            of the owners for dividing allotments and quotas if the county
            committee determines that the use of the cropland method would
            result in an inequitable division of the parent farm&apos;s
            allotments and quotas and the use of the history method would
            provide more favorable results for all owners.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The DCP cropland method is the pro-rata distribution of bases to
            the resulting tracts in the same proportion to the DCP cropland that
            each resulting tract bears to the DCP cropland for the parent tract.
            This method of division shall be used if paragraphs (b) and (c) of
            this section do not apply.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The default method is the separation of tracts from a farm with
            each tract maintaining the bases attributed to the tract when the
            reconstitution is initiated.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Allotments, quotas, and bases apportioned among the resulting farms
            pursuant to paragraphs (d) through (h) of this section may be
            increased or decreased with respect to a farm by as much as 10
            percent of the parent farm&apos;s allotment, quota, or base
            determined under such subsections for the parent farm if:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The owners agree in writing; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The county committee determines the method used did not provide an
            equitable distribution considering available land, cultural
            operations, and changes in the type of farming conducted on the
            farm. Any increase in an allotment, quota, or base with respect to a
            tract pursuant to this paragraph shall be offset by a corresponding
            decrease for such allotments, quotas or bases established with
            respect to the other tracts which constitute the farm.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Farm program payment yields calculated for the resulting farms of a
            division may be increased or decreased if the county committee
            determines the method used did not provide an equitable distribution
            considering available land, cultural operations, and changes in the
            type of farming conducted on the farm. Any increase in a farm
            program payment yield on a resulting farm shall be offset by a
            corresponding decrease on another resulting farm of the division.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a farm with burley tobacco quota is divided through
            reconstitution and one or more of the farms resulting from the
            division are apportioned less than 1,000 pounds of burley tobacco
            quota, the owners of such farms shall take action as provided in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='723' tq='N'>
                723 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
             to comply with the 1,000 pound minimum by July 1 of the current
            year or the quota shall be dropped. Exceptions to this are farms
            divided:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Among family members;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             By the estate method; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When no sale or change in ownership of land occurs; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             With one resulting farm receiving all of the quota.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6597'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:B:718:C:718.207
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        718.207
      </num>
      <head>
        Determining allotments, quotas, and bases when reconstitution is made by
        combination.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='46' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='718' sect='207' psec='' tq='N'>
              718.207
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Determining allotments, quotas, and bases when reconstitution is made
          by combination.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          When two or more farms or tracts are combined for a year, that
          year&apos;s allotments, quotas, and bases, with respect to the
          combined farm or tract, as required by applicable commodity
          regulations, shall not be greater than the sum of the allotments,
          quotas, and bases for each of the farms or tracts comprising the
          combination, subject to the provisions of 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='718' sect='204' psec='' tq='N'>
              718.204
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6598'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:B:718:D:718.301
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        718.301
      </num>
      <head>
        Applicability.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='718' sect='301' psec='' tq='N'>
              718.301
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Applicability.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This subpart is applicable to programs administered by the Farm
            Service Agency under chapters VII and XIV of this title, except for
            an agricultural credit program carried out under the Consolidated
            Farm and Rural Development Act (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='1921' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1921.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 1921
              </subref>
            </aref>
            <E T='03'>
              et seq.
            </E>
            ). Administration of this subpart shall be under the supervision of
            the Deputy Administrator, except that such authority shall not limit
            the exercise of authority allowed State Executive Directors of the
            Farm Service agency as provided for in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='718' sect='307' psec='' tq='N'>
                718.307
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              Sections 
              <subref title='7' part='718' sect='303' psec='' tq='N'>
                718.303
              </subref>
              , 
              <subref title='7' part='718' sect='304' psec='' tq='N'>
                718.304
              </subref>
              , and 
              <subref title='7' part='718' sect='307' psec='' tq='N'>
                718.307
              </subref>
            </aref>
             do not apply where the action for which relief is requested
            occurred before May 13, 2002. In such cases, authority that was
            effective prior to May 13, 2002, may be applied.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              Section 
              <subref title='7' part='718' sect='306' psec='' tq='N'>
                718.306
              </subref>
            </aref>
             does not apply to a function performed under either 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 376 of
            </aref>
             the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='1921' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1921.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 1921
              </subref>
            </aref>
            <E T='03'>
              et seq.
            </E>
            ), or a conservation program administered by the Natural Resources
            Conservation Service of the United States Department of Agriculture.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6599'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:B:718:D:718.302
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        718.302
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions and abbreviations.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='718' sect='302' psec='' tq='N'>
              718.302
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions and abbreviations.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          In addition to the definitions provided in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='718' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              718.2
            </subref>
             of this part
          </aref>
          , the following terms apply to this subpart:
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Agricultural commodity
          </E>
           means any agricultural commodity, food, feed, fiber, or livestock
          that is subject to a covered program.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Covered program
          </E>
           means a program specified in 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            § 718.301 of
          </aref>
           this subpart.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            FSA
          </E>
           means the Farm Service Agency of the United States Department of
          Agriculture.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            OGC
          </E>
           means the Office of the General Counsel of the United States
          Department of Agriculture.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            SED
          </E>
           means, for activities within a particular state, the State Executive
          Director of the United States Department of Agriculture, FSA, for that
          state.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6600'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:B:718:D:718.303
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        718.303
      </num>
      <head>
        Reliance on incorrect actions or information.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='718' sect='303' psec='' tq='N'>
              718.303
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Reliance on incorrect actions or information.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notwithstanding any other law, action or inaction by a participant
            in a covered program that is to the detriment of the participant,
            and that is based upon good faith reliance on the action or advice
            of an authorized representative of a County or State FSA Committee,
            may be approved by the Administrator, FSA or the Executive Vice
            President, CCC, as applicable, or their designee, as meeting the
            requirements of the program, and benefits may be extended or
            payments made in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='718' sect='305' psec='' tq='N'>
                718.305
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This section applies only to a participant who relied upon the
            action of, or information provided by, a county or State FSA
            committee or an authorized representative of such committee and the
            participant acted, or failed to act, as a result of the Agency
            action or information. This part does not apply to cases where the
            participant had sufficient reason to know that the action or
            information upon which they relied was improper or erroneous or
            where the participant acted in reliance on their own
            misunderstanding or misinterpretation of program provisions, notices
            or information.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6601'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:B:718:D:718.304
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        718.304
      </num>
      <head>
        Failure to fully comply.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='718' sect='304' psec='' tq='N'>
              718.304
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Failure to fully comply.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Under a covered program, when the failure of a participant to fully
            comply with the terms and conditions of a program authorized by this
            chapter precludes the providing of payments or benefits, relief may
            be authorized in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='718' sect='305' psec='' tq='N'>
                718.305
              </subref>
            </aref>
             if 
            <PRTPAGE P='47' />
            the participant made a good faith effort to comply fully with the
            requirements of the covered program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This section only applies to participants who are determined by the
            FSA approval official to have made a good faith effort to comply
            fully with the terms and conditions of the program and rendered
            substantial performance.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6602'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:B:718:D:718.305
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        718.305
      </num>
      <head>
        Forms of relief.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='718' sect='305' psec='' tq='N'>
              718.305
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Forms of relief.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Administrator of FSA, Executive Vice President of CCC, or their
            designee, may authorize a participant in a covered program to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Retain loans, payments, or other benefits received under the
            covered program;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Continue to receive loans, payments, and other benefits under the
            covered program;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Continue to participate, in whole or in part, under any contract
            executed under the covered program;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the case of a conservation program, re-enroll all or part of the
            land covered by the program; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Receive such other equitable relief as determined to be
            appropriate.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             As a condition of receiving relief under this subpart, the
            participant may be required to remedy their failure to meet the
            program requirement, or mitigate its affects.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6603'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:B:718:D:718.306
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        718.306
      </num>
      <head>
        Finality.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='718' sect='306' psec='' tq='N'>
              718.306
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Finality.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A determination by a State or county FSA committee made on or after
            October 13, 1994, becomes final and binding 90 days from the date
            the application for benefits has been filed, and supporting
            documentation required to be supplied by the producer as a condition
            for eligibility for the particular program has been filed, unless
            one of the following conditions exist:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The participant has requested an administrative review of the
            determination in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='780' tq='N'>
                780 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The determination was based on misrepresentation, false statement,
            fraud, or willful misconduct by or on behalf of the participant;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The determination was modified by the Administrator, FSA, or in the
            case of CCC programs conducted under Chapter XIV of this title, the
            Executive Vice President, CCC; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The participant had reason to know that the determination was
            erroneous.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Should an erroneous determination become final under the provisions
            of this section, it shall only be effective through the year in
            which the error was found and communicated to the participant.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6604'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VII:B:718:D:718.307
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        718.307
      </num>
      <head>
        Special relief approval authority for State Executive Directors.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='718' sect='307' psec='' tq='N'>
              718.307
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Special relief approval authority for State Executive Directors.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General nature of the special authority.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notwithstanding provisions in this subpart providing supervision
            and relief authority to other officials, an SED without further
            review by other officials (other than the Secretary) may grant
            relief to a participant under the provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='718' sect='303' psec='' tq='N'>
                718.303
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='718' sect='304' psec='' tq='N'>
                718.304
              </subref>
            </aref>
             as if the SED were the final arbiter within the agency of such
            matters so long as:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The program matter with respect to which the relief is sought is a
            program matter in a covered program which is operated within the
            State under the control of the SED;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The total amount of relief which will be provided to the person
            (that is, to the individual or entity that applies for the relief)
            by that SED under this special authority for errors during that year
            is less than $20,000 (including in that calculation, any loan amount
            or other benefit of any kind payable for that year and any other
            year);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The total amount of such relief which has been previously provided
            to the participant using this special authority for errors in that
            year, as calculated above, is not more than $5,000;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The total amount of loans, payments, and benefits of any kind for
            which relief is provided to similarly situated participants by the
            SED (or the SED&apos;s predecessor) for errors for any year under
            the authority provided in this section, as calculated above, is not
            more than $1,000,000.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Report of the exercise of the power.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A grant of relief shall be considered to be under this section and
            subject to the special finality provided in this section only if the
            SED grants the relief in writing when granting the relief to the
            party who will receive the benefit of 
            <PRTPAGE P='48' />
            such relief and only if, in that document, the SED declares that
            they are exercising that power. The SED must report the exercise of
            that power to the Deputy Administrator so that a full accounting may
            be made in keeping with the limitations of this section. Absent such
            a report, relief will not be considered to have been made under this
            section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Additional limits on the authority.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The authority provided under this section does not extend to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The administration of payment limitations under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
                1400 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
             (
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 1001
            </aref>
             to 1001F of 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='1308' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1308.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 1308
              </subref>
            </aref>
            <E T='03'>
              et seq.
            </E>
            );
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The administration of payment limitations under a conservation
            program administered by the Secretary; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Highly erodible land and wetland conservation requirements under
            subtitles B or C of Title XII of the Food Security Act of 1985 (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='16' sect='3811' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/3811.html'>
                16 U.S.C. 3811
              </subref>
            </aref>
            <E T='03'>
              et seq.
            </E>
            ) as administered under 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='12' tq='N'>
                12
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Relief may not be provided by the SED under this section until a
            written opinion or written acknowledgment is obtained from OGC that
            grounds exist for determination that the program participant has, in
            good faith, detrimentally relied on the guidance or actions of an
            authorized FSA representative in accordance with the provisions of
            this subpart, or that the producer otherwise failed, in good faith,
            to fully comply with the requirements of the program and that the
            granting of the relief is within the lawful authority of the SED.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Relation to other authorities.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The authority provided under this section is in addition to any
            other applicable authority that may allow relief. Generally, the SED
            may, without consultation other than with OGC, decide all matters
            under $20,000 but those decisions shall not be subject to
            modification within the Farm Service Agency to the extent provided
            for under the rules of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>