<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol1'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15
    </extid>
    <num>
      15
    </num>
    <head>
      NONDISCRIMINATION
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='5' sect='301' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/5/301.html'>
              5 U.S.C. 301
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='29' sect='794' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/29/794.html'>
              29 U.S.C. 794
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </AUTH>
    </text>
    <section orderid='531'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:A:15.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.1
      </num>
      <head>
        Purpose and application of part.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          29 FR 16274
        </aref>
        , Dec. 4, 1964, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          38 FR 17925
        </aref>
        , July 5, 1973; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          68 FR 51341
        </aref>
        , Aug. 26, 2003]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Purpose and application of part.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The purpose of the regulations in this part is to effectuate the
            provisions of title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (hereinafter
            referred to as the “Act”) to the end that no person in the United
            States shall, on the ground of race, color, or national origin, be
            excluded from participation in, be denied the benefits of, or be
            otherwise subjected to discrimination under any program or activity
            of an applicant or recipient receiving Federal financial assistance
            from the Department of Agriculture or any Agency thereof.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The regulations in this part apply to any program or activity of an
            applicant or recipient for which Federal financial assistance is
            authorized under a law administered by the Department including, but
            not limited to, the Federal financial assistance listed in the
            appendix to this part. They apply to 
            <PRTPAGE P='401' />
            money paid, property transferred, or other Federal financial
            assistance extended to an applicant or recipient for its program or
            activity after the effective date of these regulations pursuant to
            an application approved or statutory or other provision made
            therefor prior to such effective date. The regulations in this part
            do not apply to (1) any Federal financial assistance by way of
            insurance or guaranty contract, (2) money paid, property
            transferred, or other assistance extended prior to the effective
            date of the regulations in this part, (3) any assistance to an
            applicant or recipient who is an ultimate beneficiary, or (4) except
            as provided in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='15' sect='3' psec='#c' tq='N'>
                15.3(c)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , any employment practice of any employer, employment agency or
            labor organization. The fact that a specific kind of Federal
            financial assistance is not listed in the appendix, shall not mean,
            if title VI of the Act is otherwise applicable, that such Federal
            financial assistance is not covered. Other Federal financial
            assistance under statutes now in force or hereinafter enacted may be
            added to this list by notice approved and issued by the Secretary
            and published in the 
            <E T='04'>
              Federal Register.
            </E>
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            29 FR 16274
          </aref>
          , Dec. 4, 1964, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            38 FR 17925
          </aref>
          , July 5, 1973; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            68 FR 51341
          </aref>
          , Aug. 26, 2003]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='532'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:A:15.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          29 FR 16274
        </aref>
        , Dec. 4, 1964, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          36 FR 3411
        </aref>
        , Feb. 24, 1971; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          38 FR 17925
        </aref>
        , July 5, 1973; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          68 FR 51340, 51341
        </aref>
        , Aug. 26, 2003]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Department
            </E>
             means the Department of Agriculture, and includes each of its
            operating agencies and other organizational units.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Agency
            </E>
             means any service, bureau, agency, office, administration,
            instrumentality of or corporation within the U.S. Department of
            Agriculture extending Federal financial assistance to any program or
            activity, or any officer or employee of the Department to whom the
            Secretary delegates authority to carry out any of the functions or
            responsibilities of an agency under this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Secretary
            </E>
             means the Secretary of Agriculture or any officer or employee of
            the Department to whom the Secretary has heretofore delegated, or to
            whom the Secretary may hereafter delegate, the authority to act in
            his stead under the regulations in this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Hearing Officer
            </E>
             means a hearing examiner appointed pursuant to 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='5' sect='3105' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/5/3105.html'>
                5 U.S.C. 3105
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , and designated to hold hearings under the regulations in this part
            or any person authorized to hold a hearing and make a final decision
            under the regulations in this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Recipient
            </E>
             means any State, political subdivision of any State, or
            instrumentality of any State or political subdivision, any public or
            private agency, institution, or organization, or other entity or any
            individual in any State, to whom Federal financial assistance is
            extended, directly or through another recipient, including any
            successor, assignee, or transferee thereof, but such term does not
            include any ultimate beneficiary.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Primary recipient
            </E>
             includes any recipient which is authorized or required to extend
            Federal financial assistance to another recipient.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Federal financial assistance
            </E>
             or 
            <E T='03'>
              financial assistance
            </E>
             includes (1) grants and loans of Federal funds, (2) the grant or
            donation of Federal property and interests in property, (3) the
            detail of Federal personnel, (4) the sale and lease of, and the
            permission to use (on other than a casual or transient basis),
            Federal property or any interest in such property or the furnishing
            of services without consideration or at a nominal consideration, or
            at a consideration which is reduced for the purpose of assisting the
            recipient, or in recognition of the public interest to be served by
            such sale, lease or furnishing of services to the recipient, and (5)
            any Federal agreement, arrangement, or other contract which has as
            one of its purposes the provision of assistance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Grant, loan or contract
            </E>
             includes any grant, loan agreement or commitment to loan, contract
            or agreement to provide financial assistance or any other
            arrangement between the Department or any Agency and a recipient of
            financial assistance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              United States
            </E>
             means the States of the United States, the District of Columbia,
            Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, American Samoa, Guam, Wake Island,
            the Canal Zone, and the territories and possessions of the United
            States, and the term 
            <E T='03'>
              State
            </E>
             means any one of the foregoing.
            <PRTPAGE P='402' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Applicant
            </E>
             means one who submits an application, request, or plan required to
            be approved by an Agency, or by a primary recipient, as a condition
            to eligibility for Federal financial assistance, and 
            <E T='03'>
              application
            </E>
             means such an application, request, or plan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Program or activity
            </E>
             and 
            <E T='03'>
              program
            </E>
             mean all of the operations of any entity described in paragraphs
            (k)(1) through (4) of this section, any part of which is extended
            Federal financial assistance:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='k_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='k_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A department, agency, special purpose district, or other
            instrumentality of a State or of a local government; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='k_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The entity of such State or local government that distributes such
            assistance and each such department or agency (and each other State
            or local government entity) to which the assistance is extended, in
            the case of assistance to a State or local government;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='k_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='k_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A college, university, or other postsecondary institution, or a
            public system of higher education; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='k_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A local educational agency (as defined in 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='20' sect='7801' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/20/7801.html'>
                20 U.S.C. 7801
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ), system of vocational education, or other school system;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='k_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An entire corporation, partnership, or other private organization,
            or an entire sole proprietorship—
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_3_ii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If assistance is extended to such corporation, partnership, private
            organization, or sole proprietorship as a whole; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='i_3_ii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Which is principally engaged in the business of providing
            education, health care, housing, social services, or parks and
            recreation; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The entire plant or other comparable, geographically separate
            facility to which Federal financial assistance is extended, in the
            case of any other corporation, partnership, private organization, or
            sole proprietorship; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any other entity which is established by two or more of the
            entities described in paragraph (k)(1), (2), or (3) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='l'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (l)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Facility
            </E>
             includes all or any portion of structures, equipment, or other real
            or personal property or interests therein, and the provision of
            facilities includes the construction, expansion, renovation,
            remodeling, alteration or acquisition of facilities.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            29 FR 16274
          </aref>
          , Dec. 4, 1964, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            36 FR 3411
          </aref>
          , Feb. 24, 1971; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            38 FR 17925
          </aref>
          , July 5, 1973; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            68 FR 51340, 51341
          </aref>
          , Aug. 26, 2003]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='533'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:A:15.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Discrimination prohibited.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          29 FR 16274
        </aref>
        , Dec. 4, 1964, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          35 FR 18383
        </aref>
        , Dec. 3, 1970; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          38 FR 17925
        </aref>
        , July 5, 1973; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          68 FR 51341
        </aref>
        , Aug. 26, 2003]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Discrimination prohibited.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No person in the United States shall, on the ground of race, color,
            or national origin, be excluded from participation in, be denied the
            benefits of, or be otherwise subjected to discrimination under any
            program or activity of the applicant or recipient to which these
            regulations apply. These regulations apply, but are not restricted,
            to unequal treatment in priority, quality, quantity, methods or
            charges for service, use, occupancy or benefit, participation in the
            service or benefit available, or in the use, occupancy or benefit of
            any structure, facility, or improvement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Specific discriminatory actions prohibited.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A recipient under any program to which the regulations in this part
            apply may not, directly or through contractual or other arrangements
            on the ground of race, color, or national origin:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Deny an individual any service, financial aid, or other benefit
            provided under the program;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provide any service, financial aid, or other benefit, to an
            individual which is different, or is provided in a different manner,
            from that provided to others under the program;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subject an individual to segregation or separate treatment in any
            matter related to his receipt of any service, financial aid, or
            other benefit under the program;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Restrict an individual in any way in the enjoyment of any advantage
            or privilege, enjoyed by others receiving any service, financial
            aid, or other benefit under the program;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Treat an individual differently from others in determining whether
            he satisfies any admission, enrollment, quota, eligibility,
            membership or other requirement or condition which individuals must
            meet in order to be provided any service, financial aid, or other
            benefit provided under the program;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Deny an individual an opportunity to participate in the program 
            <PRTPAGE P='403' />
            through the provisions of services or otherwise or afford him an
            opportunity to do so which is different from that afforded others
            under the program (including the opportunity to participate in the
            program as an employee but only to the extent set forth in paragraph
            (c) of this section).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_vii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Deny a person the opportunity to participate as a member of a
            planning or advisory body which is an integral part of the program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A recipient, in determining the types of services, financial aid,
            or other benefits, or facilities which will be provided under any
            such program, or the class of individuals to whom, or the situations
            in which, such services, financial aid, other benefits, or
            facilities will be provided under any such program or the class of
            individuals to be afforded an opportunity to participate in any such
            program, may not, directly or through contractual or other
            arrangements, utilize criteria or methods of administration which
            have the effect of subjecting individuals to discrimination because
            of their race, color, or national origin, or have the effect of
            defeating or substantially impairing accomplishment of the
            objectives of the program as respects individuals of a particular
            race, color, or national origin.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In determining the site or location of facilities, an applicant or
            recipient may not make selections with the purpose or effect of
            excluding individuals from, denying them the benefits of, or
            subjecting them to discrimination under any of its programs or
            activities to which the regulations in this part apply, on the
            grounds of race, color, or national origin; or with the purpose or
            effect of defeating or substantially impairing the accomplishment of
            the objectives of the Act and the regulations in this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             As used in this section, the services, financial aid, or other
            benefit provided under a program or activity of an applicant or
            recipient receiving Federal financial assistance shall be deemed to
            include any and all services, financial aid, or other benefit
            provided in or through a facility provided or improved in whole or
            part with the aid of Federal financial assistance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The enumeration of specific forms of prohibited discrimination in
            these regulations does not limit the applicability of the provisions
            of paragraph (a) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_6_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In administering a program regarding which the recipient has
            previously discriminated against persons on the ground of race,
            color, or national origin, the recipient must take affirmative
            action to overcome the effects of prior discrimination.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_6_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Even in the absence of such prior discrimination, a recipient in
            administering a program may take affirmative action to overcome the
            effects of conditions which resulted in limiting participation by
            persons of a particular race, color or national origin.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Employment practices.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Where a primary objective of the Federal financial assistance to a
            program to which the regulations in this part apply is to provide
            employment, a recipient may not, directly or through contractual or
            other arrangements, subject an individual to discrimination on the
            ground of race, color, or national origin in its employment
            practices under the program including recruitment or recruitment
            advertising, employment, layoff or termination, upgrading, demotion,
            or transfer, rates of pay or other forms of compensation, and use of
            facilities. This paragraph applies to programs where a primary
            objective of the Federal financial assistance is (1) to reduce
            unemployment, (2) to assist individuals in meeting expenses incident
            to the commencement or continuation of their education or training,
            or (3) to provide work experience which contributes to education or
            training. Where a primary objective of the Federal financial
            assistance is not to provide employment, but discrimination on the
            grounds of race, color, or national origin in the employment
            practices of the recipient or other persons subject to the
            regulations in this part, tends, on the grounds of race, color, or
            national origin, to exclude individuals from participation in, to
            deny them the benefits of, or to subject them to discrimination
            under any program or activity of the applicant or recipient to which
            these regulations apply, the foregoing provisions of this 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='15' sect='3' psec='#c' tq='N'>
                15.3(c)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             shall apply to 
            <PRTPAGE P='404' />
            the employment practices of the recipient or other persons subject
            to these regulations, to the extent necessary to assure equality of
            opportunity to, and nondiscriminatory treatment of, beneficiaries.
            The requirements applicable to construction employment under any
            program or activity of the applicant or recipient shall be those
            specified in or pursuant to part III of Executive Order 11246 or any
            Executive order which supersedes it.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Examples.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In order that all parties may have a clear understanding of the
            applicability of the regulations in this part to their activities,
            there are listed in this section types of Federal financial
            assistance together with illustrations, by way of example only, of
            types of activity covered by the regulations in this part. These
            illustrations and examples, however, are not intended to be all
            inclusive. The fact that a particular type of Federal financial
            assistance is not listed does not, of course, indicate that a
            program is not covered by the regulations in this part. Moreover,
            the examples set forth with respect to any particular listed type of
            Federal financial assistance are not limited to that program alone
            and the prohibited actions described may also be prohibited in other
            programs or activities whether or not listed below.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Cooperative Agricultural Extension Program.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Discrimination in making available or in the manner of making
            available instructions, demonstrations, information, and
            publications offered by or through the Cooperative Extension
            Service;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Discrimination in the use in any program or activity funded by the
            Cooperative Extension Service of any facility, including offices,
            training facilities, lecture halls, or other structures or
            improvements; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Discrimination in training activities, admission to or
            participation in fairs, competitions, field days, and encampments,
            conducted or sponsored by, or in which the Cooperative Extension
            Service participates.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Rural Electrification and Rural Telephone Programs.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Refusal or failure by a borrower to accept applications for
            membership or applications to purchase shares of stock, or
            discrimination by a borrower in the terms and conditions of
            membership or stock ownership, where such membership or stock
            ownership is a condition prerequisite to the furnishing of electric
            or telephone service by the borrower, or to the receipt of any
            benefits or advantages related to such service;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Refusal or failure by a borrower to extend, or discrimination by a
            borrower in the extension of, electric or telephone service to
            unserved persons;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Denial by a borrower to any person of the benefits of improvement,
            expansion or upgrading, or discrimination by a borrower among
            consumers or subscribers in improving, expanding or upgrading, of
            electric or telephone service;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Discrimination by a borrower in respect of rates, or terms or
            conditions of, service among consumers or subscribers;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Exclusion by a borrower of any member or stockholder, if the
            borrower is a cooperative or mutual type of corporation, from
            participation in any meeting of members or stockholders of the
            borrower, discrimination among its members or stockholders in
            respect of the exercise of any of their rights as members or
            stockholders, or in the manner of the exercise of such rights; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Exclusion by a borrower of any consumer or subscriber from, denial
            by a borrower to any consumer or subscriber of the use of, or
            discrimination by a borrower against any consumer or subscriber in
            his use of, any of the borrower&apos;s facilities.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Direct Distribution Program.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Exclusion of an otherwise eligible recipient agency (school, summer
            camp for children, institution, welfare agency or disaster
            organization) or person from participation in the Direct
            Distribution Program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Discrimination in the allocation of food to eligible persons.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Discrimination in the manner in which or the place or times at
            which foods donated under the Program are distributed by recipient
            agencies to eligible persons.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_3_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Segregation of persons served in different meal periods or by
            different seating or serving or different food or different size
            portions by recipient 
            <PRTPAGE P='405' />
            agencies serving prepared meals containing donated foods.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
            <head>
              National School Lunch Program.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_4_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Discrimination by a State agency in the selection of schools to
            participate in the Program or in the assignment to schools of rates
            of reimbursement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_4_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Exclusion of any child from participation in the Program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_4_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Discrimination by school officials in the selection of children to
            receive free or reduced-price lunches.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_4_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Segregation of participating children in different lunch periods or
            different seating, and discrimination by serving different food or
            different size portions.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_4_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Failure to offer free and reduced-price lunches, on an equitable
            basis in schools of a school district in which children are assigned
            to schools on the basis of race, color, or national origin.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Food Stamp Program.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_5_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Discrimination by a State agency in certifying households as
            eligible for the Program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_5_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Segregation or other discrimination in the manner in which or the
            times at which eligible households are issued food coupons.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Special Milk Program for Children.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_6_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Discrimination by a State agency in the selection of schools and
            child-care institutions to participate in the Program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_6_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Discrimination by a State agency in the selection of needy schools
            to receive reimbursement for milk served free.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_6_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Discrimination by a State agency in the assignment of reimbursement
            rates to schools and child-care institutions or in the adjustment of
            such rates, or in fixing allowable distribution costs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_6_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Exclusion of any child from participation in the Program and
            segregation of participating children in different serving periods
            or different places of service.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_6_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Discrimination by school officials or child-care institutions in
            the selection of children to receive free milk.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Price Support Programs carried out through producer associations
              or cooperatives or through persons who are required to provide
              specified benefits to producers.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_7_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Denial of the benefits of price support for a producers commodity.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_7_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Denial of membership or stock ownership to any producer by any
            association or cooperative.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_7_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Discrimination among producers in the manner of making or paying
            any price support advances, loans, or payments.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_7_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Discrimination in the fees or charges collected from or in the net
            gains distributed to producers.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_7_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Discrimination in the use of facilities and services generally made
            available to members or patrons under the Price Support Program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Forest Service Programs.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_8_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Refusal or failure by a recipient of a permit or lease to provide
            to any person the benefits from the use of land administered by the
            Forest Service, the resources therefrom, or improvements thereon.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_8_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Refusal or failure by any recipient to provide to any person the
            benefits from Federal payments based on a share of the receipts from
            lands administered by the Forest Service.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_8_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Refusal or failure by any recipient to provide to any person the
            benefits from Federal assistance in cooperative programs for the
            protection, development, management, and use of forest resources.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_8_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Refusal or failure by any cooperator or other recipient to provide
            to any person the benefits from Federal assistance through grants or
            advances of funds for research.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Farmers Home Administration Programs—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Direct soil and water loans to association.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             (
            <E T='03'>
              a
            </E>
            ) A borrower&apos;s denial of, or discrimination in furnishing,
            services under a program or activity financed wholly or partially
            with the aid of the loan, as in the case of a water supply system.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          (
          <E T='03'>
            b
          </E>
          ) A borrower&apos;s denial of, or discrimination or segregation in
          permitting, the use of facilities which are part of a project financed
          wholly or partially with the aid of the loan, as in the case of a golf
          course, swimming pool, tennis courts, parking areas, lounges, dining
          rooms, and rest rooms of a recreation association.
        </P>
        <P>
          (
          <E T='03'>
            c
          </E>
          ) Discrimination by a borrower in the terms and conditions of
          membership or stock ownership, or refusal or failure of a borrower to
          accept applications for membership or for purchase of shares of stock,
          or discrimination by a 
          <PRTPAGE P='406' />
          borrower in acting or failing to act upon such applications, where
          such membership or stock ownership is a prerequisite to the
          participation in services furnished by, or the use of facilities of,
          the borrower which are financed wholly or partially with the aid of
          the loan or to the receipt of any benefits or advantages related to
          such services or the use of such facilities.
        </P>
        <P>
          (
          <E T='03'>
            d
          </E>
          ) Denial or impairment by a borrower of any person&apos;s rights as a
          member or stockholder of the borrower, or borrower&apos;s
          discrimination against or segregation of persons in the exercise of
          their rights as members or stockholders of the borrower.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Direct senior citizens rental housing loans to private nonprofit
              corporations and consumer cooperatives.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             (
            <E T='03'>
              a
            </E>
            ) A borrower&apos;s exclusion of any person from, discrimination in
            the terms and conditions of eligibility for, or discrimination
            against or segregation of any person in, the use and occupancy of
            the housing and related facilities financed wholly or partially with
            the aid of the loan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          (
          <E T='03'>
            b
          </E>
          ) Discrimination by a borrower in the terms and conditions of
          membership or stock ownership, or refusal or failure of a borrower to
          accept applications for membership or for purchase of shares of stock,
          or discrimination by a borrower in acting or failing to act upon such
          applicattions, where such membership or stock ownership is a condition
          of eligibility for use and occupancy of the housing and related
          facilities financed wholly or partially with the aid of the loan or to
          the receipt of any benefits or advantages related to such housing or
          facilities.
        </P>
        <P>
          (
          <E T='03'>
            c
          </E>
          ) Denial or impairment by a borrower of any person&apos;s rights as a
          member or stockholder of the borrower, or a borrower&apos;s
          discrimination against or segregation of persons in the exercise of
          their rights as members or stockholders of the borrower.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='ii_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Cooperative State Research Programs.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='ii_10_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Discrimination in making available information whether published or
            provided through public or private statement, correspondence,
            demonstration or field day.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='ii_10_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Discrimination in participation in any Cooperative Research Program
            or project.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='ii_10_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Discrimination in the use of any facility, including offices,
            laboratories, or other structures, or research plots or fields.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='ii_10_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Discrimination in employment of graduate students to conduct
            research when such students receive substantial research training
            benefits as a result of such employment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            29 FR 16274
          </aref>
          , Dec. 4, 1964, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            35 FR 18383
          </aref>
          , Dec. 3, 1970; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            38 FR 17925
          </aref>
          , July 5, 1973; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            68 FR 51341
          </aref>
          , Aug. 26, 2003]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='534'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:A:15.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Assurances required.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          29 FR 16274
        </aref>
        , Dec. 4, 1964, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          32 FR 3967
        </aref>
        , Mar. 11, 1967; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          35 FR 18383
        </aref>
        , Dec. 3, 1970; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          38 FR 17926
        </aref>
        , July 5, 1973; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          68 FR 53141
        </aref>
        , Aug. 26, 2003]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Assurances required.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Every application for Federal financial assistance to which these
            regulations apply, except an application to which paragraph (b) of
            this section applies, and every application for Federal financial
            assistance to provide a facility, shall as a condition to its
            approval and the extension of any Federal financial assistance
            pursuant to the application, contain or be accompanied by an
            assurance that the applicant&apos;s program or activity will be
            conducted or the facility operated in compliance with all
            requirements imposed by or pursuant to the Act and the regulations
            in this part. In the case where the Federal financial assistance is
            to provide or is in the form of personal property, or real property
            or interest therein, or structures thereon, the assurance shall
            obligate the recipient, or, in the case of a subsequent transfer,
            the transferee, for the period during which the property is used for
            the purpose for which the Federal financial assistance is extended
            or for another purpose involving the provision of similar services
            and benefits or for as long as the recipient retains ownership or
            possession of the property, whichever is longer. In all other cases,
            the assurance shall obligate the recipient for the period during
            which Federal financial assistance is extended pursuant to the
            application. The Agency shall specify the form of the foregoing
            assurances and the extent to which like assurances will be required
            of subgrantees, contractors, and subcontractors, successors in
            interest and other participants. Any such assurance shall include
            provisions which give the United States a right to seek its judicial
            enforcement.
            <PRTPAGE P='407' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the case of real property, structures, or improvements thereon,
            or interests therein, which was acquired through Federal financial
            assistance, or in the case where Federal financial assistance is
            provided in the form of a transfer of real property or interest
            therein from the Federal Government, the instrument effecting or
            recording the transfer shall contain a covenant running with the
            land assuring nondiscrimination for the period during which the real
            property is used for a purpose for which the Federal financial
            assistance is extended or for another purpose involving the
            provision of similar services or benefits, or for as long as the
            recipient retains ownership or possession of the property, whichever
            is longer. Where no transfer of property is involved, but property
            is improved through Federal financial assistance, the recipient
            shall agree to include such a covenant in any subsequent transfer of
            such property. Where the property is obtained from the Federal
            Government, such covenant may also include a condition coupled with
            a right to be reserved by the Agency to revert title to the property
            in the event of a breach of the covenant where, in the discretion of
            the Agency concerned, such a condition and right of reverter is
            appropriate to the purposes of the Federal financial assistance
            under which the real property is obtained and to the nature of the
            grant and the grantee. In such event, if a transferee of real
            property proposes to mortgage or otherwise encumber the real
            property as security for financing construction of new, or
            improvement of existing, facilities on such property for the
            purposes for which the property was transferred, the Agency may
            agree, upon request of the transferee and if necessary to accomplish
            such financing, and upon such conditions as it deems appropriate to
            forbear the exercise of such right to revert title for so long as
            the lien of such mortgage or other encumbrance remains effective.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Transfers of surplus property are subject to regulations issued by
            the Administrator of General Services (
            <aref type='CFR'>
              41 CFR 
              <subref title='41' part='101-6' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
                101-6.2
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Every application by a State or a State Agency, including a State
            Extension Service, but not including an application for aid to an
            institution of higher education, continuing Federal financial
            assistance to which the regulations in this part apply shall as a
            condition to its approval and the exension of any Federal financial
            assistance pursuant to the application (1) contain or be accompanied
            by a statement that the program is (or, in the case of a new
            program, will be) conducted in compliance with all requirements
            imposed by or pursuant to this part, and (2) provide or be
            accompanied by provision for such methods of administration for the
            program as are found by the Agency to give reasonable assurance that
            the applicant and all recipients of Federal financial assistance
            under such program will comply with all requirements imposed by or
            pursuant to the regulations in this part: 
            <E T='03'>
              Provided,
            </E>
             That where no application is required prior to payment, the State
            or State Agency, including a State Extension Service, shall, as a
            condition to the extension of any Federal financial assistance,
            submit an assurance complying with the requirements of paragraphs
            (b)(1) and (2) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Assurances from institutions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The assurance required with respect to an institution of higher
            education, or any other institution, insofar as the assurance
            relates to the institution&apos;s practices with respect to
            admission or other treatment of individuals or to the opportunity to
            participate in the provision of services or other benefits to such
            individuals, shall be applicable to the entire institution.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Recipients other than applicants.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each recipient not required to submit an application for Federal
            financial assistance, shall furnish, as a condition to the extension
            of any such assistance, an assurance or statement as is required of
            applicants under paragraphs (a), (b)(1) and (2) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Elementary and secondary schools.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The requirements of paragraphs (a), (b), or (d) of this section
            with respect to any elementary or secondary school or school system
            shall be deemed to be satisfied if such school or school system (1)
            is subject to a final order of a court of the United States for the
            desegregation of such school or school system, and provides an
            assurance that 
            <PRTPAGE P='408' />
            it will comply with such order, including any future modification of
            such order, or (2) submits a plan for the desegregation of such
            school or school system which the responsible official of the
            Department of Health, Education, and Welfare determines is adequate
            to accomplish the purposes of the Act and this part, and provides
            reasonable assurance that it will carry out such plan; in any case
            of continuing Federal financial assistance the said responsible
            official of the Department of Health, Education, and Welfare may
            reserve the right to redetermine, after such period as may be
            specified by him, the adequacy of the plan to accomplish the
            purposes of the Act and this part within the earliest practical
            time. In any case in which a final order of a court of the United
            States for the desegregation of such school or school system is
            entered after submission of such a plan, such plan shall be revised
            to conform to such final order, including any future modification of
            such order.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            29 FR 16274
          </aref>
          , Dec. 4, 1964, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            32 FR 3967
          </aref>
          , Mar. 11, 1967; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            35 FR 18383
          </aref>
          , Dec. 3, 1970; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            38 FR 17926
          </aref>
          , July 5, 1973; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            68 FR 53141
          </aref>
          , Aug. 26, 2003]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='535'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:A:15.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.5
      </num>
      <head>
        Compliance.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          29 FR 16274
        </aref>
        , Dec. 4, 1964, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          29 FR 16966
        </aref>
        , Dec. 11, 1964; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          38 FR 17926
        </aref>
        , July 5, 1973; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          68 FR 51341
        </aref>
        , Aug. 26, 2003]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Compliance.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Cooperation and assistance.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each Agency shall to the fullest extent practicable seek the
            cooperation of recipients in obtaining compliance with the
            regulations and this part and shall provide assistance and guidance
            to recipients to help them comply voluntarily with the regulations
            in this part. As a normal part of the administration of Federal
            financial assistance covered by the regulations in this part,
            designated personnel will in their reviews and other activities or
            as specifically directed by the Agency, review the activities of
            recipients to determine whether they are complying with the
            regulations in this part. Reports by such personnel shall include
            statements regarding compliance and instances, if any, of
            noncompliance. In the event of noncompliance, the Agency shall seek
            to secure voluntary compliance by all appropriate means.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Compliance reports.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each recipient shall keep such records and submit to the Agency
            timely, complete and accurate compliance reports at such times, and
            in such form and containing such information, as the Agency may
            determine to be necessary to ascertain whether the recipient has
            complied or is complying with the regulations in this part. In the
            case in which a primary recipient extends Federal financial
            assistance to any other recipient, such other recipient shall also
            submit such compliance reports to the primary recipient as may be
            necessary to enable the primary recipient to carry out its
            obligations under the regulations in this part. In general,
            recipients should have available for the Agency racial and ethnic
            data showing the extent to which members of minority groups are
            beneficiaries of federally assisted programs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Access to sources of information.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each recipient shall permit access by authorized employees of this
            Department during normal business hours to such of its books,
            records, accounts, and other sources of information, and its
            facilities as may be pertinent to ascertain compliance with the
            regulations in this part. Where any information required of a
            recipient is in the exclusive possession of any other agency,
            institution or person and this agency, institution or person shall
            fail or refuse to furnish this information, the recipient shall so
            certify in its report and shall set forth what efforts it has made
            to obtain the information.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Information to beneficiaries and participants.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each recipient shall make available to participants, beneficiaries,
            and other interested persons such information regarding the
            provisions of the regulations in this part and their applicability
            to the program for Federal statutes, authorities, or other means by
            which Federal financial assistance is extended and which the
            recipient receives Federal financial assistance, and make such
            information available to them in such manner, as the Department or
            its Agencies finds necessary to apprise such persons of the
            protections against discrimination assured them by the Act and the
            regulations in this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            29 FR 16274
          </aref>
          , Dec. 4, 1964, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            29 FR 16966
          </aref>
          , Dec. 11, 1964; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            38 FR 17926
          </aref>
          , July 5, 1973; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            68 FR 51341
          </aref>
          , Aug. 26, 2003]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='536'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:A:15.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.6
      </num>
      <head>
        Complaints.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          50 FR 25687
        </aref>
        , June 21, 1985, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          68 FR 27449
        </aref>
        , May 20, 2003]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='409' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Complaints.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Any person who believes himself/herself or any specific class of
          individuals to be subjected to discrimination prohibited by the
          regulations in this part may by himself/herself or by an authorized
          representative file with the Secretary or any Agency a written
          complaint. A complaint must be filed not later than 180 days from the
          date of the alleged discrimination, unless the time for filing is
          extended by the Agency or by the Secretary. Such complaint shall be
          promptly referred to the Assistant Secretary for Civil Rights. The
          complaint shall be investigated in the manner determined by the
          Assistant Secretary for Civil Rights and such further action taken by
          the Agency or the Secretary as may be warranted.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            50 FR 25687
          </aref>
          , June 21, 1985, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            68 FR 27449
          </aref>
          , May 20, 2003]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='537'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:A:15.7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.7
      </num>
      <head>
        Intimidatory or retaliatory acts prohibited.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Intimidatory or retaliatory acts prohibited.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          No recipient or other person shall intimidate, threaten, coerce, or
          discriminate against any individual for the purpose of interfering
          with any right or privilege secured by 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 601 of
          </aref>
           the Act or the regulations in this part, or because he has made a
          complaint, testified, assisted, or participated in any manner in an
          investigation, proceeding, or hearing under the regulations in this
          part. The identity of complainants shall be kept confidential except
          to the extent necessary to carry out the purposes of the regulations
          in this part, including the conduct of any hearing or judicial
          proceeding arising thereunder.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='538'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:A:15.8
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.8
      </num>
      <head>
        Procedure for effecting compliance.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.8
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Procedure for effecting compliance.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If there appears to be a failure or threatened failure to comply
            with the regulations in this part, and if the noncompliance or
            threatened noncompliance cannot be corrected by informal means,
            compliance with the regulations in this part may be effected by the
            suspension or termination of or refusal to grant or to continue
            Federal financial assistance, upon a finding, in accordance with the
            procedure hereinafter prescribed, or by any other means authorized
            by law. Such other means may include, but are not limited to, (1) a
            reference to the Department of Justice with a recommendation that
            appropriate proceedings be brought to enforce any rights of the
            United States under any law of the United States (including other
            titles of the Act), or any assurance or other contractual
            undertaking, and (2) any applicable proceeding under State or local
            law.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Noncompliance with 
              <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
                § 
                <subref title='7' part='15' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
                  15.4
                </subref>
              </aref>
              .
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If an applicant fails or refuses to furnish an assurance required
            under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='15' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
                15.4
              </subref>
            </aref>
             or otherwise fails or refuses to comply with the requirements
            imposed by or pursuant to that section, Federal financial assistance
            may be refused in accordance with the procedures of paragraph (c) of
            this section. The Department shall not be required to provide
            assistance in such a case during the pendency of the administrative
            proceedings under such paragraph, except that the Department shall
            continue assistance during the pendency of such proceedings where
            such assistance is due and payable pursuant to an application
            therefor approved prior to the effective date of the regulations in
            this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Termination of or refusal to grant or to continue Federal
              financial assistance.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No order suspending, terminating, or refusing to grant or to
            continue Federal financial assistance shall become effective until
            (1) the Agency has advised the applicant or recipient of his failure
            to comply and has determined that compliance cannot be secured by
            voluntary means, (2) there has been an express finding on the
            record, after opportunity for hearing, of a failure by the applicant
            or recipient to comply with the requirement imposed by or pursuant
            to the regulations in this part, (3) the action has been approved by
            the Secretary pursuant to 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='15' sect='10' psec='#e' tq='N'>
                15.10(e), and (4)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             the expiration of 30 days after the Secretary has filed with the
            committee of the House and the committee of the Senate, having
            legislative jurisdiction over the program involved, a full written
            report of the circumstances and the grounds for such action. Any
            action to suspend or terminate or to refuse to grant or to continue
            Federal financial assistance shall be limited to the particular
            political entity, or part thereof, or other applicant or recipient
            as to whom such a 
            <PRTPAGE P='410' />
            finding has been made and shall be limited in its effect to the
            particular program, or part thereof, in which such noncompliance has
            been so found.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Other means authorized by law.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No action to effect compliance by any other means authorized by law
            shall be taken until (1) the Secretary has determined that
            compliance cannot be secured by voluntary means, (2) the recipient
            or other person has been notified of its failure to comply and of
            the action to be taken to effect compliance, and (3) the expiration
            of at least ten days from the mailing of such notice to the
            recipient or other person. During this period of at least ten days,
            additional efforts shall be made to persuade the recipient or other
            person to comply with the regulations in this part and to take such
            corrective action as may be appropriate.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='539'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:A:15.9
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.9
      </num>
      <head>
        Hearings.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          29 FR 16274
        </aref>
        , Dec. 4, 1964, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          35 FR 18384
        </aref>
        , Dec. 3, 1970; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          38 FR 17926
        </aref>
        , July 5, 1973; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          68 FR 51341
        </aref>
        , Aug. 26, 2003]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.9
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Hearings.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Opportunity for hearing.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whenever an opportunity for a hearing is required under the
            regulations in this part, reasonable notice shall be given by
            registered or certified mail, return receipt requested, to the
            affected applicant or recipient. This notice shall advise the
            applicant or recipient of the action proposed to be taken, the
            specific provision under which the proposed action against it is to
            be taken, and the matters of fact or law asserted as the basis for
            this action, and either (1) fix a date not less than 20 days after
            the date of such notice within which the applicant or recipient may
            request of the Secretary or the Agency that the matter be scheduled
            for hearing or (2) advise the applicant or recipient that the matter
            in question has been set down for hearing at a stated place and
            time. The time and place so fixed shall be reasonable and shall be
            subject to change for cause. The complainant, if any, shall be
            advised of the time and place of the hearing. An applicant or
            recipient may waive a hearing and submit written information and
            argument for the record. The failure of an applicant or recipient to
            request a hearing under this subsection or to appear at a hearing
            for which a date has been set shall be deemed to be a waiver of the
            right to a hearing under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 602 of
            </aref>
             the Act and the regulations in this part and consent to the making
            of a decision on the basis of such information as is available.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Time and place of hearing.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Hearings shall be held at the offices of the Department in
            Washington, DC, at a time fixed by the hearing officer or by the
            Secretary unless it is determined that the convenience of the
            applicant or recipient or of the Department requires that another
            place be selected. Hearings shall be held before a hearing officer.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Right to counsel.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In all proceedings under this section, the applicant or recipient
            and the Department shall have the right to be represented by
            counsel.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Procedures, evidence, and record.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The hearing, decision, and any administrative review thereof shall
            be conducted in conformity with 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='5' sect='554-557' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/5/554-557.html'>
                5 U.S.C. 554-557
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , and in accordance with such rules of procedure promulgated by the
            Secretary as not inconsistent with this section, relating to the
            conduct of the hearing, giving of notices subsequent to those
            provided for in paragraph (a) of this section, taking of testimony,
            exhibits, arguments and briefs, requests for findings, and other
            related matters. Both the Department, and the applicant or recipient
            shall be entitled to introduce all relevant evidence on the issues
            as stated in the notice for hearing or as determined by the hearing
            officer conducting the hearing at the outset of or during the
            hearing.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Technical rules of evidence shall not apply to hearings conducted
            pursuant to these regulations in this part, but rules or principles
            designed to assure production of the most credible evidence
            available and to subject testimony to test by cross-examination
            shall be applied where reasonably necessary by the hearing officer.
            The hearing officer may exclude irrelevant, immaterial, or unduly
            repetitious evidence. All documents and other evidence offered or
            taken for the record shall be open to examination by the parties and
            opportunity shall be given to refute facts and arguments advanced on
            either side of the issues. A transcript shall be made of the oral
            evidence except to the extent the substance thereof is stipulated
            for the record. All decisions shall be based 
            <PRTPAGE P='411' />
            upon the hearing record and written findings shall be made.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Consolidated or joint hearings.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In cases in which the same or related facts are asserted to
            constitute noncompliance with these regulations with respect to two
            or more to which the regulations in this part apply, or
            noncompliance with the regulations in this part and the regulations
            of one or more other Federal Departments or Agencies issued under
            title VI of the Act, the Secretary may, by agreement with such other
            Departments or Agencies, where applicable provide for the conduct of
            consolidated or joint hearings, and for the application to such
            hearings of rules of procedure not inconsistent with the regulations
            in this part. Final decisions in such cases, insofar as the
            regulations in this part are concerned, shall be made in accordance
            with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='15' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
                15.10
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            29 FR 16274
          </aref>
          , Dec. 4, 1964, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            35 FR 18384
          </aref>
          , Dec. 3, 1970; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            38 FR 17926
          </aref>
          , July 5, 1973; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            68 FR 51341
          </aref>
          , Aug. 26, 2003]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='540'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:A:15.10
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.10
      </num>
      <head>
        Decisions and notices.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          29 FR 16274
        </aref>
        , Dec. 4, 1964, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          35 FR 18384
        </aref>
        , Dec. 3, 1970; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          38 FR 17926
        </aref>
        , July 5, 1973; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          68 FR 51341
        </aref>
        , Aug. 26, 2003]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.10
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Decisions and notices.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Decision by hearing officer or Secretary.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The hearing officer shall either make an initial decision, if so
            authorized, or certify the entire record including his recommended
            findings, and proposed decision to the Secretary for a final
            decision, and a copy of such initial decision or certification shall
            be mailed to the applicant or recipient. The applicant or recipient
            may within 30 days of the mailing of such notice of initial decision
            file with the Secretary his exceptions to the initial decision, with
            his reasons therefor.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the absence of exceptions, the Secretary may on his own motion
            within 45 days after the initial decision serve on the applicant or
            recipient a notice that he will review the decision. Upon the filing
            of such exceptions or of such notice of review the Secretary shall
            review the initial decision and issue his own decision thereon
            including the reasons therefor. In the absence of either exceptions
            or a notice of review the initial decision shall constitute the
            final decision of the Secretary.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Decisions on record or review.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whenever a record is certified to the Secretary for decision or he
            reviews the decision of a hearing officer pursuant to paragraph (a),
            the applicant or recipient shall be given reasonable opportunity to
            file with him briefs or other written statements of its contentions,
            and a copy of the final decision of the Secretary shall be given in
            writing to the applicant or recipient, and to the complainant, if
            any.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Decisions on record where a hearing is waived.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whenever a hearing is waived pursuant to 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='15' sect='9' psec='#a' tq='N'>
                15.9(a)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , a decision shall be made by the Secretary on the record and a copy
            of such decision shall be given in writing to the applicant or
            recipient, and to the complainant, if any.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Rulings required.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each decision of a hearing officer shall set forth his ruling on
            each finding, conclusion, or exception presented, and shall identify
            the requirement or requirements imposed by or pursuant to the
            regulations in this part with which it is found that the applicant
            or recipient has failed to comply.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Decision by Secretary.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Secretary shall make any final decision which provides for the
            suspension or termination of, or the refusal to grant or continue
            Federal financial assistance, or the imposition of any other
            sanction available under the regulations in this part or the Act.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Content of orders.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The final decision may provide for suspension or termination of, or
            refusal to grant or continue Federal financial assistance, in whole
            or in part, to which this regulation applies, and may contain such
            terms, conditions, and other provisions as are consistent with and
            will effectuate the purposes of the Act and the regulations in this
            part, including provisions designed to assure that no Federal
            financial assistance to which this regulation applies will
            thereafter be extended to the applicant or recipient determined by
            such decision to be in default in its performance of an assurance
            given by it pursuant to the regulations in this part, or to have
            otherwise failed to comply with the regulations in this part, unless
            and until it corrects its noncompliance and satisfies the Agency
            that it will fully comply with the regulations in this part.
            <PRTPAGE P='412' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Post termination proceedings.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An applicant or recipient adversely affected by an order issued
            under paragraph (f) of this section shall be restored to full
            eligibilty to receive Federal financial assistance if it satisfies
            the terms and conditions of that order for such eligibility or if it
            brings itself into compliance with the Act and the regulations in
            this part and provides reasonable assurance that it will fully
            comply therewith. An elementary or secondary school or school system
            which is unable to file an assurance of compliance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='15' sect='4' psec='#a' tq='N'>
                15.4 (a), (b), or (d)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             shall be restored to full eligibility to receive Federal financial
            assistance if it complies with the requirements of a 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='15' sect='4' psec='#e' tq='N'>
                15.4(e)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and is otherwise in compliance with the Act and the regulations in
            this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any applicant or recipient adversely affected by an order entered
            pursuant to paragraph (f) of this section may at any time request
            the Secretary to restore fully its eligibility to receive Federal
            financial assistance. Any such request shall be supported by
            information showing that the applicant or recipient has met the
            requirements of paragraph (g)(1) of this section. If the Secretary
            determines that those requirements have been satisfied, he shall
            restore such eligibility.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the Secretary denies any such request, the applicant or
            recipient may submit a request for a hearing in writing, specifying
            why it believes the denial to have been in error. It shall thereupon
            be given an expeditious hearing, with a decision on the record, in
            accordance with rules of procedure set forth in subpart C of this
            part. The applicant or recipient will be restored to such
            eligibility if it proves at such a hearing, that it has satisfied
            the requirements of paragraph (g)(1) of this section. While
            proceedings under this paragraph are pending, the sanctions imposed
            by the order issued under paragraph (f) of this section shall remain
            in effect.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            29 FR 16274
          </aref>
          , Dec. 4, 1964, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            35 FR 18384
          </aref>
          , Dec. 3, 1970; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            38 FR 17926
          </aref>
          , July 5, 1973; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            68 FR 51341
          </aref>
          , Aug. 26, 2003]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='541'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:A:15.11
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.11
      </num>
      <head>
        Judicial review.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.11
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Judicial review.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Action taken pursuant to 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 602 of
          </aref>
           the Act is subject to judicial review as provided in 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 603 of
          </aref>
           the Act.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='542'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:A:15.12
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.12
      </num>
      <head>
        Effect on other regulations; forms and instructions.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          29 FR 16274
        </aref>
        , Dec. 4, 1964, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          38 FR 17927
        </aref>
        , July 5, 1973; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          68 FR 51341
        </aref>
        , Aug. 26, 2003]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='12' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.12
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Effect on other regulations; forms and instructions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Effect on other regulations.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All regulations, orders, or like directions heretofore issued by
            any officer of the Department which impose requirements designed to
            prohibit any discrimination against individuals on the ground of
            race, color, or national origin under any program to which the
            regulations in this part apply, and which authorize the suspension
            or termination of or refusal to grant or to continue Federal
            financial assistance to any applicant for or recipient of such
            assistance for failure to comply with such requirements, are hereby
            superseded to the extent that such discrimination is prohibited by
            the regulations in this part, except that nothing in the regulations
            in this part shall be deemed to relieve any person of any obligation
            assumed or imposed under any such superseded regulation, order,
            instruction, or like direction prior to the effective date of the
            regulations in this part. Nothing in these regulations, however,
            shall be deemed to supersede any of the following including future
            amendments thereof:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Executive Order 11246 and regulations issued thereunder; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Executive Order 11063 and regulations issued thereunder or any
            other regulations or instructions insofar as they prohibit
            discrimination on the ground of race, color, or national origin in
            any program or situation to which the regulations in this part are
            inapplicable, or prohibit discrimination on any other ground.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Forms and instructions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each Agency shall issue and promptly make available forms and such
            implementing instructions and procedures consistent with the
            regulations in this part as may be necessary. Each Agency in making
            available Federal financial assistance to any program or activity
            may utilize contractual commitments in obtaining compliance with the
            regulations in this part, including obtaining compliance by
            recipients other than the contracting recipient.
            <PRTPAGE P='413' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Supervision and coordination.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Secretary may from time to time assign to officials of other
            Departments or Agencies of the Government with the consent of such
            Department or Agency, responsibilities in connection with the
            effectuation of the purposes of title VI of the Act and the
            regulations in this part (other than responsibility for final
            decision as provided in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='15' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
                15.10
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) including the achievement of effective coordination and maximum
            uniformity within the Department and within the Executive Branch of
            the Government in the application of title VI and these regulations
            to similar programs and in similar situations. Any action taken,
            determination made, or requirement imposed by an official of another
            Department or Agency acting under this paragraph shall have the same
            effect as though such action had been taken by the Secretary or any
            Agency of this Department.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            29 FR 16274
          </aref>
          , Dec. 4, 1964, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            38 FR 17927
          </aref>
          , July 5, 1973; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            68 FR 51341
          </aref>
          , Aug. 26, 2003]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='543'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:C:15.60
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.60
      </num>
      <head>
        Scope of rules.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='60' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.60
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Scope of rules.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The rules of practice and procedure in this subpart supplement 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.9
            </subref>
             and 15.10 of
          </aref>
           subpart A of this part and govern the practice for hearings,
          decisions, and administrative review conducted by the Department of
          Agriculture, pursuant to title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964, 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            section 602
          </aref>
           (
          <aref target='_blank' href='http://frwebgate.access.gpo.gov/cgi-bin/getpage.cgi?dbname=88_statutes2_at_large&amp;position=all&amp;page=252'>
            78 Stat. 252
          </aref>
          ) and this part, title 7, CFR, except these rules shall not apply to
          any stage of a proceeding which has occurred prior to the effective
          date hereof.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='544'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:C:15.61
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.61
      </num>
      <head>
        Records to be public.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='61' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.61
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Records to be public.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          All documents and papers filed in any proceeding under this part may
          be inspected and copied in the Office of the Department Hearing Clerk.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='545'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:C:15.62
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.62
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='62' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.62
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          All terms used in this subpart shall, unless the context otherwise
          requires, have the same meaning as defined in subpart A of this part.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='546'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:C:15.63
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.63
      </num>
      <head>
        Computation of time.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='63' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.63
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Computation of time.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          A period of time begins with the day following the act or event and
          includes the last day of the period, unless it is a Saturday, Sunday,
          or legal holiday observed in the District of Columbia, in which case
          it shall be the following workday. When the period of time prescribed
          or allowed is less than 7 days, intermediate Saturdays, Sundays, and
          legal holidays shall be excluded from the computation.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='547'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:C:15.64
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.64
      </num>
      <head>
        Parties.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='64' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.64
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Parties.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The term 
          <E T='03'>
            party
          </E>
           shall include an applicant or recipient with respect to whom the
          agency has issued a notice of hearing or opportunity to request a
          hearing in accordance with subpart A of this part and 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='81' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.81
            </subref>
          </aref>
          . The agency shall be deemed a party to all proceedings.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='548'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:C:15.65
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.65
      </num>
      <head>
        Appearance.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='65' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.65
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Appearance.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Any party may appear in person or by counsel or authorized
          representative and participate fully in any proceeding.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='549'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:C:15.66
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.66
      </num>
      <head>
        Complainants not parties.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='66' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.66
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Complainants not parties.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          A person submitting a complaint pursuant to 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
           is not a party to the proceedings governed by this subpart, but may
          petition, after proceedings have been commenced, to become an
          intervener.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='550'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:C:15.67
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.67
      </num>
      <head>
        Intervener.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='67' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.67
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Intervener.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Any interested person or organization may file a petition to intervene
          which will include a statement of position and a statement of what
          petitioner expects to contribute to the hearing, and a copy of the
          petition will be served on all parties. Such petition should be filed
          prior to the prehearing conference, or if none is held, before the
          commencement of the hearing, unless the petitioner shows good cause
          for filing the petition later. The hearing officer may grant the
          petition if he believes that such participation will not unduly delay
          a hearing and will contribute materially to the proceeding. An
          intervener is not a party and may not introduce evidence at a hearing,
          or propound questions to a witness, unless the hearing officer
          determines that the proposed additional evidence is relevant and will
          clarify the facts. The intervener may submit and serve on all parties
          a brief in support or opposition to any brief of a party. All service
          and notice required by and upon a party shall apply to an intervener.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='551'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:C:15.68
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.68
      </num>
      <head>
        Ex parte communications.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='68' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.68
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          <E T='7462'>
            Ex parte
          </E>
           communications.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             After proceedings have been commenced, any communication or
            discussion 
            <E T='03'>
              ex parte,
            </E>
             as regards the merits of the proceeding or a factually related
            proceeding, between an employee of the Department involved in the
            decisional process and a person not employed by the Department, and
            any such communication or discussion between any employee of the
            Department, who is or has been engaged in any way in the
            investigation or prosecution of the proceeding or a factually
            related proceeding, and an employee of the Department who is
            involved or may be involved in the decisional process of a
            proceeding, except at a conference, hearing or review proceeding
            under these rules is improper and prohibited.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Request for information.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A request for information about the status of a 
            <PRTPAGE P='419' />
            proceeding without discussing issues or expressing points of view
            and inquiries with respect to procedural matters or an emergency
            request for an extension of time are not deemed 
            <E T='03'>
              ex parte
            </E>
             communications. When practical all parties should be notified of
            any request for an extension of time. Communication between an
            applicant or recipient and the agency or the Secretary with respect
            to securing voluntary compliance with any requirement of subpart A
            of this part is not prohibited.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Unsponsored written material.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Letters expressing views or urging action and other unsponsored
            written material regarding matters in issue in a proceeding will be
            placed in the correspondence section of the docket of the
            proceeding. Such are not deemed part of the evidence or record.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='552'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:C:15.71
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.71
      </num>
      <head>
        Form of documents to be filed.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='71' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.71
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Form of documents to be filed.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          All copies of documents filed in a proceeding shall be dated, signed
          in ink, shall show the address and position or title of the signatory,
          and shall show the docket number and title of the proceeding on the
          front page.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='553'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:C:15.72
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.72
      </num>
      <head>
        Filing.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='72' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.72
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Filing.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          All documents relating to a proceeding under this subpart shall be
          filed in an original and two copies of such document with the Office
          of the Hearing Clerk at Room 112, Administration Building, Department
          of Agriculture, Washington, D.C., 20250, during regular business
          hours. Regular business hours are every Monday through Friday (legal
          holidays in the District of Columbia excepted) from 9 a.m. to 5:30
          p.m., eastern standard or daylight saving time, whichever is effective
          in the District of Columbia at the time.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='554'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:C:15.73
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.73
      </num>
      <head>
        Service.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='73' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.73
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Service.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Service shall be made by the Hearing Clerk by personal delivery of one
          copy to each person to be served or by mailing by first-class mail, or
          air mail if more than 300 miles, properly addressed with postage
          prepaid. When a party or intervener has appeared by attorney or
          representative, service upon such attorney or representative will be
          deemed proper service. The initial notice of hearing, opportunity to
          request a hearing, or notice setting a date for a hearing shall be by
          certified mail, return receipt requested.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='555'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:C:15.74
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.74
      </num>
      <head>
        Date of service.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='74' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.74
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Date of service.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The date of service shall be the day when the matter is deposited in
          the U.S. mail or is delivered in person, except that the date of
          service of the initial notice a hearing or notice of opportunity to
          request a hearing or notice setting a date for a hearing shall be the
          date of its delivery, or of its attempted delivery if delivery is
          refused.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='556'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:C:15.81
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.81
      </num>
      <head>
        How proceedings are commenced.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='81' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.81
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          How proceedings are commenced.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Proceedings are commenced by mailing a notice to an applicant or
          recipient of alleged noncompliance with the Act and the
          Secretary&apos;s regulations thereunder. The notice will be signed by
          the interested agency head or by the Secretary and shall be filed with
          the hearing clerk for proper service by the hearing clerk according to
          the rules of this subpart. The notice shall include either a notice of
          hearing or notice of opportunity to request a hearing as determined by
          the Secretary and shall comply with the requirements of 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='9' psec='#a' tq='N'>
              15.9(a)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='557'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:C:15.82
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.82
      </num>
      <head>
        Notice of hearing and response thereto.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='82' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.82
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Notice of hearing and response thereto.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          A notice of hearing shall fix a date not less than 30 days from the
          date of service of the notice of a hearing on matters alleged in the
          notice. If the applicant or recipient does not desire a hearing, he
          should so state in writing, in which case the applicant or recipient
          shall have the right to submit written information and argument for
          the record, and the additional right to further participate in the
          proceeding. Failure to appear at the time set for a hearing, without
          good cause, shall be deemed a waiver of the right to a hearing under 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 602 of
          </aref>
           the Act and the regulations in this part and consent to the making of
          a decision on such information as is available which may be presented
          for the record.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='558'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:C:15.83
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.83
      </num>
      <head>
        Notice of opportunity to request a hearing and response thereto.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='420' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='83' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.83
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Notice of opportunity to request a hearing and response thereto.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          A notice of opportunity to request a hearing shall set a date not less
          than 20 days from service of said notice within which the applicant or
          recipient may file a request for a hearing, or may wiave a hearing and
          submit written information and argument for the record, in which case,
          the applicant or recipient shall have the right to further participate
          in the proceeding. When the applicant or recipient elects to file a
          request for a hearing, a time shall be set for the hearing at a date
          not less than 20 days from the date applicant or recipient is notified
          of the date set for the hearing. Failure of the applicant or recipient
          to request a hearing or to appear at the date set shall be deemed a
          waiver of the right to a hearing, under 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 602 of
          </aref>
           the Act and the regulations in this part and consent to the making of
          a decision on such information as is available which may be presented
          for the record.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='559'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:C:15.84
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.84
      </num>
      <head>
        Answer.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='84' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.84
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Answer.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          In any case covered by 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='82' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.82
            </subref>
          </aref>
           or 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='83' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.83
            </subref>
          </aref>
           the applicant or recipient shall file an answer. Said answer shall
          admit or deny each allegation of the notice, unless the applicant or
          recipient is without knowledge, in which case the answer shall so
          state, and the statement will be considered a denial. Failure to file
          an answer shall be deemed an admission of all allegations of fact in
          the notice. Allegations of fact in the notice not denied or
          controverted by answer shall be deemed admitted. Matters intended to
          be offered as affirmative defenses must be stated as a separate part
          of the answer. The answer under 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='82' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.82
            </subref>
          </aref>
           shall be filed within 20 days from the date of service of the notice
          of hearing. The answer under 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='83' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.83
            </subref>
          </aref>
           shall be filed within 20 days of service of the notice of opportunity
          to request a hearing.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='560'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:C:15.85
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.85
      </num>
      <head>
        Amendment of notice or answer.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='85' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.85
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Amendment of notice or answer.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The notice of hearing or notice of opportunity to request a hearing
          may be amended once as a matter of course before an answer thereto is
          served, and each applicant or recipient may amend his answer once as a
          matter of course not later than 10 days before the date fixed for
          hearing but in no event later than 20 days from the date of service of
          his original answer. Otherwise a notice or answer may be amended only
          by leave of the hearing officer. An applicant or recipient shall file
          his answer to an amended notice within the time remaining for filing
          the answer to the original notice or within 10 days after service of
          the amended notice, whichever period may be the longer, unless the
          hearing officer otherwise orders.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='561'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:C:15.86
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.86
      </num>
      <head>
        Consolidated or joint hearings.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='86' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.86
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Consolidated or joint hearings.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Two or more proceedings against the same respondent, or against
          different respondents in which the same or related facts are asserted
          to constitute noncompliance, may be consolidated for hearing or
          decision or both by the agency head, if he has the principal
          responsibility within the Department for the administration of all the
          laws extending the Federal financial assistance involved. If laws
          administered by more than one agency head are involved, such officials
          may by agreement order consolidation for hearing. The Secretary may
          order proceedings in the Department consolidated for hearing with
          proceedings in other Federal Departments or agencies, by agreement
          with such other Departments or agencies. All parties to any proceeding
          consolidated subsequently to service of the notice of hearing or
          notice of opportunity to request a hearing shall be promptly served
          with notice of such consolidation.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='562'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:C:15.91
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.91
      </num>
      <head>
        Who presides.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='91' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.91
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Who presides.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          A hearing officer shall preside over all proceedings held under this
          part. The hearing officer shall be a hearing examiner qualified under 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 11 of
          </aref>
           the Administrative Procedure Act (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='5' sect='1001' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/5/1001.html'>
              5 U.S.C. 1001
            </subref>
          </aref>
          <E T='03'>
            et seq.
          </E>
          ), and designated to hold hearings under the regulations in this
          subpart or any person authorized to hold a hearing and make a final
          decision. The hearing officer will serve until he has made an initial
          decision, certified the record to the Secretary, or made a final
          decision if so authorized.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='563'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:C:15.92
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.92
      </num>
      <head>
        Designation of hearing officer.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='421' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='92' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.92
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Designation of hearing officer.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Unless otherwise provided by an order of the Secretary at the time the
          notice of alleged noncompliance provided in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='81' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.81
            </subref>
          </aref>
           is filed with the Office of the Hearing Clerk, the hearing shall be
          held before a hearing examiner, who shall be appointed by the Chief
          Hearing Examiner, Office of Hearing Examiners within five days after
          the filing of such notice. Unless otherwise provided, the hearing
          examiner shall certify the entire record with his recommended findings
          and proposed decision to the Secretary for final decision.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='564'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:C:15.93
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.93
      </num>
      <head>
        Time and place of hearing.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='93' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.93
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Time and place of hearing.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          When a notice of hearing is sent to an applicant or recipient, the
          time and place of hearing shall be fixed by the Secretary, and when
          the applicant or recipient requests a hearing, the time and place
          shall be set by the hearing officer and in either case in conformity
          with 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='9' psec='#b' tq='N'>
              15.9(b)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          . The complainant, if any, shall be advised of the time and place of
          the hearing.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='565'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:C:15.94
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.94
      </num>
      <head>
        Disability of hearing officer.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='94' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.94
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Disability of hearing officer.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          In the case of death, illness, disqualification, or unavailability of
          the designated hearing officer, another hearing officer may be
          designated by the Secretary to take his place. If such death, illness,
          disqualification or unavailability occurs during the course of a
          hearing, the hearing will be either continued under a substitute
          hearing officer, or terminated and tried de novo in the discretion of
          the Secretary. In the absence of the designated hearing officer any
          hearing examiner may rule on motions and other interlocutory papers.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='566'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:C:15.95
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.95
      </num>
      <head>
        Responsibilities and duties of hearing officer.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='95' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.95
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Responsibilities and duties of hearing officer.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The hearing officer shall have the duty to conduct a fair hearing, to
          take all necessary action to avoid delay, and to maintain order. He
          shall have all powers necessary to these ends, including (but not
          limited to) the power to:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Arrange and issue notice of the date, time and place of hearings,
            or, upon due notice to the parties, to change the date, time and
            place of hearings previously set.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Hold conferences to settle, simplify, or fix the issues in a
            proceeding, or to consider other matters that may aid in the
            expeditious disposition of the proceeding.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Require parties and interveners to state their position with
            respect to the various issues in the proceeding.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Administer oaths and affirmations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Rule on motions, and other procedural items on matters pending
            before him.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Regulate the course of the hearing and conduct of parties therein.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Examine witnesses and direct witnesses to testify.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Receive, rule on, exclude or limit evidence.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Fix the time for filing motions, petitions, briefs, or other items
            in matters pending before him.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In accordance with his authority issue an initial decision, or
            recommended findings and proposed decision, or final decision.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Take any other action a hearing officer is authorized to take under
            these rules or subpart A of this part.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='567'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:C:15.101
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.101
      </num>
      <head>
        Form and content.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='101' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.101
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Form and content.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Motions shall state the relief sought and the authority relied
            upon. If made before or after the hearing, the motion shall be in
            writing and filed with the hearing clerk with a copy to all parties.
            If made at the hearing, they should be stated orally but the hearing
            officer may require that any motion be reduced to writing and filed
            and served on all parties in the same manner as a formal motion.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Extension of time or postponement.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A request for an extention of time should be filed and served on
            all parties and should set forth the reasons for the request and may
            be granted upon a showing of good cause. Answers to such requests
            are permitted, if made promptly.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='568'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:C:15.102
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.102
      </num>
      <head>
        Responses to motions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='102' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.102
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Responses to motions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Within 8 days or such reasonable time as may be fixed by the hearing
          officer, or Secretary, if the motion is properly addressed to him, any
          party 
          <PRTPAGE P='422' />
          may file a response to the motion, unless the motion is made at a
          hearing in which case an immediate response may be required. The
          hearing officer may dispose of motions at a prehearing conference.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='569'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:C:15.103
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.103
      </num>
      <head>
        Disposition of motions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='103' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.103
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Disposition of motions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The hearing officer may not sustain or grant a motion prior to
          expiration of the time for filing responses thereto, but may overrule
          or deny such motion without waiting on a response: 
          <E T='03'>
            Provided, however,
          </E>
           That prehearing conferences, hearings, and decisions need not be
          delayed pending disposition of motions. Oral motions may be ruled on
          immediately. Motions submitted to the hearing officer not disposed of
          in separate rulings or in his decision will be deemed denied. Oral
          argument shall not be held on written motions unless expressly
          ordered. Interlocutory appeals from rulings on motions shall be
          governed by 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='123' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.123
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='570'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:C:15.110
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.110
      </num>
      <head>
        Prehearing conferences.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='110' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.110
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Prehearing conferences.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In any case in which it appears that such procedure will expedite
            the proceeding, the hearing officer may, prior to the commencement
            of the hearing, request the parties to meet with him or to
            correspond with him regarding any of the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Simplification and clarification of the issues;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Necessity or desirability of amendments to the pleadings;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Stipulations, admissions of fact and of the contents and
            authenticity of documents;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Matters of which official notice will be taken;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Limitation of the number of experts or other witnesses;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Disposal of all motions; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Such other matters as may expedite and aid in the disposition of
            the proceeding.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The hearing officer shall enter in the record a written summary of
            the results of the conference or correspondence with the parties.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='571'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:C:15.111
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.111
      </num>
      <head>
        Purpose of hearing.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='111' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.111
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Purpose of hearing.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The hearing is directed to receiving factual evidence and expert
            opinion testimony related to the issues in the proceeding. Argument
            will not be received in evidence; rather it should be presented in
            statements, memoranda or briefs, as determined by the hearing
            officer. Brief opening statements, which shall be limited to a
            statement of the party&apos;s position and what he intends to prove,
            may also be made at hearings.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Hearings for the reception of evidence will be held only in cases
            where issues of fact must be resolved in order to determine whether
            the respondent has failed to comply with one or more applicable
            requirements of subpart A of this part. In any case where it appears
            from the answer of the applicant or recipient to the notice of
            hearing or notice of opportunity to request a hearing, from his
            failure timely to answer, or from his admissions or stipulations in
            the record that there are no matters of material fact in dispute,
            the hearing officer may enter an order so finding, and fixing the
            time for the submission of evidence by the Government for the
            record. Thereafter, the proceedings shall go to conclusion in
            accordance with subpart A of this part and the rules of this
            subpart. An appeal from such order may be allowed in accordance with
            the rules for interlocutory appeal in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='15' sect='123' psec='' tq='N'>
                15.123
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='572'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:C:15.112
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.112
      </num>
      <head>
        Statement of position and brief.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='112' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.112
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Statement of position and brief.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The hearing officer may require all parties and any intervener to file
          a written statement of position or brief prior to the beginning of a
          hearing.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='573'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:C:15.113
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.113
      </num>
      <head>
        Testimony.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='113' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.113
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Testimony.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Testimony shall be given orally under oath or affirmation by
            witnesses at the hearing, but the hearing officer, in his
            discretion, may require or permit that the testimony of any witness
            be prepared in writing and served on all parties in advance of the
            hearing. Such testimony may be adopted by the witness at the hearing
            and filed as part of the record thereof. Unless authorized by the
            hearing officer, witnesses will not be permitted to read prepared
            testimony into the record. Except as provided in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='15' sect='115' psec='' tq='N'>
                15.115
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='15' sect='116' psec='' tq='N'>
                15.116
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , witnesses shall be available at the hearing for cross-examination.
            <PRTPAGE P='423' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Proposed exhibits shall be exchanged either at a prehearing
            conference, or otherwise prior to the hearing. Proposed exhibits not
            so exchanged may be denied admission as evidence unless good cause
            is shown why they were not exchanged. The authenticity of all
            proposed exhibits exchanged prior to hearing will be deemed admitted
            unless written objection thereto is filed prior to the hearing or
            unless good cause is shown at the hearing for failure to file such
            written objection.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='574'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:C:15.115
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.115
      </num>
      <head>
        Affidavits.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='115' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.115
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Affidavits.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          An affidavit, intended to be used as evidence without
          cross-examination of the affiant, will be filed and served on the
          parties at least 15 days prior to the hearing; and not less than seven
          days prior to hearing a party may file and serve written objections to
          any affidavit on the ground that he believes it necessary to test the
          truth of assertions therein by cross-examination. In such event, the
          affidavit objected to will not be received in evidence unless the
          affiant is made available for cross-examination at the hearing or
          otherwise as prescribed by the hearing officer. In absence of an
          objection being filed within the time specified, such affidavit will
          be received in evidence.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='575'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:C:15.116
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.116
      </num>
      <head>
        Depositions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='116' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.116
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Depositions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Upon such terms as may be just, the hearing officer, in his
          discretion, may authorize the testimony of any witness to be taken by
          deposition.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='576'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:C:15.117
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.117
      </num>
      <head>
        Evidence.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='117' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.117
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Evidence.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Irrelevant, immaterial, unreliable, and unduly repetitious evidence
          will be excluded, and technical rules of evidence shall not apply but
          rules or principles designed to assure the most credible evidence
          available and to subject testimony to test by cross-examination shall
          apply.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='577'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:C:15.118
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.118
      </num>
      <head>
        Cross-examination.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='118' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.118
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Cross-examination.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Cross-examination will be limited to the scope of direct examination
          and matters at issue in the hearing.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='578'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:C:15.119
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.119
      </num>
      <head>
        Objections.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='119' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.119
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Objections.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Objections to evidence shall be timely and briefly state the ground
          relied upon. The ruling of the hearing officer will be part of the
          record. Argument in support of the objection will not be part of the
          record.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='579'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:C:15.120
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.120
      </num>
      <head>
        Exceptions to rulings of hearing officer unnecessary.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='120' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.120
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Exceptions to rulings of hearing officer unnecessary.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Exceptions to rulings of the hearing officer are unnecessary. It is
          sufficient that a party, at the time the ruling of the hearing officer
          is sought, makes known the action which he desires the hearing officer
          to take, or his objection to an action taken, and his grounds
          therefor.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='580'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:C:15.121
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.121
      </num>
      <head>
        Official notice.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='121' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.121
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Official notice.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          A public document, or part thereof, such as an official report
          decision, opinion, or published scientific or economic statistical
          data issued by any branch of the Federal or a State Government which
          has been shown to be reasonably available to the public, may be
          offered for official notice and accepted in the record without further
          proof of authenticity. Where official notice is to be taken, any
          party, on timely request, shall have an opportunity to show the
          contrary.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='581'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:C:15.122
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.122
      </num>
      <head>
        Offer of proof.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='122' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.122
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Offer of proof.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          An offer of proof made in connection with an objection taken to any
          ruling of the hearing officer rejecting or excluding proposed oral
          testimony shall consist of a statement for the record of the substance
          of the evidence which counsel contends would be adduced by such
          testimony; and, if the excluded evidence consists of evidence in
          documentary or written form or of reference to documents or records, a
          copy of such evidence shall be marked for identification and shall
          accompany the record as an offer of proof.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='582'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:C:15.123
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.123
      </num>
      <head>
        Appeals from ruling of hearing officer.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='123' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.123
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Appeals from ruling of hearing officer.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          A ruling of the hearing officer may not be appealed to the Secretary
          prior to consideration of the entire proceeding by the hearing officer
          except with the consent of the hearing officer and where he certifies
          on the record or in writing that the allowance of an interlocutory
          appeal is clearly necessary to prevent exceptional delay, expense, or
          prejudice to any part or substantial 
          <PRTPAGE P='424' />
          detriment to the public interest. If an appeal is allowed, any party
          may file a brief with the Secretary within such period as the hearing
          officer directs. Oral argument will be heard in the discretion of the
          Secretary.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='583'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:C:15.124
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.124
      </num>
      <head>
        Admissions as to facts and documents.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          31 FR 8586
        </aref>
        , June 21, 1966]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='124' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.124
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Admissions as to facts and documents.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Not later than 15 days prior to the scheduled date of the hearing
          except for good cause shown, or prior to such earlier date as the
          hearing officer may order, any party may serve upon an opposing party
          a written request for the admission of the genuineness and
          authenticity of any relevant documents described in and exhibited with
          the request, or for the admission of the truth of any relevant matters
          of fact stated in the request. Each of the matters of which an
          admission is requested shall be deemed admitted, unless within a
          period designated in the request (not less than 10 days after service
          thereof, or within such further time as the hearing officer may allow
          upon motion and notice) the party to whom the request is directed
          serves upon the requesting party a sworn statement either denying
          specifically the matters of which an admission is requested or setting
          forth in detail the reasons why he cannot truthfully either admit or
          deny such matters. Copies of requests for admission and answers
          thereto shall be served on all parties. Any admission made by a party
          to such request is only for the purposes of the pending proceeding, or
          any proceeding or action instituted for the enforcement of any order
          entered therein, and shall not constitute an admission by him for any
          other purpose or be used against him in any other proceeding or
          action.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            31 FR 8586
          </aref>
          , June 21, 1966]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='584'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:C:15.131
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.131
      </num>
      <head>
        Official transcript.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='131' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.131
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Official transcript.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The hearing clerk will designate the official reporter for all
          hearings. The official transcript of testimony taken, together with
          any affidavits, exhibits, depositions, briefs, or memoranda of law
          shall be filed with the hearing clerk. Transcripts of testimony in
          hearings will be supplied by the official reporter to the parties and
          to the public at rates not to exceed the maximum rates fixed by the
          contract between the Department and the reporter. Upon notice to all
          parties, the hearing officer may authorize corrections to the
          transcript which involve matters of substance.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='585'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:C:15.132
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.132
      </num>
      <head>
        Record for decision.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='132' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.132
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Record for decision.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The transcript of testimony, exhibits, affidavits, depositions,
          briefs, memoranda of law, and all pleadings, motions, papers, and
          requests filed in the proceeding, except the correspondence section of
          the docket, including rulings, and any recommended findings and
          proposed decision, or initial decision shall constitute the exclusive
          record for final decision.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='586'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:C:15.135
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.135
      </num>
      <head>
        Posthearing briefs.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='135' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.135
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Posthearing briefs.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The hearing officer shall fix a reasonable time for filing posthearing
          briefs, which may contain proposed findings of fact and conclusions of
          law, and, if permitted, reply briefs. Briefs should include a summary
          of the evidence relied upon together with references to exhibit
          numbers and pages of the transcript, with citations of the authorities
          relied upon. Briefs shall be filed in the Office of the Hearing Clerk
          with a copy to all parties.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='587'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:C:15.136
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.136
      </num>
      <head>
        Decisions and notices.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='136' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.136
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Decisions and notices.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          When the time for submission of posthearing briefs has expired the
          hearing officer shall either make an initial decision or final
          decision, if so authorized, or certify the entire record including his
          recommended findings and proposed decision to the Secretary for a
          final decision and a copy of such initial, or final decision or
          certification shall be mailed to the applicant or recipient and other
          parties by the hearing clerk.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='588'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:C:15.137
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.137
      </num>
      <head>
        Exceptions to initial or proposed decision.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='137' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.137
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Exceptions to initial or proposed decision.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Within 30 days of the mailing of such notice of initial or recommended
          findings and proposed decision, the applicant or recipient and other
          parties may file with the hearing clerk for consideration by the
          Secretary exceptions to 
          <PRTPAGE P='425' />
          the initial or recommended findings and proposed decision, with
          reasons therefor. Each party will be given reasonable opportunity to
          file briefs or other written statements of contentions in which the
          party may request that the decision be modified, reversed, affirmed or
          adopted.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='589'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:C:15.138
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.138
      </num>
      <head>
        Review of initial decision.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='138' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.138
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Review of initial decision.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          In the absence of exceptions to an initial decision, the Secretary may
          on his own motion within 45 days after an initial decision serve upon
          the parties a notice that he will review the decision and will give
          the parties reasonable opportunity to file briefs or other written
          statements of contentions. At the expiration of said time for filing
          briefs, the Secretary will review the initial decision and issue a
          final decision thereon. In the absence of either exceptions to an
          initial decision or a notice or review, the initial decision shall
          constitute the final decision of the Secretary.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='590'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:C:15.139
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.139
      </num>
      <head>
        Oral argument.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='139' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.139
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Oral argument.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          If any party desires to argue orally before the Secretary on the
          review of recommended findings and proposed decision, or an initial
          decision, he shall so state at the time he files his exceptions or
          brief. The Secretary may grant such request in his discretion. If
          granted, he will serve notice of oral argument on all parties and will
          set forth the order of presentation and the amount of time allotted,
          and the time and place of argument.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='591'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:C:15.140
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.140
      </num>
      <head>
        Service of decisions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='140' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.140
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Service of decisions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          All final decisions shall be promptly served on all parties and the
          complainant.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='592'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:C:15.141
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.141
      </num>
      <head>
        Contents of decision.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='141' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.141
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Contents of decision.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Each decision of a hearing officer shall set forth his ruling on each
          finding, conclusion, or exception presented, and shall identify the
          requirement or requirements imposed by or pursuant to the regulations
          in this part with which it is found that the applicant or recipient
          has failed to comply.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='593'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:C:15.142
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.142
      </num>
      <head>
        Content of orders.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='142' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.142
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Content of orders.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The final decision may provide for suspension or termination of, or
          refusal to grant or continue Federal financial assistance, in whole or
          in part, under the program involved, and may contain such terms,
          conditions, and other provisions as are consistent with and will
          effectuate the purposes of the Act and the regulations in this part,
          including provisions designed to assure that no Federal financial
          assistance will thereafter be extended under such program to the
          applicant or recipient determined by such decision to be in default in
          its performance of an assurance given by it pursuant to the
          regulations in this part, or to have otherwise failed to comply with
          the regulations in this part, unless and until it corrects its
          noncompliance and satisfies the Agency that it will fully comply with
          the regulations in this part.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='594'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:15:C:15.143
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        15.143
      </num>
      <head>
        Decision where financial assistance affected.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='15' sect='143' psec='' tq='N'>
              15.143
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Decision where financial assistance affected.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The Secretary shall make any final decision which provides for the
          suspension or termination of, or the refusal to grant or continue
          Federal financial assistance, or the imposition of any other sanction
          available under the regulations in this part or the Act.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>