<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol12'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:A:1806
    </extid>
    <num>
      1806
    </num>
    <head>
      INSURANCE
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='5' sect='301' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/5/301.html'>
              5 U.S.C. 301
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='1989' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1989.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 1989
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='42' sect='1480' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/42/1480.html'>
              42 U.S.C. 1480
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </AUTH>
    </text>
    <section orderid='14802'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:A:1806:A:1806.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1806.1
      </num>
      <head>
        General.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          41 FR 34571
        </aref>
        , Aug. 16, 1976, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          61 FR 59777
        </aref>
        , Nov. 22, 1996; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          72 FR 64121
        </aref>
        , Nov. 15, 2007]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1806' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              1806.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Authority.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This subpart sets forth the policies and procedures regarding
            insurance requirements on real property which serves as security for
            a debt under the Multi-Family Housing Programs of the Rural Housing
            Service (RHS). Any references herein to the Farmers Home
            Administration (FmHA) or its employees are intended to mean FSA or
            RHS, as applicable, and their employees. This subpart is
            inapplicable to Farm Service Agency, Farm Loan Programs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Borrower to furnish insurance.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The real estate mortgage executed by the borrower provides that he
            will furnish and continually maintain and pay for insurance on
            buildings situated or constructed on the property with companies, in
            amounts, and on terms and conditions satisfactory to the FmHA or its
            successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             until the loan is repaid.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Borrower&apos;s selection of company.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The borrower may select the insurance company provided that the
            company and insurance policy comply with all the requirements set
            forth in this Instruction.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Responsibility.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The County Supervisor is responsible for taking all actions in
            connection with insurance as may be necessary to protect the
            security interest of the FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
            . Any unusual situation that may arise with respect to obtaining or
            servicing insurance should be referred to the State Director. The
            State Director will refer any questions of a legal nature to the
            Office of the General Counsel (OGC).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Use of Form FmHA or its successor agency under 
              <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
                Public Law 103-354
              </aref>
               426-1, “Valuations of Buildings.”
            </E>
             The minimum insurance required will be indicated in the appraisal
            report by the employee who makes the appraisal of property that
            includes insurable buildings. In the case where no real estate
            appraisal is required or the appraisal report does not indicate the
            minimum insurance coverage, Form FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             426-1 will be prepared by the County Supervisor. Reevaluation of
            the buildings will not be done on appraisal reports; however, when
            new buildings are constructed or values increase or decrease
            materially and reevaluation is necessary to properly reflect the
            buildings&apos; security interest of the FmHA or its successor
            agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
            , the County Supervisor will prepare or revise Form FmHA or its
            successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             426-1 as appropriate. Changes made on 
            <PRTPAGE P='422' />
            an existing Form FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             426-1 will be dated and initialed. The reason for any deletion will
            be noted on the Form.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            41 FR 34571
          </aref>
          , Aug. 16, 1976, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            61 FR 59777
          </aref>
          , Nov. 22, 1996; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            72 FR 64121
          </aref>
          , Nov. 15, 2007]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14803'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:A:1806:A:1806.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1806.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Companies and policies.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          41 FR 34571
        </aref>
        , Aug. 16, 1976, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          41 FR 49990
        </aref>
        , Nov. 12, 1976; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          42 FR 33262
        </aref>
        , June 30, 1977; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          43 FR 56013
        </aref>
        , Nov. 30, 1978; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          44 FR 45115
        </aref>
        , Aug. 1, 1979; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          51 FR 17921
        </aref>
        , May 16, 1986; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          54 FR 35869
        </aref>
        , Aug. 30, 1989; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          56 FR 6945
        </aref>
        , Feb. 21, 1991]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1806' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              1806.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Companies and policies.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Property insurance policies or other evidence of insurance will be
          accepted from borrowers when the requirements outlined herein are
          complied with fully.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Companies.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             It is desirable that companies be licensed to do business in the
            particular State or other jurisdiction where the property is
            located, or that they be otherwise authorized by law to transact
            business within such State or other jurisdiction (hereinafter called
            “State”). If the required insurance is not available locally at
            comparable rates from an insurance company licensed or otherwise
            authorized to do business in the State, insurance may be accepted
            from another company if (1) the OGC advises that policies issued by
            such company will not be rendered unenforceable by virtue of the
            company&apos;s failure to be licensed or otherwise authorized to
            transact business in the State and that the company is a legal
            entity which may be sued in the State where the insured property is
            located, and (2) the State Director determines that the company is
            reputable and financially sound. In making the above determinations,
            the State Director will consider all relevant available information
            such as that which may be obtained from financial statements,
            Best&apos;s Insurance Reports, State insurance authorities, and
            other lending institutions.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Insurance policies—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Standard policies.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a standard fire insurance policy has been adopted for the State,
            it should be used unless State statutes exempt the company from the
            regulations requiring its use. The standard policy is one containing
            substantially the same standard provisions adopted or recommended by
            legislative action or by order of the supervisory insurance
            authorities of the State in which the security is located.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Other policies.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be acceptable, any other insurance policies must conform to the
            requirements of this Instruction.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             “Homeowner&apos;s” policies, “All Physical Loss” policies, “Broad
            Form” policies, and other such all-inclusive policies are acceptable
            if they otherwise meet the requirements of this Instruction.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A builder&apos;s risk policy naming the borrower as the insured or
            a builder&apos;s risk endorsement for a policy issued to the
            borrower may be accepted during the period a building is under
            construction if the policy otherwise meets the requirements of this
            Instruction. If such a policy or endorsement does not automatically
            convert to full coverage when the building is completed, acceptable
            insurance must be obtained simultaneously with the expiration of the
            builder&apos;s isk provisions of the policy.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A builder&apos;s risk insurance policy issued to a contractor only
            may not be substituted for the property insurance, the borrower is
            required to provide.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Borrowers eligible for insurance under the National Flood Insurance
            Act of 1968, as amended by the Flood Disaster Act of 1973, will be
            serviced in accordance with subpart B of this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              State instructions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the State Director and the OGC consider it advisable, a State
            Instruction may be issued to help County Supervisors identify
            standard insurance policies adopted for the State. The Instruction
            should also furnish a guide to assist in identifying other
            acceptable insurance policy forms that are commonly used by
            insurance companies in the State, recognizing that such information
            is not all inclusive.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Binders.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whenever there is a justifiable reason for not issuing a policy or
            endorsement, as required, a written binder will be acceptable for a
            period not to exceed 60 days from the effective date of the
            insurance. The written binder must have attached thereto the
            approved form of mortgage clause. Such a binder will be submitted to
            the County Supervisor in lieu of an insurance policy or endorsement
            and the insurance policy or endorsement will be submitted on or
            before the expiration date of the binder. The State Director, 
            <PRTPAGE P='423' />
            with the advice of the OGC and subject to prior approval of the
            National Office, may issue a State Instruction authorizing such
            binders to be accepted for periods longer than 60 days.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Submission of policies.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_5_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For Farmer Program (FP) loans secured by a first lien, the original
            policy or declaration page must be delivered to the County
            Supervisor. The original policy or declaration page will be returned
            to the borrower after one year using Form FmHA or its successor
            agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             426-4, “Notice of Expiration of Insurance.”
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_5_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For Single Family Housing (SFH) loans secured by a first lien, the
            original policy or declaration page must be delivered to the closing
            agent.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_5_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In cases where an FP or SFH loan is secured by other than a first
            lien and the mortgage clauses include the names of the prior
            mortgagees, a certificate of insurance, copy of the policy, or other
            evidence of insurance is acceptable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_5_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The County Supervisor will process an advance to pay for insurance
            only in strict compliance with provisions of 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              § 1806.6 of
            </aref>
             this subpart.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Master sets.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the master sets meet all of the requirements of this Instruction
            they may be accepted in lieu of an original policy for each FmHA or
            its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             borrower.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_6_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             One complete master set of the different insurance forms for
            policies issued by the insurance company must be on file in each
            County Office where the company insures property of FmHA or its
            successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             borrowers.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_6_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The “Declaration Page” furnished by the insurance company for each
            borrower insured, in lieu of a complete policy, will be filed in the
            borrower&apos;s case folder. When a “Declaration Page” in the form
            of a computer printout is used by an insurance company an
            endorsement on every policy issued by that company or a letter from
            that company will be obtained and attached to the printout. However,
            a letter signed by an authorized official of the company and
            addressed to the State Director may cover all policies issued by
            that company in the State. Any such endorsements or letters should
            clearly state that the company considers the printout to be an
            original “Declaration Page”. Such endorsements or letters are not
            necessary if the printout itself clearly states that it is an
            original “Declaration Page.”
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Name and location.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The policy should contain names of all the borrowers who are owners
            of the property being insured, and it will be returned for
            correction if it does not do so. The location of the property should
            be so described in the policy that the property can easily be
            identified. The complete legal description of the property by metes
            and bounds is not required. Any deviation from the requirements of
            this paragraph must first be cleared with the National Office.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Loss or damage covered.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Buildings must be insured against loss or damage by fire,
            lightning, windstorm, hail, explosion, riot, civil commotion,
            aircraft, vehicles, and smoke.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Effective date of insurance.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If there are insurable buildings located on the property, the
            borrower will arrange with his agent or company to have adequate
            insurance in force at the time the loan, assumption, or credit sale
            is closed so that the policy will properly insure the borrower and
            the mortgagees. When new buildings are erected or major improvements
            are made to existing buildings, such insurance will be made
            effective as of the date materials are delivered to the property.
            The County Supervisor will make no payments from loan funds for
            labor or materials until the borrower has furnished adequate
            insurance to protect the interest of the FmHA or its successor
            agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             in the buildings being erected or improved.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Term.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The borrower will be required to furnish insurance for a term of at
            least one year with evidence that a full year&apos;s premium is
            paid. The term “premium” as used herein includes any assessments
            which may be charged to the borrower. If the assessments are of the
            type imposed only after a loss occurs involving property insured by
            the insurance company, then the borrower must present evidence (such
            as a letter from the company) that he currently does not owe any
            such assessments. The borrower may receive a discount for insuring
            for a longer period such as 
            <PRTPAGE P='424' />
            three years or five years and with an annual premium. If the
            insurance contains an automatic renewal clause, its provision should
            be substantially the following to be acceptable to FmHA or its
            successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
            : 
          </text>
        </P>
        <EXTRACT>
          <FP>
            This policy will be automatically extended for successive terms at
            expiration of the original term and of each extension thereof, upon
            payment of renewal premiums. It is a condition of this policy that
            if the policy expires or is canceled for nonpayment of premium, or
            for any other reason, the mortgagee will be given 10 days notice.
          </FP>
        </EXTRACT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_11'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (11)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Mortgage clause.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The standard mortgage clause adopted by the State must be attached
            to or printed in the policy, or Form FmHA or its successor agency
            under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             426-2, “Property Insurance Mortgage Clause (Without Contribution),”
            must be attached to or the provisions thereof printed in the policy.
            A letter signed by an authorized official of an insurance company to
            the State Director, stating that all insurance policies the company
            issues in the State and in which the FmHA or its successor agency
            under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             has a mortgage interest incorporates all of the provisions of Form
            FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             426-2 may be accepted in lieu of attaching Form FmHA or its
            successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             426-2 to each policy. If such a blanket letter is used, the FmHA or
            its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             will be named in the loss payable clause and a State Instruction
            will be issued, after prior approval is obtained from the National
            Office, authorizing the use of such method.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_11_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the use of a mortgage clause, other than the standard mortgage
            clause (without contribution), has been made mandatory by State laws
            or insurance regulations, a State Instruction will be issued, after
            prior approval is obtained from the National Office, authorizing the
            use of such a form.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_11_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When an approved mortgage clause is printed in the policy a “Loss
            Payable Clause” is acceptable provided the FmHA or its successor
            agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
            , as mortgagee, would receive payment in case of loss even though
            the company would not be liable to the borrower. A “Loss Payable
            Clause” which contains the statement that the mortgagee is “subject
            to all terms and conditions of the policy” is not acceptable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_11_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whenever a new mortgage clause including the interest of the FmHA
            or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             is issued after the policy has been in force, the new mortgage
            clause must be signed by an authorized agent or officer of the
            company that issued the policy. Form FmHA or its successor agency
            under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             426-6, “Transmittal of Property Insurance Mortgage Clause,” may be
            used to transmit the mortgage clause to the insurance official.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_11_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             and all other mortgagees whose interests are insured by the policy
            will be shown either in the mortgage clause or in the “Declaration
            Page” in the order of priority of their mortgages.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='b_11_iv_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             “United States of America (Farmers Home Administration or its
            successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
            )” will be named in the mortgage clause for direct and insured loan
            mortgages naming FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             as mortgagee, whether in its own right or as trustee under a 2(f)
            or other agreement with a State Rural Rehabilitation Corporation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='b_11_iv_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             “United States of America (Farmers Home Administration or its
            successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
            ), as first mortgagee or as statutory agent and insurer of such
            mortgagee,” will be named in the mortgage clause for insured FO
            mortgages naming the lender as mortgagee, whether the mortgage is
            held by the original or a subsequent lender or by the insurance fund
            or by FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             under a trust agreement or declaration of trust.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='b_11_iv_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the designation is not identical to that set forth in paragraphs
            (b)(11)(iv)(A) or (B) of this section, whichever is applicable, it
            will be sufficient if the mortgagee is readily identifiable as the
            Farmers Home Administration or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
            .
            <PRTPAGE P='425' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Evidence of premium payment.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When Form FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             426-2 is attached to or the provisions thereof are printed in the
            policy, or a blanket letter from an insurance company incorporating
            the provisions of Form FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             426-2 in all policies in which the FmHA or its successor agency
            under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             has a mortgagee interest in effect, in accordance with paragraph
            (b)(11) of this section, no evidence of premium or assessment
            payment is required except for the first year of the loan. When a
            subsequent FP or 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 502
            </aref>
             RH loan is made to build, buy or rehabilitate essential buildings
            an endorsement to the existing policy including coverage for the
            property improved will be sufficient.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             [Reserved]
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Policy restrictions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any insurance on essential buildings as defined in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1806' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
                1806.3
              </subref>
            </aref>
             having restrictions which limit the amount of collectible insurance
            must meet the FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             requirements set forth below (except for the clause described in
            paragraph (d)(1)(iv) of this section which is never acceptable);
            otherwise, such restrictions must be eliminated or modified to
            afford the required protection.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Coinsurance clause.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This clause generally provides that in consideration of a reduced
            rate, the borrower agrees to maintain insurance on his buildings up
            to a specified percentage (usually 80 percent) of their value and
            that the company will not be liable for a greater proportion of any
            partial loss than the amount of insurance bears to the specified
            percentage of either the undepreciated replacement value or the
            depreciated replacement value or the depreciated replacement value
            (actual cash value) of the buildings at the time of the loss. When
            the buildings are insured for the specified percentage of their
            value, the company, in the event of a partial loss, will be liable
            for the full amount of the loss not to exceed the amount of
            insurance. A coinsurance clause can be accepted only where the
            amount of insurance is at least equal to the specified percentage of
            either the undepreciated replacement value or the depreciated
            replacement value (actual cash value). For example, an 80 percent
            coinsurance clause can be accepted only where the amount of
            insurance on each insured building is at least equal to 80 percent
            of the appropriate replacement value of the insured building.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Three-fourths&apos; value clause.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This clause provides that the liability of the company shall be
            limited to three-fourths of the depreciated replacement value of the
            buildings covered at the time of the loss, not to exceed the amount
            of insurance. This clause may be accepted if the unpaid balance of
            the loan is not greater than three-fourths of the depreciated
            replacement value of the building and the amount of insurance is at
            least equal to the unpaid balance of the loan and any prior liens
            and no building is insured for more than three-fourths of its
            depreciated replacement value.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Loss deductible clause.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='d_1_iii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For all loans other than RRH, RCH, and LH organizations this clause
            generally provides that loss to each building to the extent of the
            limitation is not recoverable. The company is liable only for loss
            to each building in excess of such limitation stated in the clause.
            This clause may be accepted where the limitation does not exceed
            $150, or one percent of the insurance coverage whichever is greater.
            In no case, however, may the limitation on any one building exceed
            $500.00.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='d_1_iii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For RRH, RCH, and LH organization loans this clause generally
            provides that loss to each project to the extent of the limitation
            is not recoverable. The company is liable only for loss to each
            project in excess of such limitation stated in the clause. This
            clause may be accepted where the limitation does not exceed the
            option shown below that is chosen by the borrower and agreed to by
            the Loan Approving Official and properly annotated in the borrower
            file. The borrower and FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             Official should consider the economic impact to the project when
            selecting the appropriate option.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          (
          <E T='03'>
            1
          </E>
          ) Option 1—Up to one-fourth of one percent (0.0025) of the insurable
          value. Maximum deductible $5,000.
          <PRTPAGE P='426' />
        </P>
        <P>
          (
          <E T='03'>
            2
          </E>
          ) Option 2—Up to a maximum deductible of $500 on any project with an
          insurable value not exceeding $200,000.
        </P>
        <P>
          (
          <E T='03'>
            3
          </E>
          ) Option 3—Option 1 may be chosen and increased above the maximum
          deductible by an amount equivalent to funds specifically escrowed in
          the project replacement reserve account as an offset to the increased
          deductible.
        </P>
        <P>
          (
          <E T='03'>
            4
          </E>
          ) Option 4—Option 2 may be chosen and increased above the maximum
          deductible by an amount equivalent to funds specifically escrowed in
          the project replacement reserve account as an offset to the increased
          deductible.
        </P>
        <P>
          (
          <E T='03'>
            5
          </E>
          ) The funds used to increase the deductible in Option 3 or Option 4
          may be from project funds if it does not create an unsecure financial
          situation for the project. Also, non-project funds may be used for
          Option 3 or 4 and then repaid by withdrawal from the project at the
          rate of 75 percent of the annual insurance premium savings earned by
          the amount of escrow deposit, up to the amount deposited.
        </P>
        <P>
          (
          <E T='03'>
            6
          </E>
          ) The funds escrowed to increase the authorized deductible will be
          placed in the project reserve account as an increased amount in and
          above the amount required by the Loan Agreement/Resolution and so
          annotated in the borrower&apos;s accounting system.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Three-fourths&apos; loss clause.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This clause provides that the company will not pay more than
            three-fourths of any loss, nor more than three-fourths of the amount
            of insurance in force. This clause is never acceptable and must be
            eliminated.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Deferred loss payable clause.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This clause provides that, if the amount payable under the policy
            for any loss to any building insured shall be in excess of a
            specified portion, (usually 60 percent) of the amount of insurance
            on such building, the company will withhold from its initial loss
            payment any sum in excess of the specified portion of the amount of
            insurance on such building. If the building sustaining such loss is
            repaired or replaced within six months from the date of the fire and
            at or within 300 feet of the original location, as described in the
            policy, the company upon receipt of evidence to that effect from the
            insured will pay the full balance withheld from the initial payment,
            provided the amount expended in repairing or replacing the building
            damaged or destroyed will equal or exceed the amount of loss as
            determined under the terms of the policy. Failure to repair or
            replace any insured building within the time and manner provided
            will constitute acceptance of the initial payment as full and final
            settlement under the policy with respect to the loss. This clause
            may be accepted if the amount of insurance is for the full
            depreciated replacement value (actual cash value) of the building
            and the unpaid balance of the loan and any prior lien(s) is not
            greater than the initial loss payment made by the company.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Construction specifications and use conditions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the insurance policy contains clauses which specify certain
            standards of construction or prescribes certain uses of the property
            for the insurance to be valid, the policy is acceptable only if the
            property meets such specifications or conditions at the time of
            acceptance. For example, if the policy provides that the chimney be
            constructed of a certain type of material, the County Supervisor
            should be assured that the required material has been used, or if
            the policy provides that farming operations are not carried out on
            the premises he should be assured that this condition is met.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Policies generally will not be accepted if, under the terms of the
            policies or local laws, contributions or assessments may be made
            against the FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
            . However, policies which impose assessments on the borrower may be
            accepted only if the FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             mortgage will be recorded prior to any failure of the borrower to
            pay any such assessments. Policies also will not be accepted if, by
            their terms or other conditions, loss payments are contingent upon
            collective action by the Board of Directors, or the stockholders, or
            the members.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Buildings on leaseholds.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The policy will indicate that the insured is the lessee or tenant
            and not the owner of the buildings securing the FmHA or its
            successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             loan; or, if he is the owner of the building on the leased land,
            the policy will indicate that the insured is the 
            <PRTPAGE P='427' />
            owner of the building, but not of the land. State Directors, with
            the advice of the OGC will issue State Instructions to meet any
            other special requirements needed to conform with the insurance
            requirements of the State to enable leaseholders to obtain property
            insurance for buildings which are security for FmHA or its successor
            agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             loans.
          </text>
        </P>
        <SECAUTH>
          (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='1989' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1989.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 1989
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='42' sect='1480' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/42/1480.html'>
              42 U.S.C. 1480
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='40' sect='442' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/40/442.html'>
              40 U.S.C. 442
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='42' sect='1480' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/42/1480.html'>
              42 U.S.C. 1480
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='42' sect='2942' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/42/2942.html'>
              42 U.S.C. 2942
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='5' sect='301' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/5/301.html'>
              5 U.S.C. 301
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            Sec. 10
          </aref>
          <aref target='_blank' title='Pub. L. 93-357' alt='Pub. L. 93-357' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d93:./list/bd/d93pl.lst:357%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Pub. L. 93-357
          </aref>
          , 
          <aref target='_blank' href='http://frwebgate.access.gpo.gov/cgi-bin/getpage.cgi?dbname=93_statutes2_at_large&amp;position=all&amp;page=392'>
            88 Stat. 392
          </aref>
          ; delegation of authority by the Secretary of Agriculture, 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR 
            <subref title='7' part='2' sect='23' psec='' tq='N'>
              2.23
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; delegation of authority by the Assistant Secretary for Rural
          Development, 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR 
            <subref title='7' part='2' sect='70' psec='' tq='N'>
              2.70
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; delegations of authority by Director, OEO, 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            29 FR 14764, 33
          </aref>
           FR 9850)
        </SECAUTH>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            41 FR 34571
          </aref>
          , Aug. 16, 1976, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            41 FR 49990
          </aref>
          , Nov. 12, 1976; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            42 FR 33262
          </aref>
          , June 30, 1977; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            43 FR 56013
          </aref>
          , Nov. 30, 1978; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            44 FR 45115
          </aref>
          , Aug. 1, 1979; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            51 FR 17921
          </aref>
          , May 16, 1986; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            54 FR 35869
          </aref>
          , Aug. 30, 1989; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            56 FR 6945
          </aref>
          , Feb. 21, 1991]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14804'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:A:1806:A:1806.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1806.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Coverage requirements.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          41 FR 34571
        </aref>
        , Aug. 16, 1976, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          56 FR 6945
        </aref>
        , Feb. 21, 1991]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1806' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              1806.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Coverage requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The County Supervisor should encourage the borrower for his own
          protection to insure for their depreciated replacement value (actual
          cash value) all essential buildings. Essential buildings include the
          dwelling and any other buildings that are necessary for the operation
          of the property or that provide income to assure orderly repayment of
          the loan. If insurance is for less than the depreciated replacement
          value of all essential buildings, the County Supervisor will see that
          the coverage is obtained on one or more of the most essential
          buildings. The minimum amount of coverage will be furnished as
          prescribed below:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Loans secured by a first lien.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When the unpaid balance of the FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             loan secured by a first lien is equal to or greater than the
            depreciated replacement value of the essential buildings, or the
            cost of adequate essential buildings which can be constructed for
            amounts less than the depreciated replacement value of the existing
            buildings, the essential buildings will be insured, to the nearest
            multiple of insurance that is available, for the lesser of (i) their
            depreciated replacement value, or (ii) the cost of constructing
            adequate essential buildings. For example, if insurance is available
            in only multiples of $1,000, the minimum insurance required on an
            essential building valued at $6,600 would be $7,000, and that
            required on an essential building valued at $6,400 would be $6,000.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When the unpaid balance of the loan is less than the sum of the
            depreciated replacement value of the essential buildings to be
            insured, the total amount of insurance must be at least equal to the
            lesser of (i) the unpaid balance of the loan, or (ii) the cost of
            adequate essential buildings which can be constructed for amounts
            less than the depreciated replacement value of the existing
            buildings to be insured.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When, by the use of loan funds or otherwise, buildings are erected
            or substantial improvements are made to essential buildings, the
            amount of insurance will be adjusted in accordance with paragraphs
            (a)(1) or (2) of this section, whichever is applicable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Loans secured by other than first liens.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The amount of insurance on buildings in the case of FmHA or its
            successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             loans secured by other than a first lien will be the same as
            required in paragraph (a) of this section, with the understanding
            that the unpaid balance of the loan will be deemed for this purpose
            to be the amount of the total real estate mortgage indebtedness owed
            all prior mortgagees named in the mortgage clause, plus the debt to
            the FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             which is secured by real estate mortgage.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Exception of buildings from insurance.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Insurance will not be required on a building:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             That is not essential.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In such a state of disrepair that the cost of insurance would be
            prohibitive.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Which has a depreciated replacement value of $2,500 or less.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Which is being or has been repaired with a 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 504
            </aref>
             loan of $7,500 or less. Families receiving 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 504
            </aref>
             loans should be encouraged but not required to carry insurance on
            their home.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             On LH security property which was not built or repaired with FmHA
            or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             loan funds provided that the State Director determines that the 
            <PRTPAGE P='428' />
            land and other structures adequately secure the FmHA or its
            successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             loan and any prior liens.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             On which the hazards are so slight because of the character and
            construction of the building, or the cost of the insurance is so
            high in comparison with the value of the building that, according to
            common standards of judgment, it should not be insured, including
            but not limited to windmills, silos, and fire-cured tobacco barns.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_vii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In cases where the unpaid balance of the FmHA or its successor
            agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             loans and any prior liens have been reduced to $2,500 or less,
            property insurance need not be required if the borrower wants to
            discontinue it, provided the County Supervisor determines that the
            value of the land security itself is sufficient to protect the FmHA
            or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             in its collection of the amount of the outstanding indebtedness.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_viii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (viii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If insurance for windstorm and hail to meet all FmHA or its
            successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             requirements is not available in a hurricane area, the County
            Supervisor may accept from the borrower or applicant the windstorm
            and hail insurance policy that most nearly conforms to FmHA or its
            successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             requirements. If such an exception is made, the situation should be
            fully documented in the borrower&apos;s case file. However, if the
            best insurance policy a borrower or applicant can obtain at the time
            he receives a loan contains a loss deductible clause for windstorm
            and hail damage exceeding $250 or 10 percent of the actual cash
            value of the buildings, whichever amount is greater, the insurance
            policy, with an explanation of the reasons why more adequate
            insurance is not available will be submitted to the State Office for
            prior approval.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             [Reserved]
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            41 FR 34571
          </aref>
          , Aug. 16, 1976, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            56 FR 6945
          </aref>
          , Feb. 21, 1991]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14805'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:A:1806:A:1806.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1806.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Examining and general servicing of insurance.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          41 FR 34571
        </aref>
        , Aug. 16, 1976, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          42 FR 33262
        </aref>
        , June 30, 1977; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          50 FR 39638
        </aref>
        , Sept. 30, 1985; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          54 FR 35869
        </aref>
        , Aug. 30, 1989; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          57 FR 36590
        </aref>
        , Aug. 14, 1992; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          69 FR 69103
        </aref>
        , Nov. 26, 2004]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1806' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              1806.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Examining and general servicing of insurance.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Examination by county office of policies, endorsements, binders,
              and other evidence of insurance.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon receipt in the County Office of a policy, endorsement, binder,
            or other evidence of insurance, submitted by a borrower, it will be
            examined promptly for compliance with the requirements of this
            Instruction. If the evidence of insurance is found to be acceptable,
            it will be placed in the borrower&apos;s case folder.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Unacceptable policies.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When the borrower furnishes any policy or other evidence of
            insurance which does not meet the requirements of this Instruction
            such policy or other evidence of insurance will be returned to the
            borrower with the reasons why it is not acceptable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the borrower does not furnish acceptable insurance by the date
            the previous policy expired or was canceled, the County Supervisor
            will proceed as provided in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1806' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
                1806.6
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Expiration records and notices.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In cases other than those involving FP or 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 502
            </aref>
             RH borrowers, the County Supervisor will notify the borrower of the
            expiration of his insurance at least 30 days in advance of such
            expiration unless he has received written evidence that the
            insurance has been renewed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FP and 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              Section 502
            </aref>
             RH borrowers will be informed during the tenth month after the date
            of loan closing of their responsibility to carry insurance. Form
            FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             426-4 will be sent to these borrowers, regardless of whether there
            is evidence that the insurance has been renewed. Thereafter, the
            County Supervisor will not be required to further determine whether
            the borrower has adequately maintained insurance; however, if a
            further notice of expiration is received in the County Office, the
            County Supervisor will again notify the borrower by using Form FmHA
            or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             426-4 of his responsibility.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Release of mortgage interest.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When the borrower&apos;s loan has been paid in full and the
            satisfaction or release of the mortgage has been executed, the
            County Supervisor or his delegate will execute the following Release
            of Mortgage Interest on the mortgage clause attached to the policy
            or other evidence of insurance and transmit it with 
            <PRTPAGE P='429' />
            the policy or other evidence of insurance, the paid-in-full note,
            and the satisfaction to the borrower: 
          </text>
        </P>
        <EXTRACT>
          <FP>
            It is understood and agreed that the interest of the United States
            of America in the property insured hereunder ceased as of (Date of
            Final Payment), and that the Government shall have no interest in
            any loss or damage to such property occurring thereafter.
          </FP>
        </EXTRACT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Lost or misplaced policies.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When an unexpired insurance policy or other evidence of insurance
            is lost or misplaced, it will be necessary to obtain a replacement
            policy or other evidence of insurance. The County Supervisor is
            authorized to sign a Lost Policy Receipt on behalf of the FmHA or
            its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
            . For FP and 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 502
            </aref>
             RH loans, this paragraph applies only during the period the policy
            is retained in the County Office.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Disposition of expired and canceled policies.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An expired or canceled policy or other evidence of insurance will
            be returned to the borrower, unless there is a loss settlement
            pending.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Special servicing of insurance—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Vacancy or unoccupancy—tenant occupancy—increased hazard.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the County Supervisor has knowledge that insured property is
            vacant or unoccupied or that the ownership or occupancy has changed
            from owner to tenant, or that the hazards otherwise are increased,
            he will examine the policy to determine whether the policy permits
            such conditions. Unless the insurance permits such conditions, the
            County Supervisor will immediately notify the company or agent in
            writing. In any case where there is an additional premium due
            because of vacancy, unoccupancy, tenant occupancy, or other
            increased hazard, and upon demand to FmHA or its successor agency
            under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             from the company or agent because the borrower cannot, or will not,
            pay the additional premium, it may be paid in accordance with FmHA
            or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             Instruction 2024-A, to the company or agent. For FP and 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 502
            </aref>
             RH borrowers, property insurance will not be obtained except in
            cases where an unusual and severe hazard exists and insurance is
            necessary to protect the interests of the Government.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Transfer of property.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When a borrower or transferee requests the consent of FmHA or its
            successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             to a transfer of the security property which already has been made,
            or when the County Supervisor learns that any such transfer has been
            made, he will immediately inform the transferee that the mortgage
            requires the owner to provide and maintain adequate insurance
            acceptable to, and with loss payable to, FmHA or its successor
            agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             as mortgagee. The transferee may obtain a new insurance policy or
            the transferor may have the insurance company or agent issue an
            endorsement to the current insurance policy changing the name of the
            assured to that of the transferee. If a new insurance policy is
            obtained, the old policy or other evidence of insurance will be
            returned to the transferor unless there is an unsettled loss. If
            there is an unsettled loss, the policy or other evidence of
            insurance will not be returned until the claim has been settled. The
            County Supervisor, with the concurrence of the State Director and
            the OGC, will notify the borrower and transferee that acceptance of
            the new policy or endorsement will not constitute consent by the
            Government to the transfer even though the Government is protected
            by a loss payable clause in such an insurance policy.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In a transfer with assumption, insurance will be required in the
            same amount and according to the same provisions as for an initial
            loan of the same type.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Voluntary conveyance of property to the Government and
              foreclosure.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Insurance will not be carried on buildings which the Government has
            acquired. After a foreclosure sale has been held, or after a deed of
            conveyance to the Government in lieu of foreclosure has been filed
            for record, insurance will not be maintained by the Government
            (whether or not subject to redemption).
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            41 FR 34571
          </aref>
          , Aug. 16, 1976, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            42 FR 33262
          </aref>
          , June 30, 1977; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            50 FR 39638
          </aref>
          , Sept. 30, 1985; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            54 FR 35869
          </aref>
          , Aug. 30, 1989; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            57 FR 36590
          </aref>
          , Aug. 14, 1992; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            69 FR 69103
          </aref>
          , Nov. 26, 2004]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14806'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:A:1806:A:1806.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1806.5
      </num>
      <head>
        Losses.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          41 FR 34571
        </aref>
        , Aug. 16, 1976, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          50 FR 39638
        </aref>
        , Sept. 30, 1985]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='430' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1806' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              1806.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Losses.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Protecting property.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             It is the responsibility of the borrower to immediately notify the
            County Supervisor and insurance company or agent of any loss or
            damage to insured property and collect the amount of the loss. When
            the County Supervisor learns of a loss to property which secures an
            FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             loan, he will:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Check the borrower&apos;s casefile for an insurance policy or other
            evidence of insurance. When a policy or other evidence of insurance
            has not been retained by the FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
            , such as for FP and 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 502
            </aref>
             RH borrowers, the County Supervisor will determine whether the
            property was insured and whether FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             was named as mortgagee in the insurance policy.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Determine that the borrower has taken such steps as are necessary
            to protect the interest of the FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             in the security property against further damage. When serious
            problems arise with respect to protecting the property from further
            damage, the borrower cannot or will not arrange adequate protection
            for the property, or when legal action appears to be necessary, the
            County Supervisor will arrange for emergency protection and
            immediately refer the case with complete information to the State
            Director.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Loss covered by insurance.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             is listed as mortgagee in the insurance policy, the County
            Supervisor will collect the amount of the loss and may consent to
            the borrower using funds to repair or replace damaged or destroyed
            property or to apply loss proceeds to his loan account or to any
            prior liens that might exist in the order of their priority.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             is not listed as mortgagee in the insurance policy, the County
            Supervisor will contact the borrower to determine whether he has
            received the loss proceeds. If the borrower has received the loss
            proceeds but not yet paid for improvements to repair or replace the
            property, or has not received the loss proceeds the County
            Supervisor will:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notify the insurance company in writing of the FmHA or its
            successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
            &apos;s interest in the security property and request that the loss
            proceeds be made payable jointly to the FmHA or its successor agency
            under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             and the borrower.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Inform the borrower of his responsibility for repairing or
            replacing the damaged or destroyed property or for authorized
            disposition of the loss proceeds as outlined in paragraph (b)(1) of
            this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Loss drafts—when loan is secured by a first mortgage.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A loss draft which in the opinion of the County Supervisor
            represents a satisfactory adjustment of the loss will be endorsed
            immediately without recourse and deposited in a supervised bank
            account to be used in repairing or replacing the damaged building,
            except:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Where the amount of the loss is $1,000 or less and the borrower
            will use the funds for repairing or replacing an essential building,
            the loss draft may be endorsed without recourse and given to the
            borrower upon satisfactory proof that the repairs or replacements
            have been made, or upon satisfactory assurance that the work will be
            performed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When (A) the essential buildings are not to be repaired or replaced
            and other suitable buildings are not to be erected, or (B) a balance
            remains after all repairs, replacements, and other authorized
            disbursements have been made, such insurance funds will be applied
            on prior liens or as an extra payment to the borrower&apos;s loan
            accounts secured by the real estate or disposed of in accordance
            with the general principles applicable to the use of proceeds from
            the sale of a part of the security contained in applicable security
            servicing regulations for the type loan involved.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An insurance payment for loss or damage to a nonessential building
            the borrower voluntarily insured will be (A) applied on prior liens,
            or to current delinquencies to FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             or as an extra payment on the borrower&apos;s loan accounts secured
            by real estate, (B) disposed of as authorized by the 
            <PRTPAGE P='431' />
            State Director in accordance with the general principles applicable
            to the use of proceeds from the sale of a part of the security
            contained in applicable security servicing regulations for the type
            loan involved, or (C) used for other purposes as authorized by the
            State Director if the loan is adequately secured and the loan
            account is current.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When the indebtedness secured by the insured property has been paid
            in full or the draft is in payment for loss of property on which the
            FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             has no claim, a loss draft which includes the FmHA or its successor
            agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             as a joint payee may be endorsed without recourse and delivered to
            the borrower.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Loss drafts—When loan is secured by other than first mortgage.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When the loss draft does not include the interest of a prior
            mortgagee, it will be processed as provided in paragraph (c) of this
            section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When the loss draft includes the interest of a prior mortgagee, the
            County Supervisor is authorized to endorse and process the draft as
            follows:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When the prior mortgagee will permit the use of such loss funds to
            repair or replace the damaged building, the draft may be endorsed
            without recourse upon satisfactory proof that the repairs or
            replacements have been made or upon satisfactory assurance that the
            work will be performed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When the amount of the draft does not exceed the amount of the
            indebtedness then secured by the prior mortgage as stated in writing
            by the holder of the prior mortgage, and the holder of the prior
            mortgage has agreed in a written statement to the County Supervisor
            that he will apply such funds as a payment on the borrower&apos;s
            prior mortgage indebtedness, the draft may be endorsed without
            recourse.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When the amount of the draft exceeds the amount of the indebtedness
            then secured by the prior mortgage, as stated in writing by the
            holder, and he has agreed in writing to pay such indebtedness from
            the loss funds, the draft will be endorsed without recourse only
            after all parties named as payees in the draft have signed an
            agreement to deliver the draft “in escrow” to a bank acceptable to
            the named parties. The agreement will specify the manner in which
            the funds will be disbursed by the bank, as escrow agent, to the
            several mortgagees named in the draft. After the loss funds have
            been collected by the bank, it will issue cashier&apos;s checks in
            the manner prescribed in the escrow agreement (see exhibit A for
            suggested form). If this procedure is found to be impractical in an
            individual instance, the State Director may authorize an alternative
            method for disbursing the loss funds to protect the
            Government&apos;s financial interest.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Drafts which have been endorsed by all other payees will be
            endorsed immediately without recourse. Such drafts or other loss
            funds will be processed in accordance with the methods described in
            paragraph (c) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Servicing insurance losses under special circumstances—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Foreclosures and voluntary conveyances.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Losses on properties in process of foreclosure or voluntary
            conveyance will be handled with the advice of the OGC. If the
            necessary cooperation of the borrower cannot be obtained, the State
            Director, with the advice of the OGC, will determine the proper
            action to be taken. To the extent feasible from a legal and
            practical standpoint, all loss payments should be received for a
            damaged or destroyed building and applied on the borrower&apos;s
            real estate indebtedness before title to the property is taken by
            the Government through foreclosure sale, voluntary conveyance, or
            otherwise, unless absolute assignment has been made by the borrower
            to the Government of all loss funds due from the insurance company.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Subrogation agreements.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When a company claims nonliability to the borrower and subrogation
            to the rights of the FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
            , the County Supervisor will forward a full report of the facts in
            the case to the State Director. The State Director will upon advice
            from OGC, instruct the County Supervisor regarding further action to
            be taken.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Repairs and replacements.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When any loss payments have been deposited in a supervised bank
            account, all repairs and replacements done by or 
            <PRTPAGE P='432' />
            under the direction of the borrower, or by contract, will be
            planned, performed, inspected, and paid for in the same manner as
            improvements financed with loan funds.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Completing adjustment.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The borrower must complete the adjustment of the loss with the
            company or its authorized representatives. The County Supervisor,
            upon request of the borrower may consult with the borrower regarding
            the loss adjustment, but will not enter into negotiations with
            insurance adjusters or company representatives relative to the
            adjustment or settlement of losses on borrower property, or make any
            commitments, or sign any forms in connection with the adjustment of
            the loss. The FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             will not waive any rights which it may have against the company
            except when the borrower&apos;s account or the FmHA or its successor
            agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             claim has been paid-in-full.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The County Supervisor will maintain a proper followup on all losses
            until satisfactory settlement has been made by the company.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Where the County Supervisor has evidence that the adjustment agreed
            to by the borrower is significantly less than the amount of damage
            to which the borrower is entitled under the terms of the policy, the
            loss draft accompanied by a report will be sent to the State
            Director so that he may reopen the adjustment, if he considers it is
            in the interest of the FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             to do so.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When it appears evident that the amount of the loss is $1,000 or
            less, the County Supervisor may rely on estimates of contractors,
            building supply firms, reliable carpenters, or other evidence rather
            than personal inspection in determining whether the adjustment is
            equitable and the Government&apos;s interest is protected.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Reinstatement after loss.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In cases where insurance in the amount of the loss is not
            reinstated automatically by the provisions of the policy, it will be
            the responsibility of the County Supervisor to have the borrower
            reinstate as much of the insurance as may be necessary to fulfill
            the requirements of the FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Losses not covered by insurance.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When a loss occurs and insurance is not in force, the County
            Supervisor will:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Inform the borrower that he has violated the security instrument by
            not providing insurance coverage and that it is his responsibility
            to make the needed replacements or repairs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the borrower is unable or unwilling to make needed repairs or
            replacements from his own resources, the County Supervisor will
            submit complete information to the FmHA or its successor agency
            under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             official authorized to determine whether FmHA or its successor
            agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             will or will not continue with the loan. The County
            Supervisor&apos;s report will include recommendations on the
            following items:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The advisability and possibility of making a subsequent loan to pay
            for needed repairs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subordination of the FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             real estate lien to permit the borrower to obtain funds for needed
            repairs from another source.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The possibility of the borrower obtaining funds secured by a junior
            lien from another source.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_2_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whether an advance is needed to protect the Government&apos;s
            interest in the property.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the loan will not be continued with the borrower, it must be
            serviced in accordance with the applicable Instructions.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the borrower has improperly disposed of loss proceeds, the
            County Supervisor will refer the case with complete information and
            recommendations to the State Director. The State Director will
            consult the Regional Attorney when necessary and advise the County
            Supervisor as to appropriate servicing actions.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            41 FR 34571
          </aref>
          , Aug. 16, 1976, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            50 FR 39638
          </aref>
          , Sept. 30, 1985]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14807'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:A:1806:A:1806.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1806.6
      </num>
      <head>
        Failure of borrower to provide insurance.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          41 FR 34571
        </aref>
        , Aug. 16, 1976, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          42 FR 33263
        </aref>
        , June 30, 1977; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          43 FR 34430
        </aref>
        , Aug. 4, 1978; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          50 FR 39638
        </aref>
        , Sept. 30, 1985; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          56 FR 6945
        </aref>
        , Feb. 21, 1991; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          57 FR 36590
        </aref>
        , Aug. 14, 1992; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          67 FR 78326
        </aref>
        , Dec. 24, 2002]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1806' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              1806.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Failure of borrower to provide insurance.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          When a borrower fails to provide and maintain property insurance which
          meets the requirements set forth in 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            § 1806.2 of
          </aref>
           this subpart, every effort will be made to have the borrower provide 
          <PRTPAGE P='433' />
          coverage acceptable to FmHA or its successor agency under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
          . It will be emphasized that under the terms of the security
          instrument, it is the borrower&apos;s responsibility to provide and
          maintain proper insurance coverage. Existing borrowers required to
          escrow will be notified by letter at least 90 days prior to initiating
          escrowing for insurance. Failure to provide insurance is a nonmonetary
          default and will be a consideration in determining if the loan is to
          be continued. For FP or SFH borrowers 
          <E T='03'>
            not
          </E>
           required to escrow, the County Supervisor will obtain insurance
          coverage and voucher for the insurance premium only in cases where: An
          unusual and severe hazard, such as recurring fires or unstable ground
          conditions, exists, or, an SFH borrower on a moratorium is unable to
          pay the insurance premium and the borrower requests that FmHA or its
          successor agency under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
           pay the premium. For SFH borrowers required to escrow, force placed
          insurance will be obtained if the borrower fails to provide acceptable
          insurance. Borrowers being phased into escrow will be given at least
          30 days to obtain coverage, after which force placed insurance will be
          obtained. If the escrow account contains insufficient funds to pay the
          insurance when due, the County Supervisor will request the borrower to
          pay an amount equal to the difference between the premium due and the
          escrow balance in a lump sum within 30 days after notification. If the
          borrower fails to remit the amount requested, the amount will be
          advanced and charged to the borrower&apos;s account as a recoverable
          cost. The amortization period for an advance due to an escrow shortage
          will be one year. Insurance coverage shall be provided continuously
          unless the property is acquired by FmHA or its successor agency under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
          . The cost of obtaining such a policy shall be advanced and charged to
          the borrower&apos;s account as a recoverable cost. Amortization of the
          charge will be handled in accordance with
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR part 
            <subref title='7' part='3550' tq='N'>
              3550
            </subref>
          </aref>
          . If a borrower indebted for other than an FP or SFH loan fails to
          provide acceptable insurance, the Servicing Official will take the
          following action:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Expired policies.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The County Supervisor will request the insurance agency or broker
            who issued the expired policy to issue a new policy which is
            acceptable to the FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The new policy will be effective as of the date of the County
            Supervisor&apos;s contact with the insurance agency or broker or as
            soon thereafter as possible, and will be for a term of one year. If
            State insurance regulations require a longer term, the State
            Director will issue a State Instruction authorizing County
            Supervisors to obtain policies for the minimum period permitted by
            State insurance regulations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             will be shown in the loss payable clause and in the mortgage clause
            in the proper order of priority.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Insurance coverage on each building usually will be the same as
            shown on the expired policy if it meets or exceeds FmHA or its
            successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             requirements. If the coverage shown on the expired policy does not
            meet FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             requirements, proper coverage will be obtained.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The County Supervisor will, if possible, have an automatic renewal
            provision included in the policy.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the borrower refuses to pay the insurance premium with his own
            funds or arrange with the agent for subsequent payment by premium
            not or otherwise, the County Supervisor will pay the amount of the
            insurance premium in accordance with FmHA or its successor agency
            under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             Instruction 2024-A. The amount of the premium payment will be
            charged to the borrower&apos;s FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             account with the highest lien priority as a recoverable cost item.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the insurance agency or broker who issued the expired policy
            refuses to issue a new policy, the County Supervisor will have the
            borrower designate in writing another insurance agency or broker
            from whom the insurance can be obtained.
            <PRTPAGE P='434' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_vii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             After the County Supervisor and the borrower exhaust all efforts to
            obtain acceptable insurance, the County Supervisor will request
            advice from the State Office as to companies issuing acceptable
            policies in the State and from which the borrower might be able to
            obtain an acceptable policy. If the borrower still cannot obtain an
            acceptable policy from any such company, and the determination has
            been made to continue with the borrower, the County Supervisor will
            temporarily accept from the borrower the available insurance policy
            the FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             determines most nearly conforms to the requirements of 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              § 1806.2 of
            </aref>
             this subpart.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='a_1_vii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In making this determination, the following deficiencies become
            more objectionable in the order from (
            <E T='03'>
              1
            </E>
            ) to (
            <E T='03'>
              5
            </E>
            ) paragraphs (a)(1)(vii)(A) of this section:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          (
          <E T='03'>
            1
          </E>
          ) A policy written for an initial term of less than one year.
        </P>
        <P>
          (
          <E T='03'>
            2
          </E>
          ) A policy which will insure the most essential buildings but will not
          cover all essential buildings.
        </P>
        <P>
          (
          <E T='03'>
            3
          </E>
          ) A policy which covers major risks such as fire and lightning, but
          does not include one or more of the other risks specified in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1806' sect='2' psec='#8' tq='N'>
              1806.2(8)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          (
          <E T='03'>
            4
          </E>
          ) A policy for a lesser amount of insurance than is required by 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1806' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              1806.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          (
          <E T='03'>
            5
          </E>
          ) A policy that is issued by a company which is not licensed to do
          business in the State or otherwise does not meet the requirements of 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1806' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              1806.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='a_1_vii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whenever adequate insurance becomes available, the County
            Supervisor will require the borrower to deliver to the County Office
            an acceptable insurance policy. The temporary policy will be
            returned to the borrower for cancellation after all losses claimed
            under the policy have been settled.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='a_1_vii_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the borrower is unable to furnish a property insurance policy of
            any kind, he is still responsible for the debt in the event of loss.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='a_1_vii_D'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (D)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the County Supervisor accepts an inadequate insurance policy
            under these conditions or the borrower fails to furnish any
            insurance policy, the County Supervisor will include in his report
            to the State Director an explanation of the efforts he and the
            borrower made to obtain acceptable insurance and his justification
            for accepting an inadequate policy, or for not obtaining an
            insurance policy of any kind.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Insurance canceled for reasons other than nonpayment of insurance
              premium.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The County Supervisor, immediately upon receipt of a 10-day notice
            of cancellation for a policy, will urge the borrower to provide
            acceptable insurance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the borrower fails to provide acceptable insurance before the
            cancellation is effective, the County Supervisor will contact the
            insurance agency or broker who issued the insurance policy to
            determine the reasons for cancellation and, if possible, have the
            policy reinstated.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the insurance company will not reinstate the policy, the County
            Supervisor will attempt to obtain an acceptable insurance policy
            from another agency or broker in accordance with the provisions of
            paragraph (a) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Insurance canceled for nonpayment of premium.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The County Supervisor, immediately upon receiving a 10-day
            cancellation notice for a policy, will, if possible, contact the
            borrower in an effort to have him pay the insurance premium from his
            own funds or arrange with the agent for subsequent payment by
            premium note, or otherwise.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the borrower does not pay or arrange to pay the premium before
            the policy cancellation is effective, the County Supervisor will,
            before the cancellation becomes effective, notify the insurance
            company or broker by certified mail (return receipt requested), that
            the FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             as mortgagee (or trustee) will pay the premium for one year to
            continue the policy in effect for that period. The County Supervisor
            will, in accordance with FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             Instruction 2024-A, pay the amount of the premium for a period of
            one year. The amount of the premium will be charged to the
            borrower&apos;s loan account as a recoverable cost item.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a property insurance mortgage clause other than Form FmHA or its
            successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             426-2 is used in connection with the policy and the insurance
            company or broker refuses to accept payment from 
            <PRTPAGE P='435' />
            the FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             in this manner to reinstate or continue the policy, the County
            Supervisor will attempt to obtain an acceptable insurance policy
            from another insurance company or broker in accordance with the
            provisions of paragraph (a) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <SECAUTH>
          (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='1989' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1989.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 1989
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='42' sect='1480' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/42/1480.html'>
              42 U.S.C. 1480
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='42' sect='2942' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/42/2942.html'>
              42 U.S.C. 2942
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='5' sect='301' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/5/301.html'>
              5 U.S.C. 301
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            Sec. 10
          </aref>
          <aref target='_blank' title='Pub. L. 93-357' alt='Pub. L. 93-357' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d93:./list/bd/d93pl.lst:357%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Pub. L. 93-357
          </aref>
          , 
          <aref target='_blank' href='http://frwebgate.access.gpo.gov/cgi-bin/getpage.cgi?dbname=93_statutes2_at_large&amp;position=all&amp;page=392'>
            88 Stat. 392
          </aref>
          ; delegation of authority by the Secretary of Agriculture, 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR 
            <subref title='7' part='2' sect='23' psec='' tq='N'>
              2.23
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; delegation of authority by the Assistant Secretary for Rural
          Development, 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR 
            <subref title='7' part='2' sect='70' psec='' tq='N'>
              2.70
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; delegation of authority by Director OEO 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            29 FR 14764, 33
          </aref>
           FR 9850)
        </SECAUTH>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            41 FR 34571
          </aref>
          , Aug. 16, 1976, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            42 FR 33263
          </aref>
          , June 30, 1977; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            43 FR 34430
          </aref>
          , Aug. 4, 1978; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            50 FR 39638
          </aref>
          , Sept. 30, 1985; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            56 FR 6945
          </aref>
          , Feb. 21, 1991; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            57 FR 36590
          </aref>
          , Aug. 14, 1992; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            67 FR 78326
          </aref>
          , Dec. 24, 2002]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14808'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:A:1806:B:1806.21
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1806.21
      </num>
      <head>
        General.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          39 FR 17093
        </aref>
        , May 13, 1974, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          69 FR 69103
        </aref>
        , Nov. 26, 2004; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          72 FR 64121
        </aref>
        , Nov. 15, 2007]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1806' sect='21' psec='' tq='N'>
              1806.21
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Authority.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This subpart prescribes the policies and procedures to be followed
            in implementing the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 as amended
            by the Flood Disaster Protection Act of 1973. The provisions of
            these Acts are applicable to Farmers Home Administration (FmHA) or
            its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             authorities permitting financing of buildings of any type now
            located in or to be located in special flood or mudslide prone areas
            as designated by the Federal Insurance Administration (FIA) of the
            Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD), and any
            machinery, equipment, fixtures and furnishings contained or to be
            contained therein. This subpart does not apply to Farm Service
            Agency, Farm Loan Programs and to Rural Rental Housing, Rural
            Cooperative Housing, or Farm Labor Housing programs of the Rural
            Housing Service.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Background.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Congress has found that annual losses throughout the nation
            caused by floods and mudslides are increasing at an alarming rate,
            largely as a result of the accelerated development and concentration
            of populations in areas subject to floods and mudslides. The
            availability of Federal funds in the form of loans, grants,
            guarantees, insurance and other forms of financial assistance are
            often determining factors in the utilization of land and the
            location and construction of industrial, commercial and residential
            facilities.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Scope.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The National Flood Insurance Program (the program) was authorized
            and created because the private insurance industry has been unable
            to provide insurance coverage at reasonable prices for such natural
            disasters as floods and mudslides. Subsidized and affordable
            insurance has been made available under the Act through an agreement
            between the Federal Insurance Administration and the National Flood
            Insurers Association.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            39 FR 17093
          </aref>
          , May 13, 1974, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            69 FR 69103
          </aref>
          , Nov. 26, 2004; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            72 FR 64121
          </aref>
          , Nov. 15, 2007]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14809'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:A:1806:B:1806.22
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1806.22
      </num>
      <head>
        Areas of responsibility.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='436' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1806' sect='22' psec='' tq='N'>
              1806.22
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Areas of responsibility.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Federal Insurance Administration
            </E>
             (
            <E T='03'>
              FIA
            </E>
            ). (1) Identify and publish information with respect to all areas in
            the country which are subject to floods and mudslides and designate
            those areas on Flood Hazard Boundary maps.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notify affected communities of their designations and encourage
            them to adopt and enforce land use and other control measures and to
            adopt ordinances or laws which will regulate and control
            construction in areas designated as having special flood or mudslide
            hazards.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Make flood insurance available at reasonable rates in sufficient
            amounts, within the statutory limits, to adequately protect owners
            against loss to their buildings and contents when those buildings
            are located in or will be located in designated special flood and
            mudslide prone areas in communities participating in the National
            Flood Insurance Program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Farmers Home Administration or its successor agency under 
              <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
                Public Law 103-354
              </aref>
              .
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State Director, after being notified by the FmHA or its
            successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             National Office or FIA of designated flood or mudslide hazard areas
            and receiving flood hazard boundary maps identifying the hazard
            areas, FIA insurance rate charts, or other information concerning
            the program, will inform the appropriate County Supervisors and
            provide them the maps, rate charts, and other relevant information
            concerning the program in areas they serve. Permanent records
            indicating the date a community was notified as containing
            identified flood hazard areas, communities participating in the
            program, and communities eligible to participate but not
            participating in the program will be maintained in the State Office.
            County Supervisors will notify, in writing, those borrowers whose
            insurable buildings are located in designated flood or mudslide
            hazard areas of the availability of national flood insurance and
            encourage them to obtain flood insurance to protect their and the
            Government&apos;s financial interest.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Community.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Communities are required to participate in the National Flood
            Insurance Program within 1 year after notification of its formal
            identification as a community containing one or more special flood
            and mudslide prone areas, or by July 1, 1975, whichever is later, or
            be denied Federal financial assistance or Federally-related
            financial assistance for acquisition or construction purposes in
            such areas. Communities wishing to qualify for the program may
            submit a completed application to: Administrator, Federal Insurance
            Administration, Department of Housing and Urban Development, 451
            Seventh Street, SW., Washington, DC 20410.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Lender.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The lender must determine whether real property is located in an
            area identified as having special flood or mudslide hazards and
            cannot discharge the responsibility merely by obtaining a
            self-certification from the applicant that the property is not
            located in an area having special flood hazards.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14810'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:A:1806:B:1806.23
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1806.23
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1806' sect='23' psec='' tq='N'>
              1806.23
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          For the purpose of this subpart, the following definitions apply:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Financial assistance
            </E>
             means any form of direct, insured or guaranteed loan, including
            reamortization and assumption on new terms of any loan, any form of
            grant, or other form of direct or indirect assistance extended by
            the FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Financial assistance for acquisition or construction purposes
            </E>
             means any form of Federal financial assistance which is intended in
            whole or in part for the acquisition, construction, reconstruction,
            or substantial improvement of any building and for any machinery,
            equipment, fixtures and furnishings contained or to be contained in
            such buildings.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Community means
            </E>
             any state or political subdivision thereof, such as county, parish,
            township, city or other local government which has zoning and
            building code jurisdiction over a particular area having special
            flood hazards.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Eligible community
            </E>
             means a community in which the Administrator of FIA has authorized
            the sale of flood insurance under the program.
            <PRTPAGE P='437' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Designated special flood
            </E>
             or
            <E T='03'>
              mudslide prone
            </E>
             area means those areas in a community subject to flood or mudslide
            which have been identified by flood hazard boundary maps or those
            areas not identified by maps but where, due to emergency, the FIA
            Administrator has authorized the sale of flood insurance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Flood
            </E>
             means a general and temporary condition of partial or complete
            inundation of normally dry land areas from the overflow of streams,
            rivers, or other inland water, the collapse or subsidence of land
            along the shore of a lake or other body of water as a result of
            erosion or undermining caused by waves or currents of water
            exceeding anticipated cyclical levels, or abnormally high tidal
            water or rising coastal waters resulting from severe storms,
            hurricanes, or tidal waves resulting from volcano eruptions or
            earthquakes.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Mudslide
            </E>
             or 
            <E T='03'>
              mudflow
            </E>
             means a major occurrence involving the appearance of a large river
            or flow of “liquid mud” down a hillside, usually as a result of
            earlier brushfires followed by heavy rains over a widespread area.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Flood insurance
            </E>
             means insurance coverage for floods and/or mudslides under the
            program or otherwise acceptable to FIA.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Building
            </E>
             means any walled and roofed structure, other than a gas or liquid
            tank, that is principally above ground and affixed to a permanent
            site. Residential and most types of industrial, commercial, and
            agricultural buildings, such as lumber sheds, machinery storage
            sheds, grain storage bins, and silos, are included in this
            definition.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Substantial improvement
            </E>
             means any repair, reconstruction or improvement of a structure, the
            cost of which equals or exceeds 50 percent of the actual cash value
            of the structure either before the improvement is started or, if the
            structure has been damaged and is being restored, before the damage
            occurred.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14811'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:A:1806:B:1806.24
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1806.24
      </num>
      <head>
        Eligibility.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1806' sect='24' psec='' tq='N'>
              1806.24
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Eligibility.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          In addition to an applicant meeting the requirements for the type of
          financial assistance requested, the following requirements for
          eligibility of applicants for financial assistance for acquisition and
          construction purposes in designated special flood and mudslide prone
          areas must be met:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If flood insurance is available, to be eligible after March 1,
            1974, the applicant must have purchased a flood insurance policy at
            the time the loan or grant is closed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Applicants will not receive financial assistance in those
            communities that have been notified as having special flood and
            mudslide prone areas and where flood insurance is not available
            within 1 year after such notification or by July 1, 1975, whichever
            is later.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14812'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:A:1806:B:1806.25
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1806.25
      </num>
      <head>
        Conditions.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          39 FR 17093
        </aref>
        , May 13, 1974, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          52 FR 8002
        </aref>
        , Mar. 13, 1987; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          56 FR 6945
        </aref>
        , Feb. 21, 1991]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1806' sect='25' psec='' tq='N'>
              1806.25
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Conditions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          FmHA or its successor agency under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
           financial assistance may be extended to eligible applicants meeting
          the eligibility requirements of 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            § 1806.24 of
          </aref>
           this subpart, provided the following conditions are also met:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Dwelling and multi-unit housing facilities.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the financial assistance is to buy a dwelling or multi-unit
            housing facility:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The first floor elevation of the habitable space of the dwelling or
            housing unit must be above the 100-year flood level.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The housing must be served by public utilities and facilities, such
            as sewer, gas, electrical and water systems that are located and
            constructed to minimize or eliminate flood damage, or have an onsite
            water supply system and waste disposal system located so as to avoid
            impairment of such systems and contamination from the waste disposal
            system to the water supply system from flooding.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the financial assistance is to build or provide substantial
            improvement, the requirements of paragraph (a)(1) of this section
            must be met and all construction must meet requirements of the
            applicable development standards, and:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A building permit must be issued by the appropriate governing
            officials having jurisdiction in the area and compliance must be had
            with the zoning code or other established legal requirements of the
            area for reducing or eliminating flood or mudslide damage.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The structure must be designed and anchored to prevent flotation,
            collapse or lateral movement of the structure.
            <PRTPAGE P='438' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Construction materials and utility equipment that are resistant to
            flood damage must be used.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Construction methods and practices that will minimize flood damage
            must be followed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the financial assistance is to make minor repairs, the
            conditions of paragraphs (a)(1) (i) and (ii) and (2) (i), (ii) and
            (iii) of this section must be met or the building must have existed
            on the site prior to the date the area was identified as having
            special flood or mudslide hazards and the loan approval official
            must determine that the dwelling is suitable as a residence.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When applications for financial assistance are received in areas
            identified as having special flood and mudslide hazards, the loan
            approval official will consider the expected severity and frequency
            of floods and mudslides in determining whether any housing loans
            should be made in the area. He should be sure, if loans are made,
            that the objectives of the loans can be accomplished and the
            Government&apos;s financial interest will be adequately protected.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Nonresidential buildings.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Construction plans and specifications for new buildings or
            improvements to existing buildings must comply with flood plain area
            management or control laws, regulations or ordinances.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Flood insurance coverage.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any property on which flood insurance is required must be covered
            by such insurance during its anticipated economic and useful life in
            an amount at least equal to its development or replacement cost
            (except estimated land cost), or to the maximum limit of coverage
            made available with respect to the particular type of property under
            the National Flood Insurance Program, whichever is less. However, if
            the financial assistance provided is in the form of a loan, the
            amount of flood insurance required need not exceed the outstanding
            principal balance of the loan and need not be required beyond the
            term of the loan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The contents of a building must be insured separately from a
            building but coverage cannot be written on the contents of a
            three-walled machinery shed or similar type open building.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Flood insurance shall not be required on any state owned property
            that is covered under an adequate state policy of self-insurance
            satisfactory to the Secretary of HUD, who will publish a list of
            states with such policies.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             It will be emphasized that under the terms of the security
            instrument it is the borrower&apos;s responsibility to provide and
            maintain proper flood insurance coverage. If flood insurance is not
            provided on any property for which it is required, the flood
            insurance premium will be paid to protect the Government&apos;s
            security interest. For borrowers required to escrow for flood
            insurance, payment of the premium will be handled in accordance with
            
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              § 1806.28 of
            </aref>
             this subpart. Existing borrowers required to escrow will be
            notified by letter at least 90 days prior to initiating escrowing
            for flood insurance. If FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             pays the flood insurance premium for borrowers not required to
            escrow, the cost will be charged to the borrower&apos;s account as a
            recoverable cost. Failure to provide flood insurance is a
            nonmonetary default and will be a consideration in determining if
            the loan is to be continued.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            39 FR 17093
          </aref>
          , May 13, 1974, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            52 FR 8002
          </aref>
          , Mar. 13, 1987; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            56 FR 6945
          </aref>
          , Feb. 21, 1991]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14813'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:A:1806:B:1806.26
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1806.26
      </num>
      <head>
        Coverage and premium rates.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1806' sect='26' psec='' tq='N'>
              1806.26
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Coverage and premium rates.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Exhibit A sets forth limits of coverage and chargeable premium rates
          under the program. Insurance policies under the program can be
          obtained from any licensed property insurance agent or broker serving
          the eligible community or from the National Flood Insurers Association
          Serving Company (Serving Company) for the state. The Servicing Company
          for each state is shown in exhibit B.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14814'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:A:1806:B:1806.27
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1806.27
      </num>
      <head>
        Acceptable policies and servicing.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1806' sect='27' psec='' tq='N'>
              1806.27
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Acceptable policies and servicing.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The general acceptance of policies and servicing of insurance will be
          performed in accordance with Subpart A of this part. Any unusual
          situations that may arise with respect to obtaining or servicing flood
          insurance should be referred to the State Director. The State Director
          will attempt to resolve 
          <PRTPAGE P='439' />
          any problems concerning the flood insurance program in the state with
          the Servicing Company. Flood hazard boundary maps, insurance rate
          tables, the insurability of specific structures, and other information
          concerning the program may be obtained from the Servicing Company.
          Difficulties in administering the program which the State Director is
          unable to resolve should be referred to the National Office for
          Assistance.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14815'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:A:1806:B:1806.28
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1806.28
      </num>
      <head>
        Borrowers required to escrow.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          56 FR 6946
        </aref>
        , Feb. 21, 1991, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          67 FR 78326
        </aref>
        , Dec. 24, 2002]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1806' sect='28' psec='' tq='N'>
              1806.28
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Borrowers required to escrow.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          For borrowers required to use escrow accounts for the payment of real
          estate taxes and insurance, the flood insurance premium will be paid
          when due from funds contained in the escrow account. If the escrow
          account contains insufficient funds to pay the flood insurance premium
          when due, the County Supervisor will request the borrower to pay an
          amount equal to the difference between the premium due and the escrow
          balance in a lump sum within 30 days after notification. If the
          borrower fails to remit the amount requested, the amount will be
          advanced and charged to the borrower&apos;s account as a recoverable
          cost. The amortization period for an advance due to an escrow shortage
          will be one year. Amortization of the charge will be handled in
          accordance with
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR part 
            <subref title='7' part='3550' tq='N'>
              3550
            </subref>
          </aref>
          . When a borrower has more than one loan secured by the real estate on
          which the flood insurance premium is being paid, the advance will be
          charged to the initial or lowest numbered loan.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            56 FR 6946
          </aref>
          , Feb. 21, 1991, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            67 FR 78326
          </aref>
          , Dec. 24, 2002]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>