<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol6'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:C:625
    </extid>
    <num>
      625
    </num>
    <head>
      HEALTHY FORESTS RESERVE PROGRAM
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='16' sect='6571-657' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/6571-657.html'>
              16 U.S.C. 6571-657
            </subref>
          </aref>
          8.
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 6546
          </aref>
          , Feb. 10, 2010, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='6257'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:C:625:-:625.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        625.1
      </num>
      <head>
        Purpose and scope.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='489' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='625' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              625.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Purpose and scope.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The purpose of the Healthy Forests Reserve Program (HFRP) is to
            assist landowners, on a voluntary basis, in restoring, enhancing,
            and protecting forestland resources on private lands through
            easements, 30-year contracts, and 10-year cost-share agreements.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The objectives of HFRP are to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Promote the recovery of endangered and threatened species under the
            Endangered Species Act of 1973 (ESA);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Improve plant and animal biodiversity; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Enhance carbon sequestration.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The regulations in this part set forth the policies, procedures,
            and requirements for the HFRP as administered by the Natural
            Resources Conservation Service (NRCS) for program implementation and
            processing applications for enrollment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Chief may implement HFRP in any of the 50 States, District of
            Columbia, Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, Virgin Islands,
            American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana
            Islands.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6258'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:C:625:-:625.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        625.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='625' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              625.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The following definitions will be applicable to this part:
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            30-year Contract
          </E>
           means a contract that is limited to acreage owned by Indian tribes.
          The 30-year contract is not eligible for use on tribal lands held in
          trust or subject to Federal restrictions against alienation.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Acreage Owned by Indian Tribes
          </E>
           means lands to which the title is held by individual Indians and
          Indian tribes. This term does not include land held in trust by the
          United States or lands where the fee title contains restraints against
          alienation.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Biodiversity (Biological Diversity)
          </E>
           means the variety and variability among living organisms and the
          ecological complexes in which they live.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Candidate Conservation Agreement with Assurances (CCAA)
          </E>
           means a voluntary arrangement between the U.S. Fish and Wildlife
          Service (FWS) or the National Marine Fisheries Service (NMFS), and
          cooperating non-Federal landowners under the authority of 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 10(a)(1) of
          </aref>
           the Endangered Species Act of 1973, 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='16' sect='1539' note='' psec='#a_1' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/1539.html#a_1'>
              16 U.S.C. 1539(a)(1)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          . Under the CCAA and an associated enhancement of survival permit, the
          non-Federal landowner implements actions that are consistent with the
          conditions of the permit. CCAA with FWS are also subject to
          regulations at 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            50 CFR 
            <subref title='50' part='17' sect='22' psec='#d' tq='N'>
              17.22(d)
            </subref>
          </aref>
           for endangered species or 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            50 CFR 
            <subref title='50' part='17' sect='32' psec='#d' tq='N'>
              17.32(d)
            </subref>
          </aref>
           for threatened species, or applicable subsequent regulations.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Carbon sequestration
          </E>
           means the long-term storage of carbon in soil (as soil organic
          matter) or in plant material (such as in trees).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Chief
          </E>
           means the Chief of the Department of Agriculture (USDA) NRCS, or
          designee.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Confer
          </E>
           means to discuss for the purpose of providing information; to offer
          an opinion for consideration; or to meet for discussion, while
          reserving final decision-making authority with NRCS.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Conservation practice
          </E>
           means one or more conservation improvements and activities, including
          structural practices, land management practices, vegetative practices,
          forest management, and other improvements that benefit the eligible
          land and optimize environmental benefits, planned and applied
          according to NRCS standards and specifications.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Conservation treatment
          </E>
           means any and all conservation practices, measures, activities, and
          works of improvement that have the purpose of alleviating resource
          concerns, solving or reducing the severity of natural resource use
          problems, or taking advantage of resource opportunities, including the
          restoration, enhancement, maintenance, or management of habitat
          conditions for HFRP purposes.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Coordination
          </E>
           means to obtain input and involvement from others while reserving
          final decision-making authority with NRCS.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Cost-share agreement
          </E>
           means a legal document that specifies the rights and obligations of
          any participant accepted into the program. A HFRP cost-share agreement
          is a binding agreement for the transfer of assistance from USDA to the
          participant to share in the costs of applying conservation. A
          cost-share agreement under HFRP has a duration of 10-years.
          <PRTPAGE P='490' />
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Cost-share payment
          </E>
           means the payment made by NRCS to a program participant or vendor to
          achieve the restoration, enhancement, and protection goals of enrolled
          land in accordance with the HFRP restoration plan.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Easement
          </E>
           means a conservation easement, which is an interest in land defined
          and delineated in a deed whereby the landowner conveys certain rights,
          title, and interests in a property to the United States for the
          purpose of protecting the forest ecosystem and the conservation values
          of the property.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Easement area
          </E>
           means the land encumbered by an easement.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Easement payment
          </E>
           means the consideration paid to a landowner for an easement conveyed
          to the United States under the HFRP.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Fish and Wildlife Service
          </E>
           is an agency of the Department of Interior.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Forest Service
          </E>
           is an agency of USDA.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Forest ecosystem
          </E>
           means a dynamic set of living organisms, including plants, animals,
          and microorganisms interacting among themselves and with the
          environment in which they live. A forest ecosystem is characterized by
          predominance of trees, and by the fauna, flora, and ecological cycles
          (energy, water, carbon, and nutrients).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            HFRP restoration plan
          </E>
           means the document that identifies the conservation treatments that
          are scheduled for application to land enrolled in HFRP in accordance
          with NRCS standards and specifications.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Indian tribe
          </E>
           means any Indian tribe, band, Nation, or other organized group or
          community, including any Alaska Native village or regional or village
          corporation as defined in or established pursuant to the Alaska Native
          Claims Settlement Act (
          <aref target='_blank' href='http://frwebgate.access.gpo.gov/cgi-bin/getpage.cgi?dbname=92_statutes_at_large&amp;position=all&amp;page=688'>
            85 Stat. 688
          </aref>
          , 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='43' sect='1601' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/43/1601.html'>
              43 U.S.C. 1601
            </subref>
          </aref>
          <E T='03'>
            et seq.
          </E>
          ), which is recognized as eligible for the special programs and
          services provided by the United States to Indians because of their
          status as Indians.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Landowner
          </E>
           means an individual or entity having legal ownership of land. The
          term landowner may also include all forms of collective ownership
          including joint tenants, tenants in common, and life tenants.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Landowner protections
          </E>
           means protections and assurances made available by NRCS to HFRP
          participants, when requested, and whose voluntary conservation
          activities result in a net conservation benefit for listed, candidate,
          or other species and meet other requirements of the program. These
          Landowner Protections are subject to a HFRP restoration plan and
          associated cost-share agreement, 30-year contract, or easement being
          properly implemented. Landowner protections made available by the
          Secretary of Agriculture to HFRP participants may include an
          incidental take authorization received by NRCS from FWS or NMFS, or
          may be provided by a Safe Harbor Agreement (SHA) or CCAA directly
          between the HFRP participant and FWS or NMFS, as appropriate.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Liquidated damages
          </E>
           means a sum of money stipulated in the HFRP restoration agreement
          that the participant agrees to pay NRCS if the participant fails to
          adequately complete the terms of the restoration agreement. The sum
          represents an estimate of the expenses incurred by NRCS to service the
          restoration agreement, and reflects the difficulties of proof of loss
          and the inconvenience or non-feasibility of otherwise obtaining an
          adequate remedy.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Maintenance
          </E>
           means work performed to keep the applied conservation practice
          functioning for the intended purpose during its life span. Maintenance
          includes work to prevent deterioration of the practice, repairing
          damage, or replacement of the practice to its original condition if
          one or more components fail.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Measure
          </E>
           means one or more specific actions that is not a conservation
          practice, but has the effect of alleviating problems or improving the
          treatment of the resources.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            National Marine Fisheries Service
          </E>
           is an agency of the United States Department of Commerce.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Natural Resources Conservation Service
          </E>
           is an agency of USDA which has the responsibility for administering
          HFRP.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Participant
          </E>
           means a person, entity, or Indian tribe who is a party to a 10-year
          cost share agreement, 30-year contract, or an agreement to purchase an
          easement.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Private land
          </E>
           means land that is not owned by a local, State, or Federal
          governmental entity, and includes land 
          <PRTPAGE P='491' />
          that meets the definition of “acreage owned by Indian tribes.”
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Restoration
          </E>
           means implementing any conservation practice (vegetative, management,
          or structural) or measure that improves forest ecosystem values and
          functions (native and natural plant communities).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Restoration agreement
          </E>
           means a cost-share agreement between the program participant and NRCS
          to restore, enhance, and protect the functions and values of a forest
          ecosystem for the purposes of HFRP under either an easement, 30-year
          contract, or a 10-year cost-share agreement enrollment option.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Safe Harbor Agreement
          </E>
           means a voluntary arrangement between FWS or NMFS and cooperating
          non-Federal landowners under the authority of 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 10(a)(1) of
          </aref>
           the Endangered Species Act of 1973, 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='16' sect='1539' note='' psec='#a_1' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/1539.html#a_1'>
              16 U.S.C. 1539(a)(1)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          . Under the SHA and an associated enhancement of survival permit, the
          private property owner implements actions that are consistent with the
          conditions of the permit. SHAs with FWS are also subject to
          regulations at 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            50 CFR 
            <subref title='50' part='17' sect='22' psec='#c' tq='N'>
              17.22(c)
            </subref>
          </aref>
           for endangered species or 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            50 CFR 
            <subref title='50' part='17' sect='32' psec='#c' tq='N'>
              17.32(c)
            </subref>
          </aref>
           for threatened species, or applicable subsequent regulations.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State-listed species
          </E>
           means a species listed as threatened or endangered under State
          endangered species laws, a candidate for such listing, or a species
          listed in a State Wildlife Action Plan as a Species of Greatest
          Conservation Need.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Sign-up notice
          </E>
           means the public notification document that NRCS provides to describe
          the particular requirements for a specific HFRP sign-up.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State Conservationist
          </E>
           means the NRCS employee authorized to implement HFRP and direct and
          supervise NRCS activities in a State, Caribbean Area, or Pacific
          Islands Area.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Technical service provider
          </E>
           means an individual, private-sector entity, or public agency
          certified by NRCS to provide technical services to program
          participants in lieu of or on behalf of NRCS.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6259'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:C:625:-:625.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        625.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Administration.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='625' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              625.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Administration.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The regulations in this part will be administered under the general
            supervision and direction of the Chief.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Chief may modify or waive a provision of this part if the Chief
            determines that the application of such provision to a particular
            limited situation is inappropriate and inconsistent with the goals
            of the program. This authority cannot be further delegated. The
            Chief may not modify or waive any provision of this part which is
            required by applicable law.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No delegation in this part to lower organizational levels will
            preclude the Chief from determining any issue arising under this
            part or from reversing or modifying any determination arising from
            this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State Conservationist will develop a list of eligible
            restoration practices, payment rates and cost-share percentages, a
            priority ranking process, and any related technical matters.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS will coordinate with FWS and NMFS in the implementation of the
            program and in establishing program policies. In carrying out this
            program, NRCS may confer with private forest landowners, including
            Indian tribes, the Forest Service and other Federal agencies, State
            fish and wildlife agencies, State forestry agencies, State
            environmental quality agencies, other State conservation agencies,
            and nonprofit conservation organizations. No determination by the
            FWS, NMFS, Forest Service, any Federal, State, or tribal agency,
            conservation district, or other organization will compel NRCS to
            take any action which NRCS determines will not serve the purposes of
            the program established by this part.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6260'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:C:625:-:625.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        625.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Program requirements.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 6546
        </aref>
        , Feb. 10, 2010, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          76 FR 19684
        </aref>
        , Apr. 8, 2011]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='625' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              625.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Program requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Under the HFRP, NRCS will purchase conservation easements from, or
            enter into 30-year contracts or 10-year cost-share agreements with,
            eligible landowners who voluntarily cooperate in the restoration and
            protection of forestlands and associated lands. To participate in
            HFRP, a landowner will agree to the implementation of a HFRP
            restoration plan, the effect of which is to restore, protect,
            enhance, maintain, and manage the habitat conditions necessary to
            increase the likelihood of recovery of listed species under the ESA,
            or measurably improve the well-being of species that are not listed
            as endangered 
            <PRTPAGE P='492' />
            or threatened under the ESA but are candidates for such listing,
            State-listed species, or species identified by the Chief for special
            consideration for funding. NRCS may provide cost-share assistance
            for the activities that promote the restoration, protection,
            enhancement, maintenance, and management of forest ecosystem
            functions and values. Specific restoration, protection, enhancement,
            maintenance, and management activities may be undertaken by the
            landowner or other NRCS designee.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Of the total amount of funds expended under the program for a
            fiscal year to acquire easements and enter into 10-year cost-share
            agreements, not more than 40 percent will be used for cost-share
            agreements, and not more than 60 percent will be used for easements.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Chief may use any funds that are not obligated by April 1 of
            the fiscal year for which the funds are made available to carry out
            a different method of enrollment during that fiscal year.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Landowner eligibility.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be eligible to enroll an easement in the HFRP, an individual or
            entity must:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be the landowner of eligible land for which enrollment is sought;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Agree to provide such information to NRCS, as the agency deems
            necessary or desirable, to assist in its determination of
            eligibility for program benefits and for other program
            implementation purposes; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Comply with applicable registration and reporting requirements of
            the Federal Funding Accountability and Transparency Act of 2006 (
            <aref target='_blank' title='Pub. L. 109-282' alt='Pub. L. 109-282' href='http://www.gpo.gov/fdsys/pkg/PLAW-109publ282/html/PLAW-109publ282.htm'>
              Pub. L. 109-282
            </aref>
            , as amended), and 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              2 CFR parts 
              <subref title='2' part='25' tq='N'>
                25
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='2' part='170' tq='N'>
                170
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Eligible land.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS, in coordination with FWS or NMFS, will determine whether land
            is eligible for enrollment and whether once found eligible, the
            lands may be included in the program based on the likelihood of
            successful restoration, enhancement, and protection of forest
            ecosystem functions and values when considering the cost of
            acquiring the easement, 30-year contract, or 10-year cost share
            agreement, and the restoration, protection, enhancement,
            maintenance, and management costs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land will be considered eligible for enrollment in the HFRP only if
            NRCS determines that:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Such private land will contribute to the restoration or enhancement
            of the habitat or otherwise measurably increase the likelihood of
            recovery for a selected species listed under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 4 of
            </aref>
             the ESA; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Such private land will contribute to the restoration or enhancement
            of the habitat or otherwise measurably improve the well-being of a
            selected species not listed under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 4 of
            </aref>
             the ESA but is a candidate for such listing, or the selected
            species is a State-listed species, or is a species identified by the
            Chief for special consideration for funding.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS may also enroll land adjacent to eligible land if the
            enrollment of such adjacent land would contribute significantly to
            the practical administration of the easement area, but not more than
            it determines is necessary for such contribution.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To be enrolled in the program, eligible land must be configured in
            a size and with boundaries that allow for the efficient management
            of the area for easement purposes and otherwise promote and enhance
            program objectives.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the case of acreage owned by an Indian tribe, NRCS may enroll
            acreage into the HFRP which is privately owned by either the tribe
            or an individual.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Ineligible land.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The following land is not eligible for enrollment in the HFRP:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land owned by the United States, States, or units of local
            government;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land subject to an easement or deed restriction that already
            provides for the protection of fish and wildlife habitat or that
            would interfere with HFRP purposes, as determined by NRCS; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land that would not be eligible for HFRP under paragraphs (c)(1)
            through (c)(5).
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 6546
          </aref>
          , Feb. 10, 2010, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 19684
          </aref>
          , Apr. 8, 2011]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6261'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:C:625:-:625.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        625.5
      </num>
      <head>
        Application procedures.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='625' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              625.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Application procedures.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Sign-up process.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             As funds are available, the Chief will solicit project proposals
            from the State Conservationist. The State Conservationist may
            consult 
            <PRTPAGE P='493' />
            with other agencies at the State, Federal, and local levels to
            develop proposals. The State Conservationist will submit the
            proposal(s) to the Chief for funding selection. Upon selection for
            funding, the State Conservationist will issue a public sign-up
            notice which will announce and explain the rationale for decisions
            based on the following information:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The geographic scope of the sign-up;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any additional program eligibility criteria that are not
            specifically listed in this part;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any additional requirements that participants must include in their
            HFRP applications that are not specifically identified in this part;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Information on the priority order of enrollment for funding;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An estimate of the total funds NRCS expects to obligate during a
            given sign-up; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The schedule for the sign-up process, including the deadline(s) for
            applying.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Application for participation.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To apply for enrollment through an easement, 30-year contract, or
            10-year cost-share agreement, a landowner must submit an application
            for participation in the HFRP during an announced period for such
            sign-up.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Preliminary agency actions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             By filing an application for participation, the applicant consents
            to an NRCS representative entering upon the land for purposes of
            determining land eligibility, and for other activities that are
            necessary or desirable for NRCS to make offers of enrollment. The
            applicant is entitled to accompany an NRCS representative on any
            site visits.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Voluntary reduction in compensation.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In order to enhance the probability of enrollment in HFRP, an
            applicant may voluntarily offer to accept a lesser payment than is
            being offered by NRCS. Such offer and subsequent payments may not be
            less than those rates set forth in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='625' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
                625.8
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='625' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
                625.10
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6262'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:C:625:-:625.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        625.6
      </num>
      <head>
        Establishing priority for enrollment in HFRP.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='625' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              625.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Establishing priority for enrollment in HFRP.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Ranking considerations.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Based on the specific criteria set forth in a sign-up announcement
            and the applications for participation, NRCS, in coordination FWS
            and NMFS, may consider the following factors to rank properties:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Estimated conservation benefit to habitat required by threatened or
            endangered species listed under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 4 of
            </aref>
             the ESA;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Estimated conservation benefit to habitat required by species not
            listed as endangered or threatened under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 4 of
            </aref>
             the ESA but that are candidates for such listing, State-listed
            species, or species identified by the Chief for special
            consideration for funding;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Estimated improvement of biological diversity, if enrolled;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Potential for increased capability of carbon sequestration, if
            enrolled;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Availability of contribution of non-Federal funds;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Significance of forest ecosystem functions and values;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Estimated cost-effectiveness of the particular restoration
            cost-share agreement, contract, or easement, and associated HFRP
            restoration plan; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Other factors identified in a HFRP sign-up notice.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS may place higher priority on certain forest ecosystems based
            regions of the State or multi-State area where restoration of
            forestland may better achieve NRCS programmatic and sign-up goals
            and objectives.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notwithstanding any limitation of this part, NRCS may enroll
            eligible lands at any time in order to encompass project areas
            subject to multiple land ownership or otherwise to achieve program
            objectives. Similarly, NRCS may, at any time, exclude otherwise
            eligible lands if the participation of the adjacent landowners is
            essential to the successful restoration of the forest ecosystem and
            those adjacent landowners are unwilling to participate.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If available funds are insufficient to accept the highest ranked
            application, and the applicant is not interested in reducing the
            acres offered to match available funding, NRCS may select a lower
            ranked application that can be fully funded. In cases where HFRP
            funds are not sufficient to cover the costs of an application
            selected for funding, the applicant may lower the cost of the
            application by changing the duration of the easement or agreement 
            <PRTPAGE P='494' />
            or reducing the acreage offered, unless these changes result in a
            reduction of the application ranking score below that of the score
            of the next available application on the ranking list.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6263'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:C:625:-:625.7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        625.7
      </num>
      <head>
        Enrollment of easements, contracts, and agreements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='625' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              625.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Enrollment of easements, contracts, and agreements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Offers of enrollment.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Based on the priority ranking, NRCS will notify an affected
            landowner of tentative acceptance into the program. This notice of
            tentative acceptance into the program does not bind NRCS or the
            United States to enroll the proposed project in HFRP, nor does it
            bind the landowner to convey an easement, or to contract or agree to
            HFRP activities. The letter notifies the landowner that NRCS intends
            to continue the enrollment process on their land unless otherwise
            notified by the landowner.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Acceptance of offer of enrollment.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An agreement to purchase or a restoration cost-share agreement or
            contract will be presented by NRCS to the landowner which will
            describe the easement, agreement, or contract area; the easement,
            agreement, or contract terms and conditions; and other terms and
            conditions for participation that may be required by NRCS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Effect of the acceptance of the offer.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             After the agreement to purchase or restoration cost-share agreement
            or contract is executed by NRCS and the landowner, the land will be
            considered enrolled in the HFRP. For easements, NRCS will proceed
            with various easement acquisition activities, which may include
            conducting a survey of the easement area, securing necessary
            subordination agreements, procuring title insurance, and conducting
            other activities necessary to record the easement or implement the
            HFRP, as appropriate for the enrollment option being considered. For
            restoration cost-share agreements and contracts, the landowner will
            proceed to implement the restoration plan with technical assistance
            and cost-share from NRCS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Withdrawal of offers.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Prior to execution of an agreement to purchase, a restoration
            cost-share agreement, or contract between the United States and the
            landowner, NRCS may withdraw the land from enrollment at any time
            due to lack of availability of funds, inability to clear title, or
            other reasons. An agreement to purchase will be void, and the offer
            withdrawn, if not executed by the landowner within the time
            specified.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6264'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:C:625:-:625.8
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        625.8
      </num>
      <head>
        Compensation for easements and 30-year contracts.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='625' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              625.8
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Compensation for easements and 30-year contracts.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Determination of easement payment rates.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS will offer to pay not less than 75 percent, nor more than 100
            percent of the fair market value of the enrolled land during the
            period the land is subject to the easement, less the fair market
            value of the land encumbered by the easement for permanent easements
            or easements for the maximum duration allowed under State law.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS will offer to pay not more than 75 percent of the fair market
            value of the enrolled land, less the fair market value of the land
            encumbered by the easement for 30-year easements or 30-year
            contracts.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Acceptance and use of contributions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS may accept and use contributions of non-Federal funds to make
            payments under this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Acceptance of offered easement or 30-year contract compensation.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS will not acquire any easement or 30-year contract unless the
            landowner accepts the amount of the payment that is offered by NRCS.
            The payment may or may not equal the fair market value of the
            interests and rights to be conveyed by the landowner under the
            easement or 30-year contract. By voluntarily participating in the
            program, a landowner waives any claim to additional compensation
            based on fair market value.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payments may be made in a single payment or no more than 10 annual
            payments of equal or unequal size, as agreed to between NRCS and the
            landowner.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a landowner believes they may be eligible for a bargain sale tax
            deduction that is the difference between the fair market value of
            the easement conveyed to the United States and the easement payment
            made to the landowner, it is the landowner&apos;s responsibility to
            discuss those matters with the Internal Revenue Service. NRCS
            disclaims any representations concerning 
            <PRTPAGE P='495' />
            the tax implications of any easement or cost-share transaction.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Per acre payments.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If easement payments are calculated on a per acre basis, adjustment
            to stated easement payment will be made based on final determination
            of acreage.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Ecosystem Services Credits for Conservation Improvements.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             USDA recognizes that environmental benefits will be achieved by
            implementing conservation practices and activities funded through
            HFRP, and that environmental credits may be gained as a result of
            implementing activities compatible with the purposes of a HFRP
            easement, 30-year contract, or restoration cost-share agreement.
            NRCS asserts no direct or indirect interest in these credits.
            However, NRCS retains the authority to ensure the requirements of a
            HFRP easement, contract, cost-share agreement, or restoration plan
            are met consistent with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='625' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
                625.9
              </subref>
            </aref>
             through 625.13 of this part. Where activities required under an
            environmental credit agreement may affect land covered under a HFRP
            easement, restoration cost-share agreement, or 30-year contract,
            participants are highly encouraged to request a compatibility
            assessment from NRCS prior to entering into such agreements.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6265'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:C:625:-:625.9
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        625.9
      </num>
      <head>
        10-year restoration cost-share agreements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='625' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
              625.9
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          10-year restoration cost-share agreements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The restoration plan developed under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='625' sect='13' psec='' tq='N'>
                625.13
              </subref>
            </aref>
             forms the basis for the 10-year cost-share agreement and its terms
            are incorporated therein.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A 10-year cost-share agreement will:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Incorporate all portions of a restoration plan;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be for a period of 10 years;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Include all provisions as required by law or statute;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Specify the requirements for operation and maintenance of applied
            conservation practices;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Include any participant reporting and recordkeeping requirements to
            determine compliance with the agreement and HFRP;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be signed by the participant;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Identify the amount and extent of cost-share assistance that NRCS
            will provide for the adoption or implementation of the approved
            conservation treatment identified in the restoration plan; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Include any other provision determined necessary or appropriate by
            the NRCS representative.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Once the participant and NRCS have signed a 10-year cost-share
            agreement, the land will be considered enrolled in HFRP.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State Conservationist may, by mutual agreement with the parties
            to the 10-year cost-share agreement, consent to the termination of
            the restoration agreement where:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The parties to the 10-year cost-share agreement are unable to
            comply with the terms of the restoration agreement as the result of
            conditions beyond their control;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Compliance with the terms of the 10-year cost-share agreement would
            work a severe hardship on the parties to the agreement; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Termination of the 10-year cost-share agreement would, as
            determined by the State Conservationist, be in the public interest.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a 10-year cost-share agreement is terminated in accordance with
            the provisions of this section, the State Conservationist may allow
            the participants to retain any cost-share payments received under
            the 10-year cost-share agreement where forces beyond the
            participant&apos;s control prevented compliance with the agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6266'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:C:625:-:625.10
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        625.10
      </num>
      <head>
        Cost-share payments.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='625' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
              625.10
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Cost-share payments.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS may share the cost with landowners of restoring land enrolled
            in HFRP as provided in the HFRP restoration plan. The HFRP
            restoration plan may include periodic manipulation to maximize fish
            and wildlife habitat and preserve forest ecosystem functions and
            values, and measures that are needed to provide the Landowner
            Protections under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 7(b)(4)
            </aref>
             or 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 10(a)(1) of
            </aref>
             the ESA, including the cost of any permit.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Landowner Protections may be made available to landowners enrolled
            in the HFRP who agree, for a specified period, to restore, protect,
            enhance, maintain, and manage the habitat conditions on their land
            in a manner that is reasonably expected to result in a net
            conservation benefit that contributes to the recovery of listed
            species 
            <PRTPAGE P='496' />
            under the ESA, candidate, or other species covered by this
            regulation. These protections operate with lands enrolled in the
            HFRP and are valid for as long as the landowner is in compliance
            with the terms and conditions of such assurances, any associated
            permit, the easement, contract, or the restoration agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the Landowner Protections, or any associated permit, require the
            adoption of a conservation practice or measure in addition to the
            conservation practices and measures identified in the applicable
            HFRP restoration plan, NRCS and the landowner will incorporate the
            conservation practice or measure into the HFRP restoration plan as
            an item eligible for cost-share assistance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Failure to perform planned management activities can result in
            violation of the easement, 10-year cost-share agreement, or the
            agreement under which Landowner Protections have been provided. NRCS
            will work with landowners to plan appropriate management activities.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The amount and terms and conditions of the cost-share assistance
            will be subject to the following restrictions on the costs of
            establishing or installing NRCS approved conservation practices or
            implementing measures specified in the HFRP restoration plan:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             On enrolled land subject to a permanent easement or an easement for
            the maximum duration allowed under State law, NRCS will offer to pay
            not less than 75 percent nor more than 100 percent of the average
            cost, and;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             On enrolled land subject to a 30-year easement or 30-year contract,
            NRCS will offer to pay not more than 75 percent of the average cost.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             On enrolled land subject to a 10-year cost-share agreement without
            an associated easement, NRCS will offer to pay not more than 50
            percent of the average costs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Cost-share payments may be made only upon a determination by NRCS
            that an eligible conservation practice or measure has been
            established in compliance with appropriate standards and
            specifications. Identified conservation practices and measures may
            be implemented by the landowner or other designee.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Cost-share payments may be made for the establishment and
            installation of additional eligible conservation practices and
            measures, or the maintenance or replacement of an eligible
            conservation practice or measure, but only if NRCS determines the
            practice or measure is needed to meet the objectives of HFRP, and
            the failure of the original conservation practices or measures was
            due to reasons beyond the control of the landowner.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6267'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:C:625:-:625.11
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        625.11
      </num>
      <head>
        Easement participation requirements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='625' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
              625.11
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Easement participation requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To enroll land in HFRP through a permanent easement, an easement
            for the maximum duration allowed under State law, or 30-year
            enrollment option, a landowner will grant an easement to the United
            States. The easement deed will require that the easement area be
            maintained in accordance with HFRP goals and objectives for the
            duration of the term of the easement, including the restoration,
            protection, enhancement, maintenance, and management of habitat and
            forest ecosystem functions and values.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For the duration of its term, the easement will require, at a
            minimum, that the landowner and the landowner&apos;s heirs,
            successors, and assignees, will cooperate in the restoration,
            protection, enhancement, maintenance, and management of the land in
            accordance with the easement and with the terms of the HFRP
            restoration plan. In addition, the easement will grant to the United
            States, through NRCS:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A right of access to the easement area by NRCS or its
            representative;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The right to determine and permit compatible uses on the easement
            area and specify the amount, method, timing, intensity, and duration
            of the compatible use, if such use is consistent with the long-term
            protection and enhancement of the purposes for which the easement
            was established;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The rights, title, and interest to the easement area as specified
            in the conservation easement deed; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The right to perform restoration, protection, enhancement,
            maintenance, and management activities on the easement area.
            <PRTPAGE P='497' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The landowner will convey title to the easement which is acceptable
            to NRCS. The landowner will warrant that the easement granted to the
            United States is superior to the rights of all others, except for
            exceptions to the title which are deemed acceptable by NRCS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The landowner will:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Comply with the terms of the easement;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Comply with all terms and conditions of any associated agreement or
            contract;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Agree to the long-term restoration, protection, enhancement,
            maintenance, and management of the easement in accordance with the
            terms of the easement and related agreements;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Have the option to enter into an agreement with governmental or
            private organizations to assist in carrying out any landowner
            responsibilities on the easement area; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Agree that each person who is subject to the easement will be
            jointly and severally responsible for compliance with the easement
            and the provisions of this part, and for any refunds or payment
            adjustment which may be required for violation of any terms or
            conditions of the easement or the provisions of this part.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6268'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:C:625:-:625.12
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        625.12
      </num>
      <head>
        30-year contracts.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='625' sect='12' psec='' tq='N'>
              625.12
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          30-year contracts.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To enroll land in HFRP through the 30-year contract option, a
            landowner will sign a 30-year contract with NRCS. The contract will
            require that the contract area be maintained in accordance with HFRP
            goals and objectives for the duration of the term of the contract,
            including the restoration, protection, enhancement, maintenance, and
            management of habitat and forest ecosystem functions and values.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For the duration of its term, the 30-year contract will require, at
            a minimum, that the landowner and the landowner&apos;s assignees,
            will cooperate in the restoration, protection, enhancement,
            maintenance, and management of the land in accordance with the
            contract and with the terms of the HFRP restoration plan. In
            addition, the contract will grant to the United States through NRCS:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A right of access to the contract area by NRCS or its
            representative;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The right to allow such activities by the landowner as hunting and
            fishing, managed timber harvest, or periodic haying or grazing, if
            such use is consistent with the long-term protection and enhancement
            of the purposes for which the contract was established;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The right to specify the amount, method, timing, intensity, and
            duration of the activities listed in paragraph (b)(2) of this
            section, as incorporated into the terms of the contract; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The right to perform restoration, protection, enhancement,
            maintenance, and management activities on the contract area.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The landowner will:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Comply with the terms of the contract;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Comply with all terms and conditions of any associated agreement or
            contract; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Agree to the long-term restoration, protection, enhancement,
            maintenance, and management of the contract area in accordance with
            the terms of the contract and related agreements.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A 30-year contract will:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be signed by the participant;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Identify the amount and extent of cost-share assistance that NRCS
            will provide for the adoption or implementation of the approved
            conservation treatment identified in the restoration plan; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Include any other provision determined necessary or appropriate by
            the NRCS representative.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Once the landowner and NRCS have signed a 30-year contract, the
            land will be considered enrolled in HFRP.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6269'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:C:625:-:625.13
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        625.13
      </num>
      <head>
        The HFRP restoration plan development and Landowner Protections.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='625' sect='13' psec='' tq='N'>
              625.13
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          The HFRP restoration plan development and Landowner Protections.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The development of the HFRP restoration plan will be made through
            an NRCS representative, who will confer with the program participant
            and with the FWS and NMFS, as appropriate.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The HFRP restoration plan will specify the manner in which the
            enrolled land under easement, 30-year 
            <PRTPAGE P='498' />
            contract, or 10-year cost-share agreement will be restored,
            protected, enhanced, maintained, and managed to accomplish the goals
            of the program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Eligible restoration practices and measures may include land
            management, vegetative, and structural practices and measures that
            will restore and enhance habitat conditions for listed species,
            candidate, State-listed, and other species identified by the Chief
            for special funding consideration. To the extent practicable,
            eligible practices and measures will improve biodiversity and
            optimize the sequestration of carbon through management that
            maintains diverse and high quality native forests to accomplish the
            goals of the restoration plan. NRCS, in coordination with FWS and
            NMFS, will determine the conservation practices and measures. The
            State Conservationist will develop and make available to the public
            a list of eligible practices, and will determine payment rates and
            cost-share percentages within statutory limits.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Landowner Protections. An HFRP participant who enrolls land in HFRP
            and whose conservation treatment results in a net conservation
            benefit for listed, candidate, or other species, may request such
            Landowner Protections as follows:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Incidental Take Authorization.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS will extend to participants the incidental take authorization
            received by NRCS from FWS or NMFS through biological opinions issued
            as part of the interagency cooperation process under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 7(a)(2) of
            </aref>
             the ESA;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS will provide assurances, as a provision of the restoration
            plan, that when a participant is provided authorization for
            incidental take of a listed species, NRCS will not require
            management activities related to that species to be undertaken in
            addition to or different from those specified in the restoration
            plan without the participant&apos;s consent;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The program participant will be covered by the authorization to
            NRCS for incidental take associated with restoration actions or
            management activities. The incidental take may include a return to
            baseline conditions at the end of the applicable period, if the
            landowner so desires.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provided the landowner has acted in good faith and without intent
            to violate the terms of the HFRP restoration plan, NRCS will pursue
            all appropriate options with the participant to avoid termination in
            the event of the need to terminate an HFRP restoration plan that is
            being properly implemented; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_1_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the 30-year contract or 10-year restoration cost-share agreement
            is terminated, any requested assurances, including an incidental
            take authorization under this section, provided by NRCS will be
            voided. As such, the landowner will be responsible to FWS or NMFS
            for any violations of the ESA.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             SHA or CCAA.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS will provide technical assistance to help participants design
            and use their HFRP restoration plan for the dual purposes of
            qualifying for HFRP financial assistance and as a basis for entering
            into a SHA or CCAA with FWS or NMFS and receiving an associated
            permit under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 10(a)(1)(a) of
            </aref>
             the ESA.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In exchange for a commitment to undertake conservation measures,
            the landowner may receive a permit under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 10 of
            </aref>
             the ESA from FWS or NMFS authorizing incidental take of species
            covered by the SHA or CCAA that may occur as a result of restoration
            actions, management activities, and for a listed species covered by
            a SHA, a return to baseline conditions at the end of the applicable
            period.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All SHAs and associated permits issued by FWS or NMFS are subject
            to the Safe Harbor Policy jointly adopted by FWS and NMFS according
            to the regulations at 
            <aref type='FREGIST'>
              64 FR 32717
            </aref>
             or applicable subsequently adopted policy, and SHAs with FWS also
            are subject to regulations at 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              50 CFR 
              <subref title='50' part='17' sect='22' psec='#c' tq='N'>
                17.22(c)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             for endangered species or 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              50 CFR 
              <subref title='50' part='17' sect='32' psec='#c' tq='N'>
                17.32(c)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             for threatened species, or applicable subsequent regulations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All CCAAs and associated permits issued by FWS or NMFS are subject
            to the CCAAs policy jointly adopted by FWS and NMFS according to the
            regulations at 
            <aref type='FREGIST'>
              64 FR 32706
            </aref>
             or applicable subsequently adopted policy, and CCAAs with FWS also
            are subject to 
            <PRTPAGE P='499' />
            regulations at 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              50 CFR 
              <subref title='50' part='17' sect='22' psec='#d' tq='N'>
                17.22(d)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             for endangered species or 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              50 CFR 
              <subref title='50' part='17' sect='32' psec='#d' tq='N'>
                17.32(d)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             for threatened species, or applicable subsequent regulations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='d_2_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the 30-year contract or 10-year restoration cost-share agreement
            is terminated, the landowner will be responsible to notify and
            coordinate with FWS and NMFS or any other relevant party to the
            specific SHA or CCAA, as appropriate, for any modifications related
            to the SHA or CCAA.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6270'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:C:625:-:625.14
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        625.14
      </num>
      <head>
        Modification of the HFRP restoration plan.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='625' sect='14' psec='' tq='N'>
              625.14
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Modification of the HFRP restoration plan.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The State Conservationist may approve modifications to the HFRP
          restoration plan that do not modify or void provisions of the
          easement, contract, restoration agreement, or Landowner Protections,
          and are consistent with applicable law. NRCS may obtain and receive
          input from the landowner and coordinate with FWS and NMFS to determine
          whether a modification to the restoration plan is justified. Any HFRP
          restoration plan modification must meet HFRP program objectives, and
          must result in equal or greater wildlife benefits and ecological and
          economic values to the United States. Modifications to the HFRP
          restoration plan which are substantial and affect provisions of the
          contract, restoration cost-share agreement, or Landowner Protections
          will require agreement from the landowner, any relevant party to a
          specific SHA or CCAA, FWS, or NMFS, as appropriate, and may require
          execution of an amended contract or 10-year restoration cost-share
          agreement and modification to the Landowner Protection provisions.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6271'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:C:625:-:625.15
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        625.15
      </num>
      <head>
        Transfer of land.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='625' sect='15' psec='' tq='N'>
              625.15
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Transfer of land.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Offers voided prior to enrollment.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any transfer of the property prior to the applicant&apos;s
            acceptance into the program will void the offer of enrollment. At
            the option of the State Conservationist, an offer can be extended to
            the new landowner if the new landowner agrees to the same or more
            restrictive easement, agreement, and contract terms and conditions.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Actions following transfer of land.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For easements or 30-year contracts with multiple annual payments,
            any remaining payments will be made to the original landowner unless
            NRCS receives an assignment of proceeds.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Eligible cost-share payments will be made to the new landowner upon
            presentation of an assignment of rights or other evidence that title
            has passed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Landowner protections will be available to the new landowner, and
            the new landowner will be held responsible for assuring completion
            of all measures and conservation practices required by the contract,
            deed, and incidental take permit.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a SHA or CCAA is involved, the previous and new landowner may
            coordinate with FWS or NMFS, as appropriate, to transfer the
            agreement and associated permits and assurances.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The landowner and NRCS may agree to transfer a 30-year contract.
            The transferee must be determined by NRCS to be eligible to
            participate in HFRP and must assume full responsibility under the
            contract, including operation and maintenance of all conservation
            practices and measures required by the contract.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Claims to payments.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             With respect to any and all payments owed to a person, the United
            States will bear no responsibility for any full payments or partial
            distributions of funds between the original landowner and the
            landowner&apos;s successor. In the event of a dispute or claim on
            the distribution of cost-share payments, NRCS may withhold payments
            without the accrual of interest pending an agreement or adjudication
            on the rights to the funds.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6272'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:C:625:-:625.16
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        625.16
      </num>
      <head>
        Violations and remedies.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='625' sect='16' psec='' tq='N'>
              625.16
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Violations and remedies.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Easement violations.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the event of a violation of the easement or any associated
            agreement involving a landowner, the landowner will be given
            reasonable notice and an opportunity to voluntarily correct the
            violation within 30 days of the date of the notice, or such
            additional time as the State Conservationist determines is necessary
            to correct the violation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notwithstanding paragraph (a)(1) of this section, NRCS reserves the
            right to enter upon the easement area at any time to remedy
            deficiencies or easement violations. Such entry may be made at the
            discretion of NRCS 
            <PRTPAGE P='500' />
            when such actions are deemed necessary to protect important listed
            species, candidate species, and forest ecosystem functions and
            values or other rights of the United States under the easement. The
            landowner will be liable for any costs incurred by the United States
            as a result of the landowner&apos;s negligence or failure to comply
            with easement or contractual obligations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In addition to any and all legal and equitable remedies as may be
            available to the United States under applicable law, NRCS may
            withhold any easement and cost-share payments owed to landowners at
            any time there is a material breach of the easement covenants,
            associated restoration agreement, or any associated contract. Such
            withheld funds may be used to offset costs incurred by the United
            States in any remedial actions or retained as damages pursuant to
            court order or settlement agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The United States will be entitled to recover any and all
            administrative and legal costs, including attorney&apos;s fees or
            expenses, associated with any enforcement or remedial action.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              30-year contract and 10-year cost-share agreement violations.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If NRCS determines that a participant is in violation of the terms
            of a 30-year contract, or 10-year cost-share agreement, or documents
            incorporated by reference into the 30-year contract or 10-year
            cost-share agreement, the landowner will be given reasonable notice
            and an opportunity to voluntarily correct the violation within 30
            days of the date of the notice, or such additional time as the State
            Conservationist determines is necessary to correct the violation. If
            the violation continues, the State Conservationist may terminate the
            30-year contract or 10-year cost-share agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph (b)(1) of this section,
            a 10-year cost-share agreement or 30-year contract termination is
            effective immediately upon a determination by the State
            Conservationist that the participant has: submitted false
            information; filed a false claim; engaged in any act for which a
            finding of ineligibility for payments is permitted under this part;
            or taken actions NRCS deems to be sufficiently purposeful or
            negligent to warrant a termination without delay.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If NRCS terminates a 10-year cost-share agreement or 30-year
            contract, the participant will forfeit all rights for future
            payments under the 10-year cost-share agreement or 30-year contract,
            and must refund all or part of the payments received, plus interest,
            and liquidated damages.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When making any 30-year contract or 10-year cost-share agreement
            termination decisions, the State Conservationist may provide
            equitable relief in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='635' tq='N'>
                635
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6273'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:C:625:-:625.17
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        625.17
      </num>
      <head>
        Payments not subject to claims.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='625' sect='17' psec='' tq='N'>
              625.17
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Payments not subject to claims.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Any cost-share, contract, or easement payment or portion thereof due
          any person under this part will be allowed without regard to any claim
          or lien in favor of any creditor, except agencies of the United States
          Government.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6274'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:C:625:-:625.18
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        625.18
      </num>
      <head>
        Assignments.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='625' sect='18' psec='' tq='N'>
              625.18
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Assignments.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Any person entitled to any cash payment under this program may assign
          the right to receive such cash payments in whole or in part.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6275'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:C:625:-:625.19
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        625.19
      </num>
      <head>
        Appeals.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='625' sect='19' psec='' tq='N'>
              625.19
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Appeals.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A person participating in the HFRP may obtain a review of any
            administrative determination concerning eligibility for
            participation utilizing the administrative appeal regulations
            provided in 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR parts 
              <subref title='7' part='11' tq='N'>
                11
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='614' tq='N'>
                614
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Before a person may seek judicial review of any administrative
            action concerning eligibility for program participation under this
            part, the person must exhaust all administrative appeal procedures
            set forth in paragraph (a) of this section, and for purposes of
            judicial review, no decision will be a final agency action except a
            decision of the Chief under these procedures.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any appraisals, market analysis, or supporting documentation that
            may be used by NRCS in determining property value are considered
            confidential information, and will only be disclosed as determined
            at the sole discretion of NRCS in accordance with applicable law.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Enforcement actions undertaken by NRCS in furtherance of its
            federally 
            <PRTPAGE P='501' />
            held property rights are under the jurisdiction of the Federal
            District Court, and are not subject to review under administrative
            appeal regulations.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6276'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:C:625:-:625.20
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        625.20
      </num>
      <head>
        Scheme and device.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='625' sect='20' psec='' tq='N'>
              625.20
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Scheme and device.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If it is determined by NRCS that a person has employed a scheme or
            device to defeat the purposes of this part, any part of any program
            payment otherwise due or paid to such person during the applicable
            period may be withheld or be required to be refunded with interest
            thereon, as determined appropriate by NRCS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A scheme or device includes, but is not limited to, coercion,
            fraud, misrepresentation, depriving any other person of payments for
            10-year cost-share agreements, contracts, or easements for the
            purpose of obtaining a payment to which a person would otherwise not
            be entitled.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A person who succeeds to the responsibilities under this part will
            report in writing to NRCS any interest of any kind in enrolled land
            that is held by a predecessor or any lender. A failure of full
            disclosure will be considered a scheme or device under this section.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>