<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol3'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97
    </extid>
    <num>
      97
    </num>
    <head>
      PLANT VARIETY AND PROTECTION
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          Plant Variety Protection Act, as amended, 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='2321' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/2321.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 2321
            </subref>
          </aref>
          <E T='03'>
            et seq.
          </E>
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 42435
          </aref>
          , Aug. 9, 1993, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='4079'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.1
      </num>
      <head>
        General.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 42435
        </aref>
        , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          60 FR 17189
        </aref>
        , Apr. 4, 1995]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Certificates of protection are issued by the Plant Variety Protection
          office 
          <PRTPAGE P='261' />
          for new, distinct, uniform, and stable varieties of sexually
          reproduced or tubor propagated plants. Each certificate of plant
          variety protection certifies that the breeder has the right, during
          the term of the protection, to prevent others from selling the
          variety, offering it for sale, reproducing it, importing or exporting
          it, conditioning it, stocking it, or using it in producing a hybrid or
          different variety from it, as provided by the Act.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 42435
          </aref>
          , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            60 FR 17189
          </aref>
          , Apr. 4, 1995]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4080'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Meaning of words.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 42435
        </aref>
        , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          60 FR 17189
        </aref>
        , Apr. 4, 1995; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          61 FR 248
        </aref>
        , Jan. 4, 1996; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          70 FR 28785
        </aref>
        , May 19, 2005]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Meaning of words.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Words used in the regulations in this part in the singular form will
          import the plural, and vice versa, as the case may demand. The
          definitions of terms contained in the Act shall apply to such terms
          when used in this part. As used throughout the regulations in this
          part, unless the context requires otherwise, the following terms will
          be construed to mean:
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Abandoned application.
          </E>
           An application which has not been pursued to completion within the
          time allowed by the Office or has been voluntarily abandoned.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Act.
          </E>
           The Plant Variety Protection Act (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='2321' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/2321.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 2321
            </subref>
          </aref>
           et seq.).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Administrator.
          </E>
           The Administrator of the Agricultural Marketing Service of the U.S.
          Department of Agriculture, or any other officer or employee of the
          Department of Agriculture to whom authority has heretofore been
          delegated, or to whom authority may hereafter be delegated, to act in
          his or her stead.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Applicant.
          </E>
           The person who applied for a certificate of plant variety protection.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Application.
          </E>
           An application for plant variety protection under the Act.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Assignee.
          </E>
           A person to whom an owner assigns his/her rights in whole or in part.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Board.
          </E>
           The Plant Variety Protection Board appointed by the Secretary.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Certificate.
          </E>
           A certificate of plant variety protection issued under the Act by the
          Office.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Certified seed.
          </E>
           Seed which has been determined by an official seed certifying agency
          to conform to standards of genetic purity and identity as to variety,
          which standards have been approved by the Secretary.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Commissioner.
          </E>
           The Examiner in Chief of the Office.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Decision and order.
          </E>
           Includes the Secretary&apos;s findings of fact; conclusions with
          respect to all material issues of fact and law, as well as the reasons
          or basis therefor; and order.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Examiner.
          </E>
           An employee of the Plant Variety Protection Office who determines
          whether a certificate is entitled to be issued. The term shall, in all
          cases, include the Commissioner.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Foreign application.
          </E>
           An application for plant variety protection filed in a foreign
          country.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Hearing Clerk.
          </E>
           The Hearing Clerk, U.S. Department of Agriculture, Washington, DC.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Hearing Officer.
          </E>
           An Administrative Law Judge, U.S. Department of Agriculture, or other
          officer or employee of the Department of Agriculture, duly assigned to
          preside at a hearing held pursuant to the rules of this part.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Office or Plant Variety Protection Office.
          </E>
           The Plant Variety Protection Office, Science and Technology Programs,
          AMS, USDA.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Official Journal.
          </E>
           The “Official Journal of the Plant Variety Protection Office.”
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Owner.
          </E>
           A breeder who developed or discovered and developed a variety for
          which plant variety protection may be applied for under the Act, or a
          person to whom the rights to such variety have been assigned or
          transferred.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Person.
          </E>
           An individual, partnership, corporation, association, government
          agency, or other business or governmental entity.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Secretary.
          </E>
           The Secretary of Agriculture of the United States or any other
          officer or employee of the U.S. Department of Agriculture, to whom
          authority has heretofore been delegated, or to whom authority may
          hereafter be delegated to act in his or her stead.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Seed certifying agency.
          </E>
           It shall be defined as set forth in the Federal Seed Act (
          <aref target='_blank' href='http://frwebgate.access.gpo.gov/cgi-bin/getpage.cgi?dbname=76_statutes_at_large&amp;position=all&amp;page=1275'>
            53 Stat. 1275
          </aref>
          ).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Sale for other than seed purposes.
          </E>
           The transfer of title to and possession of the seed by the owner to a
          grower or other person, for reproduction for the 
          <PRTPAGE P='262' />
          owner, for testing, or for experimental use, and not for commercial
          sale of the seed or the reproduced seed for planting purposes.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 42435
          </aref>
          , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            60 FR 17189
          </aref>
          , Apr. 4, 1995; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            61 FR 248
          </aref>
          , Jan. 4, 1996; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            70 FR 28785
          </aref>
          , May 19, 2005]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4081'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Plant Variety Protection Board.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 42435
        </aref>
        , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          61 FR 248
        </aref>
        , Jan. 4, 1996]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Plant Variety Protection Board.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Plant Variety Protection Board shall consist of 14 members
            appointed for a 2-year term. The Board shall be appointed every 2
            years and shall consist of individuals who are experts in various
            areas of varietal development. The membership of the Board, which
            shall include farmer representation, shall be drawn approximately
            equally from the private or seed industry sector and from the
            government or public sector. No member shall be eligible to act on
            any matter involving any appeal or questions under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 44 of
            </aref>
             the Act, in which the member or his or her employer has a direct
            financial interest.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The functions of the Board are to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Advise the Secretary concerning adoption of rules and regulations
            to facilitate the proper administration of the Act;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Make advisory decisions on all appeals from the examiner or
            Commissioner;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Advise the Secretary on the declaration of a protected variety open
            to use in the public interest; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Advise the Secretary on any other matters under the regulations in
            this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The proceedings of the Board shall be conducted in accordance with
            the Federal Advisory Committee Act, Administrative Regulations of
            the U.S. Department of Agriculture (
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='25' tq='N'>
                25
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ), and such additional operating procedures as are adopted by
            members of the Board.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 42435
          </aref>
          , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            61 FR 248
          </aref>
          , Jan. 4, 1996]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4082'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.5
      </num>
      <head>
        General requirements.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 42435
        </aref>
        , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          60 FR 17189
        </aref>
        , Apr. 4, 1995; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          61 FR 248
        </aref>
        , Jan. 4, 1996; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          70 FR 28785
        </aref>
        , May 19, 2005]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Protection under the Act shall be afforded only as follows:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Nationals and residents of the United States shall be eligible to
            receive all of the protection under the Act.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Nationals and residents of Member States of the International Union
            for the Protection of New Varieties of Plants (including states
            which are members of an intergovernmental organization which is a
            UPOV member) shall be eligible to receive the same protection under
            the Act as is provided to nationals of the United States.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Persons who are not entitled to protection under paragraph (a)(1)
            or (2) of this section, and who are nationals of a foreign state
            which is not a member of the International Union for the Protection
            of New Varieties of Plants, shall be entitled to only so much of the
            protection provided under the Act, as is afforded by such foreign
            state to nationals of the United States, for the same genus and
            species under the laws of such foreign state in effect at the time
            that the application for protection under the Act is filed, except
            where further protection under the Act must be provided in order to
            avoid the violation of a treaty to which the United States is a
            party.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Applications for certificates shall be made to the Plant Variety
            Protection Office. An application shall consist of:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A completed application form, except that the section specifying
            that seed of the variety shall be sold by variety name only, as a
            class of certified seed, need not be completed at the time of
            application.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A completed set of the exhibits, as specified in the application
            form, unless the examiner waives submission of certain exhibits as
            unnecessary, based on other claims and evidence presented in
            connection with the application.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Language and legibility: (i) Applications and exhibits must be in
            the English language and legibly written, typed or printed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any interlineation, erasure, cancellation, or other alteration must
            be made in permanent ink before the application is signed and shall
            be clearly initialed and dated by the applicant to indicate
            knowledge of such fact at the time of signing.
            <PRTPAGE P='263' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To determine the extent of reciprocity of the protection to be
            provided under the Act, persons filing an application for plant
            variety protection in the United States under the provisions of
            paragraph (a)(3) of this section shall, upon request 
            <SU>
              1
            </SU>
            <FTREF />
            , furnish the Plant Variety Protection Office with a copy of the
            current plant variety protection laws and regulations for the
            country of which the applicant is a national, and an accurate
            English translation of such laws and regulations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <FTNT>
          <P>
            <SU>
              1
            </SU>
             Copies and translations of foreign laws and regulations will be
            requested only if they are not in the files of the Plant Variety
            Protection Office. Applicants may learn whether such a request will
            be made by writing to the address given in paragraph (c) of this
            section.
          </P>
        </FTNT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Application and exhibit forms shall be issued by the Commissioner.
            (Copies of the forms may be obtained from the Plant Variety
            Protection Office, National Agricultural Library, Room 401, 10301
            Baltimore Avenue, Beltsville, MD 20705-2351).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Effective the date of these regulations and rules of practice, the
            signature of the applicant, or his or her agent or attorney on any
            affidavit or other statement filed pursuant to these regulations and
            rules constitutes a certification by the applicant. The signature
            certifies that all information relied on in any affidavit or
            statement filed in the course of the proceeding is knowingly correct
            and false claims have not been made to mislead.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 42435
          </aref>
          , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            60 FR 17189
          </aref>
          , Apr. 4, 1995; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            61 FR 248
          </aref>
          , Jan. 4, 1996; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            70 FR 28785
          </aref>
          , May 19, 2005]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4083'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.6
      </num>
      <head>
        Application for certificate.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 42435
        </aref>
        , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          60 FR 17189
        </aref>
        , Apr. 4, 1995; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          61 FR 248
        </aref>
        , Jan. 4, 1996; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          70 FR 28785
        </aref>
        , May 19, 2005; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          70 FR 54611
        </aref>
        , Sept. 19, 2005]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Application for certificate.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An application for a plant variety protection certificate shall be
            signed by, or on behalf, of the applicant.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The application shall state the full name, including the full first
            name and the middle initial or name, if any, and the capacity of the
            person executing it.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The fees for filing an application, and search or examination,
            shall be submitted with the application in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='97' sect='175' psec='' tq='N'>
                97.175
              </subref>
            </aref>
             through 97.178.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The applicant shall submit with the application:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A declaration that at least 3,000 seeds of the viable basic seed
            required to reproduce the variety will be deposited in a public
            depository approved by the Commissioner and will be maintained for
            the duration of the certificate; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             With the application for a tuber propagated variety, a declaration
            that a viable cell culture will be deposited in a public depository
            approved by the Commissioner and will be maintained for the duration
            of the certificate; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             With the application for a hybrid from self-incompatible parents, a
            declaration that a plot of vegetative material for each parent will
            be established in a public depository approved by the Commissioner
            and will be maintained for the duration of the certificate.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 42435
          </aref>
          , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            60 FR 17189
          </aref>
          , Apr. 4, 1995; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            61 FR 248
          </aref>
          , Jan. 4, 1996; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            70 FR 28785
          </aref>
          , May 19, 2005; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            70 FR 54611
          </aref>
          , Sept. 19, 2005]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4084'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.7
      </num>
      <head>
        Deposit of Voucher Specimen.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          70 FR 54611
        </aref>
        , Sept. 16, 2005]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Deposit of Voucher Specimen.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Voucher specimen types.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             As regards the deposit of voucher specimen material for purposes of
            plant variety protection applications under 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='2321' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/2321.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 2321
              </subref>
            </aref>
            <E T='03'>
              et seq.
            </E>
            , the term voucher specimen shall include material that is capable
            of self-replication either directly or indirectly. Representative
            examples include seeds, plant tissue cells, cell lines, and plots of
            vegetative material of self-incompatible parental lines of hybrids.
            Seed samples should not be treated with chemicals or coatings.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Need to make a deposit.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Applications for plant variety protection require deposit of a
            voucher specimen of the variety. The deposit shall be acceptable if
            made in accordance with these regulations. Sample packages shall
            meet the packaging and deposit requirements of the depository.
            Samples and correspondence about samples shall be identified,
            minimally, by:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The application number assigned by the Office;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The crop kind, genus and species, and variety denomination; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The name and address of the depositor.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Acceptable depository.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A deposit shall be recognized for the purposes of these regulations
            if made in:
            <PRTPAGE P='264' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The National Center for Genetic Resources Preservation, ARS, USDA,
            1111 South Mason Street, Fort Collins, CO 80521-4500, or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any other depository recognized to be suitable by the Office.
            Suitability will be determined by the Commissioner on the basis of
            the administrative and technical competence, and agreement of the
            depository to comply with the terms and conditions applicable to
            deposits for plant variety protection purposes. The Commissioner may
            seek the advice of impartial consultants on the suitability of a
            depository. The depository must:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Have a continuous existence;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Exist independent of the control of the depositor;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Possess the staff and facilities sufficient to examine the
            viability and quantity of a deposit, and store the deposit in a
            manner which ensures that it is kept viable and uncontaminated;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provide for sufficient safety measures to minimize the risk of
            losing biological material deposited with it;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be impartial and objective;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Refrain from distributing samples while the application is being
            examined and during the term of protection but, after control of the
            sample is transferred by the Office to the depository, furnish
            samples of the deposited material in an expeditious and proper
            manner;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_vii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Have the capability to destroy samples or return samples to the
            Office when requested by the Office; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_viii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (viii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Promptly notify the Office of low viability or low quantity of the
            sample.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A depository seeking status under paragraph (c)(2) of this section
            must direct a communication to the Commissioner which shall:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Indicate the name and address of the depository to which the
            communication relates;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Contain detailed information as to the capacity of the depository
            to comply with the requirements of paragraph (c)(2) of this section,
            including information on its legal status, scientific standing,
            staff, and facilities;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Indicate that the depository intends to be available, for the
            purposes of deposit, to any depositor under these same conditions;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_3_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Where the depository intends to accept for deposit only certain
            kinds of biological material, specify such kinds; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_3_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Indicate the amount of any fees that the depository will, upon
            acquiring the status of suitable depository under paragraph (c)(2)
            of this section, charge for storage, viability statements and
            furnishings of samples of the deposit.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A depository having status under paragraph (c)(2) of this section
            limited to certain kinds of biological material may extend such
            status to additional kinds of biological material by directing a
            communication to the Commissioner in accordance with paragraph
            (c)(3) of this section. If a previous communication under paragraph
            (c)(3) of this section is of record, items in common with the
            previous communication may be incorporated by reference.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Once a depository is recognized to be suitable by the Commissioner
            or has defaulted or discontinued its performance under this section,
            notice thereof will be published in the Official Journal of the
            Plant Variety Protection Office or by other methods typically used
            for dissemination of information related to the procedures of the
            Office.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Time of making an original deposit.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An original deposit of materials for seed-reproduced plants shall
            be made within three months of the filing date of the application or
            prior to issuance of the certificate, whichever occurs first. A
            waiver may be granted for good cause, such as delays in obtaining a
            phytosanitary certificate for the importation of voucher sample
            materials. When the original deposit is made, the applicant must
            promptly submit a statement from a person in a position to
            corroborate the fact, stating that the voucher specimen material
            which is deposited is the variety specifically identified in the
            application as filed. Such statement must be filed in the
            application and must contain the identifying information listed in
            paragraph (b) of this section and:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The name and address of the depository;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The date of deposit;
            <PRTPAGE P='265' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The accession number given by the depository; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A statement that the deposit is capable of reproduction.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Replacement or supplement of deposit.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the depository possessing a deposit determines either that the
            sample viability is low or that the sample quantity is low, and if
            this finding is made during the pendency of an application or during
            the term of protection of the certificate, the Office shall notify
            the depositor of the need for making a replacement or supplemental
            deposit. Such deposits will be governed by the same considerations
            governing the need for making an original deposit under the
            provisions set forth in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='97' sect='7' psec='#d' tq='N'>
                97.7(d)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . Notification to the Office concerning deposit of the replacement
            or supplemental sample shall contain a statement from a person in a
            position to corroborate the fact, stating that the replacement or
            supplemental deposit is of a biological material which is identical
            to that originally deposited.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Term of deposit.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A voucher specimen deposit made in support of an application for
            plant variety protection shall be made for a term of at least twenty
            (20) years. In any case, samples must be stored under agreements
            that would make them available to the Office during the enforceable
            life of the certificate for which the deposit was made.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Viability of deposit.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A deposit of biological material that is capable of
            self-replication either directly or indirectly must be viable at the
            time of deposit and during the term of deposit. Viability may be
            tested by the depository periodically. The test must conclude only
            that the deposited material is capable of reproduction. No evidence
            necessarily is required regarding the ability of the deposited
            material to perform any function described in the application. If a
            viability test indicates that the deposit is not viable upon receipt
            or that the quantity of material is insufficient, the examiner shall
            proceed as if no deposit was made. The examiner will accept the
            conclusion set forth in a viability statement issued by a depository
            recognized under paragraph 97.7(c).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Furnishing of samples.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A deposit must be made under conditions that assure that:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Public access to the deposit will not be available during pendency
            of the application or during the term of protection, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All restrictions on the availability to the public of the deposited
            material will be irrevocably removed upon the abandonment,
            cancellation, expiration, or withdrawal of the certificate.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Examination procedures.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The examiner shall determine, prior to issuance of the certificate,
            in each application if a voucher sample deposit actually made is
            acceptable for plant variety protection purposes.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            70 FR 54611
          </aref>
          , Sept. 16, 2005]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4085'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.8
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.8
      </num>
      <head>
        Specimen requirements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.8
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Specimen requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The applicant may be required by the examiner to furnish
            representative specimens of the variety, or its flower, fruit, or
            seeds, in a quantity and at a specified stage of growth, as may be
            necessary to verify the statements in the application. Such
            specimens shall be packed and forwarded in conformity with
            instructions furnished by the examiner. If the applicant requests
            the examiner to inspect plants in the field before a final decision
            is made, all such inspection costs shall be borne by the applicant
            by payment of fees sufficient to reimburse the Office for all costs,
            including travel, per diem or subsistence, and salary.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Plant specimens submitted in support of an application shall not be
            removed from the Office except by an employee of the Office or other
            person authorized by the Secretary.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Plant specimens submitted to the Office shall, except as provided
            below, and upon request, be returned to the applicant at his or her
            expense after the specimens have served their intended purpose. The
            Commissioner, upon a finding of good cause, may require that certain
            specimens be retained in the Office for indefinite periods of time.
            Specimens which are not returned or not retained as provided above
            shall be destroyed.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4086'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.9
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.9
      </num>
      <head>
        Drawings and photographs.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='266' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.9
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Drawings and photographs.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Drawings or photographs submitted with an application shall
            disclose the distinctive characteristics of the variety.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Drawings or photographs shall be in color when color is a
            distinguishing characteristic of the variety, and the color shall be
            described by use of Nickerson&apos;s or other recognized color
            chart.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Drawings should be sent flat, or may be sent in a suitable mailing
            tube, in accordance with instructions furnished by the Commissioner.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Drawings or photographs submitted with an application shall be
            retained by the Office as part of the application file.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4087'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.10
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.10
      </num>
      <head>
        Parts of an application to be filed together.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.10
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Parts of an application to be filed together.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          All parts of an application, including exhibits, should be submitted
          to the Office together, otherwise, each part shall be accurately and
          clearly referenced to the application.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4088'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.11
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.11
      </num>
      <head>
        Application accepted and filed when received.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 42435
        </aref>
        , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          60 FR 17189
        </aref>
        , Apr. 4, 1995]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.11
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Application accepted and filed when received.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An application, if materially complete when initially submitted,
            shall be accepted and filed to await examination.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If any part of an application is so incomplete, or so defective
            that it cannot be handled as a completed application for
            examination, as determined by the Commissioner, the applicant will
            be notified. The application will be held a maximum of 3 months for
            completion. Applications not completed at the end of the prescribed
            period will be considered abandoned. The application fee in such
            cases will not be refunded.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 42435
          </aref>
          , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            60 FR 17189
          </aref>
          , Apr. 4, 1995]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4089'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.12
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.12
      </num>
      <head>
        Number and filing date of an application.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='12' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.12
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Number and filing date of an application.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Applications shall be numbered and dated in sequence in the order
            received in the Office. Applicants will be informed in writing as
            soon as practicable of the number and effective filing date of the
            application.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An applicant may claim the benefit of the filing date of a prior
            foreign application in accordance with 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 55 of
            </aref>
             the Act. A certified copy of the foreign application shall be filed
            upon request made by the examiner. If a foreign application is not
            in the English language, an English translation, certified as
            accurate by a sworn or official translator, shall be submitted with
            the application.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4090'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.13
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.13
      </num>
      <head>
        When the owner is deceased or legally incapacitated.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='13' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.13
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          When the owner is deceased or legally incapacitated.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          In case of the death of the owner or if the owner is legally
          incapacitated, the legal representative (executor, administrator, or
          guardian) or heir or assignee of the deceased owner may sign as the
          applicant. If an applicant dies between the filing of his or her
          application and the granting of a certificate thereon, the certificate
          may be issued to the legal representative, heir, or assignee, upon
          proper intervention.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4091'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.14
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.14
      </num>
      <head>
        Joint applicants.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='14' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.14
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Joint applicants.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Joint owners shall file a joint application by signing as joint
            applicants.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If an application for certificate is made by two or more persons as
            joint owners, when they were not in fact joint owners, the
            application shall be amended prior to issuance of a certificate by
            filing a corrected application, together with a written explanation
            signed by the original applicants. Such statement shall also be
            signed by the assignee, if any.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If an application has been made by less than all the actual joint
            owners, the application shall be amended by filing a corrected
            application, together with a written explanation, signed by all of
            the joint owners. Such statement shall also be signed by the
            assignee, if any.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a joint owner refuses to join in an application or cannot be
            found after diligent effort, the remaining owner may file an
            application on behalf of him or herself and the missing owner. Such
            application shall be accompanied by a written explanation and shall
            state the last known address of the missing owner. Notice of the
            filing of the application shall be forwarded by the Office to the
            missing owner at the last known address. If such notice is returned
            to the Office undelivered, or if 
            <PRTPAGE P='267' />
            the address of the missing owner is unknown, notice of the filing of
            the application shall be published once in the Official Journal.
            Prior to the issuance of the certificate, a missing owner may join
            in an application by filing a written explanation. A certificate
            obtained by less than all of the joint owners under this paragraph
            conveys the same rights and privileges to said owners as though all
            of the original owners had joined in an application.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4092'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.15
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.15
      </num>
      <head>
        Assigned varieties and certificates.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 42435
        </aref>
        , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          60 FR 17189
        </aref>
        , Apr. 4, 1995]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='15' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.15
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Assigned varieties and certificates.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          In case the whole or a part interest in a variety is assigned, the
          application shall be made by the owner or one of the persons
          identified in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='13' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.13
            </subref>
          </aref>
          . However, the certificate may be issued to the assignee, or jointly
          to the owner and the assignee, when a part interest in a variety is
          assigned.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 42435
          </aref>
          , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            60 FR 17189
          </aref>
          , Apr. 4, 1995]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4093'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.16
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.16
      </num>
      <head>
        Amendment by applicant.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='16' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.16
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Amendment by applicant.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          An application may be amended before or after the first examination
          and action by the Office, after the second or subsequent examination
          or reconsideration as specified in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='107' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.107
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , or when and as specifically required by the examiner. Such amendment
          may include a specification that seed of the variety be sold by
          variety name only as a class of certified seed, if not previously
          specified or if previously declined. Once an affirmative specification
          is made, no amendment to reverse such a specification will be
          permitted unless the variety has not been sold and labeled or
          publication made in any manner that the variety is to be sold by
          variety name, only as a class of certified seed.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4094'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.17
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.17
      </num>
      <head>
        Papers of completed application to be retained.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='17' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.17
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Papers of completed application to be retained.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The papers submitted with a completed application shall be retained by
          the Office except as provided in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='23' psec='#c' tq='N'>
              97.23(c)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          . After issuance of a certificate of protection the Office will
          furnish copies of the application and related papers to any person
          upon payment of the specified fee.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4095'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.18
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.18
      </num>
      <head>
        Applications handled in confidence.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='18' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.18
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Applications handled in confidence.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Pending applications shall be handled in confidence. Except as
            provided below, no information may be given by the Office respecting
            the filing of an application, the pendency of any particular
            application, or the subject matter of any particular application.
            Also, nor will access be given to or copies furnished of any pending
            application or papers relating thereto, without written authority of
            the applicant, or his or her assignee or attorney or agent.
            Exceptions to the above may be made by the Commissioner in
            accordance with 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='5' sect='552' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/5/552.html'>
                5 U.S.C. 552
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
                1.4
              </subref>
               of this title
            </aref>
            , and upon a finding that such action is necessary to the proper
            conduct of the affairs of the Office, or to carry out the provisions
            of any Act of Congress, or as provided in 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              sections 56 or 57 of
            </aref>
             the Act and 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='97' sect='19' psec='' tq='N'>
                97.19
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Abandoned applications shall not be open to public inspection.
            However, if an abandoned application is directly referred to in an
            issued certificate and is available, it may be inspected or copies
            obtained by any person on written request, and with written
            authority received from the applicant. Abandoned applications shall
            not be returned.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Decisions of the Commissioner on abandoned applications not
            otherwise open to public inspection (see paragraph (b) of this
            section) may be published or made available for publication at the
            Commissioner&apos;s discretion. When it is proposed to release such
            a decision, the applicant shall be notified directly or through the
            attorney or agent of record, and a time, not less than 30 days,
            shall be set for presenting objections.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4096'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.19
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.19
      </num>
      <head>
        Publication of pending applications.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 42435
        </aref>
        , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          60 FR 17189
        </aref>
        , Apr. 4, 1995; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          61 FR 248
        </aref>
        , Jan. 4, 1996]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='19' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.19
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Publication of pending applications.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Information relating to pending applications shall be published in the
          Official Journal periodically as determined by the Commissioner to be
          necessary in the public interest. With respect to each application,
          the Official Journal shall show:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Application number and date of filing;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The name of the variety or temporary designation;
            <PRTPAGE P='268' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The name of the kind of seed; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whether the applicant specified that the variety is to be sold by
            variety name only as a class of certified seed, together with a
            limitation in the number of generations that it can be certified.
          </text>
        </P>
        <FP>
          Additional information, such as the name and address of the applicant
          or a brief description of the distinctive features of the variety, may
          be published only upon request or approval received from the
          applicant, at the time the application is filed or at any time before
          the notice of allowance of a certificate is issued.
        </FP>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 42435
          </aref>
          , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            60 FR 17189
          </aref>
          , Apr. 4, 1995; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            61 FR 248
          </aref>
          , Jan. 4, 1996]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4097'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.20
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.20
      </num>
      <head>
        Abandonment for failure to respond within the time limit.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 42435
        </aref>
        , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          60 FR 17189
        </aref>
        , Apr. 4, 1995]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='20' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.20
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Abandonment for failure to respond within the time limit.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as otherwise provided in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='97' sect='104' psec='' tq='N'>
                97.104
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , if an applicant fails to advance actively his or her application
            within 30 days after the date when the last request for action was
            mailed to the applicant by the Office, or within such longer time as
            may be fixed by the Commissioner, the application shall be deemed
            abandoned. The application fee in such cases will not be refunded.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The submission of an amendment to the application, not responsive
            to the last request by the Office for action, and any proceedings
            relative thereto, shall not operate to save the application from
            abandonment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When the applicant makes a bona fide attempt to advance the
            application, and is in substantial compliance with the request for
            action, but has inadvertently failed to comply with some procedural
            requirement, opportunity to comply with the procedural requirement
            shall be given to the applicant before the application shall be
            deemed abandoned. The Commissioner may set a period, not less than
            30 days, to correct any deficiency in the application.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 42435
          </aref>
          , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            60 FR 17189
          </aref>
          , Apr. 4, 1995]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4098'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.21
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.21
      </num>
      <head>
        Extension of time for a reply.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 42435
        </aref>
        , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          61 FR 248
        </aref>
        , Jan. 4, 1996]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='21' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.21
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Extension of time for a reply.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The time for reply by an applicant to a request by the Office for
          certain action, shall be extended by the Commissioner only for good
          and sufficient cause, and for a specified reasonable time. A request
          for extension and appropriate fee shall be filed on or before the
          specified time for reply. In no case shall the mere filing of a
          request for extension require the granting of an extension or state
          the time for reply.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 42435
          </aref>
          , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            61 FR 248
          </aref>
          , Jan. 4, 1996]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4099'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.22
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.22
      </num>
      <head>
        Revival of an application abandoned for failure to reply.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='22' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.22
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Revival of an application abandoned for failure to reply.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          An application abandoned for failure on the part of the applicant to
          advance actively his or her application to its completion, in
          accordance with the regulations in this part, may be revived as a
          pending application within 3 months of such abandonment, upon a
          finding by the Commissioner that the failure was inadvertent or
          unavoidable and without fraudulent intent. A request to revive an
          abandoned application shall be accompanied by a written statement
          showing the cause of the failure to respond, a response to the last
          request for action, and by the specified fee.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4100'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.23
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.23
      </num>
      <head>
        Voluntary withdrawal and abandonment of an application.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 42435
        </aref>
        , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          60 FR 17189
        </aref>
        , Apr. 4, 1995]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='23' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.23
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Voluntary withdrawal and abandonment of an application.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An application may be voluntarily withdrawn or abandoned by
            submitting to the Office a written request for withdrawal or
            abandonment, signed by the applicant or his or her attorney or agent
            of record, if any, or the assignee of record, if any.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An application which has been voluntarily abandoned may be revived
            within 3 months of such abandonment by the payment of the prescribed
            fee and a showing that the abandonment occurred without fraudulent
            intent.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An original application which has been voluntarily withdrawn shall
            be returned to the applicant and may be reconsidered only by
            refiling and payment of a new application fee.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Transitional provision. An applicant whose application is pending
            on April 4, 1995, may notify the Plant Variety Protection Office in
            writing that he or she wishes to withdraw the application and refile
            it under the Plant Variety Protection Act as amended in 
            <PRTPAGE P='269' />
            1994. Payment of the current application fee is required but no
            other formalities are necessary.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 42435
          </aref>
          , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            60 FR 17189
          </aref>
          , Apr. 4, 1995]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4101'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.24
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.24
      </num>
      <head>
        Assignee.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='24' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.24
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Assignee.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The assignee of record of the entire interest in an application is
          entitled to advance actively or abandon the application to the
          exclusion of the applicant.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4102'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.100
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.100
      </num>
      <head>
        Examination of applications.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 42435
        </aref>
        , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          60 FR 17189
        </aref>
        , Apr. 4, 1995]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='100' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.100
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Examination of applications.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             [Reserved]
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Examinations of applications shall include a review of all
            available documents, publications, or other material relating to
            varieties of the species involved in the application, except that if
            there are fundamental defects in the application, as determined by
            the examiner, the examination may be limited to an identification of
            such defects and notification to the applicant of needed corrective
            action. However, matters of form or procedure need not, but may, be
            raised by an examiner until a variety is found to be new, distinct,
            uniform, and stable and entitled to protection.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 42435
          </aref>
          , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            60 FR 17189
          </aref>
          , Apr. 4, 1995]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4103'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.101
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.101
      </num>
      <head>
        Notice of allowance.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='101' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.101
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Notice of allowance.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          If, on examination, it shall appear that the applicant is entitled to
          a certificate, a notice of allowance shall be sent to the applicant or
          his or her attorney or agent of record, if any, calling for the
          payment of the prescribed fee, which fee shall be paid within 1 month
          from the date of the notice of allowance. Thereafter, a fee for
          delayed payment shall be made as required under 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='175' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.175
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4104'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.102
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.102
      </num>
      <head>
        Amendments after allowance.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='102' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.102
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Amendments after allowance.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Amendments to the application, after the notice of allowance is
          issued, may be made, if the certificate has not been issued.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4105'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.103
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.103
      </num>
      <head>
        Issuance of a certificate.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='103' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.103
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Issuance of a certificate.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             After the notice of allowance has been issued, the prescribed fee
            is received by the Office, and the applicant has clearly specified
            whether or not the variety shall be sold by variety name only as a
            class of certified seed, the certificate shall be promptly issued.
            Once an election is made and a certificate issued specifying that
            seed of the variety shall be sold by variety name only as a class of
            certified seed, no waiver of such rights shall be permitted by
            amendment of the certificate.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The certificate shall be delivered or mailed to the owner.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4106'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.104
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.104
      </num>
      <head>
        Application or certificate abandoned.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 42435
        </aref>
        , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          60 FR 17189
        </aref>
        , Apr. 4, 1995; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          70 FR 28785
        </aref>
        , May 19, 2005]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='104' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.104
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Application or certificate abandoned.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as provided in paragraph (c) of this section, if the fee
            specified in the notice of allowance is not paid within 1 month from
            the date of the notice, the application shall be considered
            abandoned.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon request by the Office, the owner shall replenish the viable
            basic seed sample of the variety and shall pay the handling fee for
            replenishment. Upon request, the sample of seed which has been
            replaced shall be returned to the owner, otherwise it shall be
            destroyed. Failure to replenish viable basic seed within 3 months
            from the date of request shall result in the certificate being
            regarded as abandoned. No sooner than 1 year after the date of such
            request, notices of abandoned certificates shall be published in the
            Official Journal, indicating that the variety has become open for
            use by the public and, if previously specified to be sold by variety
            name as “certified seed only,” that such restriction no longer
            applies.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the allowance fee, the viable basic seed sample or the fee for
            delayed payment are submitted within 9 months of the final due date,
            it may be accepted by the Commissioner as though no abandonment had
            occurred. For good cause, the Commissioner may extend for a
            reasonable time the period for submitting a viable basic seed sample
            before declaring the certificate abandoned.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A certificate may be voluntarily abandoned by the applicant or his
            or 
            <PRTPAGE P='270' />
            her attorney or agent of record or the assignee of record by
            notifying the Commissioner in writing. Upon receipt of such notice,
            the Commissioner shall publish a notice in the Official Journal that
            the variety has become open for use by the public, and if previously
            specified to be sold by variety name as “certified seed only,” that
            such restriction no longer applies.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 42435
          </aref>
          , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            60 FR 17189
          </aref>
          , Apr. 4, 1995; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            70 FR 28785
          </aref>
          , May 19, 2005]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4107'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.105
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.105
      </num>
      <head>
        Denial of an application.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 42435
        </aref>
        , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          60 FR 17189
        </aref>
        , Apr. 4, 1995]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='105' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.105
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Denial of an application.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the variety is found by the examiner to be not new, distinct,
            uniform, and stable, the application shall be denied.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In denying an application, the examiner shall cite the reasons the
            application was denied. When a reason involves the citation of
            certain material which is complex, the particular part of the
            material relied on shall be designated as nearly as practicable. The
            pertinence of each reason, if not obvious, shall be clearly
            explained.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If prior domestic certificates are cited as a reason for denial,
            their numbers and dates and the names of the owners shall be stated.
            If prior foreign certificates or rights are cited, as a reason for
            denial, their nationality or country, numbers and dates, and the
            names of the owners shall be stated, and such other data shall be
            furnished, as may be necessary to enable the applicant to identify
            the cited certificates or rights.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If printed publications are cited as a reason for denial, the
            author (if any), title, date, pages or plates, and places of
            publication, or place where a copy can be found shall be given.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When a denial is based on facts known to the examiner, and upon
            request by the applicant, the denial shall be supported by the
            affidavit of the examiner. Such affidavit shall be subject to
            contradiction or explanation by the affidavits of the applicant and
            other persons.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Abandoned applications may not be cited as reasons for denial.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 42435
          </aref>
          , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            60 FR 17189
          </aref>
          , Apr. 4, 1995]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4108'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.106
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.106
      </num>
      <head>
        Reply by applicant; request for reconsideration.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 42435
        </aref>
        , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          60 FR 17190
        </aref>
        , Apr. 4, 1995]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='106' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.106
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Reply by applicant; request for reconsideration.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             After an adverse action by the examiner, the applicant may respond
            to the denial and may request a reconsideration, with or without
            amendment of his or her application. Any amendment shall be
            responsive to the reason or reasons for denial specified by the
            examiner.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To obtain a reconsideration, the applicant shall submit a request
            for reconsideration in writing and shall specifically point out the
            alleged errors in the examiner&apos;s action. The applicant shall
            respond to each reason cited by the examiner as the basis for the
            adverse action. A request for reconsideration of a denial based on a
            faulty form or procedure may be held in abeyance by the Commissioner
            until the question of the variety being new, distinct, uniform, and
            stable is settled.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An applicant&apos;s request for a reconsideration must be a bona
            fide attempt to advance the case to final action. A general
            allegation by the applicant that certain language which he or she
            cites in the application or amendment thereto establishes the
            variety is new, distinct, uniform, and stable without specifically
            explaining how the language distinguishes the alleged new, distinct,
            uniform, and stable variety from the material cited by the examiner
            shall not be grounds for a reconsideration.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 42435
          </aref>
          , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            60 FR 17190
          </aref>
          , Apr. 4, 1995]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4109'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.107
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.107
      </num>
      <head>
        Reconsideration and final action.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 42435
        </aref>
        , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          70 FR 28785
        </aref>
        , May 19, 2005]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='107' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.107
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Reconsideration and final action.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          If, upon reconsideration, the application is denied by the
          Commissioner, the applicant shall be notified by the Commissioner of
          the reason or reasons for denial in the same manner as after the first
          examination. Any such denial shall be final unless appealed by the
          applicant to the Secretary. If the denial is sustained by the
          Secretary on appeal, the denial shall be final subject to appeal to
          the courts, as provided in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='500' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.500
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 42435
          </aref>
          , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            70 FR 28785
          </aref>
          , May 19, 2005]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4110'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.108
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.108
      </num>
      <head>
        Amendments after final action.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 42435
        </aref>
        , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          70 FR 28785
        </aref>
        , May 19, 2005]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='271' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='108' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.108
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Amendments after final action.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             After a final denial by the Commissioner, amendments to the
            application may be made to overcome the reason or reasons for
            denial. The acceptance or refusal of any such amendment by the
            Office and any proceedings relative thereto shall not relieve the
            applicant from the time limit set for an appeal or an abandonment
            for failure to reply.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No amendment of the application can be made in an appeal
            proceeding. After decision on appeal, amendments can only be made in
            accordance with the decision.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 42435
          </aref>
          , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            70 FR 28785
          </aref>
          , May 19, 2005]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4111'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.120
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.120
      </num>
      <head>
        Corrected certificate—office mistake.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='120' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.120
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Corrected certificate—office mistake.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          When a certificate is incorrect because of a mistake in the Office,
          the Commissioner may issue a corrected certificate stating the fact
          and nature of such mistake, under seal, without charge, to be issued
          to the owner and recorded in the records at the Office.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4112'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.121
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.121
      </num>
      <head>
        Corrected certificate—applicant&apos;s mistake.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='121' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.121
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Corrected certificate—applicant&apos;s mistake.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          When a certificate is incorrect because of a mistake by the applicant
          of a clerical or typographical nature, or of minor character, or in
          the description of the variety (including, but not limited to, the use
          of a misleading variety name or a name assigned to a different variety
          of the same species), and the mistake is found by the Commissioner to
          have occurred in good faith and does not require a further
          examination, the Commissioner may, upon payment of the required fee
          and return of the original certificate, correct the certificate by
          issuing a corrected certificate, in accordance with 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 85 of
          </aref>
           the Act. If the mistake requires a reexamination, a correction of the
          certificate shall be dependent on the results of the reexamination.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4113'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.122
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.122
      </num>
      <head>
        Certified seed only election.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='122' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.122
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Certified seed only election.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          When an owner elects after a certificate is issued to sell the
          protected variety by variety name only as a class of certified seed, a
          new certificate may be issued upon return of the original certificate
          to the Office and payment of the appropriate fee.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4114'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.130
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.130
      </num>
      <head>
        Recording of assignments.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 42435
        </aref>
        , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          60 FR 17190
        </aref>
        , Apr. 4, 1995]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='130' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.130
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Recording of assignments.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any assignment of an application for a certificate, or of a
            certificate of plant variety protection, or of any interest in a
            variety, or any license or grant and conveyance of any right to use
            of the variety, may be submitted for recording in the Office in
            accordance with 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 101 of
            </aref>
             the Act (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='2531' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/2531.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 2531
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No instrument shall be recorded which is not in the English
            language or which does not identify the certificate or application
            to which it relates.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An instrument relating to title of a certificate shall identify the
            certificate by number and date, the name of the owner, and the name
            of the variety as stated in the certificate. An instrument relating
            to title of an application shall identify an application by number
            and date of filing, the name of the owner, and the name of the
            variety as stated in the application.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If an assignment is executed concurrently or subsequent to the
            filing of an application, but before its number and filing date are
            ascertained, the assignment shall identify the application by the
            date of the application, the name of the owner, and the name of the
            variety.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 42435
          </aref>
          , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            60 FR 17190
          </aref>
          , Apr. 4, 1995]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4115'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.131
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.131
      </num>
      <head>
        Conditional assignments.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='131' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.131
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Conditional assignments.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Assignments recorded in the Office are regarded as absolute
          assignments for Office purposes until canceled in writing by both
          parties to the assignment or by a decree of a court of competent
          jurisdiction. The Office shall not determine whether conditions
          precedent to the assignment, such as the payment of money, have been
          fulfilled.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4116'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.132
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.132
      </num>
      <head>
        Assignment records open to public inspection.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='272' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='132' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.132
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Assignment records open to public inspection.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Assignment records relating to original or amended certificates
            shall be open to public inspection and copies of any recorded
            document may be obtained upon payment of the prescribed fee.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Assignment records relating to any pending or abandoned application
            shall not be available for inspection except to the extent that
            pending applications are published as provided in 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 57 of
            </aref>
             the Act and 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='97' sect='19' psec='' tq='N'>
                97.19
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , or where necessary to carry out the provisions of any Act of
            Congress. Copies of assignment records and information on pending or
            abandoned applications shall be obtainable only upon written
            authority of the applicant or his or her assignee, or attorney or
            agent of record, or where necessary to carry out the provisions of
            any Act of Congress. An order for a copy of an assignment shall give
            the proper identification of the assignment.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4117'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.140
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.140
      </num>
      <head>
        After filing.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 42435
        </aref>
        , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          60 FR 17190
        </aref>
        , Apr. 4, 1995; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          61 FR 248
        </aref>
        , Jan. 4, 1996]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='140' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.140
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          After filing.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Upon filing an application for protection of a variety and payment of
          the prescribed fee, the owner, or his or her designee, may label the
          variety or containers of the seed of the variety or plants produced
          from such seed, substantially as follows: “Unauthorized Propagation
          Prohibited—(Unauthorized Seed Multiplication Prohibited)—U.S. Variety
          Protection Applied For.” Where applicable, “PVPA 1994” or “PVPA
          1994—Unauthorized Sales for Reproductive Purposes Prohibited” may be
          added to the notice.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 42435
          </aref>
          , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            60 FR 17190
          </aref>
          , Apr. 4, 1995; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            61 FR 248
          </aref>
          , Jan. 4, 1996]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4118'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.141
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.141
      </num>
      <head>
        After issuance.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 42435
        </aref>
        , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          60 FR 17190
        </aref>
        , Apr. 4, 1995; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          61 FR 248
        </aref>
        , Jan. 4, 1996]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='141' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.141
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          After issuance.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Upon issuance of a certificate, the owner of the variety, or his or
          her designee, may label the variety or containers of the seed of the
          variety or plants produced from such seed substantially as follows:
          “Unauthorized Propagation Prohibited—(Unauthorized Seed Multiplication
          Prohibited)—U.S. Protected Variety.” Where applicable, “PVPA 1994” or
          “PVPA 1994—Unauthorized Sales for Reproductive Purposes Prohibited”
          may be added to the notice.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 42435
          </aref>
          , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            60 FR 17190
          </aref>
          , Apr. 4, 1995; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            61 FR 248
          </aref>
          , Jan. 4, 1996]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4119'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.142
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.142
      </num>
      <head>
        For testing or increase.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 42435
        </aref>
        , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          60 FR 17190
        </aref>
        , Apr. 4, 1995]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='142' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.142
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          For testing or increase.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          An owner who contemplates filing an application and releases for
          testing or increase, seed of the variety or reproducible plant
          material of the variety, may label such plant material or containers
          of the seed or plant material substantially as follows: “Unauthorized
          Propagation Prohibited—For Testing (or Increase) Only.”
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 42435
          </aref>
          , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            60 FR 17190
          </aref>
          , Apr. 4, 1995]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4120'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.143
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.143
      </num>
      <head>
        Certified seed only.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='143' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.143
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Certified seed only.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon filing an application, or amendment thereto, specifying seed
            of the variety is to be sold by variety name only as a class of
            certified seed, the owner, or his or her designee, may label
            containers of seed of the variety substantially as follows:
            “Unauthorized Propagation Prohibited—U.S. Variety Protection Applied
            for Specifying That Seed of This Variety Is To Be Sold By Variety
            Name Only as a Class of Certified Seed.”
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An owner who has received a certificate specifying that a variety
            is to be sold by variety name only, as a class of certified seed,
            may label containers of the seed of the variety substantially as
            follows: “Unauthorized Propagation Prohibited—To Be Sold By Variety
            Name Only as a Class of Certified Seed—U.S. Protected Variety.”
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4121'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.144
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.144
      </num>
      <head>
        Additional marking or labeling.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='144' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.144
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Additional marking or labeling.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Additional clarifying information that is not false or misleading may
          be used by the owner, in addition to the above markings or labeling.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4122'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.150
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.150
      </num>
      <head>
        Right to be represented.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='150' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.150
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Right to be represented.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          An applicant may actively advance an application or may be represented
          by an attorney or agent authorized in writing.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4123'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.151
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.151
      </num>
      <head>
        Authorization.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='273' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='151' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.151
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Authorization.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Only attorneys or agents specified by the applicant shall be allowed
          to inspect papers or take action of any kind, on behalf of the
          applicant, in any pending application or proceedings.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4124'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.152
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.152
      </num>
      <head>
        Revocation of authorization; withdrawal.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='152' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.152
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Revocation of authorization; withdrawal.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          An authorization of an attorney or agent may be revoked by an
          applicant at any time, and an attorney or agent may withdraw, upon
          application to the Commissioner. When the authorization is so revoked,
          or the attorney or agent has so withdrawn, the Office shall inform the
          interested parties and shall thereafter communicate directly with the
          applicant, or with such other attorney or agent as the applicant may
          appoint. An assignment will not of itself operate as a revocation of
          authorization previously given, but the assignee of the entire
          interest may revoke previous authorizations and be represented by an
          attorney or agent of his or her own selection.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4125'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.153
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.153
      </num>
      <head>
        Persons recognized.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='153' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.153
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Persons recognized.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Unless specifically authorized as provided in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='151' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.151
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , no person shall be permitted to file or advance applications before
          the Office on behalf of another person.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4126'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.154
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.154
      </num>
      <head>
        Government employees.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='154' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.154
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Government employees.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Officers and employees of the United States who are disqualified by
          statute (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='18' sect='203' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/18/203.html'>
              18 U.S.C. 203
            </subref>
             and 
            <subref title='18' sect='205' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/18/205.html'>
              205
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ) from practicing as attorneys or agents in proceedings or other
          matters before government departments or agencies, shall not be
          eligible to represent applicants, except officers and employees whose
          official duties require the preparation and prosecution of
          applications for certificates of variety protection.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4127'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.155
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.155
      </num>
      <head>
        Signatures.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='155' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.155
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Signatures.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Every document filed by an attorney or agent representing an applicant
          or party to a proceeding in the Office shall bear the signature of
          such attorney or agent, except documents which are required to be
          signed by the applicant or party.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4128'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.156
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.156
      </num>
      <head>
        Addresses.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='156' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.156
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Addresses.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Attorneys and agents practicing before the Plant Variety Protection
          Office shall notify the Office in writing of any change of address.
          The Office shall address letters to any person at the last address
          received.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4129'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.157
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.157
      </num>
      <head>
        Professional conduct.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='157' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.157
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Professional conduct.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Attorneys and agents appearing before the Office shall conform to the
          standards of ethical and professional conduct, generally applicable to
          attorneys appearing before the courts of the United States.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4130'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.175
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.175
      </num>
      <head>
        Fees and charges.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          70 FR 54612
        </aref>
        , Sept. 16, 2005]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='175' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.175
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Fees and charges.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The following fees and charges apply to the services and actions
          specified below:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Filing the application and notifying the public of filing—$518.00.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Search or examination—$3,864.00.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Submission of new application data, after notice of allowance,
            prior to issuance of certificate—$432.00.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Allowance and issuance of certificate and notifying public of
            issuance—$768.00.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Revive an abandoned application—$518.00.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Reproduction of records, drawings, certificates, exhibits, or
            printed material (cost per page of material)—$1.80.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Authentication (each page)—$1.80.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Correcting or re-issuance of a certificate—$518.00.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Recording an assignment, any revision of an assignment, or
            withdrawal or revocation of an assignment (per certificate or
            application)—$41.00.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Copies of 8 × 10 photographs in color—$41.00.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Additional fee for reconsideration—$518.00.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='l'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (l)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Additional fee for late payment—$41.00.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='m'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (m)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Fee for handling replenishment seed sample (applicable only for
            certificates issued after June 20, 2005)—$38.00.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='n'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (n)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Additional fee for late replenishment of seed—$41.00.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='o'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (o)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Filing a petition for protest proceeding—$4,118.00.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='p'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (p)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Appeal to Secretary (refundable if appeal overturns the
            Commissioner&apos;s decision)—$4,942.00.
            <PRTPAGE P='274' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='q'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (q)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Granting of extensions for responding to a request—$89.00.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='r'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (r)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Field inspections by a representative of the Plant Variety
            Protection Office, made at the request of the applicant, shall be
            reimbursable in full (including travel, per diem or subsistence, and
            salary) in accordance with Standardized Government Travel
            Regulation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='s'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (s)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any other service not covered above will be charged for at rates
            prescribed by the Commissioner, but in no event shall they exceed
            $107.00 per employee-hour. Charges also will be made for materials,
            space, and administrative costs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            70 FR 54612
          </aref>
          , Sept. 16, 2005]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4131'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.176
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.176
      </num>
      <head>
        Fees payable in advance.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='176' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.176
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Fees payable in advance.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Fees and charges shall be paid at the time of making application or at
          the time of submitting a request for any action by the Office for
          which a fee or charge is payable and established in this part.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4132'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.177
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.177
      </num>
      <head>
        Method of payment.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='177' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.177
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Method of payment.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Checks or money orders shall be made payable to the Treasurer of the
          United States. Remittances from foreign countries must be payable and
          immediately negotiable in the United States for the full amount of the
          prescribed fee. Money sent by mail to the Office shall be sent at the
          sender&apos;s risk.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4133'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.178
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.178
      </num>
      <head>
        Refunds.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='178' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.178
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Refunds.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Money paid by mistake or excess payments shall be refunded, but a mere
          change of plans after the payment of money, as when a party decides to
          withdraw an application or to withdraw an appeal, shall not entitle a
          party to a refund. However, the examination or search fee shall be
          refunded if an application is voluntarily abandoned pursuant to 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='23' psec='#a' tq='N'>
              97.23(a)
            </subref>
          </aref>
           before a search or examination has begun. Amounts of $1 or less shall
          not be refunded unless specifically demanded.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4134'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.179
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.179
      </num>
      <head>
        Copies and certified copies.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='179' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.179
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Copies and certified copies.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon request, copies of applications, certificates, or of any
            records, books, papers, drawings, or photographs in the custody of
            the Office and which are open to the public, will be furnished to
            persons entitled thereto, upon payment of the prescribed fee.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon request, copies will be authenticated by imprint of the seal
            of the Office and certified by the official, authorized by the
            Commissioner upon payment of the prescribed fee.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4135'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.190
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.190
      </num>
      <head>
        When open records are available.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='190' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.190
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          When open records are available.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Copies of records, which are open to the public and in the custody of
          the Office, may be examined in the Office during regular business
          hours upon approval by the Commissioner.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4136'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.200
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.200
      </num>
      <head>
        Protests to the grant of a certificate.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='200' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.200
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Protests to the grant of a certificate.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Opposition on the part of any person to the granting of a certificate
          shall be permitted while an application is pending and for a period
          not to exceed 5 years following the issuance of a certificate.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4137'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.201
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.201
      </num>
      <head>
        Protest proceedings.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 42435
        </aref>
        , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          60 FR 17190
        </aref>
        , Apr. 4, 1995]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='201' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.201
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Protest proceedings.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Opposition shall be made by submitting in writing a petition for
            protest proceedings, which petition shall be supported by affidavits
            and shall show the reason or reasons for opposing the application or
            certificate. The petition and accompanying papers shall be filed in
            duplicate. If it appears to an examiner that a variety involved in a
            pending application or covered by a certificate may not be or may
            not have been entitled to protection under the Act, a protest
            proceeding may be permitted by the Commissioner.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             One copy of the petition and accompanying papers shall be served by
            the Office upon the applicant or owner, or his or her attorney or
            agent of record.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An answer, by the applicant or owner of the certificate, or his or
            her assignee, in response to the petition, may be filed with the
            Commissioner within 60 days after service of the petition, upon such
            person. If no answer is filed within said period, the Commissioner
            shall decide the matter on the basis of the allegations set forth in
            the petition.
            <PRTPAGE P='275' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the petition and answer raise any issue of fact needing proof,
            the Commissioner shall afford each of the parties a period of 60
            days in which to file sworn statements or affidavits in support of
            their respective positions.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             As soon as practicable after the petition or the petition and
            answer are filed, or after the expiration of any period for filing
            sworn statements or affidavits, the Commissioner shall issue a
            decision as to whether the protests are upheld or denied. The
            Commissioner may, following the protest proceeding, cancel any
            certificate issued and may grant another certificate for the same
            variety to a person who proves to the satisfaction of the
            Commissioner, that he or she is the breeder or discoverer. The
            decision shall be served upon the parties in the manner provided in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='97' sect='403' psec='' tq='N'>
                97.403
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 42435
          </aref>
          , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            60 FR 17190
          </aref>
          , Apr. 4, 1995]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4138'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.300
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.300
      </num>
      <head>
        Petition to the Secretary.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 42435
        </aref>
        , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          60 FR 8464
        </aref>
        , Feb. 14, 1995]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='300' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.300
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Petition to the Secretary.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Petition may be made to the Secretary from any final action of the
            Commissioner denying an application or refusing to allow a
            certificate to be issued, or from any adverse decision of the
            Commissioner made under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='97' sect='18' psec='#c' tq='N'>
                97.18(c)
              </subref>
              , 
              <subref title='7' part='97' sect='107' psec='' tq='N'>
                97.107
              </subref>
              , 
              <subref title='7' part='97' sect='201' psec='#e' tq='N'>
                97.201(e)
              </subref>
              , and 
              <subref title='7' part='97' sect='220' psec='' tq='N'>
                97.220
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any such petition shall contain a statement of the facts involved
            and the point or points to be reviewed, and the actions requested.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A petition to the Secretary shall be filed in duplicate and
            accompanied by the prescribed fee (see 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='97' sect='175' psec='' tq='N'>
                97.175
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon request, an opportunity to present data, views, and arguments
            orally, in an informal manner or in a formal hearing, shall be given
            to interested persons. If a formal hearing is requested, the
            proceeding shall be conducted in accordance with the Rules of
            Practice Governing Formal Adjudicatory Proceedings Instituted by the
            Secretary Under Various Statutes set forth in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='1' sect='130' psec='' tq='N'>
                1.130
              </subref>
            </aref>
             through 1.151 of this title.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as otherwise provided in the rules in this part, any such
            petition not filed within 60 days from the action complained of
            shall be dismissed as untimely.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 42435
          </aref>
          , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            60 FR 8464
          </aref>
          , Feb. 14, 1995]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4139'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.301
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.301
      </num>
      <head>
        Commissioner&apos;s answer.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='301' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.301
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Commissioner&apos;s answer.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Commissioner may, within such time as may be directed by the
            Secretary, furnish a written statement to the Secretary in answer to
            the appellant&apos;s petition, including such explanation of the
            reasons for the action as may be necessary and supplying a copy to
            the appellant.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Within 20 days from the date of such answer, the appellant may file
            a reply statement directed only to such new points of argument as
            may be raised in the Commissioner&apos;s answer.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4140'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.302
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.302
      </num>
      <head>
        Decision by the Secretary.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='302' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.302
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Decision by the Secretary.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Secretary, after receiving the advice of the Board, may affirm
            or reverse the decision of the Commissioner, in whole or in part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Should the decision of the Secretary include an explicit statement
            that a certificate be allowed, based on an amended application, the
            applicant shall have the right to amend his or her application in
            conformity with such statement and such decision shall be binding on
            the Commissioner.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4141'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.303
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.303
      </num>
      <head>
        Action following the decision.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 42435
        </aref>
        , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          60 FR 17190
        </aref>
        , Apr. 4, 1995]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='303' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.303
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Action following the decision.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Copies of the decision of the Secretary shall be served upon the
            appellant and the Commissioner in the manner provided in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='97' sect='403' psec='' tq='N'>
                97.403
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When an appeal petition is dismissed, or when the time for appeal
            to the courts pursuant to the Act has expired and no such appeal or
            civil action has been filed, proceedings in the appeal shall be
            considered terminated as of the dismissal or expiration date, except
            in those cases in which the nature of the decision requires further
            action by the Commissioner. If the decision of the Secretary is
            appealed or a civil action has been filed pursuant to the Act, the
            decision of the Secretary will be stayed pending the outcome of the
            court appeal or civil action.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 42435
          </aref>
          , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            60 FR 17190
          </aref>
          , Apr. 4, 1995]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4142'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.400
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.400
      </num>
      <head>
        Extensions of time.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='400' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.400
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Extensions of time.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Upon a showing of good cause, extensions of time not otherwise
          provided for may be granted by the Commissioner or, if an appeal has
          been filed by the Secretary for taking any action required in any
          priority, protest, or appeal proceeding.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4143'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.401
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.401
      </num>
      <head>
        Miscellaneous provisions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='401' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.401
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Miscellaneous provisions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Petitions for reconsideration or modification of the decision of
            the Commissioner in priority or protest proceedings shall be filed
            within 20 days after the date of the decision.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Commissioner may consider on petition any matter involving
            abuse of discretion in the exercise of an examiner&apos;s authority,
            or such other matters as may be deemed proper to consider. Any such
            petition, if not filed within 20 days from the decision complained
            of, may be dismissed as untimely.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4144'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.402
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.402
      </num>
      <head>
        Service of papers.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='402' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.402
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Service of papers.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Every paper required to be served on opposing parties and filed in
            the Office in any priority, protest, or appeal proceeding, must be
            served by the Secretary in the manner provided in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='97' sect='403' psec='' tq='N'>
                97.403
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The requirement in certain sections that a specified paper shall be
            served includes a requirement that all related supporting papers
            shall also be served. Proof of such service upon other parties to
            the proceeding must be made before the supporting papers will be
            considered by the Commissioner or Secretary.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4145'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.403
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.403
      </num>
      <head>
        Manner of service.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='403' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.403
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Manner of service.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Service of any paper under this part must be on the attorney or agent
          of the party if there be such, or on the party if there is no attorney
          or agent, and may be made in any of the following ways:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             By mailing a copy of the paper to the person served by certified
            mail, with the date of the return receipt controlling the date of
            service;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             By leaving a copy at the usual place of business of the person
            served with someone in his or her employ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When the person served has no usual place of business, by leaving a
            copy at his or her home with a member of the family over 14 years of
            age and of discretion; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whenever it shall be found by the Commissioner or Secretary that
            none of the above modes of serving the paper is practicable, service
            may be by notice, published once in the Office Journal.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4146'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.500
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.500
      </num>
      <head>
        Appeal to U.S. Courts.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 42435
        </aref>
        , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          60 FR 17190
        </aref>
        , Apr. 4, 1995]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='500' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.500
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Appeal to U.S. Courts.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Any applicant dissatisfied with the decision of the Secretary on
          appeal may appeal to the U.S. Court of Customs and Patent Appeals or
          the U.S. Courts of Appeals, or institute a civil action in the U.S.
          District Court as set forth in the Act. In such cases, the appellant
          or plaintiff shall give notice to the Secretary, state the reasons for
          appeal or civil action, and obtain a certified copy of the record. The
          certified copy of the record shall be forwarded to the Court by the
          Plant Variety Protection Office on order of, and at the expense of the
          appellant or plaintiff.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 42435
          </aref>
          , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            60 FR 17190
          </aref>
          , Apr. 4, 1995]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4147'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.600
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.600
      </num>
      <head>
        Rules of practice.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='600' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.600
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Rules of practice.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Any proceedings instituted under 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 128 of
          </aref>
           the Act for false marking shall be conducted in accordance with 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='202' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
              202.10
            </subref>
          </aref>
           through 202.29 of this chapter (rules of practice under the Federal
          Seed Act) (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='1551' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1551.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 1551
            </subref>
          </aref>
          <E T='03'>
            et seq.
          </E>
          ), except that all references in those rules and regulations to
          “Examiner” shall be construed to be an Administrative Law Judge, U.S.
          Department of Agriculture, and not an “Examiner” as defined in the
          regulations under the Plant Variety Protection Act.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4148'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.700
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.700
      </num>
      <head>
        Public interest in wide usage.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='700' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.700
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Public interest in wide usage.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the Secretary has reason to believe that a protected variety
            should be declared open to use by the public in accordance with 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 44 of
            </aref>
             the Act, the Secretary shall give the owner of the variety
            appropriate notice and an 
            <PRTPAGE P='277' />
            opportunity to present views orally or in writing, with regard to
            the necessity for such action to be taken in the public interest.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon the expiration of the period for the presentation of views by
            the owner, as provided in paragraph (a) of this section, the
            Secretary shall refer the matter to the Plant Variety Protection
            Board for advice, including advice on any limitations or rate of
            remuneration.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon receiving the advice of the Plant Variety Protection Board,
            the Secretary shall advise the owner of the variety, the members of
            the Plant Variety Protection Board, and the public, by issuance of a
            press release, of any decision based on the provisions of 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 44 of
            </aref>
             the Act to declare a variety open to use by the public. Any
            decision not to declare a variety open to use by the public will be
            transmitted only to the owner of the variety and the members of the
            Plant Variety Protection Board.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4149'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.800
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.800
      </num>
      <head>
        Publication of public variety descriptions.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 42435
        </aref>
        , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          60 FR 17190
        </aref>
        , Apr. 4, 1995]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='800' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.800
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Publication of public variety descriptions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Voluntary submissions of varietal descriptions of “public varieties”
          on forms obtainable from the Office will be accepted for publication
          in the Official Journal. Such publication shall not constitute
          recognition that the variety is, in fact, distinct, uniform, and
          stable.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 42435
          </aref>
          , Aug. 9, 1993, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            60 FR 17190
          </aref>
          , Apr. 4, 1995]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4150'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:97:-:97.900
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        97.900
      </num>
      <head>
        Form of official identification symbol.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          65 FR 47244
        </aref>
        , Aug. 2, 2000]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='97' sect='900' psec='' tq='N'>
              97.900
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Form of official identification symbol.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The symbol set forth in Figure 1, containing the words “Plant Variety
          Protection Office” and “U.S. Department of Agriculture,” shall be the
          official identification symbol of the Plant Variety Protection Office.
          This information symbol, used by the Plant Variety Protection Office
          on the seal on certificates of Plant Variety Protection, has been
          approved by the Office of Communications to be added to the USDA/AMS
          inventory of symbols. It is approved for use with AMS materials.
        </P>
        <GPH DEEP='215' SPAN='2'>
          <GID>
            ER02AU00.006
          </GID>
        </GPH>
        <PRTPAGE P='278' />
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            65 FR 47244
          </aref>
          , Aug. 2, 2000]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>