<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol10'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1455
    </extid>
    <num>
      1455
    </num>
    <head>
      VOLUNTARY PUBLIC ACCESS AND HABITAT INCENTIVE PROGRAM
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='15' sect='714b' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/15/714b.html'>
              15 U.S.C. 714b
            </subref>
             and 
            <subref title='15' sect='714c' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/15/714c.html'>
              714c
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='16' sect='3839' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/3839.html'>
              16 U.S.C. 3839
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 39140
          </aref>
          , July 8, 2010, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='12882'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1455:-:1455.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1455.1
      </num>
      <head>
        Purpose and administration.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1455' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              1455.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Purpose and administration.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The purpose of this part is to specify requirements and definitions
            for the Voluntary Public Access and Habitat Incentive Program
            (VPA-HIP).
            <PRTPAGE P='761' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             VPA-HIP provides, within funding limits, grants to State and tribal
            governments to encourage owners and operators of privately-held
            farm, ranch, and forest land to voluntarily make that land available
            for access by the public for wildlife-dependent recreation,
            including hunting and fishing under programs administered by State
            and tribal governments. VPA-HIP is not an entitlement program and no
            grant will be made unless the application is acceptable to the
            Commodity Credit Corporation (CCC). CCC may reject a application for
            any reason deemed sufficient by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The regulations in this part are administered under the general
            supervision and direction of the Executive Vice President, CCC, or a
            designee, or the Deputy Administrator, Farm Programs (Deputy
            Administrator), Farm Service Agency (FSA).
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12883'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1455:-:1455.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1455.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1455' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              1455.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The definitions in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='718' tq='N'>
                718 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
             apply to this part and all documents issued in accordance with this
            part, except as otherwise provided in this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The following definitions apply to this part:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Appropriate wildlife habitat
          </E>
           means habitat that is suitable or proper, as determined by the
          applicable State or tribal government, to support fish and wildlife
          populations in the area.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Farm land
          </E>
           means the land that meets definition of “farmland” in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='718' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              718.2
            </subref>
             of this title
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Forest land
          </E>
           means land at least 120 feet wide and 1 acre in size with at least 10
          percent cover (or equivalent stocking) by live trees of any size,
          including land that formerly had such tree cover and that will be
          naturally or artificially regenerated. Forest land includes transition
          zones, such as areas between forest and nonforest lands that have at
          least 10 percent cover (or equivalent stocking) with live trees and
          forest areas adjacent to urban and built-up lands. Roadside,
          streamside, and shelterbelt strips of trees must have a crown width of
          at least 120 feet and continuous length of at least 363 feet to
          qualify as forest land. Unimproved roads and trails, streams, and
          clearings in forest areas are classified as forest if they are less
          than 120 feet wide or an acre in size. Tree-covered areas in
          agricultural production settings, such as fruit orchards, or
          tree-covered areas in urban settings, such as city parks, are not
          considered forest land.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Privately-held land
          </E>
           means farm, ranch, or forest land that is owned or operated by an
          individual or entity that is not an entity of any government unit or
          Tribe.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Ranch land
          </E>
           means land that meets the definition of “farmland.”
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State
          </E>
           or 
          <E T='03'>
            State government
          </E>
           means any State or local government, including State, city, town, or
          county government.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Tribal government
          </E>
           means any Federally-recognized Indian tribe, band, nation, or other
          organized group, or community, including pueblos, rancherias, colonies
          and any Alaska Native Village, or regional or village corporation as
          defined in or established pursuant to the Alaska Native Claims
          Settlement Act (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='43' sect='1601-162' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/43/1601-162.html'>
              43 U.S.C. 1601-162
            </subref>
          </aref>
          9h), which is recognized as eligible for the special programs and
          services provided by the United States to Indians because of their
          status as Indians.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Wildlife-dependent recreation
          </E>
           means a land use involving hunting, fishing, wildlife-observation,
          photography, environmental education and interpretation, or other
          activities as determined by CCC.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12884'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1455:-:1455.10
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1455.10
      </num>
      <head>
        Eligible grant applicants.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1455' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
              1455.10
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Eligible grant applicants.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A State or Tribal government may apply for a VPA-HIP grant.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any applications received by an individual or entity that is not a
            State or tribal government will not be considered.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12885'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1455:-:1455.11
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1455.11
      </num>
      <head>
        Application procedure.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1455' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
              1455.11
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Application procedure.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Request for applications (RFA).
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC will issue periodic RFAs for VPA-HIP on 
            <E T='03'>
              www.grants.gov
            </E>
            , subject to available funding. Unless otherwise specified in the
            applicable RFA, applicants must file an original and one hard copy
            of the required forms and an application.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Single application.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A State or tribal government must include all proposed activity
            under a single application per RFA review period. Multiple
            applications from an applicant during a 
            <PRTPAGE P='762' />
            single RFA period will not be considered. The applicant is the
            individual State or Tribe; any application from any unit of the
            State or tribal government must be coordinated for a single
            submission of one application from the State or Tribe.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Incomplete applications.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Incomplete applications will not be considered for funding.
            However, incomplete applications may be returned, and may be
            resubmitted, if time permits.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Providing data.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Data furnished by grant applicants will be used to determine
            eligibility for the VPA-HIP benefits. Furnishing the data is
            voluntary; however, the failure to provide data could result in
            program benefits being withheld or denied.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Required forms.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The following forms must be completed, signed, and submitted as
            part of the application; other forms may be required, as specified
            in the applicable RFA:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Application for Federal Assistance;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Budget Information—Non-Construction Programs; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Assurances—Non-Construction Programs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Application.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each application must contain the following elements; additional
            required elements may be specified in the applicable RFA:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Title page;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Table of contents;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Executive summary, which includes;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Activities.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provide a summary of the application that briefly describes
            activities proposed to be funded under the grant.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Objectives, funding, performance, and other resources.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Include objectives and tasks to be accomplished, the amount of
            funding requested, how the work will be performed, whether
            organizational staff, consultants or contractors will be used, and
            whether other resources will be used;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Eligibility certification that certifies that the applicant is a
            State or tribal government and the individual submitting the
            application is acting in a representative capacity on behalf of the
            State or tribal government;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Application narrative that must include, but is not limited to, the
            following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_5_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Project title.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The title of the proposed project must be brief (not to exceed 75
            characters) yet describe the essentials of the project.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_5_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Information sheet.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A separate one-page information sheet listing each of the
            evaluation criteria referenced in the RFA, followed by the page
            numbers of all relevant material and documentation contained in the
            application that address or support the criteria.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_5_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Objectives of the project.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This section must include the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='f_5_iii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A description of how the VPA-HIP funding will be used to encourage
            public access to private farm, ranch, and forest land for hunting,
            fishing, and other recreational purposes;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='f_5_iii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A description of the methods that will be used to achieve the
            provisions of paragraph (f)(5)(iii)(A) of this section;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='f_5_iii_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A description of how and to what extent the proposed program will
            meet with widespread acceptance among landowners;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='f_5_iii_D'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (D)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A detailed description of how and to what extent the land enrolled
            will have appropriate wildlife habitat and how program funds may be
            used to improve those habitats;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='f_5_iii_E'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (E)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A detailed description of how and to what extent public hunting and
            other recreational access will be increased on land enrolled under a
            Conservation Reserve Enhancement Program as specified under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='50' psec='' tq='N'>
                1410.50
              </subref>
               of this chapter
            </aref>
            , or if Conservation Reserve Enhancement Program land is not
            available, specify that there is no impact;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='f_5_iii_F'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (F)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A detailed description of how any additional Federal, State, tribal
            government, or private resources will be used to carry out grant
            activities; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='f_5_iii_G'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (G)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A detailed description of how the public will be made aware of the
            location of the land enrolled.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_5_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Work plan.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Applications must discuss the specific tasks to be completed using
            grant and matching funds. The work plan should show how customers
            will be identified, key personnel to be involved with administration
            of the grant, and the evaluation methods to be used to determine the
            success of specific tasks and overall objectives of a VPA-HIP grant.
            The budget must present a breakdown of the estimated 
            <PRTPAGE P='763' />
            costs associated with VPA-HIP activities and allocate these costs to
            each of the tasks to be undertaken. Additional funds from Federal,
            State, tribal government, or private resources as well as grant
            funds and resources provided in kind must be accounted for in the
            budget.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_5_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Performance evaluation criteria.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Applications should discuss how the State or tribal government will
            evaluate whether the program for which the grant is being sought
            will meet the stated goals for the State or tribal program,
            including but not limited to landowner and recreationist
            participation, outreach, and cost-effectiveness.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_5_vii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vii)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Other similar efforts.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The applicant must describe its previous accomplishments and
            outcomes in public access activities, if any.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='f_5_viii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (viii)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Qualifications of personnel.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Applicants must describe the qualifications of personnel expected
            to perform key tasks, and whether these personnel are to be full- or
            part-time employees or contract personnel.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12886'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1455:-:1455.20
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1455.20
      </num>
      <head>
        Criteria for grant selection.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1455' sect='20' psec='' tq='N'>
              1455.20
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Criteria for grant selection.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Incomplete or non-responsive applications will not be evaluated.
            Applicants may revise their applications and re-submit them prior to
            the published deadline if there is sufficient time to do so.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             After all applications have been evaluated using the evaluation
            criteria and scored in accordance with the point allocation
            specified in the RFA, a list of all applications in ranked order,
            together with funding level recommendations, will be submitted to
            the Deputy Administrator, FSA.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Unless supplemented in a RFA, applications for grants for VPA-HIP
            will be evaluated using the criteria listed in this section. The
            distribution of points to be awarded per criterion will be
            identified in the RFA.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Benefits.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The application will be evaluated to determine whether and to what
            extent the project&apos;s anticipated outcomes promote improvement
            of public access for wildlife-dependent recreation and intended
            environmental benefits.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Project description and feasibility.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The application will be evaluated on the extent and quality to
            which the applicant demonstrates a reasonable approach to the
            project, sufficient resources to complete the project, and a
            capability to complete the project in a timely manner.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Widespread acceptance and maximizing participation of landowners.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The application will be evaluated based on the applicant&apos;s
            plan for encouraging the participation of owners and operators of
            privately-held farm, ranch, and forest land, and for engaging the
            public users. Additionally, the extent to which the applicant has
            identified and established relationships with the partners necessary
            to achieve the project&apos;s goals will be evaluated.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Appropriate wildlife habitat.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The application will be evaluated to determine whether the
            applicant demonstrates expertise in providing technical assistance
            with respect to establishing and maintaining appropriate wildlife
            habitat on public access land.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Strengthening wildlife habitat for lands under the Conservation
              Reserve Enhancement Program (CREP).
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The application will be evaluated to determine whether the project
            proposes to provide incentives to increase public hunting and other
            recreational access on land enrolled under CREP as authorized by 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1410' sect='50' psec='' tq='N'>
                1410.50
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Additional private, Federal, State, or tribal government
              resources.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The application will be evaluated to determine the extent to which
            the support letters provided by other organizations involved with
            the project demonstrate specific and quantified commitments to the
            project. Applications that demonstrate additional resources will
            receive more points, all else being equal, than those that do not.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Making available the location of enrolled land.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The application will be evaluated to determine how the project
            proposes to make available to the public the location of the land
            enrolled.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Performance evaluation criteria.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The application will be evaluated to determine whether the
            applicant has included outcome-based performance measures.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Administrative capabilities.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The application will be evaluated to determine whether the grant
            applicant has a track record of administering the project or, in the
            absence of a track 
            <PRTPAGE P='764' />
            record, the capacity to administer the project. Applicants that have
            demonstrated capable financial systems and audit controls, personnel
            and program administration performance measures, and clear rules of
            governance will receive more points than those not evidencing this
            capacity.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Delivery.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The application will be evaluated to determine whether the
            applicant has a track record in implementing public access or
            similar programs or, in the absence of an actual track record, the
            capacity to implement a public access program. The applicant&apos;s
            potential for delivering an effective public access program and the
            expected effects of that program will also be assessed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_11'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (11)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Work plan and budget.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The work plan will be reviewed for detailed actions and an
            accompanying timetable for implementing the components of the
            application. Clear, logical, realistic, and efficient plans will
            result in a higher score. Budgets will be reviewed for completeness
            and whether and to what extent additional resources were committed
            by Federal, State, or tribal government, and private resources.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_12'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (12)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Qualifications of those performing the tasks.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The application will be reviewed to determine if key personnel have
            appropriate knowledge, skills, and abilities with respect to
            wildlife-dependent recreation including hunting or fishing on
            privately-held farm, ranch, and forest land, funds control, grants
            management, performance monitoring and evaluation, or other
            activities relevant to the success of the proposed public access
            program.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12887'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1455:-:1455.21
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1455.21
      </num>
      <head>
        Additional responsibilities of grantee.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1455' sect='21' psec='' tq='N'>
              1455.21
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Additional responsibilities of grantee.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Before receiving grant funding, the grantee will be required to
            sign an agreement similar in form and substance to the form of
            agreement published within or as an appendix to the RFA. The
            agreement will require the grantee to commit to do all of the
            following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Take all practicable steps to develop continuing sources of
            financial support from other Federal, State, tribal government, or
            private resources;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Make arrangements for the monitoring and evaluation of the
            activities related to implementation of the public access program of
            the owners or operators that enroll farm, ranch, and forest land;
            and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provide an accounting for the money received by the grantee under
            this subpart.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Grantees will be required to monitor funds or services as specified
            in paragraph (c) of this section, and must agree to that monitoring
            before grant funds are awarded.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The grantee must certify that the grant funds and services will not
            be used for ineligible purposes. Specifically, grant funds and
            services may not be used to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Duplicate or replace current services; however, grant funds may be
            used to expand the level of effort or service beyond what is
            currently being provided;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Pay costs of preparing the application for funding under VPA-HIP;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Pay costs of the project incurred prior to the date of grant
            approval;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Fund political activities;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Pay any judgment or debt owed to the United States;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Pay for the design, repair, rehabilitation, acquisition, or
            construction of a building or facility (including a processing
            facility);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Purchase, rent or pay for the installation of fixed equipment,
            other than property identification signs;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Pay for the repair of privately owned vehicles; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Pay for research and development not directly related to
            quantifying the performance of VPA-HIP lands enrolled with funding
            from VPA-HIP.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Grant agreements under this part will be for a term of up to 3
            years.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Grantees that are States will have the grant amount reduced by 25
            percent if opening dates for migratory bird hunting in the State are
            not consistent for residents and non-residents. This paragraph does
            not apply to grantees that are Tribal governments.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Failure of the grantee to execute a grant agreement in a timely
            fashion, as determined by the CCC, will be construed to be a
            withdrawal from VPA-HIP.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12888'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1455:-:1455.30
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1455.30
      </num>
      <head>
        Reporting requirements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='765' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1455' sect='30' psec='' tq='N'>
              1455.30
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Reporting requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Grantees must provide the following to FSA:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A “Financial Status Report” listing expenditures according to
            agreed upon budget categories, on a periodic basis as specified in
            the grant document.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Annual performance reports that compare accomplishments to the
            objectives stated in the application, and that also:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Identify all tasks completed to date and provide documentation
            supporting the reported results;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the original schedule provided in the work plan is not being
            met, the report must discuss the problems or delays that may affect
            completion of the project;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             List objectives for the next reporting period; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Discuss compliance with any special conditions on the use of award
            funds. Reports are due as provided in paragraph (a)(1) of this
            section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Final project performance reports, inclusive of supporting
            documentation. The final performance report is due within 90 days of
            the completion of the project.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All reports submitted to the Agency will be held in confidence to
            the extent permitted by law.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12889'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1455:-:1455.31
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1455.31
      </num>
      <head>
        Miscellaneous.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1455' sect='31' psec='' tq='N'>
              1455.31
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Miscellaneous.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Inspection.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Grantees must permit periodic inspection of the program operations
            by a CCC representative, as determined by CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Performance evaluation.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC will incorporate performance criteria in grant award
            documentation and will regularly evaluate the progress and
            performance of grant awardees.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Suspend, terminate, or require refund.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC may elect to suspend or terminate a grant in all or part, or
            funding of a particular workplan activity, and require refund of
            part or all of the grant, with interest, where CCC has determined:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             That the grantee or subrecipient of grant funds has demonstrated
            insufficient progress in complying with the terms of the grant
            agreement;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The opening dates for migratory bird hunting in a State have been
            changed so as to be not consistent for residents and non-residents
            during the term of the grant;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             There is reasonable evidence that shows joint funding has not been
            or will not be forthcoming on a timely basis; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Such other cause as CCC identifies in writing to the grantee based
            on reasonable evidence (including but not limited to the use of
            Federal grant funds for ineligible purposes).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Advance or reimbursement.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Grantees must use the request for advance or reimbursement form,
            which will be provided by CCC, to request advances or
            reimbursements;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Appeals.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Appeals will be handled according to 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR parts 
              <subref title='7' part='11' tq='N'>
                11
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='780' tq='N'>
                780
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Environmental review.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All grants made under this subpart are subject to the requirements
            of 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='799' tq='N'>
                799
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          Applicants for grant funds must consider and document within their
          plans the important environmental factors within the planning area and
          the potential environmental impacts of the plan on the planning area,
          as well as the alternative planning strategies that were reviewed.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Civil rights.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC prohibits discrimination in all its programs and activities on
            the basis of race, color, national origin, age, disability, and
            where applicable, sex, marital status, familial status, parental
            status, religion, sexual orientation, genetic information, political
            beliefs, reprisal, or because all or a part of an individual&apos;s
            income is derived from any public assistance program. VPA-HIP will
            also be administered in accordance with all other applicable civil
            rights law.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Other USDA regulations.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The grant program under this part is subject to the provisions of
            the following regulations, as applicable:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3015' tq='N'>
                3015
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , Uniform Federal Assistance Regulations;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3016' tq='N'>
                3016
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , Uniform Administrative Requirements for Grants and Cooperative
            Agreements to State and Local Governments;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3017' tq='N'>
                3017
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , Governmentwide Debarment and Suspension (nonprocurement) and
            Governmentwide Requirements for Drug-Free Workplace (Grants);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3018' tq='N'>
                3018
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , New Restrictions on Lobbying;
            <PRTPAGE P='766' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3019' tq='N'>
                3019
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , Uniform Administrative Requirements for Grants and Agreements with
            Institutions of Higher Education, Hospitals and Other Non-profit
            Organizations; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3052' tq='N'>
                3052
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , Audits of States, Local Governments and Non-profit Organizations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Audit.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Grantees must comply with the audit requirements of 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3052' tq='N'>
                3052
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . The audit requirements apply to the years in which grant funds are
            received and years in which work is accomplished using grant funds.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Change in scope or objectives.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Grantee must obtain prior approval from FSA for any change to
            the scope or objectives of the approved project. Failure to obtain
            prior approval of changes to the scope of work or budget may result
            in suspension, termination, or recovery of grant funds.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Exceptions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC may, in individual cases, make an exception to any requirement
            or provision of this part, provided that any such exception is not
            inconsistent with any applicable law or opinion of the Comptroller
            General, and provided further, that CCC determines that the
            application of the requirement or provision would adversely affect
            the Federal Government&apos;s interest.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='l'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (l)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Enforcement and refunds; liens and schemes or devices.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Grantees must comply with all conditions of the grant and any
            monies not spent or improperly spent must be returned immediately
            with interest to run at the normal rate for CCC obligations.
            Interest charges will be computed from the date of the CCC
            disbursement. Grantees must insure that parties that receive funds
            from the grantee comply with the grantee&apos;s application and
            return funds made available by the grantee where there is no such
            compliance. Any scheme or device to avoid any limits of this part
            will be considered to be a program violation with respect to any
            grant to which that scheme or device is related. Grant funds will be
            made available to the States or Tribes that are grantees under this
            part without regard to the claims of others, unless CCC determines
            otherwise.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>