<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol12'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1900
    </extid>
    <num>
      1900
    </num>
    <head>
      GENERAL
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='5' sect='301' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/5/301.html'>
              5 U.S.C. 301
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='1989' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1989.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 1989
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='6991' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/6991.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 6991
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , et. seq.; 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='42' sect='1480' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/42/1480.html'>
              42 U.S.C. 1480
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; Reorganization Plan No. 2 of 1953 (5 U.S.C. App.).
        </P>
      </AUTH>
    </text>
    <section orderid='14837'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1900:A:1900.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1900.1
      </num>
      <head>
        General.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          44 FR 18162
        </aref>
        , Mar. 27, 1979]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1900' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              1900.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The authorities contained in this subpart apply to all assets,
          functions, and programs now or hereafter administered or serviced by
          the Farmers Home Administration or its successor agency under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
          , including but not limited to those relating to indebtedness,
          security, and other assets obtained or contracted through the
          Secretary of Agriculture, Resettlement Administration, Farm Security
          Administration, or Emergency Crop and Feed Loan Offices of the Farm
          Credit Administration, the Soil Conservation Service in connection
          with water conservation and utilization projects; the Puerto Rico
          Hurricane Relief Commission and successor agencies in connection with
          Puerto Rico Hurricane relief loans to individuals; State Rural
          Rehabilitation Corporations, the United States of America or its
          officials as trustees of the assets of State Rural Rehabilitation
          Corporations, Regional Agricultural Credit Corporations, Defense
          Relocation Corporations, land leasing and purchasing associations,
          corporations, and agencies, and whether the interest of the 
          <PRTPAGE P='455' />
          United States in the indebtedness, instrument of debt, security,
          security instrument, or other assets is that of obligee, owner,
          holder, insurer, assignee, mortgagee, beneficiary, trustee or other
          interest.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            44 FR 18162
          </aref>
          , Mar. 27, 1979]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14838'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1900:A:1900.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1900.2
      </num>
      <head>
        National office staff and state directors.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          44 FR 18162
        </aref>
        , Mar. 27, 1979, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          47 FR 5700
        </aref>
        , Feb. 8, 1982; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          50 FR 23901
        </aref>
        , June 7, 1985; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          52 FR 44375
        </aref>
        , Nov. 19, 1987; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          56 FR 6946
        </aref>
        , Feb. 21, 1991]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1900' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              1900.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          National office staff and state directors.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The following officials of the Farmers Home Administration or its
          successor agency under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
          , in accordance with applicable laws, and the regulations implementing
          these laws, are severally authorized, for and on behalf of and in the
          name of the United States of America or the Farmers Home
          Administration or its successor agency under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
          , to do and perform all acts necessary in connection with making and
          insuring loans, making grants and advances, servicing loans and other
          indebtedness and obtaining, servicing and enforcing security and other
          instruments related thereto: The Deputy Administrator Program
          Operations, the Assistant Administrators for Farmer Programs, Housing,
          and Community and Business Programs, the Assistant Administrator
          Accounting and Director Finance Office; each Director and the Insured
          Loan Officer, Finance Office; the Directors for the Water and Waste
          Disposal Division, the Community Facilities Division, the Business and
          Industry Division, the Multi-Family Housing Processing Division, the
          Multi-Family Housing Servicing and Property Management Division, the
          Single Family Housing Processing Division, the Single Family Housing
          Servicing and Property Management Division, the Farm Real Estate and
          Production Division, the Emergency Division; and each State Director
          within the area of that State Director&apos;s jurisdiction; and in the
          absence or disability of any such official, the person acting in that
          official&apos;s position; and the delegates of any such official. The
          authority includes, but is not limited to, the authority to:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Effect the assignment of, or the declaration of trust with respect
            to, insured security instruments to place them in trust with the
            United States of America as trustee for the benefit of any holder of
            the promissory note or bond secured by such security instrument.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Acknowledge receipt of notice of sale or assignment of insured
            loans and security instruments.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Appoint or request the appointment of substitute trustees in deeds
            of trust.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Execute proofs of claim in bankruptcy, death, and other cases.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Consent to sale or assignment of, or sell or assign, direct or
            insured loans and security instruments (except that in the case of
            Agency asset sales, District Directors and County Supervisors are
            delegated the authority to assign security instruments),
            endorsements, reinsurance agreements, or other instruments in
            connection therewith; and execute agreements to insure and reinsure,
            and to purchase and repurchase insured loans and security
            instruments.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Compromise, adjust, cancel or charge off indebtedness (except that
            County Supervisors are delegated authority to approve all
            settlements of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              sections 502 and 504
            </aref>
             single family housing debt(s)).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Modify contracts and other instruments and compromise claims owed
            to the Farmers Home Administration or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             and covered by the Federal Claims Collection Act of 1966 and the
            joint regulations issued under it by the Attorney General and the
            Comptroller General as provided for in applicable program
            regulations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Perform all actions pertaining to the sale (or other disposal) of
            real or chattel property or interests therein and to execute and
            deliver bills of sale or other instruments to effect such sale (or
            disposition), which includes but is not limited to offering property
            for sale; advertising; receiving and accepting offers or bids; and
            closing sale transactions, including the collection of sale
            proceeds, and delivery of quitclaim deeds, easements, and
            right-of-way conveyances after those documents have been executed.
            The authority to execute any deeds of conveyance of inventory real
            property, including quitclaim deeds, easements, rights-of-
            <PRTPAGE P='456' />
            way, or sale of any use rights is reserved to the State Director,
            and this authority may not be redelegated.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Approve and consent to transfers of security property to other
            parties with or without assumption of debts; and approve and accept
            transfers of security property or interests therein to the United
            States of America, and execute release from liability after
            determination is made in accordance with applicable program
            regulations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Execute and deliver, or approve in writing, suspensions, releases
            or terminations of assignments, of income, renewals, extensions,
            partial and full releases and satisfactions of security, and
            personal or indemnity liability for indebtedness, waivers,
            subordination agreements, severance agreements, affidavits,
            acknowlegements, certificates of residence, evidence of consent, and
            other instruments or documents.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Accelerate and declare entire real estate or chattel indebtedness
            due and payable, foreclose or request foreclosure of real estate
            security instruments by exercise of power of sale or otherwise, and
            bid for and purchase at any foreclosure or other sale or otherwise
            acquire real property pledged, mortgaged, conveyed, attached, or
            levied upon to collect indetedness, and accept title to any property
            so purchased or acquired.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='l'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (l)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Require and accept further or additional security.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='m'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (m)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Accelerate and declare entire non-real estate indebtedness due and
            payable, and foreclose or request foreclosure of chattel security
            instruments by exercise of power of sale or otherwise.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='n'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (n)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Bid for and purchase at any foreclosure or other sale, or otherwise
            acquire personal property pledged, mortgaged, conveyed, attached, or
            levied upon to collect indebtedness, and accept title to any
            property so purchased or acquired.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='o'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (o)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Take possession of, maintain, and operate security or acquired real
            or personal property or interests therein, sell or otherwise dispose
            of such personal property, and execute and deliver contracts,
            caretaker&apos;s agreements, leases, and other instruments in
            connection therewith, as appropriate.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='p'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (p)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Execute proofs of loss on insurance contracts and endorse without
            recourse loss payment drafts and checks.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='q'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (q)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Issue, publish and serve notices and other instruments.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='r'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (r)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             File or record instruments, whether separate instruments, or by
            making marginal entries, or by use of other methods permissible
            under State law.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            44 FR 18162
          </aref>
          , Mar. 27, 1979, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            47 FR 5700
          </aref>
          , Feb. 8, 1982; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            50 FR 23901
          </aref>
          , June 7, 1985; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            52 FR 44375
          </aref>
          , Nov. 19, 1987; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            56 FR 6946
          </aref>
          , Feb. 21, 1991]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14839'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1900:A:1900.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1900.3
      </num>
      <head>
        State, district, and county office employees.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          50 FR 23902
        </aref>
        , June 7, 1985, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          55 FR 43325
        </aref>
        , Oct. 29, 1990]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1900' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              1900.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          State, district, and county office employees.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The following officials and employees of the Farmers Home
          Administration or its successor agency under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
          , in accordance with applicable laws, and the regulations implementing
          these laws, for and on behalf of, and in the name of the United States
          of America or the Farmers Home Administration or its successor agency
          under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
          , are also severally authorized within the area of their respective
          jurisdictions to perform the acts specified in paragraphs (g) through
          (r) of 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1900' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              1900.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; and within their loan approval authority to sell or otherwise
          dispose of real or chattel property or interests therein and to
          execute and deliver bills of sale or other instruments to effect such
          sale or disposition: Chief, Farmer Programs/Specialist; Chief, Rural
          Housing/Specialist; Chief, Community Programs/Specialist; Chief,
          Business and Industry/Specialist; Chief, Community and Business
          Programs/Specialist; Chief, Appraisal Staff/Appraiser; Chief,
          Underwriting Staff/Underwriter; Chief, Underwriting and Appraisal
          Staff; Chief, Servicing and Inventory Staff/Credit Management
          Specialist/Realty Specialist; each District Director, Assistant
          District Director, Loan Specialist General, County (including Parish)
          Supervisor, Emergency Loan Supervisor, Assistant Emergency Loan
          Supervisor, or other supervisor or assistant supervisor, and in the
          absence or disability of any such official or employee, the person
          acting in the position.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            50 FR 23902
          </aref>
          , June 7, 1985, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            55 FR 43325
          </aref>
          , Oct. 29, 1990]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14840'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1900:A:1900.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1900.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Ratification.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          44 FR 18162
        </aref>
        , Mar. 27, 1979]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='457' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1900' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              1900.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Ratification.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          All written instruments affecting title to real or personal property,
          including but not limited to deeds, releases, satisfactions,
          subordination agreements, severance agreements, consents, waivers,
          assignments, declarations of trust, and heretofore executed by
          officials or employees of the agencies or other entities referred to
          in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1900' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              1900.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
           to carry out any purpose authorized by law, incident to the
          administration of programs under the jurisdiction of said agencies or
          other entities, are hereby approved, confirmed, and ratified.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            44 FR 18162
          </aref>
          , Mar. 27, 1979]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14841'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1900:A:1900.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1900.5
      </num>
      <head>
        Assignment of cases.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          55 FR 43325
        </aref>
        , Oct. 29, 1990]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1900' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              1900.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Assignment of cases.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The State Director may, in writing, assign responsibilities and
          functions to a different office or staff position within the FmHA or
          its successor agency under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
           State organizational structure other than that referred to in
          regulations, provided no benefits, rights, or opportunities of the
          public are changed.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            55 FR 43325
          </aref>
          , Oct. 29, 1990]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14842'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1900:A:1900.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1900.6
      </num>
      <head>
        Chair, Loan Resolution Task Force.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          59 FR 43441
        </aref>
        , Aug. 24, 1994]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1900' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              1900.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Chair, Loan Resolution Task Force.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The Chair, Loan Resolution Task Force is delegated the following
          authorities, to be exercised until September 30, 1996:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The responsibility for, under applicable Farmers Home
            Administration or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             regulations, collecting and settling all delinquent direct Farmer
            Program loans as defined in the Consolidated Farm and Rural
            Development Act, as amended, that have received all primary
            servicing rights and pre-acceleration homestead and preservation
            loan servicing rights under 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1951' tq='N'>
                1951
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , subpart S;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The responsibility for making and directing the making of loan
            servicing decisions, under applicable Farmers Home Administration or
            its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             regulations, concerning delinquent direct Farmer Programs loans for
            which accrued principal and interest equals or exceeds one million
            dollars, to extend to borrowers their remaining primary servicing
            rights and pre-acceleration homestead and preservation loan
            servicing rights under 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1951' tq='N'>
                1951
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , subpart S;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Authority for approving the grant of exceptions pursuant to 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='1951' sect='916' psec='' tq='N'>
                1951.916
              </subref>
              , 
              <subref title='7' part='1955' sect='21' psec='' tq='N'>
                1955.21
              </subref>
              , 
              <subref title='7' part='1956' sect='99' psec='' tq='N'>
                1956.99
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='1965' sect='35' psec='' tq='N'>
                1965.35
              </subref>
               of this chapter
            </aref>
            , to the extent necessary to carry out the responsibilities
            described in paragraphs (a) and (b) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            59 FR 43441
          </aref>
          , Aug. 24, 1994]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14843'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1900:A:1900.7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1900.7
      </num>
      <head>
        Effect on other regulations.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          44 FR 18162
        </aref>
        , Mar. 27, 1979. Redesignated at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          55 FR 43325
        </aref>
        , Oct. 29, 1990, and further redesignated at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          59 FR 43441
        </aref>
        , Aug. 24, 1994]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1900' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              1900.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Effect on other regulations.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          This subpart does not revoke or modify any other delegation or
          redelegation, instruction, procedure, or regulation issued by, or
          under authority of, the Administrator of the Farmers Home
          Administration or its successor agency under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            44 FR 18162
          </aref>
          , Mar. 27, 1979. Redesignated at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            55 FR 43325
          </aref>
          , Oct. 29, 1990, and further redesignated at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            59 FR 43441
          </aref>
          , Aug. 24, 1994]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14844'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1900:B:1900.51
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1900.51
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1900' sect='51' psec='' tq='N'>
              1900.51
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Act
          </E>
           means the Federal Crop Insurance Reform and Department of Agriculture
          Reorganization Act of 1994, Public Law No. 103-354 (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='6991' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/6991.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 6991
            </subref>
          </aref>
           et seq.).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Agency
          </E>
           means the Rural Utilities Service (RUS), the Rural Housing Service
          (RHS), and the Rural Business-Cooperative Development Service (RBS),
          or their successor agencies.
        </P>
        <P>
          Refer to 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR 
            <subref title='7' part='11' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              11.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
           for other definitions applicable to appeals of adverse decisions
          covered by this subpart.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14845'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1900:B:1900.52
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1900.52
      </num>
      <head>
        General.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1900' sect='52' psec='' tq='N'>
              1900.52
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          This subpart specifies procedures for use by USDA personnel and
          program participants to ensure that full and complete consideration is
          given to program participants who are affected by an agency adverse
          decision.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14846'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1900:B:1900.53
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1900.53
      </num>
      <head>
        Applicability.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1900' sect='53' psec='' tq='N'>
              1900.53
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Applicability.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Appeals of adverse decisions covered by this subpart will be
            governed by 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='11' tq='N'>
                11
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
            <PRTPAGE P='458' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The provisions of this subpart apply to adverse decisions
            concerning direct loans, loan guarantees, and grants under the
            following programs: RUS Water and Waste Disposal Facility Loans and
            Grants Program; RHS Housing and Community Facilities Loan Programs;
            RBS Loan, Grant, and Guarantee Programs and the Intermediary
            Relending Program; and determinations of the Rural Housing Trust
            1987-1 Master Servicer.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This subpart does not apply to decisions made by parties outside an
            agency even when those decisions are used as a basis for decisions
            falling within paragraph (b) of this section, for example: decisions
            by state governmental construction standards-setting agencies (which
            may determine whether RHS will finance certain houses); Davis-Bacon
            wage rates; flood plain determinations; archaeological and
            historical areas preservation requirements; and designations of
            areas inhabited by endangered species.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14847'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1900:B:1900.54
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1900.54
      </num>
      <head>
        Effect on assistance pending appeal.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1900' sect='54' psec='' tq='N'>
              1900.54
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Effect on assistance pending appeal.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Assistance will not be discontinued pending the outcome of an
            appeal of a complete or partial adverse decision.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph (a) of this section,
            administrative offsets initiated under subpart C of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1951' tq='N'>
                1951
              </subref>
            </aref>
             will not be stayed pending the outcome of an appeal and any further
            review of the decision to initiate the offset.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14848'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1900:B:1900.55
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1900.55
      </num>
      <head>
        Adverse action procedures.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1900' sect='55' psec='' tq='N'>
              1900.55
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Adverse action procedures.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If an applicant, guaranteed lender, a holder, borrower or grantee
            is adversely affected by a decision covered by this subpart, the
            decision maker will inform the participant of the adverse decision
            and whether the adverse decision is appealable. A participant has
            the right to request the Director of NAD to review the agency&apos;s
            finding of nonappealability in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR 
              <subref title='7' part='11' sect='6' psec='#a' tq='N'>
                11.6(a)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . In cases where the adverse decision is based on both appealable
            and nonappealable actions, the adverse action is not appealable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A participant affected by an adverse decision of an agency is
            entitled under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 275 of
            </aref>
             the Act to an opportunity for a separate informal meeting with the
            agency before commencing an appeal to NAD under 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='11' tq='N'>
                11
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Participants also have the right under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 275 of
            </aref>
             the Act to seek mediation involving any adverse decision appealable
            under this subpart if the mediation program of the State in which
            the participant&apos;s farming operation giving rise to the decision
            is located has been certified by the Secretary for the program
            involved in the decision. An agency shall cooperate in such
            mediation. Any time limitation for appeal will be stayed pending
            completion of the mediation process (
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR 
              <subref title='7' part='11' sect='5' psec='#c' tq='N'>
                11.5(c)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14849'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1900:B:1900.56
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1900.56
      </num>
      <head>
        Non-appealable decisions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1900' sect='56' psec='' tq='N'>
              1900.56
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Non-appealable decisions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The following are examples of decisions which are not appealable:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Decisions which do not fall within the scope of this subpart as set
            out in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1900' sect='53' psec='' tq='N'>
                1900.53
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Decisions that do not meet the definition of an “adverse decision”
            under 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='11' tq='N'>
                11
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Decisions involving parties who do not meet the definition of
            “participant” under 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='11' tq='N'>
                11
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Decisions with subject matters not covered by 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='11' tq='N'>
                11
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Interest rates as set forth in agency procedures, except for
            appeals alleging application of an incorrect interest rate.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State RECD Director&apos;s refusal to request an administrative
            waiver provided for in agency program regulations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Denials of assistance due to lack of funds or authority to
            guarantee.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14850'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1900:B:1900.57
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1900.57
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='459' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1900' sect='57' psec='' tq='N'>
              1900.57
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14851'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1900:C:1900.101
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1900.101
      </num>
      <head>
        General.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          44 FR 10979
        </aref>
        , Feb. 26, 1979, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          45 FR 8934
        </aref>
        , Feb. 11, 1980]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1900' sect='101' psec='' tq='N'>
              1900.101
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          This subpart provides Agency policy concerning:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The applicability of Federal rather than State Law in the conduct
            of Farmers Home Administration (FmHA) or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             operations, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The liability of an auctioneer for conversion of personal property
            mortgaged to FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            44 FR 10979
          </aref>
          , Feb. 26, 1979, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            45 FR 8934
          </aref>
          , Feb. 11, 1980]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14852'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1900:C:1900.102
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1900.102
      </num>
      <head>
        Applicable law.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          44 FR 10979
        </aref>
        , Feb. 26, 1979]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1900' sect='102' psec='' tq='N'>
              1900.102
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Applicable law.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Loans made by FmHA or its successor agency under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
           are authorized and executed pursuant to Federal programs adopted by
          Congress to achieve national purposes of the U.S. Government.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Instruments evidencing or securing a loan payable to or held by the
            Farmers Home Administration or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
            , such as promissory notes, bonds, guaranty agreements, mortgages,
            deeds of trust, financing statements, security agreements, and other
            evidences of debt or security shall be construed and enforced in
            accordance with applicable Federal law.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Instruments evidencing a guarantee, conditional commitment to
            guarantee, or a grant, such as contracts of guarantee, grant
            agreements or other evidences of an obligation to guarantee or make
            a grant, executed by the Farmers Home Administration or its
            successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
            , shall be construed and enforced in accordance with applicable
            Federal law.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In order to implement and facilitate these Federal loan programs,
            the application of local procedures, especially for recordation and
            notification purposes, may be utilized to the fullest extent
            feasible and practicable. However, the use of local procedures shall
            not be deemed or construed to be any 
            <PRTPAGE P='463' />
            waiver by FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             of Federal immunity from any local control, penalty, or liability,
            or to subject FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             to any State required acts or actions subsequent to the delivery by
            FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             officials of the instrument to the appropriate local or State
            official.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any person, corporation, or organization that applies for and
            receives any benefit or assistance from FmHA or its successor agency
            under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             that offers any assurance or security upon which FmHA or its
            successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             relies for the granting of such benefit or assistance, shall not be
            entitled to claim or assert any local immunity, privilege, or
            exemption to defeat the obligation such party incurred in obtaining
            or assuring such Federal benefit or assistance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The liability of an auctioneer for conversion of personal property
            mortgaged to FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             shall be determined and enforced in acceptance with the applicable
            Federal law. “Auctioneer” for the purposes of this subpart includes
            a commission merchant, market agency, factor or agent. In all cases
            in which there has been a disposition without authorization by FmHA
            or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             of personal property mortgaged to that agency, any auctioneer
            involved in said disposition shall be liable to the Government for
            conversion—notwithstanding any State statute or decisional rule to
            the contrary.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            44 FR 10979
          </aref>
          , Feb. 26, 1979]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14853'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1900:D:1900.151
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1900.151
      </num>
      <head>
        General.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 224
        </aref>
        , Jan. 5, 1993, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          71 FR 38979
        </aref>
        , July 11, 2006]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1900' sect='151' psec='' tq='N'>
              1900.151
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Farmers Home Administration (FmHA) or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             Instruction 2045-BB (available in any FmHA or its successor agency
            under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             office) requires the maintenance of high standards of honesty,
            integrity, and impartiality by employees. To reduce the potential
            for employee conflict of interest, any processing, approval,
            servicing or review activity, including access through automated
            information systems, is conducted only by authorized FmHA or its
            successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             employees who:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Are not themselves the recipient.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Are not members of the family or known close relatives of the
            recipient.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Do not have an immediate working relationship with the recipient,
            the employee related to the recipient, or the employee who would
            normally conduct the activity.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Do not have a business or close personal association with the
            recipient.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No provision of this subpart takes precedence over individual
            program requirements or restrictions, especially those restrictions
            found in FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             Instruction 2045-BB (available in any FmHA or its successor agency
            under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             office) relating to eligibility for FmHA or its successor agency
            under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             assistance of FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             employees, members of families of employees, close relatives, or
            business or close personal associates of employees.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The determination of a case&apos;s need for special handling under
            the provisions of this subpart is not an adverse action and,
            therefore, is not subject to appeal.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The provisions of this subpart do not apply to the Farm Service
            Agency. The relevant regulations applicable to the Farm Service
            Agency can be found at 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              5 CFR parts 
              <subref title='5' part='2635' tq='N'>
                2635
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='5' part='8301' tq='N'>
                8301
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 224
          </aref>
          , Jan. 5, 1993, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            71 FR 38979
          </aref>
          , July 11, 2006]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14854'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1900:D:1900.152
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1900.152
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1900' sect='152' psec='' tq='N'>
              1900.152
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Applicant or borrower.
          </E>
           All persons or organizations, individually or collectively, applying
          for or receiving insured or guaranteed loan or grant assistance from
          or through FmHA or its 
          <PRTPAGE P='464' />
          successor agency under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
          . Referred to as recipient.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Assistance.
          </E>
           Loans or grants made, insured or guaranteed, or serviced by FmHA or
          its successor agency under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Associates.
          </E>
           All persons with whom an employee has a business or close personal
          association or immediate working relationship.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Business association.
          </E>
           Business relationship between those with an identity of financial
          interest; including but not limited to a business partnership, being
          an officer, director, trustee, partner or employee of an organization,
          or other long-term contractual relationship.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Close personal association.
          </E>
           Social relationship between unrelated residents of the same
          household.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Close relatives.
          </E>
           The spouse, relatives and step-relatives of an employee or the
          employee&apos;s spouse, including Grandmother, Grandfather, Mother,
          Father, Aunt, Uncle, Sister, Brother, Daughter, Son, Niece, Nephew,
          Granddaughter, Grandson, and First Cousin.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Conflict of interest.
          </E>
           A situation (or the appearance of one) in which one could reasonably
          conclude that an FmHA or its successor agency under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
           employee&apos;s private interest conflicts with his or her Government
          duties and responsibilities, even though there may not actually be a
          conflict.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Employee.
          </E>
           All FmHA or its successor agency under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
           personnel, including gratuitous employees and those negotiating for
          or having arrangements for prospective employment, except as otherwise
          specifically stated. For the purposes of this instruction only, the
          term also refers to county or area committee members, elected or
          appointed, and to closing agents who, although they are not employees,
          have a special relationship to FmHA or its successor agency under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
           and therefore should be subject to these provisions.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Immediate working relationship.
          </E>
           A relationship between a subordinate and a supervisor in a direct
          line, or between co-workers in the same office. For the purposes of
          this subpart, the relationships among a County Supervisor and members
          of the local County Committee are immediate working relationships.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Members of family.
          </E>
           Blood and in-law relatives (such as by marriage or adoption) who are
          residents of the employee&apos;s household.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Recipient.
          </E>
           One who has applied for or received FmHA or its successor agency
          under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
           financial assistance in the form of a loan or grant. See definition
          of applicant or borrower.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14855'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1900:D:1900.153
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1900.153
      </num>
      <head>
        Identifying and reporting an employee relationship.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1900' sect='153' psec='' tq='N'>
              1900.153
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Identifying and reporting an employee relationship.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Responsiblity of applicant.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When an application for assistance is filed, the processing
            official asks if there is any known relationship or association with
            an FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             employee. The applicant is required to disclose the requested
            information under subpart A of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1910' tq='N'>
                1910 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and pertinent program regulations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Responsibility of FmHA or its successor agency under 
              <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
                Public Law 103-354
              </aref>
               employee.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             employee who knows he or she is related to or associated with an
            applicant or recipient, regardless of whether the relationship or
            association is known to others, is required to notify the FmHA or
            its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             official who is processing or servicing the assistance, in writing.
            FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             Guide Letter 1900-D-1 (available in any FmHA or its successor
            agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             office) may be used as the notice. If the appropriate official is
            not known, the State Director should be notified. Regardless of
            whether the relationship or association is defined in 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              § 1900.152 of
            </aref>
             this subpart, if the employee believes there may be a potential
            conflict of interest, the FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             official who is processing or servicing the assistance may be
            notified and special handling requested. An employee&apos;s request
            that the case receive special handling is usually honored.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Responsibility of FmHA or its successor agency under 
              <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
                Public Law 103-354
              </aref>
               official.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When any relationship or association is identified, the FmHA or its
            successor agency under Public Law 103-
            <PRTPAGE P='465' />
            354 official completes and submits FmHA or its successor agency
            under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             Guide Letter 1900-D-2 (available in any FmHA or its successor
            agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             office) to the State Director (or Administrator, under paragraph
            (e) of this section or 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              § 1900.155(a) of
            </aref>
             this subpart). When completed FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             Guide Letter 1900-D-3 (available in any FmHA or its successor
            agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             office) is returned by the State Director, the processing official;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            -(2) [Reserved]
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notifies the recipient in writing of the change in responsibility
            and any other pertinent information,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             [Reserved]
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Relationship or association established after application for FmHA
              or its successor agency under 
              <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
                Public Law 103-354
              </aref>
               assistance.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a relationship or association is established after an
            application has been filed or assistance has been provided, both
            recipient and employee are required to notify the FmHA or its
            successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             official who is processing or servicing the assistance. FmHA or its
            successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             Guide Letter 1900-D-1 (available in any FmHA or its successor
            agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             office) may be used for the notice.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Relationship or association with a State Office, Finance Office or
              National Office employee.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If an identified relationship or association is with an employee at
            a State Office (other than a State Director), Finance Office or
            National Office, the processing/servicing official completes and
            submits FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             Guide Letter 1900-D-2 (available in any FmHA or its successor
            agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             office) to the State Director in the normal manner. The State
            Director reviews the information, determines the need for special
            handling, designates the processing/servicing official, completes
            and submits FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             Guide Letter 1900-D-3 (available in any FmHA or its successor
            agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             office) to the Administrator for written concurrence. When the
            Administrator&apos;s concurrence is received, the State Director
            returns completed FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             Guide Letter 1900-D-3 to the original official who completes the
            action described in paragraph (c) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Relationship or association with a State Director.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If an identified relationship or association is with a State
            Director, the processing/servicing official completes and submits
            FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             Guide Letter 1900-D-2 (available in any FmHA or its successor
            agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             office) to the Administrator. The Administrator reviews, determines
            the need for special handling, designates the processing/servicing
            official, completes and returns FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             Guide Letter 1900-D-3 (available in any FmHA or its successor
            agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             office) to the original official who completes the action described
            in paragraph (c) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Change in relationship or association, status of FmHA or its
              successor agency under 
              <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
                Public Law 103-354
              </aref>
               assistance, or employee&apos;s duty station.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the relationship or association has changed, the application
            denied or the assistance otherwise terminated, or the FmHA or its
            successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             employee&apos;s duty station changed, the designated
            processing/servicing official completes FmHA or its successor agency
            under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             Guide Letter 1900-D-2 (available in any FmHA or its successor
            agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             office) with the new information and submits it. The review process
            takes place as described in paragraphs (a) through (e) of this
            section to determine if processing/servicing activity may return to
            normal or requires another change. If the assistance is denied or
            otherwise terminated, the designated official notifies the original
            official.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14856'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1900:D:1900.154
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1900.154
      </num>
      <head>
        Determining the need for special handling.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1900' sect='154' psec='' tq='N'>
              1900.154
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Determining the need for special handling.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The State Director (or Administrator, under 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1900' sect='153' psec='#e' tq='N'>
              1900.153(e)
            </subref>
          </aref>
           or 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            § 1900.155(a) of
          </aref>
           this subpart):
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             [Reserved]
            <PRTPAGE P='466' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Determines whether the reported relationship or association is
            defined in 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              § 1900.152 of
            </aref>
             this subpart and would violate the provisions of 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              § 1900.151(a) of
            </aref>
             this subpart,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            -(f) [Reserved]
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14857'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1900:D:1900.155
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1900.155
      </num>
      <head>
        Designating the processing/servicing official.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1900' sect='155' psec='' tq='N'>
              1900.155
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Designating the processing/servicing official.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Designating an official with equivalent authority.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State Director (or Administrator, under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              § 1900.253(e) of
            </aref>
             this subpart or this paragraph) designates a nonrelated or
            nonassociated FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             official authorized to conduct the activity under program
            regulations, established delegation of authority and approval
            authority under subpart A of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1901' tq='N'>
                1901 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , and whose duty station is most convenient to the recipient and to
            the security property. A type and/or amount of assistance processed
            or serviced by a County Supervisor or at a County Office should be
            assigned only to another County Supervisor or County Office. A type
            and/or amount of assistance processed or serviced by a District
            Director or at a District Office should be assigned only to another
            District Director or District Office.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              County Committee.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For processing or servicing decisions to be made by a County
            Committee, if the recipient is a member, a different County
            Committee is designated. If the recipient is related to or
            associated with the member, notwithstanding the provisions of 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              § 1900.151(a)(3) of
            </aref>
             this subpart, the State Director 
            <E T='03'>
              may
            </E>
             permit the decision to be made by the local committee, if the
            related/associated member abstains.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             [Reserved]
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14858'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1900:D:1900.156
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1900.156
      </num>
      <head>
        Special handling—processing.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1900' sect='156' psec='' tq='N'>
              1900.156
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Special handling—processing.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             [Reserved]
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Eligibility determination.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The designated processing official reviews the application and
            develops additional data as necessary. Upon determination of whether
            the assistance will be provided, the designated processing official
            notifies the applicant of the decision in writing under program
            regulations, subpart A of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1910' tq='N'>
                1910 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , and subpart B of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1900' tq='N'>
                1900
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . If the determination is favorable, unless otherwise designated,
            the complete application is returned to the original processing
            official for docket preparation. If the determination is
            unfavorable, the designated processing official as decisionmaker
            participates in the appeal process to its conclusion.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            -(e) [Reserved]
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Closing agent.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Unless there is a clear or apparent conflict of interest, closing
            will be at a location and by a closing agent chosen by the
            recipient.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Supervised bank account.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Unless there is a clear or apparent conflict of interest, any
            supervised bank account (or construction account) is established at
            a financial institution chosen by the recipient under subpart A of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1902' tq='N'>
                1902 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . Countersignature authority is delegated only to a nonrelated or
            nonassociated FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             official.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Construction inspection.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Construction inspections are delegated to a nonrelated or
            nonassociated employee authorized to conduct inspections, whose duty
            station is nearest the construction site. The designated
            processing/servicing official notifies the builder (or
            architect/engineer) in writing of how and from whom to request
            inspections.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14859'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1900:D:1900.157-1900.200
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1900.157-1900.200
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1900' sect='157-1900' psec='' tq='N'>
              1900.157-1900
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .200
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>