<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol1'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3
    </extid>
    <num>
      3
    </num>
    <head>
      DEBT MANAGEMENT
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='5' sect='301' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/5/301.html'>
              5 U.S.C. 301
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='31' sect='3701' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/31/3701.html'>
              31 U.S.C. 3701
            </subref>
            , 
            <subref title='31' sect='3711' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/31/3711.html'>
              3711
            </subref>
            , 
            <subref title='31' sect='3716-18' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/31/3716-18.html'>
              3716-18
            </subref>
            , 
            <subref title='31' sect='3720B' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/31/3720B.html'>
              3720B
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            31 CFR parts 
            <subref title='31' part='285' tq='N'>
              285
            </subref>
             and 
            <subref title='31' part='901-904' tq='N'>
              901-904
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            10 FR 807
          </aref>
          , Jan. 23, 1945, unless otherwise noted. Redesignated at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            13 FR 6903
          </aref>
          , Nov. 24, 1948.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='347'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:A:3.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.1
      </num>
      <head>
        Purpose and scope.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Purpose and scope.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              In general.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The regulations in this part prescribe standards and procedures for
            use by USDA agencies in the collection, compromise, suspension, or
            termination of debts owed to the United States.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The regulations in this part apply to all debts of the United
            States subject to collection by USDA agencies, except as otherwise
            specified in this part or by statute.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The regulations in this part do not preclude the Secretary from
            collection, compromise, suspension, or termination of debts as
            otherwise authorized by law. In such cases the laws and implementing
            regulations that are specifically applicable to claims collection
            activities of a particular agency generally shall take precedence
            over this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Agency specific regulations.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The regulations of this part shall apply to the Commodity Credit
            Corporation to the extent specified in 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1403' tq='N'>
                1403
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             USDA agencies may issue regulations to supplement this part in
            order to meet the specific requirements of individual programs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Inapplicability.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The regulations of this part shall not apply to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Collection of debts owed government travel card contractors by USDA
            employees;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Collection of debts owed by individual Food Stamp Program
            recipients for whom debt collection procedures are provided under 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR 
              <subref title='7' part='273' sect='18' psec='' tq='N'>
                273.18
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='348'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:A:3.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Authority.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Authority.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The regulations in this part are issued under the Debt Collection Act
          of 1982, as amended by the Debt Collection Improvement Act of 1996
          (DCIA) (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='31' sect='3701' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/31/3701.html'>
              31 U.S.C. 3701
            </subref>
          </aref>
           et seq.) and the Federal Claims Collection Standards issued pursuant
          to the DCIA by Treasury and Justice (
          <aref type='CFR'>
            31 CFR parts 
            <subref title='31' part='901-904' tq='N'>
              901-904
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ) that prescribe government-wide standards for administrative
          collection, compromise, suspension, or termination of agency
          collection action, disclosure of debt information to credit reporting
          agencies, referral of claims to private collection contractors for
          resolution, and referral to Justice for litigation to collect debts
          owed the government. The regulations under this part also are issued
          under Treasury regulations implementing DCIA (
          <aref type='CFR'>
            31 CFR part 
            <subref title='31' part='285' tq='N'>
              285
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ) and related statutes and regulations governing the offset of Federal
          salaries (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='5' sect='5512' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/5/5512.html'>
              5 U.S.C. 5512
            </subref>
             and 
            <subref title='5' sect='5514' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/5/5514.html'>
              5514
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            5 CFR part 
            <subref title='5' part='550' tq='N'>
              550
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , subpart K) and administrative offset of tax refunds (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='31' sect='3720A' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/31/3720A.html'>
              31 U.S.C. 3720A
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ).
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='349'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:A:3.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='301' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          For the purpose of this part, except as where otherwise specifically
          provided, the term or terms:
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Agency
          </E>
           means a subagency, office, or corporation within USDA subject to the
          authority or general supervision of the Secretary.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Centralized administrative offset
          </E>
           means referral of a debt to the Treasury Offset Program (TOP) for
          offset of payments made to a debtor by Federal agencies other than
          USDA.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Claim
          </E>
           and 
          <E T='03'>
            debt
          </E>
           are synonymous and interchangeable, and refer to an amount of money,
          funds, or property that has been determined by an agency official to
          be due the United States from any person, organization, or entity,
          except another Federal agency.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Commercial debt
          </E>
           means a debt arising out of a business activity.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Consumer debt
          </E>
           means a debt arising out of a personal activity.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Contracting officer
          </E>
           has the same meaning as in 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='41' sect='601' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/41/601.html'>
              41 U.S.C. 601
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Credit reporting agencies
          </E>
           (also known as 
          <E T='03'>
            credit bureaus
          </E>
          ) means major consumer credit reporting agencies that have signed
          agreements with agencies to receive and integrate credit information
          (data) from voluntary subscribers (Federal agencies and private sector
          entities) into their respective databases for the purpose of
          generating credit reports for sale to purchasers of credit data.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Creditor agency
          </E>
           means a Federal agency or USDA agency to which a debtor owes a debt,
          including a debt collection center when acting on behalf of a creditor
          agency in matters pertaining to collection of the debt.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Day
          </E>
           means calendar day unless otherwise specified.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Debt collection center
          </E>
           means Treasury or other government agency or division, designated by
          the Secretary of the Treasury with authority to collect debt on behalf
          of creditor agencies in accordance with 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='31' sect='3711' note='' psec='#g' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/31/3711.html#g'>
              31 U.S.C. 3711(g)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Debtor
          </E>
           means a person who owes a delinquent, nontax debt to the United
          States.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Delinquent
          </E>
           means a debt that has not been paid by the date specified in the
          agency&apos;s initial written demand for payment or applicable
          agreement or instrument (including a post-delinquency payment
          agreement), unless other satisfactory payment arrangements have been
          made, or as otherwise defined by program specific statutes or
          regulations.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Federal agency
          </E>
           means any other Department or entity within the Executive branch of
          the government.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Government
          </E>
           or 
          <E T='03'>
            Federal government
          </E>
           means the government of the United States, unless otherwise
          specified.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Internal administrative offset
          </E>
           means a non-centralized administrative offset between a USDA creditor
          agency and a USDA payment authorizing agency.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Justice
          </E>
           means the United States Department of Justice.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            NAD
          </E>
           means the USDA National Appeals Division.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Non-centralized administrative offset
          </E>
           means an agreement between a USDA creditor agency and a payment
          authorizing agency to offset the payments made by the payment
          authorizing agency to satisfy a USDA debt. An internal administrative
          offset is a type of non-centralized administrative offset.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Offset
          </E>
           means withholding funds payable by the United States to, or held by
          the United States for, a person to satisfy a debt owed by the payee.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            OGC
          </E>
           means the USDA Office of the General Counsel.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Payee
          </E>
           means a person who is due a payment from a payment authorizing
          agency, and includes a person who is entitled to all or part of a
          payment.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Payment authorizing agency
          </E>
           means a Federal agency or USDA agency that is authorized to disburse
          payments to a recipient.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Person
          </E>
           means an individual, corporation, partnership, association,
          organization, State or local government, or any other type of public
          or private entity other than a Federal agency.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Recoupment
          </E>
           means a special method for adjusting debts arising under the same
          transaction or occurrence, such as obligations arising under the same
          contract.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Reviewing officer
          </E>
           means a person designated by a creditor agency as responsible for
          conducting a hearing or providing documentary review on the existence
          of the debt and the propriety of an administrative collection action.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Secretary
          </E>
           means the Secretary of Agriculture, unless otherwise specified.
          <PRTPAGE P='302' />
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Treasury
          </E>
           means the United States Department of the Treasury.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            USDA
          </E>
           means the United States Department of Agriculture.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='350'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:A:3.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Delegations of authority.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Delegations of authority.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The head of an agency is authorized to exercise any or all of the
          functions provided by this part with respect to programs for which the
          head of the agency has delegated responsibility, and may delegate and
          authorize the redelegation of any of the functions vested in the head
          of the agency by this part, except as otherwise provided by this part.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='351'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:B:3.10
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.10
      </num>
      <head>
        Aggressive agency collection activity.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.10
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Aggressive agency collection activity.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          An agency shall aggressively collect all debts arising out of
          activities of, or referred or transferred for collection services to,
          that agency. Collection activities shall be undertaken promptly with
          follow-up action taken as necessary.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='352'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:B:3.11
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.11
      </num>
      <head>
        Demand for payment.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.11
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Demand for payment.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Demand Letters.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Generally, debt collection is initiated with a written demand for
            payment to the debtor unless an applicable agreement or instrument
            (including a post-delinquency payment agreement) provides otherwise
            (such as providing USDA an immediate right to collect upon
            delinquency). Written demand as described in paragraph (b) of this
            section shall be made promptly upon a debtor of the United States in
            terms that inform the debtor of the consequences of failing to
            cooperate with the agency to resolve the debt. The specific content,
            timing, and number of demand letters shall depend upon the type and
            amount of the debt and the debtor&apos;s response, if any, to the
            agency&apos;s letters or telephone calls. Where statutes or agency
            regulations are specific as to the requirements for demand letters,
            an agency shall follow its own procedures in formulating demand
            letters. Generally, one demand letter should suffice. In determining
            the timing of the demand letter(s), an agency shall give due regard
            to the need to refer debts promptly to Justice for litigation, in
            accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              31 CFR 
              <subref title='31' part='904' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
                904.1
              </subref>
            </aref>
             or otherwise. When necessary to protect the government&apos;s
            interest (for example, to prevent the running of a statute of
            limitations), written demand may be preceded by other appropriate
            actions under this part, including immediate referral for
            litigation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Required notices.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In demand letters, the USDA creditor agency shall inform the
            debtor:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The nature and amount of the debt; and the facts giving rise to the
            debt;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             How interest, penalties, and administrative costs are added to the
            debt, the date by which payment must be made to avoid such charges,
            and that such assessments must be made unless excused in accordance
            with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='3' sect='17' psec='' tq='N'>
                3.17
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The date by which payment should be made to avoid the enforced
            collection actions described in paragraph (b)(6) of this section;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The willingness of the creditor agency to discuss alternative
            payment arrangements and how the debtor may enter into a written
            agreement to repay the debt under terms acceptable to the agency (
            <E T='03'>
              see
            </E>
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='3' sect='16' psec='' tq='N'>
                3.16
              </subref>
            </aref>
            );
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The name, address, telephone number and email address (optional) of
            a contact person or office within the creditor agency;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The intention of the creditor agency to enforce collection if the
            debtor fails to pay or otherwise resolve the debt, by taking one or
            more of the following actions:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_6_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Offset.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Offset the debtor&apos;s USDA payments and refer the debtor&apos;s
            debt to TOP for offset against other Federal payments, including
            income tax refunds, in accordance with subpart D;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_6_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Private collection agency.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             [Reserved]
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_6_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Credit reporting agency reporting.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Report the debt to a credit reporting agency in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='3' sect='12' psec='' tq='N'>
                3.12
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
            <PRTPAGE P='303' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_6_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Administrative wage garnishment.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Refer the debt to Treasury in accordance with subpart E for
            possible collection by garnishing the debtor&apos;s wages through
            administrative wage garnishment;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_6_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Litigation.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Refer the debt to Justice in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='3' sect='21' psec='' tq='N'>
                3.21
              </subref>
            </aref>
             to initiate litigation to collect the debt;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_6_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Referral to Treasury.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Referral of the debt to Treasury for collection in accordance with
            subpart C of this part;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             That USDA debts over 180 days delinquent must be referred to
            Treasury for the collection actions described in paragraph (b)(6) of
            this section;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             How the debtor may inspect and copy records related to the debt;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             How the debtor may request a review of the USDA creditor
            agency&apos;s determination that the debtor owes a debt and present
            evidence that the debt is not delinquent or legally enforceable (
            <E T='03'>
              see
            </E>
             subpart F of this part);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             [Reserved]
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_11'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (11)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             How a debtor who is a Federal employee subject to Federal salary
            offset may request a hearing (
            <E T='03'>
              see
            </E>
             subpart G of this part);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_12'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (12)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             How a debtor may request a waiver of the debt, if applicable;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_13'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (13)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             How the debtor&apos;s spouse may claim his or her share of a joint
            income tax refund by filing Form 8379 with the Internal Revenue
            Service (
            <E T='03'>
              see http://www.irs.gov
            </E>
            );
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_14'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (14)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             How the debtor may exercise other statutory or regulatory rights
            and remedies available to the debtor;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_15'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (15)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             That certain debtors may be ineligible for government loans,
            guarantees, and insurance (
            <E T='03'>
              see
            </E>
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='3' sect='14' psec='' tq='N'>
                3.14
              </subref>
            </aref>
            );
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_16'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (16)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If applicable, the creditor agency&apos;s intention to suspend or
            revoke licenses, permits, or privileges (
            <E T='03'>
              see
            </E>
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='3' sect='14' psec='' tq='N'>
                3.14
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ); and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_17'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (17)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             That the debtor must advise the creditor agency of the filing of
            any bankruptcy proceedings of the debtor or of another person liable
            for the debt being collected.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Exceptions to notice requirements.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A USDA creditor agency may omit from a demand letter one or more of
            the provisions contained in paragraphs (b)(6) through (b)(17) if the
            USDA creditor agency, in consultation with OGC, determines that any
            provision is not legally required given the collection remedies to
            be applied to a particular debt.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Agencies shall exercise care to ensure that demand letters are
            mailed or hand-delivered on the same day that they are dated. There
            is no prescribed format for demand letters. Agencies shall utilize
            demand letters and procedures that will lead to the earliest
            practicable determination of whether the debt can be resolved
            administratively or must be referred for litigation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Agencies shall respond promptly to communications from debtors,
            within 30 days of receipt whenever feasible, and shall advise
            debtors who dispute debts to furnish available evidence to support
            their contentions.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Prior to the initiation of the demand process or at any time during
            or after completion of the demand process, if an agency determines
            to pursue, or is required to pursue, internal administrative offset,
            the procedures applicable to offset must be followed (
            <E T='03'>
              see
            </E>
             subpart D). The availability of funds or money for debt
            satisfaction by internal administrative offset, and the
            agency&apos;s determination to pursue collection by internal
            administrative offset, shall release the agency from the necessity
            of further compliance with paragraphs (a), (b), and (c) of this
            section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Prior to referring a debt for litigation under 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              31 CFR part 
              <subref title='31' part='904' tq='N'>
                904
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , agencies shall advise each debtor determined to be liable for the
            debt that, unless the debt can be collected administratively,
            litigation may be initiated. This notification shall comply with
            Executive Order 12988 (3 CFR, 1996 Comp., pp. 157-163) and may be
            given as part of a demand letter under paragraph (b) of this section
            or in a separate document. Litigation counsel for the government
            shall be advised that this notice has been given.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When an agency learns that a bankruptcy petition has been filed
            with respect to a debtor, before proceeding with further collection
            action, the agency shall immediately seek legal advice from OGC
            concerning the impact of the Bankruptcy Code on any pending or
            contemplated collection activities. Unless the agency is advised
            that the automatic stay imposed at the time of filing pursuant to 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='11' sect='362' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/11/362.html'>
                11 U.S.C. 362
              </subref>
            </aref>
            <PRTPAGE P='304' />
            has been lifted or is no longer in effect, in most cases collection
            activity against the debtor must stop immediately. The agency should
            take the following steps:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             After seeking legal advice, a proof of claim must be filed in most
            cases with the bankruptcy court or the Trustee. Agencies shall refer
            to the provisions of 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='11' sect='106' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/11/106.html'>
                11 U.S.C. 106
              </subref>
            </aref>
             relating to the consequences on sovereign immunity of filing a
            proof of claim.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the agency is a secured creditor, it may seek relief from the
            automatic stay regarding its security, subject to the provisions and
            requirements of 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='11' sect='362' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/11/362.html'>
                11 U.S.C. 362
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Offset is stayed in most cases by the automatic stay. However,
            agencies may seek legal advice from OGC to determine whether their
            payments to the debtor and payments of other agencies available for
            offset may be frozen by the agency until relief from the automatic
            stay can be obtained from the bankruptcy court. Agencies also may
            seek legal advice from OGC to determine whether recoupment is
            available.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='353'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:B:3.12
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.12
      </num>
      <head>
        Reporting of consumer debts.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='12' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.12
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Reporting of consumer debts.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Notice.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In demand letters to debtors sent in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='3' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
                3.11
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , agencies shall inform debtors:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The intent of the agency to report the delinquent consumer debt to
            credit reporting agencies after 60 days;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The specific information to be transmitted (
            <E T='03'>
              i.e.
            </E>
            , name, address, and taxpayer identification number, information
            about the debt);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The actions which may be taken by the debtor to prevent the
            reporting (
            <E T='03'>
              i.e.,
            </E>
             repayment in full or a repayment agreement); and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The rights of the debtor to seek review of the existence of the
            debt in accordance with subpart F.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Disclosure.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Disclosure of delinquent consumer debts must be consistent with the
            requirements of 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='31' sect='3711' note='' psec='#e' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/31/3711.html#e'>
                31 U.S.C. 3711(e)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , the Privacy Act of 1974 (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='5' sect='552a' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/5/552a.html'>
                5 U.S.C. 552a
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ), the Bankruptcy Code, and 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              31 CFR 
              <subref title='31' part='901' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
                901.4
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Non-duplication of hearings.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When an agency has given a debtor any of the notices required by
            this part and an opportunity for administrative review under subpart
            F, the agency need not duplicate such notice and review
            opportunities before reporting the delinquent debt to credit
            bureaus.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Stay of disclosure.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Agencies shall not disclose a delinquent debt to a credit reporting
            agency if a debtor requests review under subpart F until a final
            determination is made by a reviewing official that upholds the
            agency intent to disclose.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Commercial debt.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The requirement of this section does not apply to commercial debts,
            although agencies should report commercial debts to commercial
            credit bureaus.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='354'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:B:3.13
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.13
      </num>
      <head>
        Contracting with private collection contractors and with entities that
        locate and recover unclaimed assets [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='13' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.13
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Contracting with private collection contractors and with entities that
          locate and recover unclaimed assets. [Reserved]
        </SUBJECT>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='355'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:B:3.14
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.14
      </num>
      <head>
        Suspension or revocation of eligibility for loans and loan guarantees,
        licenses, permits, or privileges.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='14' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.14
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Suspension or revocation of eligibility for loans and loan guarantees,
          licenses, permits, or privileges.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Agencies are not permitted to extend financial assistance in the
            form of a loan, loan guarantee, or loan insurance to any person
            delinquent on a nontax debt owed to a Federal agency, except as
            otherwise authorized by law or upon waiver of application of this
            section by the USDA Chief Financial Officer (CFO) or Deputy CFO.
            This prohibition does not apply to disaster loans. Agencies may
            extend credit after the delinquency has been resolved. The Secretary
            of the Treasury may exempt classes of debts from this prohibition
            and has prescribed standards defining when a “delinquency” is
            “resolved” for purposes of this prohibition. 
            <E T='03'>
              See
            </E>
            <aref type='CFR'>
              31 CFR 
              <subref title='31' part='285' sect='13' psec='' tq='N'>
                285.13
              </subref>
            </aref>
             (Barring Delinquent Debtors From Obtaining Federal Loans or Loan
            Insurance or Guarantees).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Similarly, agencies also are not permitted to extend financial
            assistance (either directly or indirectly) in the form of grants,
            loans, or loan guarantees to judgment debtors who have a judgment
            lien placed against their property until the judgment is satisfied,
            unless the agency grants a waiver in accordance with agency
            regulations. 
            <E T='03'>
              See
            </E>
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='31' sect='3201' note='' psec='#e' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/31/3201.html#e'>
                31 U.S.C. 3201(e)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In non-bankruptcy cases, agencies seeking the collection of
            statutory penalties, forfeitures, or other types of claims must
            consider the suspension or revocation of licenses, permits, or other
            privileges for any inexcusable or willful failure of a debtor to pay
            such a 
            <PRTPAGE P='305' />
            debt in accordance with the agency&apos;s regulations or governing
            procedures. The debtor shall be advised in the agency&apos;s written
            demand for payment of the agency&apos;s ability to suspend or revoke
            licenses, permits, or privileges.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any agency making, guaranteeing, insuring, acquiring, or
            participating in, loans must consider suspending or disqualifying
            any lender, contractor, or broker from doing further business with
            the agency or engaging in programs sponsored by the agency if such
            lender, contractor, or broker fails to pay its debts to the
            government within a reasonable time or if such lender, contractor,
            or broker has been suspended, debarred, or disqualified from
            participation in a program or activity by another Federal agency.
            Failure to pay a single substantial debt, or a number of outstanding
            debts (including disallowed costs and overrun payments, but not
            including sums owed to the government under the Internal Revenue
            Code) owed to any Federal agency or instrumentality is grounds for
            nonprocurement suspension or debarment if the debt is uncontested
            and the debtor&apos;s legal administrative remedies for review of
            the debt are exhausted. 
            <E T='03'>
              See
            </E>
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR 
              <subref title='7' part='3017' sect='305' psec='#c_3' tq='N'>
                3017.305(c)(3)
              </subref>
               and 405(a)(2)
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The failure of any surety to honor its obligations in accordance
            with 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='31' sect='9305' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/31/9305.html'>
                31 U.S.C. 9305
              </subref>
            </aref>
             shall be reported to Treasury. Treasury will forward to all
            interested agencies notification that a surety&apos;s certificate of
            authority to do business with the government has been revoked.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The suspension or revocation of licenses, permits, or privileges
            also may extend to USDA programs or activities that are administered
            by the States on behalf of the government, to the extent that they
            affect the government&apos;s ability to collect money or funds owed
            by debtors. Therefore, States that manage USDA activities, pursuant
            to approval from the agencies, shall ensure that appropriate steps
            are taken to safeguard against issuing licenses, permits, or
            privileges to debtors who fail to pay their debts to the government.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In bankruptcy cases, before advising the debtor of an agency&apos;s
            intention to suspend or revoke licenses, permits, or privileges,
            agencies may seek legal advice from OGC concerning the impact of the
            Bankruptcy Code, particularly 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='11' sect='362' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/11/362.html'>
                11 U.S.C. 362
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='11' sect='525' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/11/525.html'>
                525
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , which may restrict such action.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='356'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:B:3.15
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.15
      </num>
      <head>
        Liquidation of collateral.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='15' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.15
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Liquidation of collateral.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In accordance with applicable statutes and regulations, agencies
            may liquidate security or collateral through a sale or a nonjudicial
            foreclosure, and apply the proceeds to the applicable debt(s), if
            the debtor fails to pay the debt(s) within a reasonable time after
            demand and if such action is in the best interest of the United
            States. Collection from other sources, including liquidation of
            security or collateral, is not a prerequisite to requiring payment
            by a surety, insurer, or guarantor unless such action is expressly
            required by statute or contract.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When an agency learns that a bankruptcy petition has been filed
            with respect to a debtor, the agency may seek legal advice from OGC
            concerning the impact of the Bankruptcy Code, including, but not
            limited to, 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='11' sect='362' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/11/362.html'>
                11 U.S.C. 362
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , to determine the applicability of the automatic stay and the
            procedures for obtaining relief from such stay prior to proceeding
            under paragraph (a) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='357'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:B:3.16
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.16
      </num>
      <head>
        Collection in installments.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='16' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.16
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Collection in installments.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whenever feasible, agencies shall collect the total amount of a
            debt in one lump sum. If a debtor is financially unable to pay a
            debt in one lump sum, agencies may accept payment in regular
            installments. Agencies shall obtain financial statements from
            debtors who represent that they are unable to pay in one lump sum
            and independently verify such representations whenever possible (
            <E T='03'>
              see
            </E>
            <aref type='CFR'>
              31 CFR 
              <subref title='31' part='902' sect='2' psec='#g' tq='N'>
                902.2(g)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             for methods of verification). Agencies that agree to accept
            payments in regular installments shall obtain a legally enforceable
            written agreement from the debtor that specifies all terms of the
            arrangement and that contains a provision accelerating the debt in
            the event of default.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The size and frequency of installment payments shall bear a
            reasonable relation to the size of the debt and the debtor&apos;s
            ability to pay. If possible, the 
            <PRTPAGE P='306' />
            installment payments shall be sufficient in size and frequency to
            liquidate the debt in three years or less.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Security for deferred payments shall be obtained in appropriate
            cases. Agencies may accept installment payments notwithstanding the
            refusal of the debtor to execute a written agreement or to give
            security, at the agency&apos;s option.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='358'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:B:3.17
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.17
      </num>
      <head>
        Interest, penalties, and administrative costs.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='17' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.17
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Interest, penalties, and administrative costs.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as provided in paragraphs (g) and (i) of this section,
            agencies shall charge interest, penalties, and administrative costs
            on debts owed to the United States pursuant to 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='31' sect='3717' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/31/3717.html'>
                31 U.S.C. 3717
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . If not included in the agency&apos;s demand notice, an agency
            shall mail or hand-deliver a written notice to the debtor, at the
            debtor&apos;s most recent address available to the agency,
            explaining the agency&apos;s requirements concerning these charges
            except where these requirements are included in a contractual or
            repayment agreement. These charges shall continue to accrue until
            the debt is paid in full or otherwise resolved through compromise,
            termination, or waiver of the charges.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Agencies shall charge interest on debts owed the United States as
            follows, except as otherwise required by law:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Interest shall accrue from the date of delinquency, or as otherwise
            provided by law.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Unless otherwise established in a contract, repayment agreement, or
            by statute, the rate of interest charged shall be the rate
            established annually by the Secretary of the Treasury in accordance
            with 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='31' sect='3717' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/31/3717.html'>
                31 U.S.C. 3717
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . Pursuant to 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='31' sect='3717' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/31/3717.html'>
                31 U.S.C. 3717
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , an agency may charge a higher rate of interest if it reasonably
            determines that a higher rate is necessary to protect the rights of
            the United States. The agency must document the reason(s) for its
            determination that the higher rate is necessary.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The rate of interest, as initially charged, shall remain fixed for
            the duration of the indebtedness. When a debtor defaults on a
            repayment agreement and seeks to enter into a new agreement, the
            agency may require payment of interest at a new rate that reflects
            the current value of funds to the Treasury at the time the new
            agreement is executed. Interest shall not be compounded, that is,
            interest shall not be charged on interest, penalties, or
            administrative costs required by this section. If, however, a debtor
            defaults on a previous repayment agreement, charges that accrued but
            were not collected under the defaulted agreement shall be added to
            the principal under the new repayment agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Agencies shall assess administrative costs incurred for processing
            and handling delinquent debts. The calculation of administrative
            costs shall be based on actual costs incurred or upon estimated
            costs as determined by the assessing agency.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Unless otherwise established in a contract, repayment agreement, or
            by statute, agencies shall charge a penalty, pursuant to 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='31' sect='3717' note='' psec='#e_2' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/31/3717.html#e_2'>
                31 U.S.C. 3717(e)(2)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , not to exceed six percent a year on the amount due on a debt that
            is delinquent for more than 90 days. This charge shall accrue from
            the date of delinquency.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Agencies may increase an “administrative debt” by the cost of
            living adjustment in lieu of charging interest and penalties under
            this section. “Administrative debt” includes, but is not limited to,
            a debt based on fines, penalties, and overpayments, but does not
            include a debt based on the extension of government credit, such as
            those arising from loans and loan guarantees. The cost of living
            adjustment is the percentage by which the Consumer Price Index for
            the month of June of the calendar year preceding the adjustment
            exceeds the Consumer Price Index for the month of June of the
            calendar year in which the debt was determined or last adjusted.
            Increases to administrative debts shall be computed annually.
            Agencies may use this alternative only when there is a legitimate
            reason to do so, such as when calculating interest and penalties on
            a debt would be extremely difficult because of the age of the debt.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When a debt is paid in partial or installment payments, amounts
            received by the agency shall be applied first to outstanding
            penalties, second 
            <PRTPAGE P='307' />
            to administrative charges, third to interest, and last to principal,
            except as otherwise required by law.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Agencies shall waive the collection of interest and administrative
            charges imposed pursuant to this section (
            <E T='03'>
              i.e.
            </E>
            , this does not apply to interest or administrative penalties
            determined by an applicable agreement or instrument such as a loan
            contract) on the portion of the debt that is paid within 30 days
            after the date on which interest began to accrue. Agencies may
            extend this 30-day period on a case-by-case basis. In addition,
            agencies may waive interest, penalties, and administrative costs
            charged under this section, in whole or in part, without regard to
            the amount of the debt, either under the criteria set forth in the
            Federal standards for the compromise of debts (
            <aref type='CFR'>
              31 CFR part 
              <subref title='31' part='902' tq='N'>
                902
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ), or if the agency determines that collection of these charges is
            against equity and good conscience or is not in the best interest of
            the United States.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             [Reserved]
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Agencies are authorized to impose interest and related charges on
            debts not subject to 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='31' sect='3717' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/31/3717.html'>
                31 U.S.C. 3717
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , in accordance with the common law. Agencies shall consult OGC
            before imposing interest and related charges under common law for
            any debt.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='359'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:B:3.18
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.18
      </num>
      <head>
        Use and disclosure of mailing addresses.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='18' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.18
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Use and disclosure of mailing addresses.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When attempting to locate a debtor in order to collect or
            compromise a debt under this part or 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              parts 902-904 of
            </aref>
             title 31 or other authority, agencies may send a request to
            Treasury to obtain a debtor&apos;s mailing address from the records
            of the Internal Revenue Service (IRS).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Agencies are authorized to use mailing addresses obtained under
            paragraph (a) of this section to enforce collection of a delinquent
            debt and may disclose such mailing addresses to other agencies and
            to collection agencies for collection purposes.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='360'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:B:3.19
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.19
      </num>
      <head>
        Standards for the compromise of claims.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='19' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.19
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Standards for the compromise of claims.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          An agency shall follow the standards set forth in 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            31 CFR part 
            <subref title='31' part='902' tq='N'>
              902
            </subref>
          </aref>
           for the compromise of debts pursuant to 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='31' sect='3711' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/31/3711.html'>
              31 U.S.C. 3711
            </subref>
          </aref>
           arising out of the activities of, or referred or transferred for
          collection services to, that agency, except where otherwise authorized
          or required by law.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='361'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:B:3.20
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.20
      </num>
      <head>
        Standards for suspending or terminating collection activities.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='20' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.20
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Standards for suspending or terminating collection activities.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          An agency shall follow the standards set forth in 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            31 CFR part 
            <subref title='31' part='903' tq='N'>
              903
            </subref>
          </aref>
           for the suspension or termination of collection activity pursuant to 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='31' sect='3711' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/31/3711.html'>
              31 U.S.C. 3711
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , except where otherwise authorized or required by law.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='362'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:B:3.21
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.21
      </num>
      <head>
        Referrals of Debts to Justice.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='21' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.21
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Referrals of Debts to Justice.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          An agency shall promptly refer to Justice for litigation debts on
          which aggressive collection activity has been taken in accordance with
          this part, and that cannot be compromised by the agency or on which
          collection activity cannot be suspended or terminated in accordance
          with 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            31 CFR parts 
            <subref title='31' part='902' tq='N'>
              902
            </subref>
             and 
            <subref title='31' part='903' tq='N'>
              903
            </subref>
          </aref>
          . Agencies shall follow the procedures set forth in 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            31 CFR part 
            <subref title='31' part='904' tq='N'>
              904
            </subref>
          </aref>
           in making such referrals.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='363'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:C:3.30
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.30
      </num>
      <head>
        General requirements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='30' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.30
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Agencies are required by law to transfer delinquent, nontax,
            legally enforceable debts to Treasury for collection through
            cross-servicing and through centralized administrative offset.
            Additionally, USDA has chosen to transfer debts to Treasury for
            collection through administrative wage garnishment. Agencies need
            not make duplicate referrals to Treasury for all these purposes; a
            debt may be referred simultaneously for purposes of collection by
            cross-servicing, centralized administrative offset, and
            administrative wage garnishment where applicable. However, in some
            instances a debt exempt from collection via cross-servicing may be
            subject to collection by centralized administrative offset so
            simultaneous referrals are not always the norm. This subpart sets
            forth rules applicable to the transfer of debts to Treasury for
            collection by cross-servicing. Rules for transfer to Treasury for
            centralized administrative offset 
            <PRTPAGE P='308' />
            are set forth in subpart D, and for administrative wage garnishment
            in subpart E.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When debts are referred or transferred to Treasury, or
            Treasury-designated debt collection centers under the authority of 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='31' sect='3711' note='' psec='#g' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/31/3711.html#g'>
                31 U.S.C. 3711(g)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , Treasury shall service, collect, or compromise the debts, or
            Treasury will suspend or terminate the collection action, in
            accordance with the statutory requirements and authorities
            applicable to the collection of such debts.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='364'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:C:3.31
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.31
      </num>
      <head>
        Mandatory referral for cross-servicing.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='31' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.31
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Mandatory referral for cross-servicing.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Agencies shall transfer to Treasury any legally enforceable nontax
            debt in excess of $25, or combination of debts less than $25 that
            exceeds $25 (in the case of a debtor whose taxpayer identification
            number (TIN) is unknown the applicable threshold is $100), that has
            or have been delinquent for a period of 180 days in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              31 CFR 
              <subref title='31' part='285' sect='12' psec='' tq='N'>
                285.12
              </subref>
            </aref>
             so that Treasury may take appropriate action on behalf of the
            creditor agency to collect or compromise, or to suspend or terminate
            collection, of the debt, including use of debt collection centers
            and private collection contractors to collect the debt or terminate
            collection action.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The requirement of paragraph (a) of this section does not apply to
            any debt that:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is in litigation or foreclosure (
            <E T='03'>
              see
            </E>
            <aref type='CFR'>
              31 CFR 
              <subref title='31' part='385' sect='12' psec='#d_2' tq='N'>
                385.12 (d)(2)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             for definition);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Will be disposed of under an approved asset sale program (
            <E T='03'>
              see
            </E>
            <aref type='CFR'>
              31 CFR 
              <subref title='31' part='285' sect='12' psec='#d_3_i' tq='N'>
                285.12(d)(3)(i)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             for definition);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Has been referred to a private collection contractor for a period
            of time acceptable to Treasury;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is at a debt collection center for a period of time acceptable to
            Treasury;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Will be collected under internal offset procedures within three
            years after the debt first became delinquent;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is exempt from this requirement based on a determination by the
            Secretary of the Treasury that exemption for a certain class of debt
            is in the best interest of the United States. Federal agencies may
            request that the Secretary of the Treasury exempt specific classes
            of debts. Any such request by an agency must be sent to the Fiscal
            Assistant Secretary of the Treasury by the USDA CFO.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A debt is considered 180 days delinquent for purposes of this
            section if it is 180 days past due and is legally enforceable. A
            debt is past due if it has not been paid by the date specified in
            the agency&apos;s initial written demand for payment or applicable
            agreement or instrument (including a post-delinquency payment
            agreement) unless other satisfactory payment arrangements have been
            made. A debt is legally enforceable if there has been a final agency
            determination that the debt, in the amount stated, is due and there
            are no legal bars to collection action. Where, for example, a debt
            is the subject of a pending administrative review process required
            by statute or regulation and collection action during the review
            process is prohibited, the debt is not considered legally
            enforceable for purposes of mandatory transfer to Treasury and is
            not to be transferred even if the debt is more than 180 days past
            due. When a final agency determination is made after an
            administrative appeal or review process (including administrative
            review under subpart F), the creditor agency must transfer such debt
            to Treasury, if more than 180 days delinquent, within 30 days after
            the date of the final decision.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='365'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:C:3.32
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.32
      </num>
      <head>
        Discretionary referral for cross-servicing.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='32' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.32
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Discretionary referral for cross-servicing.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Agencies shall consider referring legally enforceable nontax debts
          that are less than 180 days delinquent to Treasury or to
          Treasury-designated “debt collection centers” in accordance with 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            31 CFR 
            <subref title='31' part='285' sect='12' psec='' tq='N'>
              285.12
            </subref>
          </aref>
           to accomplish efficient, cost effective debt collection if no USDA
          payments will be available to collect the debt through internal
          administrative offset under 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='43' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.43
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='366'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:C:3.33
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.33
      </num>
      <head>
        Required certification.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='33' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.33
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Required certification.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Agencies referring delinquent debts to Treasury for collection via
          cross-servicing must certify, in writing, that:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The debts being transferred are valid and legally enforceable;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             There are no legal bars to collection; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The agency has complied with all prerequisites to a particular
            collection action under the laws, regulations or 
            <PRTPAGE P='309' />
            policies applicable to the agency, unless the agency and Treasury
            agree that Treasury will do so on behalf of the agency.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='367'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:C:3.34
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.34
      </num>
      <head>
        Fees.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='34' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.34
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Fees.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Federal agencies operating Treasury-designated debt collection centers
          are authorized to charge a fee for services rendered regarding
          referred or transferred debts. The fee may be paid out of amounts
          collected and may be added to the debt as an administrative cost.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='368'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:D:3.40
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.40
      </num>
      <head>
        Scope.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='40' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.40
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Scope.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This subpart sets forth the procedures to be used by agencies in
            collecting debts by administrative offset. The term “administrative
            offset” has the meaning provided in 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='31' sect='3701' note='' psec='#a_1' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/31/3701.html#a_1'>
                31 U.S.C. 3701(a)(1)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This section does not apply to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Debts arising under the Social Security Act, except as provided in 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='42' sect='404' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/42/404.html'>
                42 U.S.C. 404
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payments made under the Social Security Act, except as provided for
            in 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='31' sect='3716' note='' psec='#c' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/31/3716.html#c'>
                31 U.S.C. 3716(c)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             (
            <E T='03'>
              see
            </E>
            <aref type='CFR'>
              31 CFR 
              <subref title='31' part='285' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
                285.4
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , Federal Benefit Offset);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Debts arising under, or payments made under, the Internal Revenue
            Code (except for offset of tax refunds) or the tariff laws of the
            United States;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Offsets against Federal salaries (such offsets are covered by
            subpart F);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Offsets under 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='31' sect='3728' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/31/3728.html'>
                31 U.S.C. 3728
              </subref>
            </aref>
             against a judgment obtained by a debtor against the United States;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Offsets or recoupments under common law, State law, or Federal
            statutes specifically prohibiting offsets or recoupments of
            particular types of debts;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Offsets in the course of judicial proceedings, including
            bankruptcy; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Intracontractual offsets to satisfy contract debts taken by a
            contracting officer under the Contract Disputes Act, 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='41' sect='601-613' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/41/601-613.html'>
                41 U.S.C. 601-613
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Unless otherwise provided for by contract or law, debts or payments
            that are not subject to administrative offset under 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='31' sect='3716' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/31/3716.html'>
                31 U.S.C. 3716
              </subref>
            </aref>
             may be collected by administrative offset under the common law or
            other applicable statutory authority.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Supplemental provisions related to offsets by the Commodity Credit
            Corporation (CCC) may be found at 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1403' tq='N'>
                1403
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and for the Farm Service Agency at 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='792' tq='N'>
                792
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Unless otherwise provided by law, administrative offset of payments
            under the authority of 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='31' sect='3716' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/31/3716.html'>
                31 U.S.C. 3716
              </subref>
            </aref>
             to collect a debt may not be conducted more than 10 years after the
            government&apos;s right to collect the debt first accrued, unless
            facts material to the government&apos;s right to collect the debt
            were not known and could not reasonably have been known by the
            official or officials of the government who were charged with the
            responsibility to discover and collect such debts. This limitation
            does not apply to debts reduced to a judgment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In bankruptcy cases, agencies may seek legal advice from OGC
            concerning the impact of the Bankruptcy Code, particularly 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='11' sect='106' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/11/106.html'>
                11 U.S.C. 106
              </subref>
              , 
              <subref title='11' sect='362' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/11/362.html'>
                362
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , and 553, on pending or contemplated collections by offset.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='369'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:D:3.41
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.41
      </num>
      <head>
        Procedures for notification of intent to collect by administrative
        offset.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='41' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.41
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Procedures for notification of intent to collect by administrative
          offset.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Prior to initiation of collection by administrative offset, a
            creditor agency must:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Send the debtor a written Notice of Intent to Collect by
            Administrative Offset, by mail or hand-delivery, of the type and
            amount of the debt, the intention of the agency to use
            non-centralized administrative offset (which includes a USDA
            internal administrative offset) to collect the debt 30 days after
            the date of the Notice, the name of the Federal agency or USDA
            agency from which the creditor agency wishes to collect in the case
            of a non-centralized administrative offset, the intent to refer the
            debt to Treasury for collection through centralized administrative
            offset (including possible offset of tax refunds) 60 days after the
            date of the Notice if the debt is not satisfied by offset within
            USDA or by agreement with another Federal agency, and an explanation
            of the debtor&apos;s rights under 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='31' sect='3716' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/31/3716.html'>
                31 U.S.C. 3716
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Give the debtor the opportunity:
            <PRTPAGE P='310' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To inspect and copy agency records related to the debt;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For a review within the agency of the determination of indebtedness
            in accordance with subpart F; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To make a written agreement to repay the debt.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The procedures set forth in paragraph (a) of this section are not
            required when:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The offset is in the nature of a recoupment;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The debt arises under a contract subject to the Contracts Disputes
            Act;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the case of a non-centralized administrative offset, the agency
            first learns of the existence of the amount owed by the debtor when
            there is insufficient time before payment would be made to the
            debtor/payee to allow for prior notice and an opportunity for
            review. When prior notice and an opportunity for review are omitted,
            the agency shall give the debtor such notice and an opportunity for
            review as soon as practicable and shall promptly refund any money
            ultimately found not to have been owed to the government; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The agency previously has given a debtor any of the notice and
            review opportunities required under this part, with respect to a
            particular debt (
            <E T='03'>
              see, e.g.
            </E>
            , 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='3' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
                3.11
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ). With respect to loans paid on an installment basis, notice and
            opportunity to review under this part may only be provided once for
            the life of the loan upon the occurrence of the first delinquent
            installment. Subsequently, if an agency elects this option, credit
            reporting agencies may be furnished periodically with updates as to
            the current or delinquent status of the loan account and the
            borrower may receive notice of referral to TOP for delinquent
            installments without further opportunity for review. Any interest
            accrued or any installments coming due after the offset is initiated
            also would not require a new notice and opportunity to review.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Notice of Intent to Collect by Administrative Offset shall be
            included as part of a demand letter issued under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='3' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
                3.11
              </subref>
            </aref>
             to advise the debtor of all debt collection possibilities that the
            agency will seek to employ.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='370'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:D:3.42
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.42
      </num>
      <head>
        Debtor rights to inspect or copy records, submit repayment proposals, or
        request administrative review.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='42' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.42
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Debtor rights to inspect or copy records, submit repayment proposals,
          or request administrative review.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A debtor who intends to inspect or copy agency or USDA records with
            respect to the debt must notify the creditor agency in writing
            within 30 days of the date of the Notice of Intent to Collect by
            Administrative Offset. In response, the agency must notify the
            debtor of the location, time, and any other conditions, consistent
            with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1' tq='N'>
                1
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , subpart A, of this title, for inspecting and copying, and that the
            debtor may be liable for reasonable copying expenses. A decision by
            the agency under this paragraph shall not be subject to review under
            subpart F or by NAD under 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='11' tq='N'>
                11
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The debtor may, in response to the Notice of Intent to Collect by
            Administrative Offset, propose to the creditor agency a written
            agreement to repay the debt as an alternative to administrative
            offset. Any debtor who wishes to do this must submit a written
            proposal for repayment of the debt, which must be received by the
            creditor agency within 30 days of the date of the Notice of Intent
            to Collect by Administrative Offset or 15 days after the date of a
            decision adverse to the debtor under subpart F. In response, the
            creditor agency must notify the debtor in writing whether the
            proposed agreement is acceptable. In exercising its discretion, the
            creditor agency must balance the government&apos;s interest in
            collecting the debt against fairness to the debtor. A decision by
            the agency under this paragraph shall not be subject to review under
            subpart F or by NAD under 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='11' tq='N'>
                11
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A debtor must request an administrative review of the debt under
            subpart F within 30 days of the date of the Notice of Intent to
            Collect by Administrative Offset for purposes of a proposed
            collection by non-centralized administrative offset and within 60
            days of the date of the Notice of Intent to Collect by
            Administrative Offset for purposes of a proposed collection by
            referral to Treasury for offset against other Federal payments that
            would include tax refunds.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='371'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:D:3.43
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.43
      </num>
      <head>
        Non-centralized administrative offset.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='311' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='43' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.43
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Non-centralized administrative offset.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Scope.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In cooperation with the Federal agency certifying or authorizing
            payments to the debtor, a creditor agency may make a request
            directly to a payment authorizing agency to offset a payment due a
            debtor to collect a delinquent debt from, for example, a Federal
            employee&apos;s lump sum payment upon leaving government service in
            order to pay an unpaid advance. Also, non-centralized administrative
            offsets include USDA internal administrative offsets, for example,
            of CCC payments to pay Farm Service Agency (FSA) delinquent debts.
            Unless prohibited by law, when centralized administrative offset is
            not available or appropriate, past due, legally enforceable nontax
            delinquent debts may be collected through non-centralized
            administrative offset.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Effectuation of offset.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A non-centralized administrative offset may be effected 31 days
            after the date of the Notice of Intent to Collect by Administrative
            Offset, any time after the final determination in an administrative
            review conducted under subpart F upholds the creditor agency&apos;s
            decision to offset, or any time after the creditor agency notifies
            the debtor that its repayment proposal submitted under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='3' sect='42' psec='#c' tq='N'>
                3.42(c)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             is not acceptable if the 30-day period for the debtor to seek
            review of the Notice has expired, unless the creditor agency makes a
            determination under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='3' sect='41' psec='#b_3' tq='N'>
                3.41(b)(3)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             that immediate action to effectuate the offset is necessary.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Certification.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A payment authorizing agency may conduct a non-centralized
            administrative offset only after certification by a creditor agency
            that:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The debtor has been provided notice and opportunity for review as
            set forth in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='3' sect='41' psec='' tq='N'>
                3.41
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The payment authorizing agency has received written certification
            from the creditor agency that the debtor owes the past due, legally
            enforceable delinquent debt in the amount stated, and that the
            creditor agency has fully complied with its regulations concerning
            administrative offset.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Responsibilities of payment authorizing agencies.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payment authorizing agencies shall comply with offset requests by
            creditor agencies to collect debts owed to the United States, unless
            the offset would not be in the best interests of the United States
            with respect to the program of the payment authorizing agency, or
            would otherwise be contrary to law. Appropriate use should be made
            of the cooperative efforts of other agencies in effecting collection
            by administrative offset.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Application of recovered amounts to satisfaction of debts.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When collecting multiple debts by non-centralized administrative
            offset, agencies shall apply the recovered amounts to those debts in
            accordance with the best interests of the United States, as
            determined by the facts and circumstances of the particular case,
            particularly the applicable statute of limitations.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='372'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:D:3.44
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.44
      </num>
      <head>
        Centralized administrative offset.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='44' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.44
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Centralized administrative offset.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Mandatory referral.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             After the notice and review opportunity requirements of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='3' sect='41' psec='' tq='N'>
                3.41
              </subref>
            </aref>
             are met, an agency shall refer debts which are over 180 days
            delinquent to Treasury for collection through centralized
            administrative offset 61 days after the date of the Notice of Intent
            to Collect by Administrative Offset provided in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='3' sect='41' psec='' tq='N'>
                3.41
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . If the debtor seeks review under subpart F, referral of the debt
            must occur within 30 days of the final decision upholding the agency
            decision to offset the debt if the debt is more than 180 days
            delinquent.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Discretionary referral.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             After the notice and review opportunity requirements of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='3' sect='41' psec='' tq='N'>
                3.41
              </subref>
            </aref>
             are met, and administrative review under subpart F is not sought or
            is unsuccessful on the part of the debtor, an agency may refer a
            debt that is less than 180 days delinquent.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Procedures for referral.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Agencies shall refer debts to Treasury for collection in accordance
            with Treasury procedures set forth in 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              31 CFR part 
              <subref title='31' part='285' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
                285.5
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Payment authorizing agency responsibilities.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The names and TINs of debtors who owe debts referred to Treasury
            under this section shall be compared to the names and TINs on
            payments to be made by Federal disbursing officials. Federal
            disbursing officials include disbursing officials of Treasury, the
            Department of Defense, the United States Postal Service, other 
            <PRTPAGE P='312' />
            government corporations, and disbursing officials of the United
            States designated by Treasury. When the name and TIN of a debtor
            match the name and TIN of a payee and all other requirements for
            offset have been met, the payment authorizing agency must offset a
            payment to satisfy the debt.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any USDA official serving as a Federal disbursing official for
            purposes of effecting centralized administrative offset under this
            section must notify a debtor/payee in writing that an offset has
            occurred to satisfy, in part or in full, a past due, legally
            enforceable delinquent debt. The notice must include the information
            set forth in paragraph (d)(4) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             As described in 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              31 CFR 
              <subref title='31' part='285' sect='5' psec='#g_1' tq='N'>
                285.5(g)(1) and (2)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , any USDA official serving as a Federal disbursing official for
            purposes of centralized administrative offset under this section
            shall furnish a warning notice to a payee/debtor prior to beginning
            offset of recurring payments. Such warning notice shall include the
            information set forth in paragraph (d)(4) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The notice shall include a description of the type and amount of
            the payment from which the offset was taken, the amount of offset
            that was taken, the identity of the creditor agency requesting the
            offset, and a contact point within the creditor agency who will
            respond to questions regarding the offset.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The priorities for collecting multiple payments owed by a
            payee/debtor shall be those set forth in 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              31 CFR 
              <subref title='31' part='285' sect='5' psec='#f_3' tq='N'>
                285.5(f)(3)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='373'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:D:3.45
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.45
      </num>
      <head>
        USDA payment authorizing agency offset of pro rata share of payments due
        entity in which debtor participates.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='45' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.45
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          USDA payment authorizing agency offset of pro rata share of payments
          due entity in which debtor participates.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A USDA payment authorizing agency, to satisfy either a
            non-centralized or centralized administrative offset under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              §§ 
              <subref title='7' part='3' sect='43' psec='' tq='N'>
                3.43
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='3' sect='44' psec='' tq='N'>
                3.44
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , may offset:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A debtor&apos;s pro rata share of USDA payments due any entity in
            which the debtor participates, either directly or indirectly, as
            determined by the creditor agency or the payment authorizing agency;
            or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             USDA payments due any entity that the debtor has established, or
            reorganized, transferred ownership of, or changed in some other
            manner the operation of, for the purpose of avoiding payment on the
            claim or debt, as determined by the creditor agency or the payment
            authorizing agency.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Prior to exercising the authority of this section to offset any
            portion of a payment due an entity, the creditor agency must have
            provided notice to that entity in accordance with 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              § 3.41 of
            </aref>
             its intent to offset payments to the entity in satisfaction of the
            debt of an individual debtor participating in that entity.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='374'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:D:3.46
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.46
      </num>
      <head>
        Offset against tax refunds.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='46' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.46
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Offset against tax refunds.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          USDA will take action to effect administrative offset against tax
          refunds due to debtors under 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='26' sect='6402' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/26/6402.html'>
              26 U.S.C. 6402
            </subref>
          </aref>
           in accordance with the provisions of 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='31' sect='3720A' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/31/3720A.html'>
              31 U.S.C. 3720A
            </subref>
          </aref>
           through referral for centralized administrative offset under 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='44' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.44
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='375'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:D:3.47
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.47
      </num>
      <head>
        Offset against amounts payable from Civil Service Retirement and
        Disability Fund.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='47' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.47
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Offset against amounts payable from Civil Service Retirement and
          Disability Fund.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Upon providing the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) written
          certification that a debtor has been afforded the procedures provided
          in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='41' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.41
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , creditor agencies may request OPM to offset a debtor&apos;s
          anticipated or future benefit payments under the Civil Service
          Retirement and Disability Fund (Fund) in accordance with regulations
          codified at 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            5 CFR 
            <subref title='5' part='831' sect='1801' psec='' tq='N'>
              831.1801
            </subref>
          </aref>
           through 831.1808. Upon receipt of such a request, OPM will identify
          and “flag” a debtor&apos;s account in anticipation of the time when
          the debtor requests, or becomes eligible to receive, payments from the
          Fund. This will satisfy any requirement that offset be initiated prior
          to the expiration of the time limitations referenced in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='40' psec='#e' tq='N'>
              3.40(e)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='376'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:E:3.50
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.50
      </num>
      <head>
        Purpose.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='50' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.50
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Purpose.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          This subpart provides USDA procedures for use of administrative wage
          garnishment to garnish a debtor&apos;s disposable pay to satisfy
          delinquent nontax debt owed to USDA creditor agencies.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='377'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:E:3.51
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.51
      </num>
      <head>
        Scope.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='313' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='51' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.51
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Scope.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This subpart applies to any agency that administers a program that
            gives rise to a delinquent nontax debt owed to the United States and
            to any agency that pursues recovery of such debt.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This subpart shall apply notwithstanding any provision of State
            law.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Nothing in this subpart precludes the compromise of a debt or the
            suspension or termination of collection action in accordance with
            the provisions of this part or other applicable law.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The receipt of payments pursuant to this subpart does not preclude
            an agency from pursuing other debt collection remedies under this
            part. An agency may pursue such debt collection remedies separately
            or in conjunction with administrative wage garnishment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This subpart does not apply to the collection of delinquent nontax
            debt owed to the United States from the wages of Federal employees
            from their Federal employment. Federal pay is subject to the salary
            offset procedures of subpart G of this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Nothing in this subpart requires agencies to duplicate notices or
            administrative proceedings required by contract or other laws or
            regulations, or other provisions of this part.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='378'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:E:3.52
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.52
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='52' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.52
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          As used in this subpart the following definitions shall apply:
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Disposable pay
          </E>
           means that part of the debtor&apos;s compensation (including, but not
          limited to, salary, bonuses, commissions, and vacation pay) from an
          employer remaining after the deduction of health insurance premiums
          and any amounts required by law to be withheld. For purposes of this
          section, “amounts required by law to be withheld” include amounts for
          deductions such as social security taxes and withholding taxes, but do
          not include any amount withheld pursuant to a court order.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Employer
          </E>
           means a person or entity that employs the services of others and that
          pays their wages or salaries. The term employer includes, but is not
          limited to, State and local governments, but does not include an
          agency of the Federal government.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Garnishment
          </E>
           means the process of withholding amounts from an employee&apos;s
          disposable pay and the paying of those amounts to a creditor in
          satisfaction of a withholding order.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Withholding order
          </E>
           means any order for withholding or garnishment of pay issued by an
          agency, or judicial or administrative body. For purposes of this
          section, the terms “wage garnishment order” and “garnishment order”
          have the same meaning as “withholding order.”
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='379'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:E:3.53
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.53
      </num>
      <head>
        Procedures.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='53' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.53
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Procedures.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             USDA has determined to pursue administrative wage garnishment of
            USDA debtors by referral of nontax legally enforceable debts to
            Treasury for issuance of garnishment orders by Treasury or its
            contractors.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Pursuant to 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='3' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
                3.11
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , agencies must notify debtors of their intent to pursue garnishment
            of their disposable pay through referral of the debt to Treasury for
            issuance of an administrative wage garnishment order and provide
            debtors with the opportunity for review of the existence of the debt
            under subpart F within 60 days of the date of the demand letter.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon expiration of the 60-day period for review, or upon completion
            of a review under subpart F that upholds the agency&apos;s
            determination of the debt, USDA will transfer the debt for
            collection through administrative wage garnishment as well as other
            means through cross-servicing or centralized administrative offset.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If Treasury elects to pursue collection through administrative wage
            garnishment, Treasury, or its contractor, will notify the debtor of
            its intent to initiate garnishment proceedings and provide the
            debtor with the opportunity to inspect and copy agency records
            related to the debt, enter into a repayment agreement, or request a
            hearing as to the existence or amount of the debt or the terms of
            the proposed repayment schedule under the proposed garnishment
            order, in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              31 CFR 
              <subref title='31' part='285' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
                285.11
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the debtor requests a hearing at any time, Treasury will forward
            the request to the USDA creditor agency to 
            <PRTPAGE P='314' />
            which the debt is owed, and the creditor agency will contact the
            Office of the CFO (OCFO) for selection of a hearing official. The
            issuance of proposed garnishment orders by Treasury shall not be
            subject to appeal to NAD under 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='11' tq='N'>
                11
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . Hearings will be conducted in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              31 CFR 
              <subref title='31' part='285' sect='11' psec='#f' tq='N'>
                285.11(f)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             OCFO shall provide a copy of the hearing official&apos;s final
            decision to Treasury for implementation with respect to the subject
            garnishment order.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='380'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:F:3.60
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.60
      </num>
      <head>
        Applicability.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='60' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.60
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Applicability.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This section establishes consolidated administrative review
            procedures for debts subject to administrative offset,
            administrative wage garnishment, and disclosure to credit reporting
            agencies, under subparts D and E. A hearing or review under this
            section shall satisfy the required opportunity for administrative
            review by the agency of the determination of a debt for both
            administrative offset and administrative wage garnishment that is
            required before transfer to Treasury for collection or collection by
            the agency through non-centralized administrative offset.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For debt collection proceedings initiated by FSA, CCC, the Rural
            Housing Service, the Rural Business-Cooperative Service, the Risk
            Management Agency, the Federal Crop Insurance Corporation, the
            Natural Resources Conservation Service, Rural Development, and the
            Rural Utilities Service (but not for programs authorized by the
            Rural Electrification Act of 1936 or the Rural Telephone Bank Act, 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='901' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/901.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 901
              </subref>
            </aref>
            <E T='03'>
              et seq.
            </E>
            ), unless otherwise specified, any administrative review will be
            conducted by NAD in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='11' tq='N'>
                11
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and not the procedures of this subpart.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='381'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:F:3.61
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.61
      </num>
      <head>
        Presiding employee.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='61' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.61
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Presiding employee.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          An agency reviewing officer may be an agency employee, or the agency
          may provide for reviews to be done by another agency through an
          interagency agreement. No agency employee may act as a reviewing
          officer for the consideration of collection by administrative offset
          in a matter for which the employee was a contracting officer or a debt
          management officer.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='382'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:F:3.62
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.62
      </num>
      <head>
        Procedures.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='62' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.62
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Procedures.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A debtor who receives a Notice of Intent to Collect by
            Administrative Offset, Notice of Disclosure to Credit Reporting
            Agencies, or Notice of Intent to Collect by Administrative Wage
            Garnishment, or more than one of the above simultaneously, may
            request administrative review of the agency&apos;s determination
            that the debt exists and the amount of the debt. Any debtor who
            wishes to do this must submit a written explanation of why the
            debtor disagrees and seeks review. The request must be received by
            the creditor agency within 60 days of the date of the notice in the
            case of a Notice of Intent to Collect by Administrative Offset that
            includes referral to Treasury for offset against other Federal
            payments including tax refunds and 30 days in the case of all other
            notices.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In response, the creditor agency must notify the debtor in writing
            whether the review will be by documentary review or by hearing. An
            oral hearing is not necessary with respect to debt collection
            systems in which a determination of indebtedness rarely involves
            issues of credibility or veracity and the agency has determined that
            review of the written record is ordinarily an adequate means to
            correct prior mistakes. The agency shall provide the debtor with a
            reasonable opportunity for an oral hearing when the debtor requests
            reconsideration of the debt and the agency determines that the
            question of the indebtedness cannot be resolved by review of the
            documentary evidence, for example, when the validity of the debt
            turns on an issue of credibility or veracity. If the debtor requests
            a hearing, and the creditor agency decides to conduct a documentary
            review, the agency must notify the debtor of the reason why a 
            <PRTPAGE P='315' />
            hearing will not be granted. The agency must also advise the debtor
            of the procedures to be used in reviewing the documentary record, or
            of the date, location and procedures to be used if review is by a
            hearing.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An oral hearing may, at the debtor&apos;s option, be conducted
            either in-person or by telephone conference. All travel expenses
            incurred by the debtor in connection with an in-person hearing will
            be borne by the debtor. All telephonic charges incurred during the
            hearing will be the responsibility of the agency.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             After the debtor requests a hearing, the hearing official shall
            notify the debtor of:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The date and time of a telephonic hearing;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The date, time, and location of an in-person oral hearing; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The deadline for the submission of evidence for a documentary
            review.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Unless otherwise arranged by mutual agreement between the debtor
            and the agency, evidenced in writing, any documentary review or
            hearing will be conducted not less than 10 days and no more than 45
            days after receipt of the request for review.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Unless otherwise arranged by mutual agreement between the debtor
            and the agency, evidenced in writing, a documentary review or
            hearing will be based on agency records plus other relevant
            documentary evidence which may be submitted by the debtor within 10
            days after the request for review is received.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Hearings.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Hearings will be as informal as possible, and will be conducted by
            a reviewing officer in a fair and expeditious manner. The reviewing
            officer need not use the formal rules of evidence with regard to the
            admissibility of evidence or the use of evidence once admitted.
            However, clearly irrelevant material should not be admitted, whether
            or not any party objects. Any party to the hearing may offer
            exhibits, such as copies of financial records, telephone memoranda,
            or agreements, provided the opposing party is notified at least five
            days before the hearing.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Burden of proof.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The agency will have the burden of going forward to prove the
            existence or amount of the debt.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Thereafter, if the debtor disputes the existence or amount of the
            debt, the debtor must prove by a preponderance of the evidence that
            no debt exists or that the amount of the debt is incorrect. In
            addition, the debtor may present evidence that repayment would cause
            a financial hardship to the debtor or that collection of the debt
            may not be pursued due to operation of law
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Witnesses must testify under oath or affirmation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Debtors may represent themselves or may be represented at their own
            expense by an attorney or other person.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The substance of all significant matters discussed at the hearing
            must be recorded. No official record or transcript of the hearing
            need be created, but if a debtor requested that a transcript be
            made, it will be at the debtor&apos;s expense.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the absence of good cause shown, a debtor who fails to appear at
            a hearing scheduled pursuant to paragraph (f)(4) of this section
            will be deemed as not having timely filed a request for a hearing.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Within no more than 30 days after the hearing or receipt of
            documentation for the documentary review, the reviewing officer will
            issue a written decision to the debtor and the agency, including the
            supporting rationale for the decision. The deadline for issuance of
            the decision may be extended by the reviewing officer for good cause
            for no more than 30 days.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The written decision shall include:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A summary of the facts presented;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The hearing official&apos;s findings, analysis and conclusions; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Resolution of any significant procedural matter which was in
            dispute before or during the hearing or documentary review.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The reviewing officer&apos;s decision constitutes final agency
            action for purposes of judicial review under the Administrative
            Procedure Act (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='5' sect='701' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/5/701.html'>
                5 U.S.C. 701
              </subref>
            </aref>
            <E T='03'>
              et seq.
            </E>
            ) as to the following issues:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All issues of fact relating to the basis of the debt (including the
            existence of the debt and the propriety of administrative offset),
            in cases where the debtor previously had not been afforded due
            process; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='i_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The existence of the debt and the propriety of administrative
            offset, in 
            <PRTPAGE P='316' />
            cases where the debtor previously had been afforded due process as
            to issues of fact relating to the basis of the debt.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The reviewing officer will promptly distribute copies of the
            decision to the USDA CFO, the agency CFO (if any), the agency debt
            management officer, the debtor, and the debtor&apos;s
            representative, if any.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='383'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:G:3.70
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.70
      </num>
      <head>
        Scope.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='70' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.70
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Scope.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The provisions of this subpart set forth USDA procedures for the
            collection of a Federal employee&apos;s pay by salary offset to
            satisfy certain valid and past due debts owed the government.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             These regulations apply to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Current USDA employees and employees of other agencies who owe
            debts to USDA; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Current USDA employees who owe debts to other agencies.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             These regulations do not apply to debts owed by FSA county
            executive directors or county office employees. Salaries of those
            employees are subject to administrative offset as provided in 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='792' tq='N'>
                792
              </subref>
            </aref>
             or 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1403' tq='N'>
                1403
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             These regulations do not apply to debts or claims arising under the
            Internal Revenue Code of 1954 (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='26' sect='1' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/26/1.html'>
                26 U.S.C. 1
              </subref>
            </aref>
            <E T='03'>
              et seq.
            </E>
            ); the tariff laws of the United States; or to any case where
            collection of a debt by salary offset is explicitly provided for or
            prohibited by another statute (e.g. travel advances in 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='5' sect='5705' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/5/5705.html'>
                5 U.S.C. 5705
              </subref>
            </aref>
             or employee training expense in 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='5' sect='4108' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/5/4108.html'>
                5 U.S.C. 4108
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             These regulations identify the types of salary offset available to
            USDA, as well as certain rights provided to the employee, which
            include a written notice before deductions begin and the opportunity
            to petition for a hearing and to receive a written decision if a
            hearing is granted. The rights provided by this section do not
            extend to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any adjustment to pay arising out of an employee&apos;s election of
            coverage or a change in coverage under a Federal benefits program
            requiring periodic deductions from pay, if the amount to be
            recovered was accumulated over four pay periods or less;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A routine intra-agency adjustment of pay that is made to correct an
            overpayment of pay attributable to clerical or administrative errors
            or delays in processing pay documents, if the overpayment occurred
            within the four pay periods preceding the adjustment and, at the
            time of such adjustment, or as soon thereafter as practical, the
            individual is provided written notice of the nature and the amount
            of the adjustment and point of contact for contesting such
            adjustment; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any adjustment to collect a debt amounting to $50 or less, if, at
            the time of such adjustment, or as soon thereafter as practical, the
            individual is provided written notice of the nature and the amount
            of the adjustment and a point of contact for contesting such
            adjustment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             These regulations do not preclude an employee from:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Requesting waiver of an erroneous overpayment under 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='5' sect='5584' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/5/5584.html'>
                5 U.S.C. 5584
              </subref>
              , 
              <subref title='5' sect='10' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/5/10.html'>
                10
              </subref>
            </aref>
             U.S.C. 2774, or 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='32' sect='716' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/32/716.html'>
                32 U.S.C. 716
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Requesting waiver of any other type of debt, if waiver is available
            by statute; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Questioning the amount or validity of a debt, in the manner
            prescribed by this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Nothing in these regulations precludes the compromise, suspension
            or termination of collection actions where appropriate under USDA
            regulations contained elsewhere.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='384'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:G:3.71
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.71
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='71' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.71
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          As used in this subpart the following definitions shall apply:
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Agency
          </E>
           means an executive department or agency; a military department; the
          United States Postal Service; the Postal Rate Commission; the United
          States Senate; the United States House of Representatives; any court,
          court administrative office, or instrumentality in the judicial or
          legislative branches of the government; or a government corporation.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Debt
          </E>
           means:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An amount owed to the United States from sources which include, but
            
            <PRTPAGE P='317' />
            are not limited to, insured or guaranteed loans, fees, leases,
            rents, royalties, services, sales of real or personal property,
            overpayments, penalties, damages, interest, fines and forfeitures
            (except those arising under the Uniform Code of Military Justice).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An amount owed to the United States by an employee for pecuniary
            losses where the employee has been determined to be liable due to
            his or her negligent, willful, unauthorized or illegal acts,
            including but not limited to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Theft, misuse, or loss of government funds;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             False claims for services and travel;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Illegal, unauthorized obligations and expenditures of government
            appropriations;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Using or authorizing the use of government-owned or leased
            equipment, facilities, supplies, and services for other than
            official or approved purposes;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Lost, stolen, damaged, or destroyed government property;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Erroneous entries on accounting records or reports; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_vii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Deliberate failure to provide physical security and control
            procedures for accountable officers, if such failure is determined
            to be the proximate cause for a loss of government funds.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Disposable pay
          </E>
           means that part of current basic pay, special pay, incentive pay,
          retired pay, retainer pay, or in the case of an employee not entitled
          to basic pay, other authorized pay remaining after the deduction of
          any amount required by law to be withheld (other than deductions to
          execute garnishment orders in accordance with 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            5 CFR parts 
            <subref title='5' part='581' tq='N'>
              581
            </subref>
             and 
            <subref title='5' part='582' tq='N'>
              582
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ). Among the legally required deductions that must be applied first to
          determine disposable pay are levies pursuant to the Internal Revenue
          Code (title 26, United States Code) and deductions described in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            section 
            <subref title='7' part='581' sect='105' psec='#b' tq='N'>
              581.105(b)
            </subref>
          </aref>
           through (f) of 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='5' tq='N'>
              5 of this title
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Employee
          </E>
           means a current employee of an agency, including a current member of
          the Armed Forces or a Reserve of the Armed Forces, but does not
          include a FSA county executive director or county office employee.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Hearing official
          </E>
           means a USDA administrative law judge or some other individual not
          under the control of the Secretary.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Salary offset
          </E>
           means a reduction of a debt by offset(s) from the disposable pay of
          an employee without his or her consent.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Waiver
          </E>
           means the cancellation, remission, forgiveness, or non-recovery of a
          debt owed by an employee to an agency as permitted or required by 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='5' sect='5584' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/5/5584.html'>
              5 U.S.C. 5584
            </subref>
            , 
            <subref title='5' sect='10' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/5/10.html'>
              10
            </subref>
          </aref>
           U.S.C. 2774, or 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='32' sect='716' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/32/716.html'>
              32 U.S.C. 716
            </subref>
            , 
            <subref title='32' sect='5' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/32/5.html'>
              5
            </subref>
          </aref>
           U.S.C. 8346(b) or any other law.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='385'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:G:3.72
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.72
      </num>
      <head>
        Coordinating offset with another Federal agency.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='72' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.72
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Coordinating offset with another Federal agency.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              When USDA is owed the debt.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When USDA is owed a debt by an employee of another agency, the
            other agency shall not initiate the requested offset until USDA
            provides the agency with a written certification that the debtor
            owes USDA a debt (including the amount and basis of the debt and the
            due date of the payment) and that USDA has complied with these
            regulations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              When another agency is owed the debt.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             USDA may use salary offset against one of its employees who is
            indebted to another agency, if requested to do so by that agency.
            Such a request must be accompanied by a certification by the
            requesting agency that the person owes the debt (including the
            amount and basis of the debt and the due date of the payment) and
            that the agency has complied with its regulations required by 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='5' sect='5514' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/5/5514.html'>
                5 U.S.C. 5514
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              5 CFR part 
              <subref title='5' part='550' tq='N'>
                550
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , subpart K.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Mandatory centralized administrative offset.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Debts may be referred to Treasury under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='3' sect='44' psec='' tq='N'>
                3.44
              </subref>
            </aref>
             for collection through salary offset in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              31 CFR 
              <subref title='31' part='285' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
                285.7
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='386'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:G:3.73
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.73
      </num>
      <head>
        Determination of indebtedness.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='73' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.73
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Determination of indebtedness.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In determining that an employee is indebted to USDA and that 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              31 CFR parts 
              <subref title='31' part='900' tq='N'>
                900
              </subref>
            </aref>
             through 904 have been satisfied and that salary offset is
            appropriate, USDA will review the debt to make sure that it is valid
            and past due.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If USDA determines that any of the requirements of paragraph (a) of
            this section have not been met, no determination of indebtedness
            shall be made and salary offset will not proceed 
            <PRTPAGE P='318' />
            until USDA is assured that the requirements have been met.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='387'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:G:3.74
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.74
      </num>
      <head>
        Notice requirements before offset.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='74' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.74
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Notice requirements before offset.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Except as provided in paragraph (b) of this section, salary offset
          will not be made unless USDA first provides the employee with a
          minimum of 30 days written notice. This Notice of Intent to Offset
          Salary will state:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             That USDA has reviewed the records relating to the debt and has
            determined that a debt is owed, the amount of the debt, and the
            facts giving rise to the debt;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             USDA&apos;s intention to collect the debt by means of deduction
            from the employee&apos;s current disposable pay until the debt and
            all accumulated interest are paid in full;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The approximate beginning date, frequency, and amount of the
            intended deduction (stated as a fixed dollar amount or as a
            percentage of pay, not to exceed 15 percent of disposable pay) and;
            and the intention to continue the deductions until the debt is paid
            in full or otherwise resolved;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An explanation of USDA requirements concerning interest, penalties
            and administrative costs; unless such payments are waived in
            accordance with 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='31' sect='3717' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/31/3717.html'>
                31 U.S.C. 3717
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='3' sect='17' psec='' tq='N'>
                3.17
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The employee&apos;s right to inspect and copy USDA records relating
            to the debt;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The employee&apos;s right to enter into a written agreement with
            USDA for a repayment schedule differing from that proposed by USDA,
            so long as the terms of the repayment schedule proposed by the
            employee are agreeable to USDA;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The employee&apos;s right to a hearing conducted by a hearing
            official on USDA&apos;s determination of the debt, the amount of the
            debt, or percentage of disposable pay to be deducted each pay
            period, so long as a petition is filed by the employee as prescribed
            by USDA;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             That the timely filing of a petition for hearing will stay the
            collection proceedings;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             That a final decision on the hearing will be issued at the earliest
            practical date, but not later than 60 days after the filing of the
            petition requesting the hearing, unless the employee requests, and
            the hearing officer grants, a delay in the proceedings;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             That any knowingly false or frivolous statements, representations,
            or evidence may subject the employee to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Disciplinary procedures appropriate under 5 U.S.C. chapter 75, 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              5 CFR part 
              <subref title='5' part='752' tq='N'>
                752
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , or any other applicable statutes or regulations;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Penalties under the False Claims Act, 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='31' sect='3729-373' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/31/3729-373.html'>
                31 U.S.C. 3729-373
              </subref>
            </aref>
            1, or any other applicable statutory authority; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Criminal penalties under 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='18' sect='286' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/18/286.html'>
                18 U.S.C. 286
              </subref>
              , 
              <subref title='18' sect='287' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/18/287.html'>
                287
              </subref>
              , 
              <subref title='18' sect='1001' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/18/1001.html'>
                1001
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , and 1002 or any other applicable statutory authority;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any other rights and remedies available to the employee under
            statutes or regulations governing the program for which the
            collection is being made;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='l'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (l)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             That amounts paid on or deducted for the debt which are later
            waived or found not owed to the United States will be promptly
            refunded to the employee, unless there are applicable contractual or
            statutory provisions to the contrary;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='m'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (m)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The method and time period for requesting a hearing; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='n'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (n)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The name and address of an official of USDA to whom communications
            must be directed.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='388'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:G:3.75
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.75
      </num>
      <head>
        Request for a hearing.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='75' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.75
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Request for a hearing.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as provided in paragraph (c) of this section, an employee
            must file a petition for a hearing that is received by USDA not
            later than 30 days from the date of the USDA notice described in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='3' sect='74' psec='' tq='N'>
                3.74
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , if an employee wants a hearing concerning:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The existence or amount of the debt; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             USDA&apos;s proposed offset schedule (including percentage).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The petition must be signed by the employee and must identify and
            explain with reasonable specificity and brevity the facts, evidence
            and witnesses which the employee believes support his or her
            position. If the employee objects to the percentage of disposable
            pay to be deducted from each check, the petition must state the
            objection and the reasons for it.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the employee files a petition for a hearing later than the 30
            days as described in paragraph (a) of this section, 
            <PRTPAGE P='319' />
            the hearing officer may accept the request if the employee can show
            that the delay was because of circumstances beyond his or her
            control or because of failure to receive notice of the filing
            deadline (unless the employee has actual notice of the filing
            deadline).
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='389'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:G:3.76
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.76
      </num>
      <head>
        Result if employee fails to meet deadlines.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='76' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.76
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Result if employee fails to meet deadlines.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          An employee will not be granted a hearing and will have his or her
          disposable pay offset in accordance with USDA&apos;s offset schedule
          if the employee:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Fails to file a petition for a hearing as prescribed in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='3' sect='75' psec='' tq='N'>
                3.75
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is scheduled to appear and fails to appear at the hearing.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='390'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:G:3.77
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.77
      </num>
      <head>
        Hearing.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='77' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.77
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Hearing.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If an employee timely files a petition for a hearing under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 
              <subref title='7' part='3' sect='75' psec='' tq='N'>
                3.75
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , USDA shall select the time, date, and location for the hearing.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Hearings shall be conducted by the hearing official designated in
            accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              5 CFR 
              <subref title='5' part='550' sect='1107' psec='' tq='N'>
                550.1107
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Rules of evidence shall not be adhered to, but the hearing official
            shall consider all evidence that he or she determines to be relevant
            to the debt that is the subject of the hearing and weigh it
            accordingly, given all of the facts and circumstances surrounding
            the debt.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             USDA will have the burden of going forward to prove the existence
            of the debt.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The employee requesting the hearing shall bear the ultimate burden
            of proof.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The evidence presented by the employee must prove that no debt
            exists or cast sufficient doubt such that reasonable minds could
            differ as to the existence of the debt.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='391'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:G:3.78
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.78
      </num>
      <head>
        Written decision following a hearing.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='78' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.78
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Written decision following a hearing.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Written decisions provided after a hearing will include:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A statement of the facts presented at the hearing to support the
            nature and origin of the alleged debt and those presented to refute
            the debt;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The hearing officer&apos;s analysis, findings, and conclusions,
            considering all the evidence presented and the respective burdens of
            the parties, in light of the hearing;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The amount and validity of the alleged debt determined as a result
            of the hearing;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The payment schedule (including percentage of disposable pay), if
            applicable;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The determination that the amount of the debt at this hearing is
            the final agency action on this matter regarding the existence and
            amount of the debt for purposes of executing salary offset under 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='5' sect='5514' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/5/5514.html'>
                5 U.S.C. 5514
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . However, even if the hearing official determines that a debt may
            not be collected by salary offset, but the creditor agency finds
            that the debt is still valid, the creditor agency may still seek
            collection of the debt by other means authorized by this part; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notice that the final determination by the hearing official
            regarding the existence and amount of a debt is subject to referral
            to Treasury under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='3' sect='33' psec='' tq='N'>
                3.33
              </subref>
            </aref>
             in the same manner as any other delinquent debt.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='392'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:G:3.79
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.79
      </num>
      <head>
        Review of USDA records related to the debt.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='79' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.79
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Review of USDA records related to the debt.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Notification by employee.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An employee who intends to inspect or copy USDA records related to
            the debt must send a letter to USDA stating his or her intention.
            The letter must be received by USDA within 30 days of the date of
            the Notice of Intent to Offset Salary.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              USDA response.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In response to the timely notice submitted by the debtor as
            described in paragraph (a) of this section, USDA will notify the
            employee of the location and time when the employee may inspect and
            copy USDA records related to the debt.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='393'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:G:3.80
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.80
      </num>
      <head>
        Written agreement to repay debts as alternative to salary offset.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='80' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.80
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Written agreement to repay debts as alternative to salary offset.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Notification by employee.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The employee may propose, in response to a Notice of Intent to
            Offset Salary, a written agreement to repay the debt as an
            alternative to salary offset. Any employee who wishes to do this
            must submit a proposed written agreement to repay the debt that is
            received by USDA within 30 days of the date of the Notice of Intent
            to Offset Salary or 15 
            <PRTPAGE P='320' />
            days after the date of a hearing decision issued under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='3' sect='78' psec='' tq='N'>
                3.78
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              USDA response.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             USDA will notify the employee whether the employee&apos;s proposed
            written agreement for repayment is acceptable. USDA may accept a
            repayment agreement instead of proceeding by offset. In making this
            determination, USDA will balance the USDA interest in collecting the
            debt against hardship to the employee. If the debt is delinquent and
            the employee has not disputed its existence or amount, USDA will
            accept a repayment agreement, instead of offset, for good cause such
            as, if the employee is able to establish that offset would result in
            undue financial hardship or would be against equity and good
            conscience.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='394'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:G:3.81
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.81
      </num>
      <head>
        Procedures for salary offset: when deductions may begin.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='81' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.81
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Procedures for salary offset: when deductions may begin.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Deductions to liquidate an employee&apos;s debt will be by the
            method and in the amount stated in USDA&apos;s Notice of Intent to
            Offset Salary to collect from the employee&apos;s current pay.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the employee filed a petition for a hearing with USDA before the
            expiration of the period provided for in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='3' sect='75' psec='' tq='N'>
                3.75
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , then deductions will begin after the hearing officer has provided
            the employee with a hearing, and a final written decision has been
            rendered in favor of USDA.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If an employee retires or resigns before collection of the amount
            of the indebtedness is completed, the remaining indebtedness will be
            collected according to the procedures for administrative offset (see
            subpart D of this part).
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='395'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:G:3.82
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.82
      </num>
      <head>
        Procedures for salary offset: types of collection.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='82' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.82
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Procedures for salary offset: types of collection.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          A debt will be collected in a lump-sum or in installments. Collection
          will be by lump-sum collection unless the employee is financially
          unable to pay in one lump-sum, or if the amount of the debt exceeds 15
          percent of disposable pay for an ordinary pay period. In these cases,
          deduction will be by installments, as set forth in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='83' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.83
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='396'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:G:3.83
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.83
      </num>
      <head>
        Procedures for salary offset: methods of collection.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='83' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.83
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Procedures for salary offset: methods of collection.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A debt will be collected by deductions at officially-established
            pay intervals from an employee&apos;s current pay account, unless
            the employee and USDA agree to alternative arrangements for
            repayment under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='3' sect='80' psec='' tq='N'>
                3.80
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Installment deductions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Installment deductions will be made over a period not greater than
            the anticipated period of employment. The size and frequency of
            installment deductions will bear a reasonable relation to the size
            of the debt and the employee&apos;s ability to pay. However, the
            amount deducted for any period will not exceed 15 percent of the
            disposable pay from which the deduction is made, unless the employee
            has agreed in writing to the deduction of a greater amount. If
            possible, the installment payment will be sufficient in size and
            frequency to liquidate the debt in no more than three years.
            Installment payments of less than $25 per pay period or $50 a month
            will be accepted only in the most unusual circumstances.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Sources of deductions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             USDA will make deductions only from basic pay, special pay,
            incentive pay, retired pay, retainer pay, or in the case of an
            employee not entitled to basic pay, other authorized pay.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='397'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:G:3.84
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.84
      </num>
      <head>
        Procedures for salary offset: Imposition of interest, penalties, and
        administrative costs.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='84' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.84
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Procedures for salary offset: Imposition of interest, penalties, and
          administrative costs.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Interest, penalties and administrative costs will be charged in
          accordance with 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='17' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.17
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='398'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:G:3.85
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.85
      </num>
      <head>
        Non-waiver of rights.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='85' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.85
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Non-waiver of rights.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          So long as there are no statutory or contractual provisions to the
          contrary, no employee payment (or all or portion of a debt) collected
          under these regulations will be interpreted as a waiver of any rights
          that the employee may have under 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='5' sect='5514' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/5/5514.html'>
              5 U.S.C. 5514
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='399'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:G:3.86
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.86
      </num>
      <head>
        Refunds.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='86' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.86
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Refunds.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          USDA will refund promptly to the appropriate individual amounts offset
          under these regulations when:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A debt is waived or otherwise found not owed to the United States
            (unless expressly prohibited by statute or regulation); or
            <PRTPAGE P='321' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             USDA is directed by an administrative or judicial order to refund
            amounts deducted from the employee&apos;s current pay.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='400'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:G:3.87
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.87
      </num>
      <head>
        Agency regulations.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='87' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.87
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Agency regulations.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          USDA agencies may issue regulations or policies not inconsistent with
          OPM regulations (
          <aref type='CFR'>
            5 CFR part 
            <subref title='5' part='550' tq='N'>
              550
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , subpart K) and regulations in this subpart governing the collection
          of a debt by salary offset.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='401'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:H:3.90
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.90
      </num>
      <head>
        Reporting discharged debts to the Internal Revenue Service.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          73 FR 4
        </aref>
        , Jan. 2, 2008]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='90' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.90
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Reporting discharged debts to the Internal Revenue Service.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          When USDA discharges a debt, whether for the full value or less, it
          will report the discharge to the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) in
          accordance with current IRS instructions.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            73 FR 4
          </aref>
          , Jan. 2, 2008]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='402'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:A:-:-:3:I:3.91
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        3.91
      </num>
      <head>
        Adjusted civil monetary penalties.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          70 FR 29575
        </aref>
        , May 24, 2005. Redesignated at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          73 FR 4
        </aref>
        , Jan. 2, 2008, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          75 FR 17556
        </aref>
        , Apr. 7, 2010]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='91' psec='' tq='N'>
              3.91
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Adjusted civil monetary penalties.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              In general.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Secretary will adjust the civil monetary penalties, listed in
            paragraph (b) of this section, to take account of inflation at least
            once every 4 years as required by the Federal Civil Penalties
            Inflation Adjustment Act of 1990 (
            <aref target='_blank' title='Pub. L. 101-410' alt='Pub. L. 101-410' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d101:./list/bd/d101pl.lst:410%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Pub. L. 101-410
            </aref>
            ), as amended.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any increase in the dollar amount of a civil monetary penalty
            listed in paragraph (b) of this section shall apply only to
            violations occurring after May 7, 2010.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The descriptions of the civil monetary penalties listed in
            paragraph (b) of this section are for illustrative purposes only.
            This section does not amend, interpret, implement, or alter in any
            way the statutory provisions in which the civil monetary penalties
            listed in paragraph (b) are set. Moreover, the descriptions of the
            civil monetary penalties listed in paragraph (b) do not necessarily
            contain a complete description of the circumstances (
            <E T='03'>
              e.g.
            </E>
            , requirements regarding the “state of mind” of the violator(s),
            requirements regarding the type of law or issuance violated, etc.)
            under which the penalties are assessed. Persons should consult the
            statutory text in which the civil monetary penalties are set and any
            implementing regulations to make applicability determinations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             As used in this section, the following terms have the following
            meanings:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_4_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Secretary
            </E>
             means the Secretary of Agriculture; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_4_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <E T='03'>
              Department
            </E>
             means the United States Department of Agriculture.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Penalties.—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text />
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Agricultural Marketing Service—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for improper record keeping codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='136i-1' note='' psec='#d' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/136i-1.html#d'>
                7 U.S.C. 136i-1(d)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has: a maximum of $750 in the case of the first offense, and a
            minimum of $1,100 in the case of subsequent offenses, except that
            the penalty shall be less than $1,100 if the Secretary determines
            that the person made a good faith effort to comply.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for a violation of the unfair conduct rule under the
            Perishable Agricultural Commodities Act, in lieu of license
            revocation or suspension, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='499b' note='' psec='#5' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/499b.html#5'>
                7 U.S.C. 499b(5)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $2,200.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for violation of the licensing requirements under the
            Perishable Agricultural Commodities Act, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='499c' note='' psec='#a' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/499c.html#a'>
                7 U.S.C. 499c(a)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $1,200 for each such offense and not more than
            $350 for each day it continues, or a maximum of $350 for each
            offense if the Secretary determines the violation was not willful.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty in lieu of license suspension under the Perishable
            Agricultural Commodities Act, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='499h' note='' psec='#e' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/499h.html#e'>
                7 U.S.C. 499h(e)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum penalty of $2,000 for each violative transaction or
            each day the violation continues.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for a violation of the Export Apple Act, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='586' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/586.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 586
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a minimum of $110 and a maximum of $11,000.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for a violation of the Export Grape and Plum Act,
            codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='596' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/596.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 596
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a minimum of $110 and a maximum of $11,000.
            <PRTPAGE P='322' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_vii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for a violation of an order issued by the Secretary
            under the Agricultural Adjustment Act, reenacted with amendments by
            the Agricultural Marketing Agreement Act of 1937, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='608c' note='' psec='#14_B' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/608c.html#14_B'>
                7 U.S.C. 608c(14)(B)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $1,100.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_viii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (viii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for failure to file certain reports under the
            Agricultural Adjustment Act, reenacted by the Agricultural Marketing
            Agreement Act of 1937, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='610' note='' psec='#c' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/610.html#c'>
                7 U.S.C. 610(c)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $110.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_ix'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ix)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for a violation of a seed program under the Federal
            Seed Act, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='1596' note='' psec='#b' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1596.html#b'>
                7 U.S.C. 1596(b)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a minimum of $37.50 and a maximum of $750.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_x'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (x)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for failure to collect any assessment or fee for a
            violation of the Cotton Research and Promotion Act, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='2112' note='' psec='#b' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/2112.html#b'>
                7 U.S.C. 2112(b)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $1,100.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_xi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (xi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for failure to obey a cease and desist order, or for
            deceptive marketing, under the Plant Variety Protection Act,
            codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='2568' note='' psec='#b' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/2568.html#b'>
                7 U.S.C. 2568(b)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a minimum of $750 and a maximum of $11,000.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_xii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (xii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for failure to pay, collect, or remit any assessment
            or fee for a violation of a program under the Potato Research and
            Promotion Act, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='2621' note='' psec='#b_1' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/2621.html#b_1'>
                7 U.S.C. 2621(b)(1)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a minimum of $750 and a maximum of $7,500.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_xiii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (xiii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for failure to obey a cease and desist order under
            the Potato Research and Promotion Act, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='2621' note='' psec='#b_3' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/2621.html#b_3'>
                7 U.S.C. 2621(b)(3)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $750.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_xiv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (xiv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for failure to pay, collect, or remit any assessment
            or fee or for a violation of a program under the Egg Research and
            Consumer Information Act, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='2714' note='' psec='#b_1' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/2714.html#b_1'>
                7 U.S.C. 2714(b)(1)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a minimum of $750 and a maximum of $7,500.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_xv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (xv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for failure to obey a cease and desist order under
            the Egg Research and Consumer Information Act, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='2714' note='' psec='#b_3' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/2714.html#b_3'>
                7 U.S.C. 2714(b)(3)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $750.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_xvi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (xvi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for failure to remit any assessment or fee or for a
            violation of a program under the Beef Research and Information Act,
            codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='2908' note='' psec='#a_2' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/2908.html#a_2'>
                7 U.S.C. 2908(a)(2)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $7,500.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_xvii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (xvii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for failure to remit any assessment or for a
            violation of a program regarding wheat and wheat foods research,
            codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='3410' note='' psec='#b' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/3410.html#b'>
                7 U.S.C. 3410(b)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $1,100.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_xviii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (xviii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for failure to pay, collect, or remit any assessment
            or fee or for a violation of a program under the Floral Research and
            Consumer Information Act, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='4314' note='' psec='#b_1' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/4314.html#b_1'>
                7 U.S.C. 4314(b)(1)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a minimum of $750 and a maximum of $7,500.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_xix'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (xix)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for failure to obey a cease and desist order under
            the Floral Research and Consumer Information Act, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='4314' note='' psec='#b_3' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/4314.html#b_3'>
                7 U.S.C. 4314(b)(3)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $750.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_xx'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (xx)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for violation of an order under the Dairy Promotion
            Program, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='4510' note='' psec='#b' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/4510.html#b'>
                7 U.S.C. 4510(b)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $1,100.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_xxi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (xxi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for pay, collect, or remit any assessment or fee or
            for a violation of the Honey Research, Promotion, and Consumer
            Information Act, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='4610' note='' psec='#b_1' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/4610.html#b_1'>
                7 U.S.C. 4610(b)(1)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a minimum of $750 and a maximum of $7,500.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_xxii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (xxii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for failure to obey a cease and desist order under
            the Honey Research, Promotion, and Consumer Information Act,
            codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='4610' note='' psec='#b_3' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/4610.html#b_3'>
                7 U.S.C. 4610(b)(3)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $750.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_xxiii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (xxiii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for a violation of a program under the Pork
            Promotion, Research, and Consumer Information Act of 1985, codified
            at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='4815' note='' psec='#b_1_A_i' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/4815.html#b_1_A_i'>
                7 U.S.C. 4815(b)(1)(A)(i)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $1,100.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_xxiv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (xxiv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for failure to obey a cease and desist order under
            the Pork Promotion, Research, and Consumer Information Act of 1985,
            codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='4815' note='' psec='#b_3_A' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/4815.html#b_3_A'>
                7 U.S.C. 4815(b)(3)(A)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $750.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_xxv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (xxv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for failure to pay, collect, or remit any assessment
            or fee or for a violation of a program under the Watermelon Research
            and Promotion Act, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='4910' note='' psec='#b_1' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/4910.html#b_1'>
                7 U.S.C. 4910(b)(1)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a minimum of $750 and a maximum of $7,500.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_xxvi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (xxvi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for failure to obey a cease and desist order under
            the Watermelon Research and Promotion Act, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='4910' note='' psec='#b_3' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/4910.html#b_3'>
                7 U.S.C. 4910(b)(3)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $750.
            <PRTPAGE P='323' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_xxvii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (xxvii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for failure to pay, collect, or remit any assessment
            or fee or for a violation of a program under the Pecan Promotion and
            Research Act of 1990, codified a 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='6009' note='' psec='#c_1' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/6009.html#c_1'>
                7 U.S.C. 6009(c)(1)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a minimum of $1,100 and a maximum of $11,000.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_xxviii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (xxviii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for failure to obey a cease and desist order under
            the Pecan Promotion and Research Act of 1990, codified a 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='6009' note='' psec='#e' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/6009.html#e'>
                7 U.S.C. 6009(e)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $1,100.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_xxix'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (xxix)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for failure to pay, collect, or remit any assessment
            or fee or for a violation of a program under the Mushroom Promotion,
            Research, and Consumer Information Act of 1990, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='6107' note='' psec='#c_1' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/6107.html#c_1'>
                7 U.S.C. 6107(c)(1)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a minimum of $750 and a maximum of $7,500.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_xxx'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (xxx)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for failure to obey a cease and desist order under
            the Mushroom Promotion, Research, and Consumer Information Act of
            1990, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='6107' note='' psec='#e' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/6107.html#e'>
                7 U.S.C. 6107(e)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $750.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_xxxi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (xxxi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for failure to pay, collect, or remit any assessment
            or fee or for a violation of the Lime Research, Promotion, and
            Consumer Information Act of 1990, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='6207' note='' psec='#c_1' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/6207.html#c_1'>
                7 U.S.C. 6207(c)(1)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a minimum of $750 and a maximum of $7,500.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_xxxii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (xxxii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for failure to obey a cease and desist order under
            the Lime Research, Promotion, and Consumer Information Act of 1990,
            codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='6207' note='' psec='#e' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/6207.html#e'>
                7 U.S.C. 6207(e)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $750.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_xxxiii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (xxxiii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for failure to pay, collect, or remit any assessment
            or fee or for a violation of a program under the Soybean Promotion,
            Research, and Consumer Information Act, codified a 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='6307' note='' psec='#c_1_A' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/6307.html#c_1_A'>
                7 U.S.C. 6307(c)(1)(A)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $1,100.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_xxxiv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (xxxiv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for failure to obey a cease and desist order under
            the Soybean Promotion, Research, and Consumer Information Act,
            codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='6307' note='' psec='#e' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/6307.html#e'>
                7 U.S.C. 6307(e)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $7,500.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_xxxv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (xxxv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for failure to pay, collect, or remit any assessment
            or fee or for a violation of a program under the Fluid Milk
            Promotion Act of 1990, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='6411' note='' psec='#c_1_A' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/6411.html#c_1_A'>
                7 U.S.C. 6411(c)(1)(A)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a minimum of $750 and a maximum of $7,500, or in the case of a
            violation that is willful, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='6411' note='' psec='#c_1_B' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/6411.html#c_1_B'>
                7 U.S.C. 6411(c)(1)(B)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a minimum of $11,000 and a maximum of $140,000.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_xxxvi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (xxxvi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for failure to obey a cease and desist order under
            the Fluid Milk Promotion Act of 1990, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='6411' note='' psec='#e' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/6411.html#e'>
                7 U.S.C. 6411(e)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $7,500.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_xxxvii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (xxxvii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for knowingly labeling or selling a product as
            organic except in accordance with the Organic Foods Production Act
            of 1990, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='6519' note='' psec='#a' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/6519.html#a'>
                7 U.S.C. 6519(a)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $11,000.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_xxxviii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (xxxviii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for failure to pay, collect, or remit any assessment
            or fee or for a violation of a program under the Fresh Cut Flowers
            and Fresh Cut Greens Promotion and Information Act of 1993, codified
            at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='6808' note='' psec='#c_1_A_i' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/6808.html#c_1_A_i'>
                7 U.S.C. 6808(c)(1)(A)(i)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a minimum of $750 and a maximum of $7,500.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_xxxix'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (xxxix)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for failure to obey a cease and desist order under
            the Fresh Cut Flowers and Fresh Cut Greens Promotion and Information
            Act of 1993, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='6808' note='' psec='#e_1' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/6808.html#e_1'>
                7 U.S.C. 6808(e)(1)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $7,500.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_xl'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (xl)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for a violation of a program under the Sheep
            Promotion, Research, and Information Act of 1994, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='7107' note='' psec='#c_1_A' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/7107.html#c_1_A'>
                7 U.S.C. 7107(c)(1)(A)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $1,100.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_xli'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (xli)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for failure to obey a cease and desist order under
            the Sheep Promotion, Research, and Information Act of 1994, codified
            at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='7107' note='' psec='#e' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/7107.html#e'>
                7 U.S.C. 7107(e)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $750.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_xlii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (xlii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for a violation of an order or regulation issued
            under the Commodity Promotion, Research, and Information Act of
            1996, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='7419' note='' psec='#c_1' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/7419.html#c_1'>
                7 U.S.C. 7419(c)(1)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a minimum of $1,200 and a maximum of $12,000 for each
            violation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_xliii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (xliii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for failure to obey a cease and desist order under
            the Commodity Promotion, Research, and Information Act of 1996,
            codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='7419' note='' psec='#e' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/7419.html#e'>
                7 U.S.C. 7419(e)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a minimum of $1,200 and a maximum of $12,000 for each day the
            violation occurs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_xliv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (xliv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for a violation of an order or regulation issued
            under the Canola and Rapeseed Research, Promotion, and Consumer
            Information Act, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='7448' note='' psec='#c_1_A_i' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/7448.html#c_1_A_i'>
                7 U.S.C. 7448(c)(1)(A)(i)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $1,200 for each violation.
            <PRTPAGE P='324' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_xlv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (xlv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for failure to obey a cease and desist order under
            the Canola and Rapeseed Research, Promotion, and Consumer
            Information Act, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='7448' note='' psec='#e' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/7448.html#e'>
                7 U.S.C. 7448(e)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $7,000 for each day the violation occurs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_xlvi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (xlvi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for violation of an order or regulation issued under
            the National Kiwifruit Research, Promotion, and Consumer Information
            Act, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='7468' note='' psec='#c_1' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/7468.html#c_1'>
                7 U.S.C. 7468(c)(1)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a minimum of $700 and a maximum of $7,000 for each violation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_xlvii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (xlvii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for failure to obey a cease and desist order under
            the National Kiwifruit Research, Promotion, and Consumer Information
            Act, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='7468' note='' psec='#e' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/7468.html#e'>
                7 U.S.C. 7468(e)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $700 for each day the violation occurs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_xlviii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (xlviii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for a violation of an order or regulation under the
            Popcorn Promotion, Research, and Consumer Information Act, codified
            at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='7487' note='' psec='#a' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/7487.html#a'>
                7 U.S.C. 7487(a)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $1,200 for each violation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_xlix'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (xlix)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for certain violations under the Egg Products
            Inspection Act, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='21' sect='1041' note='' psec='#c_1_A' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/21/1041.html#c_1_A'>
                21 U.S.C. 1041(c)(1)(A)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $7,500 for each violation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='l'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (l)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for violation of an order or regulation issued under
            the Hass Avocado Promotion, Research, and Information Act of 2000,
            codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='7807' note='' psec='#c_1_A_i' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/7807.html#c_1_A_i'>
                7 U.S.C. 7807(c)(1)(A)(i)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a minimum of $1,100 and a maximum of $11,000 for each
            violation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='li'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (li)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for failure to obey a cease and desist order under
            the Hass Avocado Promotion, Research, and Information Act of 2000,
            codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='7807' note='' psec='#e_1' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/7807.html#e_1'>
                7 U.S.C. 7807(e)(1)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $11,000 for each offense.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='lii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (lii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for violation of certain provisions of the Livestock
            Mandatory Reporting Act of 1999, codified a 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='1636b' note='' psec='#a_1' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1636b.html#a_1'>
                7 U.S.C. 1636b(a)(1)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $11,000 for each violation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='liii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (liii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for failure to obey a cease and desist order under
            the Livestock Mandatory Reporting Act of 1999, codified a 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='1636b' note='' psec='#g_3' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1636b.html#g_3'>
                7 U.S.C. 1636b(g)(3)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $11,000 for each violation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='liv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (liv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for failure to obey an order of the Secretary issued
            pursuant to the Dairy Product Mandatory Reporting program, codified
            at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='1637b' note='' psec='#c_4_D_iii' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1637b.html#c_4_D_iii'>
                7 U.S.C. 1637b(c)(4)(D)(iii)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $11,000 for each offense.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='lv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (lv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for a willful violation of the Country of Origin
            Labeling program by a retailer or person engaged in the business of
            supplying a covered commodity to a retailer, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='1638b' note='' psec='#b_2' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1638b.html#b_2'>
                7 U.S.C. 1638b(b)(2)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $1,000 for each violation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='lvi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (lvi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for violations of the Dairy Research Program,
            codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='4535' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/4535.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 4535
              </subref>
            </aref>
             &amp; 4510(b), has a maximum of $1,100 for each violation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='lvi_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text />
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='lvi_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for a violation of the imported seed provisions of
            the Federal Seed Act, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='1596' note='' psec='#b' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1596.html#b'>
                7 U.S.C. 1596(b)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a minimum of $37.50 and a maximum of $750.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='lvi_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for a violation of the Animal Welfare Act, codified
            at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='2149' note='' psec='#b' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/2149.html#b'>
                7 U.S.C. 2149(b)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $10,000, and knowing failure to obey a cease and
            desist order has a civil penalty of $1,650.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='lvi_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for any person that causes harm to, or interferes
            with, an animal used for the purposes of official inspection by the
            Department, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='2279e' note='' psec='#a' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/2279e.html#a'>
                7 U.S.C. 2279e(a)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $11,000.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='lvi_2_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for a violation of the Swine Health Protection Act,
            codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='3805' note='' psec='#a' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/3805.html#a'>
                7 U.S.C. 3805(a)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $11,000.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='lvi_2_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for any person that violates the Plant Protection Act
            (PPA), or that forges, counterfeits, or, without authority from the
            Secretary, uses, alters, defaces, or destroys any certificate,
            permit, or other document provided for in the PPA, codified a 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='7734' note='' psec='#b_1' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/7734.html#b_1'>
                7 U.S.C. 7734(b)(1)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of the greater of: $60,000 in the case of any
            individual (except that the civil penalty may not exceed $1,100 in
            the case of an initial violation of the PPA by an individual moving
            regulated articles not for monetary gain), $300,000 in the case of
            any other person for each violation, $500,000 for all violations
            adjudicated in a single proceeding if the violations do not include
            a willful violation, and $1,000,000 for all violations adjudicated
            in a single proceeding if the violations include a willful
            violation; or twice the 
            <PRTPAGE P='325' />
            gross gain or gross loss for any violation, forgery, counterfeiting,
            unauthorized use, defacing, or destruction of a certificate, permit,
            or other document provided for in the PPA that results in the person
            deriving pecuniary gain or causing pecuniary loss to another.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='lvi_2_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for any person [except as provided in 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='8309' note='' psec='#d' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/8309.html#d'>
                7 U.S.C. 8309(d)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ] that violates the Animal Health Protection Act (AHPA), or that
            forges, counterfeits, or, without authority from the Secretary,
            uses, alters, defaces, or destroys any certificate, permit, or other
            document provided under the AHPA, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='8313' note='' psec='#b_1' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/8313.html#b_1'>
                7 U.S.C. 8313(b)(1)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of the greater of: $60,000 in the case of any
            individual, except that the civil penalty may not exceed $1,100 in
            the case of an initial violation of the AHPA by an individual moving
            regulated articles not for monetary gain, $300,000 in the case of
            any other person for each violation, $500,000 for all violations
            adjudicated in a single proceeding if the violations do not include
            a willful violation, and $1,000,000 for all violations adjudicated
            in a single proceeding if the violations include a willful
            violation; or twice the gross gain or gross loss for any violation,
            forgery, counterfeiting, unauthorized use, defacing, or destruction
            of a certificate, permit, or other document provided under the AHPA
            that results in the person&apos;s deriving pecuniary gain or causing
            pecuniary loss to another person.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='lvi_2_vii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for any person that violates certain regulations
            under the Agricultural Bioterrorism Protection Act of 2002 regarding
            transfers of listed agents and toxins or possession and use of
            listed agents and toxins, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='8401' note='' psec='#i_1' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/8401.html#i_1'>
                7 U.S.C. 8401(i)(1)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $300,000 in the case of an individual and
            $600,000 in the case of any other person.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='lvi_2_viii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (viii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for violation of the Horse Protection Act, codified
            at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='15' sect='1825' note='' psec='#b_1' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/15/1825.html#b_1'>
                15 U.S.C. 1825(b)(1)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $2,200.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='lvi_2_ix'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ix)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for failure to obey Horse Protection Act
            disqualification, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='15' sect='1825' note='' psec='#c' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/15/1825.html#c'>
                15 U.S.C. 1825(c)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $4,300.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='lvi_2_x'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (x)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for knowingly violating, or, if in the business as an
            importer or exporter, violating, with respect to terrestrial plants,
            any provision of the Endangered Species Act of 1973, any permit or
            certificate issued thereunder, or any regulation issued pursuant to 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              section 9(a)(1)(A)
            </aref>
             through (F), (a)(2)(A) through (D), (c), (d) (other than
            regulations relating to recordkeeping or filing reports), (f), or
            (g) of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='16' sect='1538' note='' psec='#a_1_A' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/1538.html#a_1_A'>
                16 U.S.C. 1538(a)(1)(A)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             through (F), (a)(2)(A) through (D), (c), (d), (f), and (g)), as set
            forth at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='16' sect='1540' note='' psec='#a' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/1540.html#a'>
                16 U.S.C. 1540(a)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $37,500.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='lvi_2_xi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (xi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for knowingly violating, or, if in the business as an
            importer or exporter, violating, with respect to terrestrial plants,
            any other regulation under the Endangered Species Act of 1973, as
            set forth at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='16' sect='1540' note='' psec='#a' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/1540.html#a'>
                16 U.S.C. 1540(a)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $18,200.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='lvi_2_xii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (xii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for violation, with respect to terrestrial plants, of
            the Endangered Species Act of 1973, or any regulation, permit, or
            certificate issued thereunder, as set forth at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='16' sect='1540' note='' psec='#a' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/1540.html#a'>
                16 U.S.C. 1540(a)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $750.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='lvi_2_xiii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (xiii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for knowingly and willfully violating 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='49' sect='80502' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/49/80502.html'>
                49 U.S.C. 80502
              </subref>
            </aref>
             with respect to the transportation of animals by any rail carrier,
            express carrier, or common carrier (except by air or water), a
            receiver, trustee, or lessee of one of those carriers, or an owner
            or master of a vessel, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='49' sect='80502' note='' psec='#d' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/49/80502.html#d'>
                49 U.S.C. 80502(d)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a minimum of $110 and a maximum of $650.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='lvi_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Food and Nutrition Service—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text />
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='lvi_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for violating a provision of the Food and Nutrition
            Act of 2008 (Act), or a regulation under the Act, by a retail food
            store or wholesale food concern, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='2021' note='' psec='#a' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/2021.html#a'>
                7 U.S.C. 2021(a)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and (c), has a maximum of $100,000 for each violation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='lvi_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for trafficking in food coupons, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='2021' note='' psec='#b_3_B' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/2021.html#b_3_B'>
                7 U.S.C. 2021(b)(3)(B)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $32,000 for each violation, except that the
            maximum penalty for violations occurring during a single
            investigation is $59,000.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='lvi_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for the sale of firearms, ammunitions, explosives, or
            controlled substances for coupons, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='2021' note='' psec='#b_3_C' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/2021.html#b_3_C'>
                7 U.S.C. 2021(b)(3)(C)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $32,000 for each violation, except that the
            maximum penalty for violations occurring during a single
            investigation is $59,000.
            <PRTPAGE P='326' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='lvi_3_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for any entity that submits a bid to supply infant
            formula to carry out the Special Supplemental Nutrition Program for
            Women, Infants and Children and discloses the amount of the bid,
            rebate or discount practices in advance of the bid opening or for
            any entity that makes a statement prior to the opening of bids for
            the purpose of influencing a bid, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='42' sect='1786' note='' psec='#h_8_H_i' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/42/1786.html#h_8_H_i'>
                42 U.S.C. 1786(h)(8)(H)(i)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $145,200,000.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='lvi_3_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for a vendor convicted of trafficking in food
            instruments, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='42' sect='1786' note='' psec='#o_1_A' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/42/1786.html#o_1_A'>
                42 U.S.C. 1786(o)(1)(A)
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='42' sect='42' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/42/42.html'>
                42
              </subref>
            </aref>
             U.S.C. 1786(o)(4)(B), has a maximum of $11,000 for each violation,
            except that the maximum penalty for violations occurring during a
            single investigation is $49,000.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='lvi_3_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for a vendor convicted of selling firearms,
            ammunition, explosives, or controlled substances in exchange for
            food instruments, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='42' sect='1786' note='' psec='#o_1_B' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/42/1786.html#o_1_B'>
                42 U.S.C. 1786(o)(1)(B)
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='42' sect='42' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/42/42.html'>
                42
              </subref>
            </aref>
             U.S.C. 1786(o)(4)(B), has a maximum of $11,000 for each violation,
            except that the maximum penalty for violations occurring during a
            single investigation is $49,000.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='lvi_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Food Safety and Inspection Service—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='lvi_4_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for certain violations under the Egg Products
            Inspection Act, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='21' sect='1041' note='' psec='#c_1_A' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/21/1041.html#c_1_A'>
                21 U.S.C. 1041(c)(1)(A)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $7,500 for each violation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='lvi_4_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for failure to timely file certain reports, codified
            at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='21' sect='467d' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/21/467d.html'>
                21 U.S.C. 467d
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $110 per day for each day the report is not
            filed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='lvi_4_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for failure to timely file certain reports, codified
            at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='21' sect='677' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/21/677.html'>
                21 U.S.C. 677
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $110 per day for each day the report is not
            filed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='lvi_4_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for failure to timely file certain reports, codified
            at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='21' sect='1051' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/21/1051.html'>
                21 U.S.C. 1051
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $110 per day for each day the report is not
            filed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='lvi_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Forest Service—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text />
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='lvi_5_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for willful disregard of the prohibition against the
            export of unprocessed timber originating from Federal lands,
            codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='16' sect='620d' note='' psec='#c_1_A' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/620d.html#c_1_A'>
                16 U.S.C. 620d(c)(1)(A)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $750,000 per violation or three times the gross
            value of the unprocessed timber, whichever is greater.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='lvi_5_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for a violation in disregard of the Forest Resources
            Conservation and Shortage Relief Act or the regulations that
            implement such Act regardless of whether such violation caused the
            export of unprocessed timber originating from Federal lands,
            codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='16' sect='620d' note='' psec='#c_2_A_i' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/620d.html#c_2_A_i'>
                16 U.S.C. 620d(c)(2)(A)(i)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $107,500 per violation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='lvi_5_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for a person that should have known that an action
            was a violation of the Forest Resources Conservation and Shortage
            Relief Act or the regulations that implement such Act regardless of
            whether such violation caused the export of unprocessed timber
            originating from Federal lands, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='16' sect='620d' note='' psec='#c_2_A_ii' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/620d.html#c_2_A_ii'>
                16 U.S.C. 620d(c)(2)(A)(ii)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $70,000 per violation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='lvi_5_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for a willful violation of the Forest Resources
            Conservation and Shortage Relief Act or the regulations that
            implement such Act regardless of whether such violation caused the
            export of unprocessed timber originating from Federal lands,
            codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='16' sect='620d' note='' psec='#c_2_A_iii' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/620d.html#c_2_A_iii'>
                16 U.S.C. 620d(c)(2)(A)(iii)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $725,000.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='lvi_5_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for a violation involving protections of caves,
            codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='16' sect='4307' note='' psec='#a_2' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/4307.html#a_2'>
                16 U.S.C. 4307(a)(2)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $11,000.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='lvi_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Grain Inspection, Packers and Stockyards Administration—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text />
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='lvi_6_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for a packer or swine contractor violation, codified
            at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='193' note='' psec='#b' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/193.html#b'>
                7 U.S.C. 193(b)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $11,000.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='lvi_6_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for a livestock market agency or dealer failure to
            register, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='203' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/203.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 203
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $750 and not more than $37.50 for each day the
            violation continues.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='lvi_6_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for operating without filing, or in violation of, a
            stockyard rate schedule, or of a regulation or order of the
            Secretary made thereunder, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='207' note='' psec='#g' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/207.html#g'>
                7 U.S.C. 207(g)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $750 and not more than $37.50 for each day the
            violation continues.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='lvi_6_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for a stockyard owner, livestock market agency and
            dealer violation, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='213' note='' psec='#b' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/213.html#b'>
                7 U.S.C. 213(b)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $11,000.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='lvi_6_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for a stockyard owner, livestock market agency and
            dealer compliance order, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='215' note='' psec='#a' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/215.html#a'>
                7 U.S.C. 215(a)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $750.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='lvi_6_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for failure to file required reports, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='15' sect='50' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/15/50.html'>
                15 U.S.C. 50
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $110.
            <PRTPAGE P='327' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='lvi_6_vii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for live poultry dealer violations, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='228b-2' note='' psec='#b' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/228b-2.html#b'>
                7 U.S.C. 228b-2(b)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $32,000.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='lvi_6_viii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (viii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for a violation, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='86' note='' psec='#c' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/86.html#c'>
                7 U.S.C. 86(c)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $107,500.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='lvi_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Federal Crop Insurance Corporation—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='lvi_7_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for any person who willfully and intentionally
            provides any false or inaccurate information to the Federal Crop
            Insurance Corporation or to an approved insurance provider with
            respect to any insurance plan or policy that is offered under the
            authority of the Federal Crop Insurance Act, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='1506' note='' psec='#n_1_A' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1506.html#n_1_A'>
                7 U.S.C. 1506(n)(1)(A)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $11,000.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='lvi_7_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for any person who willfully and intentionally
            provides any false or inaccurate information to the Federal Crop
            Insurance Corporation or to an approved insurance provider with
            respect to any insurance plan or policy that is offered under the
            authority of the Federal Crop Insurance Act, or who fails to comply
            with a requirement of the Federal Crop Insurance Corporation,
            codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='1515' note='' psec='#h_3_A' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1515.html#h_3_A'>
                7 U.S.C. 1515(h)(3)(A)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of the greater of: the amount of the pecuniary gain
            obtained as a result of the false or inaccurate information or the
            noncompliance; or $11,000.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='lvi_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Rural Housing Service—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='lvi_8_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for a violation of 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 536 of
            </aref>
             Title V of the Housing Act of 1949, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='42' sect='1490p' note='' psec='#e_2' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/42/1490p.html#e_2'>
                42 U.S.C. 1490p(e)(2)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $120,000 in the case of an individual, and a
            maximum of $1,200,000 in the case of an applicant other than an
            individual.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='lvi_8_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for equity skimming under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 543(a) of
            </aref>
             the Housing Act of 1949, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='42' sect='1490s' note='' psec='#a_2' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/42/1490s.html#a_2'>
                42 U.S.C. 1490s(a)(2)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $32,500.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='lvi_8_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 543b of
            </aref>
             the Housing Act of 1949 for a violation of regulations or
            agreements made in accordance with Title V of the Housing Act of
            1949, by submitting false information, submitting false
            certifications, failing to timely submit information, failing to
            maintain real property in good repair and condition, failing to
            provide acceptable management for a project, or failing to comply
            with applicable civil rights statutes and regulations, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='42' sect='1490s' note='' psec='#b_3_A' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/42/1490s.html#b_3_A'>
                42 U.S.C. 1490s(b)(3)(A)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of the greater of: twice the damages the Department,
            guaranteed lender, or project that is secured for a loan under Title
            V, suffered or would have suffered as a result of the violation; or
            $60,000 per violation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='lvi_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Farm Service Agency—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for failure to comply with certain provisions of the
            U.S. Warehouse Act, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='254' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/254.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 254
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $27,500 per violation if an agricultural product
            is not involved in the violation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Commodity Credit Corporation—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text />
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for willful failure or refusal to furnish
            information, or willful furnishing of false information under of 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 156 of
            </aref>
             the Federal Agricultural Improvement and Reform Act of 1996,
            codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='7272' note='' psec='#g_5' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/7272.html#g_5'>
                7 U.S.C. 7272(g)(5)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $10,000 for each violation.(ii) Civil penalty for
            willful failure or refusal to furnish information or willful
            furnishing of false data by a processor, refiner, or importer of
            sugar, syrup and molasses under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 156 of
            </aref>
             the Federal Agriculture Improvement and Reform Act of 1996,
            codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='7272' note='' psec='#g_5' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/7272.html#g_5'>
                7 U.S.C. 7272(g)(5)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $10,000 for each violation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for filing a false acreage report that exceeds
            tolerance under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 156 of
            </aref>
             the Federal Agriculture Improvement and Reform Act of 1996,
            codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='7272' note='' psec='#g_5' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/7272.html#g_5'>
                7 U.S.C. 7272(g)(5)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $10,000 for each violation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for knowingly violating any regulation of the
            Secretary of the Commodity Credit Corporation pertaining to flexible
            marketing allotments for sugar under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 359h(b) of
            </aref>
             the Agricultural Adjustment Act of 1938, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='1359hh' note='' psec='#b' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1359hh.html#b'>
                7 U.S.C. 1359hh(b)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $5,500 for each violation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for knowing violation of regulations promulgated by
            the Secretary pertaining to cotton insect eradication under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 104(d) of
            </aref>
             the Agricultural Act of 1949, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='1444a' note='' psec='#d' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1444a.html#d'>
                7 U.S.C. 1444a(d)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $5,500 for each offense.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='v_11'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (11)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Office of the Secretary—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='v_11_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for making, presenting, submitting or causing to be
            made, presented or submitted, a false, fictitious, or fraudulent
            claim as defined under the Program Fraud Civil Remedies Act 
            <PRTPAGE P='328' />
            of 1986, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='31' sect='3802' note='' psec='#a_1' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/31/3802.html#a_1'>
                31 U.S.C. 3802(a)(1)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $5,500.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='v_11_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Civil penalty for making, presenting, submitting or causing to be
            made, presented or submitted, a false, fictitious, or fraudulent
            written statement as defined under the Program Fraud Civil Remedies
            Act of 1986, codified at 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='31' sect='3802' note='' psec='#a_2' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/31/3802.html#a_2'>
                31 U.S.C. 3802(a)(2)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , has a maximum of $5,500.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            70 FR 29575
          </aref>
          , May 24, 2005. Redesignated at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            73 FR 4
          </aref>
          , Jan. 2, 2008, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 17556
          </aref>
          , Apr. 7, 2010]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>