<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol6'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:B:612
    </extid>
    <num>
      612
    </num>
    <head>
      SNOW SURVEYS AND WATER SUPPLY FORECASTS
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref target='_blank' href='http://frwebgate.access.gpo.gov/cgi-bin/getpage.cgi?dbname=62_statutes2_at_large&amp;position=all&amp;page=653'>
            26 Stat. 653
          </aref>
          ; 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            Sec. 8
          </aref>
          , Reorg. Plan No. IV of 1940, 
          <aref target='_blank' href='http://frwebgate.access.gpo.gov/cgi-bin/getpage.cgi?dbname=76_statutes2_at_large&amp;position=all&amp;page=1234'>
            54 Stat. 1234
          </aref>
           (5 U.S.C. App. II); 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            5 FR 2421
          </aref>
          , 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            3 CFR 1938-1943
          </aref>
           Comp. P. 1288.
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            40 FR 12067
          </aref>
          , Mar. 17, 1975, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='6157'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:B:612:-:612.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        612.1
      </num>
      <head>
        Purpose and scope.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='457' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='612' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              612.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Purpose and scope.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          This part sets forth Natural Resources Conservation Service (NRCS)
          policy and procedure for the administration of a cooperative snow
          survey and water supply forecast program. The program provides
          agricultural water users and other water management groups in the
          western states area with water supply forecasts to enable them to plan
          for efficient water management. The program also provides the public
          and the scientific community with a data base that can be used to
          accurately determine the extent of the now resource. The western
          states area comprises Alaska, Arizona, California (east side of the
          Sierra Nevada mountain range only), Colorado, Idaho, Montana, Nevada,
          New Mexico, Oregon, Utah, Washington, and Wyoming.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6158'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:B:612:-:612.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        612.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Snow survey and water supply forecast activities.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='612' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              612.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Snow survey and water supply forecast activities.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          To carry out the cooperative snow survey and water supply forecast
          program, NRCS:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Establishes, maintains, and operates manual and automated snow
            course and related hydro meteorological networks. Planning for such
            networks is carried out in accordance with OMB Circular A-62.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Determines and provides information on the expected water supply,
            including seasonal streamflow data. If pertinent and appropriate to
            the needs of cooperators and not otherwise available to them, may
            provide necessary interpretative analyses and forecasts required for
            operation of water-control structures and/or agricultural
            operations.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             On request and to the extent NRCS resources and any required
            cooperator contributions are available, establishes
            hydrometeorological stations to cllect and provide data and
            necessary interpretive analyses to the requesting party. By written
            agreement NRCS may accept cooperators&apos; funds, materials,
            equipment, and services for this purpose.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Develops and encourages use of new techniques and improving data
            collection and processing.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Cooperates with other federal, state, and local agencies,
            organizations, and Canadian provinces and agencies.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6159'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:B:612:-:612.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        612.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Data collected and forecasts.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='612' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              612.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Data collected and forecasts.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Basic data are currently collected at numerous sites in the western
            states area. Data sites generally include a snow course where both
            snow depth and water equivalent of snow are measured. However,
            special sites may measure only snow depth or water equivalent. Many
            of these sites also provide related drometeorological data, such as
            precipitation, temperature, humidity, solar tradiation, and wind.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Water supply forecasts in the western states area are generally
            made monthly from January through June. Forecasts may be made more
            frequently for an established need when data are available to NRCS.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6160'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:B:612:-:612.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        612.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Eligible individuals or groups.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='612' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              612.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Eligible individuals or groups.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any individual or group who is a significant water user and who
            would benefit from a water supply forecast may obtain forecasts from
            NRCS on a regular basis provided data are available to NRCS to
            develop a forecast at the desired location.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The program collects and interprets data as a service and an aid to
            agricultural interests, particularly those served by or affiliated
            with soil, water, and other conservation districts. Information
            collected by NRCS for these agricutural users is also made available
            to other Federal, State, and private agencies and to the general
            public without charge. Cooperator financial contribution is usually
            required for special measurements or interpretations beyond the
            scope of the regular program.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6161'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:B:612:-:612.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        612.5
      </num>
      <head>
        Dissemination of water supply forecasts and basic data.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='612' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              612.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Dissemination of water supply forecasts and basic data.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Water supply outlook reports prepared by NRCS and its cooperators
          containing water supply forecasts and basic data are usually issued
          monthly by each NRCS state office in the western states area for the
          months of January through June. Other reports jointly issued by NRCS
          and its cooperators include a fall water supply summary, annual and
          accumulative summaries of data, and a western states area report
          covering water supply outlook.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6162'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:B:612:-:612.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        612.6
      </num>
      <head>
        Application for water supply forecast service.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='458' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='612' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              612.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Application for water supply forecast service.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Requests for obtaining water supply forecasts or related assistance
          may be directed to any NRCS office in the western states areas. NRCS
          offices are described in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='600' tq='N'>
              600 of this chapter
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6163'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:B:612:-:612.7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        612.7
      </num>
      <head>
        Forecast user responsibility.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='612' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              612.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Forecast user responsibility.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The forecast user&apos;s obligation to the federal government is to
          give appropriate credit and recognition to NRCS for information
          furnished. The Federal Government does not assume any responsibility
          for management decisions the user makes which may be based in whole or
          part on information provided by NRCS.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>