<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol3'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:110
    </extid>
    <num>
      110
    </num>
    <head>
      RECORDKEEPING ON RESTRICTED USE PESTICIDES BY CERTIFIED APPLICATORS;
      SURVEYS AND REPORTS
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='136a' note='' psec='#d_1_c' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/136a.html#d_1_c'>
              7 U.S.C. 136a(d)(1)(c)
            </subref>
            , 
            <subref title='7' sect='136i-1' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/136i-1.html'>
              136i-1
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , and 450; 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR 
            <subref title='7' part='2' sect='17' psec='' tq='N'>
              2.17
            </subref>
            , 
            <subref title='7' part='2' sect='50' psec='' tq='N'>
              2.50
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 19022
          </aref>
          , Apr. 9, 1993, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='4159'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:110:-:110.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        110.1
      </num>
      <head>
        Scope.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='110' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              110.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Scope.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          This part sets forth the requirements for recordkeeping on restricted
          use pesticides by all certified applicators, both private applicators
          and commercial applicators.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4160'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:110:-:110.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        110.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 19022
        </aref>
        , Apr. 9, 1993, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          60 FR 8123
        </aref>
        , Feb. 10, 1995]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='110' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              110.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          As used in this part, the following terms shall be construed,
          respectively, to mean:
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Administrator.
          </E>
           The Administrator of the Agricultural Marketing Service, United
          States Department of Agriculture, or any individual to whom the
          Administrator delegates authority to act in his or her behalf.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Authorized representative.
          </E>
           Any person who is authorized to act on behalf of the Secretary or a
          State lead agency for the purpose of surveying records required to be
          kept under this part and enforcing this part.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Certification number.
          </E>
           A number issued by EPA or a State to an individual who is authorized
          by EPA or the State to use or supervise the use of any restricted use
          pesticide.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Certified applicator.
          </E>
           Any individual who is certified by EPA or the State to use or
          supervise the use of any restricted use pesticide covered by that
          individual&apos;s certification.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Commercial applicator.
          </E>
           A certified applicator, whether or not the individual is a private
          applicator with respect to some uses, who uses or supervises the use
          of any restricted use pesticide for any purpose on any property other
          than as provided by the definition of private applicator.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Comparable.
          </E>
           With respect to the records required to be kept under this part,
          similar to those required under EPA-approved State certification
          programs.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Complainant.
          </E>
           The Administrator or an official of a cooperating State that deals
          with pesticide use or health or environmental issues related to the
          pesticide use, who institutes a proceeding pursuant to 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='110' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              110.8
            </subref>
             of this part
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            EPA.
          </E>
           The United States Environmental Protection Agency.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            EPA registration number.
          </E>
           The number assigned to a product registered with 
          <PRTPAGE P='282' />
          EPA in accordance with 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            sections 3 or 24c of
          </aref>
           the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act and
          implementing regulations, and borne on the label of the product.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Indian governing body.
          </E>
           The governing body of any tribe, band, or group of Indians subject to
          the jurisdiction of the United States and recognized by the United
          States as possessing power of self-government.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Licensed health care professional.
          </E>
           A physician, nurse, emergency medical technician, or other qualified
          individual, licensed or certified by a State to provide medical
          treatment.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Medical emergency.
          </E>
           A situation that requires immediate medical treatment or first aid to
          treat possible symptoms of pesticide poisoning or exposure.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Parties.
          </E>
           Includes the Administrator or cooperating State agencies who
          institute proceedings against whom such proceedings are instituted,
          under 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='110' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              110.8
            </subref>
             of this part
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Person.
          </E>
           Any individual, corporation, company, association, firm, partnership,
          society, or other legal entity.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Presiding officer.
          </E>
           Any individual designated in writing by the Administrator to preside
          at a proceeding conducted pursuant to 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='110' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              110.8
            </subref>
             of this part
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Private applicator.
          </E>
           A certified applicator who uses or supervises the use of any
          restricted use pesticide for purposes of producing any agricultural
          commodity:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             On property owned or rented by the applicator or the employer of
            the applicator; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If applied without compensation, other than trading of personal
            services between producers of agricultural commodities, on the
            property of another person.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Record.
          </E>
           The legible recording of all required elements under 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            section 
            <subref title='7' part='110' sect='3' psec='#a' tq='N'>
              110.3(a) (1)
            </subref>
          </aref>
           through (6) for the application of a federally restricted use
          pesticide. 
          <SU>
            1
          </SU>
          <FTREF />
        </P>
        <FTNT>
          <P>
            <SU>
              1
            </SU>
             Records can be handwritten on individual notes or forms, consist of
            invoices, be computerized, and or be maintained in recordkeeping
            books.
          </P>
        </FTNT>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Recordkeeping.
          </E>
           The recording by the certified applicator, or the agent of the
          certified applicator, of the information required by 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='110' sect='3' psec='#a' tq='N'>
              110.3(a) and (b)
            </subref>
          </aref>
           concerning each restricted use pesticide application, either
          electronically or manually in writing, and the maintenance of such
          records in a manner accessible to authorized representatives.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Respondent.
          </E>
           The party proceeded against pursuant to 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='110' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              110.8
            </subref>
             of this part
          </aref>
          , restricted use pesticide. A pesticide that is federally classified
          for restricted use under 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 3(d)(1)(c) of
          </aref>
           the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Secretary.
          </E>
           The Secretary of Agriculture, United States Department of
          Agriculture, or any individual to whom the Secretary delegates
          authority to act in his or her behalf.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State.
          </E>
           A State of the United States, the District of Columbia, the
          Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa,
          the Northern Mariana Islands, and any other territory or possession of
          the United States, or an Indian governing body.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State lead agency.
          </E>
           The agency designated by a State to have access to the records
          required to be maintained under this part.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Supervise.
          </E>
           To provide instruction and guidance in the application of restricted
          use pesticides and exercise control over an applicator of restricted
          use pesticides in accordance with standards prescribed by the EPA in 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            40 CFR part 
            <subref title='40' part='171' tq='N'>
              171
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 19022
          </aref>
          , Apr. 9, 1993, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            60 FR 8123
          </aref>
          , Feb. 10, 1995]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4161'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:110:-:110.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        110.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Records, retention, and access to records.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 19022
        </aref>
        , Apr. 9, 1993, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          60 FR 8123
        </aref>
        , Feb. 10, 1995]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='110' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              110.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Records, retention, and access to records.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Certified applicators of restricted use pesticides shall maintain
            records of the application of restricted use pesticides. Except as
            provided in paragraph (b) of this section, these records shall
            include the following information for each application:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The brand or product name, and the EPA registration number of the
            restricted use pesticide that was applied;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The total amount of the restricted use pesticide applied;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The location of the application, the size of area treated, and the
            crop, commodity, stored product, or site to which a restricted use
            pesticide was applied. The location of the application may be
            recorded using any of the following designations:
            <PRTPAGE P='283' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             County, range, township, and section;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An identification system utilizing maps and/or written descriptions
            which accurately identify location;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An identification system established by a United States Department
            of Agriculture agency which utilizes maps and numbering system to
            identify field locations; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The legal property description.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The month, day, and year on which the restricted use pesticide
            application occurred; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The name and certification number (if applicable) of the certified
            applicator who applied or who supervised the application of the
            restricted use pesticide.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Certified applicators shall maintain records of the application of
            restricted use pesticides made on the same day in a total area of
            less than one-tenth (
            <FR>
              1/10
            </FR>
            ) of an acre. Except for applications of restricted use pesticides
            in greenhouses and nurseries, to which the requirements of paragraph
            (a) of this section apply, these records shall include the following
            information for the application:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The brand or product name, and the EPA registration number of the
            restricted use pesticide that was applied;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The total amount of the restricted use pesticide applied;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The location of the application, designated as “spot application,”
            followed by a concise description of location and treatment; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The month, day, and year on which the restricted use pesticide
            application occurred.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The information required in this section shall be recorded within
            14 days following the pesticide application. However, whether or not
            the written record has been completed, the certified applicator
            shall provide the information to be recorded in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='110' sect='5' psec='#a' tq='N'>
                110.5(a)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The records required in this section shall be retained for a period
            of 2 years from the date of the restricted use pesticide application
            and be maintained in a manner that is accessible by authorized
            representatives.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A commercial applicator shall, within 30 days of a restricted use
            pesticide application, provide a copy of records required under this
            section or under State or Federal regulations (whichever is
            applicable) under which the commercial applicator is holding
            certification, to the person for whom the restricted use pesticide
            was applied.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A certified applicator shall, upon oral request and presentation of
            credentials by an authorized representative, make available to the
            authorized representative the records required to be maintained
            under this section and permit the authorized representative to copy
            any of the records. The original of the records required to be
            maintained under this section shall be retained by the certified
            pesticide applicators.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No Federal or State agency shall release information obtained under
            this part that would directly or indirectly reveal the identity of
            producers of commodities to which restricted use pesticides have
            been applied.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Certified applicators who apply restricted use pesticides in States
            where they are required to maintain records on applications of
            restricted use pesticides, comparable to those for commercial
            applicators in that State, and such records are maintained in
            accordance with State requirements, are not subject to paragraphs
            (a), (b), and (c) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 19022
          </aref>
          , Apr. 9, 1993, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            60 FR 8123
          </aref>
          , Feb. 10, 1995]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4162'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:110:-:110.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        110.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Demonstration of compliance.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='110' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              110.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Demonstration of compliance.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The Secretary is authorized to inspect and copy any record required to
          be maintained by this part in order to determine whether a certified
          applicator is complying with this part.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4163'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:110:-:110.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        110.5
      </num>
      <head>
        Availability of records to facilitate medical treatment.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          60 FR 8123
        </aref>
        , Feb. 10, 1995]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='110' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              110.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Availability of records to facilitate medical treatment.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When the attending licensed health care professional, or an
            individual acting under the direction of the attending licensed
            health care professional, determines that any record of the
            application of any restricted use pesticide required to be
            maintained under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='110' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
                110.3
              </subref>
            </aref>
             is necessary to provide medical treatment or first aid to an
            individual who may have been exposed to the restricted use pesticide
            for which the record is or will be maintained, the 
            <PRTPAGE P='284' />
            certified applicator required to maintain the record shall promptly
            provide the record information and any available label information.
            If it is determined by the attending licensed health care
            professional, or an individual acting under the direction of the
            attending licensed health care professional, to be a medical
            emergency, the record information of the restricted use pesticide,
            relating to the medical emergency, shall be provided immediately.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The attending licensed health care professional, or an individual
            acting under the direction of the attending licensed health care
            professional, may utilize and release the record or record
            information obtained under paragraph (a) of this section when
            necessary to provide medical treatment or first aid to an individual
            who may have been exposed to the restricted use pesticide for which
            the record is or will be maintained.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The attending licensed health care professional may release the
            record or record information to appropriate federal or state
            agencies that deal with pesticide use or any health issue related to
            the use of pesticides when necessary to prevent further injury or
            illness.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A licensed health care professional may release the record or
            record information to submit pesticide poisoning incident reports to
            appropriate state or federal agencies.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            60 FR 8123
          </aref>
          , Feb. 10, 1995]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4164'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:110:-:110.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        110.6
      </num>
      <head>
        Federal cooperation with States.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='110' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              110.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Federal cooperation with States.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For the purpose of carrying out this part, the Administrator may
            enter into agreements with States.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Administrator may, after entering a State-Federal cooperative
            agreement with a State, utilize employees and facilities of the
            State to carry out any provisions of this part in that State. This
            State-Federal cooperative agreement shall specify:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The agency of the State that is designated as the State lead
            agency;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The responsibilities of State agencies for the enforcement of this
            part and the imposition of penalties under this part;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The qualifications required of the State employees administering
            and enforcing this part;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             That the State-Federal cooperative agreement may be terminated at
            any time by the mutual agreement of the parties to the agreement;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             That the State-Federal cooperative agreement may be terminated by
            either party by giving written notice to the other party at least 90
            days before a specified date of termination; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The provisions for liaison between the State and the Administrator
            concerning the administration and enforcement of this part as may be
            agreed by the Administrator and the State.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If at any time the Administrator shall determine that the State
            lead agency or other State agencies charged with carrying out the
            terms of the State-Federal cooperative agreement are unable or
            unwilling to carry out the terms of the agreement, or, if for any
            reason the Administrator or State shall determine that the agreement
            is no longer in effect, the Administrator shall administer and
            enforce this part in the State.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a State shall notify the Administrator of its readiness to enter
            into a State-Federal cooperative agreement prior to passage of State
            legislation and regulations governing recordkeeping by certified
            applicators of restricted use pesticides, the Administrator may
            enter into a State-Federal cooperative agreement with the State on
            an annual basis.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For a State to be eligible for Federal technical or financial
            assistance under a State-Federal cooperative agreement, the State
            requirements for recordkeeping by all certified applicators of
            restricted use pesticides must be comparable to the recordkeeping
            requirements under this part.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4165'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:110:-:110.7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        110.7
      </num>
      <head>
        Penalties.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          70 FR 29579
        </aref>
        , May 24, 2005]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='110' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              110.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Penalties.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Any certified applicator who violates 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='136i-1' note='' psec='#a' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/136i-1.html#a'>
              7 U.S.C. 136i-1(a)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , (b), or (c) or this part shall be subject to a civil penalty of not
          more than the amount specified in section 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='91' psec='#b_1_i_A' tq='N'>
              3.91(b)(1)(i)(A)
            </subref>
             of this title
          </aref>
           in the case of the first offense, and in the case of subsequent
          offenses, be subject to a civil penalty of not less than the 
          <PRTPAGE P='285' />
          amount specified in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='91' psec='#b_1_i_B' tq='N'>
              3.91(b)(1)(i)(B)
            </subref>
             of this title
          </aref>
           for each violation, except that the civil penalty shall be less than
          the amount specified in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='3' sect='91' psec='#b_1_i_B' tq='N'>
              3.91(b)(1)(i)(B)
            </subref>
             of this title
          </aref>
           if the Administrator determines that the certified applicator made a
          good faith effort to comply with 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='136i-1' note='' psec='#a' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/136i-1.html#a'>
              7 U.S.C. 136i-1(a)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , (b), and (c) and this part.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            70 FR 29579
          </aref>
          , May 24, 2005]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4166'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:110:-:110.8
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        110.8
      </num>
      <head>
        Rules of practice.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='110' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              110.8
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Rules of practice.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Notice of violation.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If there is reason to believe that a person has violated or is
            violating any provision of this part, the complainant may file with
            the Presiding Officer a notice of violation signed by the
            complainant. The notice of violation shall state:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The date of issuance of the notice of violation;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The nature of the proceeding;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The identification of the complainant and respondent;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The legal authority under which the proceeding is instituted;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The allegations of fact and provisions of law which constitute the
            basis for the proceeding;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The amount of the proposed civil penalty; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The name, mailing address, and telephone number of the Presiding
            Officer.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Answer.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Within 30 days after the service of the notice of violation, the
            respondent shall file with the Presiding Officer an answer signed by
            the respondent or by the attorney of record in the proceeding. The
            answer shall:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Admit, deny, or explain each of the allegations in the notice of
            violation and set forth any defense asserted by the respondent; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State that the respondent admits all the facts alleged in the
            notice of violation; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State that the respondent admits the jurisdictional allegations in
            the notice of violation and neither admits nor denies the remaining
            allegations and consents to the issuance of an order without further
            procedure.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Default.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Failure to file an answer within 30 days after service of the
            notice of violation shall be deemed, for purposes of the proceeding,
            an admission of the allegations in the notice of violation, and
            failure to deny or otherwise respond to an allegation in the notice
            of violation shall be deemed, for purposes of the proceeding, an
            admission of the allegation, unless the complainant and respondent
            have agreed to a consent decision pursuant to paragraph (e) of this
            section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Amendment of notice of violation or answer.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             At any time prior to the filing of a motion for a hearing, the
            notice of violation or answer may be amended with the consent of the
            complainant and respondent or as authorized by the Presiding Officer
            upon a showing of good cause.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Consent decision.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             At any time before the Presiding Officer files the decision, the
            complainant and respondent may agree to the entry of a consent
            decision. The agreement shall be in the form of a decision signed by
            the complainant and respondent with appropriate space for signature
            by the Presiding Officer, and shall contain an admission of at least
            the jurisdictional facts, consent to the issuance of the agreed
            decision without further procedure, and such other admissions or
            statements as may be agreed to by the complainant and respondent.
            The Presiding Officer shall enter such decision without further
            procedure, unless an error is apparent on the face of the document.
            The consent decision shall have the same force and effect as a
            decision issued after a full hearing, shall become final upon
            issuance, and shall become effective in accordance with the terms of
            the decision.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Procedure upon failure to file an answer or admission of facts.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The failure to file an answer with the Presiding Officer, or the
            admission by the answer of all the material allegations of fact
            contained in the notice of violation, shall constitute a waiver of
            hearing. Upon such admission or failure to submit an answer,
            complainant shall file with the Presiding Officer a proposed
            decision, along with a motion for the adoption of the proposed
            decision both of which shall be served upon the respondent by the
            Presiding Officer. Within 20 days after service of the motion and
            proposed decision, the respondent may file with the Presiding
            Officer objections to the motion and proposed decision. If the
            Presiding Officer finds that meritorious objections have been filed,
            
            <PRTPAGE P='286' />
            complainant&apos;s motion shall be denied with supporting reasons.
            If meritorious objections are not filed, the Presiding Officer shall
            issue a decision without further procedure or hearing. Copies of the
            decision or denial of complainant&apos;s motion shall be served by
            the Presiding Officer upon the respondent and the complainant and
            may be appealed pursuant to paragraph (l) of this section. Where the
            decision as proposed by complainant is entered, such decision shall
            become final and effective without further proceedings 35 days after
            the date of service of the decision upon the respondent, unless
            there is an appeal to the Administrator by the complainant or
            respondent, pursuant to paragraph (l) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Conferences.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon motion of the complainant or respondent, the Presiding Officer
            may direct the complainant and respondent or their counsel to attend
            a conference at any reasonable time, prior to or during the course
            of the hearing, when the Presiding Officer finds that the proceeding
            would be expedited by a conference. Reasonable notice of the time
            and place of the conference shall be given. The Presiding Officer
            may order the complainant or respondent to furnish at or subsequent
            to the conference any or all of the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An outline of the case or defense;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The legal theories upon which the party will rely;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A list of documents which the party anticipates introducing at the
            hearing; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A list of anticipated witnesses who will testify on behalf of the
            party. At the discretion of the party furnishing such list of
            witnesses, the names of the witnesses need not be furnished if they
            are otherwise identified in some meaningful way such as a short
            statement of the type of evidence they will offer.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Presiding Officer shall not order a party to furnish the
            information or documents listed in paragraph (g)(1) (i) through (iv)
            of this section if the party can show that providing the particular
            information or document is inappropriate or unwarranted under the
            circumstances of the particular case.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             At the conference, the following matters may be considered:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The simplification of issues;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The necessity of amendments to the notice of violation or answer;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The possibility of obtaining stipulations of facts and of the
            authenticity, accuracy, and admissibility of documents, which will
            avoid unnecessary proof;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_3_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The limitation of the number of expert or other witnesses;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_3_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Negotiation, compromise, or settlement of issues;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_3_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The exchange of copies of proposed exhibits;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_3_vii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The identification of documents or matters of which official notice
            may be requested;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_3_viii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (viii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A schedule to be followed by the parties for completion of the
            actions decided at the conference; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='g_3_ix'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ix)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Such other matters as may expedite and aid in the disposition of
            the proceeding.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A conference will not be stenographically reported unless so
            directed by the Presiding Officer.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the event the Presiding Officer concludes that personal
            attendance by the Presiding Officer and the parties or counsel at a
            conference is unwarranted or impractical, but determines that a
            conference would expedite the proceeding, the Presiding Officer may
            conduct the conference by telephone or correspondence.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Actions taken as a result of a conference shall be reduced to a
            written appropriate order, unless the Presiding Officer concludes
            that a stenographic report shall suffice, or, the Presiding Officer
            elects to make a statement on the record at the hearing summarizing
            the actions taken.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Procedure for hearing—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Request for hearing.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The complainant or respondent may request a hearing on the facts by
            including such a request in the notice of violation or answer, or by
            a separate request, in writing, filed with the Presiding Officer
            within the time in which an answer may be filed. Failure to request
            a hearing within the time allowed for the filing of the answer shall
            constitute a waiver of a hearing. In the event the respondent denies
            any material fact and fails to file a timely request for a hearing,
            the 
            <PRTPAGE P='287' />
            matter may be set down for hearing on motion of the complainant
            filed with the Presiding Officer or upon the Presiding
            Officer&apos;s own motion.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Time and place.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If any material issue of fact is joined by the pleading, the
            Presiding Officer, upon motion of any of the parties stating that
            the matter is at issue and is ready for hearing, shall set a time
            and place for hearing as soon as feasible with due regard for the
            public interest and the convenience and necessity of the parties.
            The Presiding Officer shall issue a notice stating the time and
            place of hearing. If any change in the time or place of the hearing
            is made, the Presiding Officer shall issue a notice of this change,
            which notice shall be served upon the complainant and respondent,
            unless it is made during the course of an oral hearing and made a
            part of the transcript, or actual notice is given to the parties.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Appearances.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The parties may appear in person or by attorney of record in the
            proceeding. Any individual who appears as an attorney must conform
            to the standard of ethical conduct required of practitioners before
            the courts of the United States.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Debarment of attorney.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whenever a Presiding Officer finds that an individual acting as
            attorney for any party to the proceeding is guilty of unethical or
            contumacious conduct, in or in connection with a proceeding, the
            Presiding Officer may order that the individual be precluded from
            further acting as attorney in the proceeding. An appeal to the
            Administrator may be taken from any such order, but no proceeding
            shall be delayed or suspended pending disposition of the appeal: 
            <E T='03'>
              Provided,
            </E>
             That the Presiding Officer shall suspend the proceeding for a
            reasonable time for the purpose of enabling the party to obtain
            another attorney.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Failure to appear.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A respondent who, after being duly notified, fails to appear at the
            hearing without good cause, shall be deemed to have waived the right
            to an oral hearing in the proceeding and to have admitted any facts
            which may be presented at the hearing. The failure by the respondent
            to appear at the hearing shall also constitute an admission of all
            the material allegations of fact contained in the notice of
            violation. The complainant shall have an election whether to follow
            the procedure set forth in paragraph (f) of this section or whether
            to present evidence, in whole or in part, in the form of affidavits,
            exhibits, or by oral testimony before the Presiding Officer. Failure
            to appear at a hearing shall not be deemed to be a waiver of the
            right to be served with a copy of the Presiding Officer&apos;s
            decision and to appeal to the Administrator pursuant to paragraph
            (l) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Order of proceeding.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as may be determined otherwise by the Presiding Officer, the
            complainant shall proceed first at the hearing.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Evidence.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_7_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The testimony of witnesses at a hearing shall be on oath or
            affirmation and subject to cross-examination.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_7_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon a finding of good cause, the Presiding Officer may order that
            any witness be examined separately and apart from all other
            witnesses except those who are parties to the proceeding.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_7_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Evidence which is immaterial, irrelevant, or unduly repetitious, or
            which is not of the sort upon which responsible persons are
            accustomed to rely, shall be excluded insofar as practicable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Objections.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_8_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a party objects to the admission of any evidence or to the
            limitation of the scope of any examination or cross-examination or
            to any other ruling of the Presiding Officer, the party shall state
            briefly the grounds of such objection, whereupon an automatic
            exception will follow if the objection is overruled by the Presiding
            Officer.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_8_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Only objections made before the Presiding Officer may subsequently
            be relied upon in the proceeding.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Exhibits.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Unless the Presiding Officer finds that the furnishing of copies is
            impracticable, four copies of each exhibit shall be filed with the
            Presiding Officer: 
            <E T='03'>
              Provided,
            </E>
             That, where there are more than two parties in the proceeding, an
            additional copy shall be filed for each additional party. A true
            copy of an exhibit may be substituted for the original.
            <PRTPAGE P='288' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Official records or documents.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An official government record or document or entry in such a record
            or document, if admissible for any purpose, shall be admissible in
            evidence without the production of the individual who made or
            prepared the same, and shall be prima facie evidence of the relevant
            facts stated in the record or document. Such record or document
            shall be evidenced by an official publication of the record or
            document or by a copy certified by an individual having legal
            authority to make such certification.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_11'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (11)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Official notice.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Official notice shall be taken of such matters as are judicially
            noticed by the courts of the United States and of any other matter
            of technical, scientific, or commercial fact of established
            character: 
            <E T='03'>
              Provided,
            </E>
             That the parties shall be given adequate notice of matters so
            noticed, and shall be given adequate opportunity to show that such
            facts are erroneously noticed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_12'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (12)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Offer of proof.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whenever evidence is excluded by the Presiding Officer, the party
            offering such evidence may make an offer of proof, which shall be
            included in the transcript. The offer of proof shall consist of a
            brief statement describing the evidence excluded. If the evidence
            consists of a brief oral statement, the statement shall be included
            in the transcript in its entirety. If the evidence consists of an
            exhibit, it shall be marked for identification and inserted in the
            hearing record. In either event, the evidence shall be considered a
            part of the transcript and hearing record if the Administrator, upon
            appeal, decides the Presiding Officer&apos;s ruling excluding the
            evidence was erroneous and prejudicial. If the Administrator, upon
            appeal, decides the Presiding Officer&apos;s ruling excluding the
            evidence was erroneous and prejudicial and that it would be
            appropriate to have such evidence considered a part of the hearing
            record, the Administrator may direct that the hearing be reopened to
            permit the taking of such evidence or for any purpose in connection
            with the excluded evidence.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_13'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (13)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Transcript.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Hearings shall be recorded and transcribed verbatim.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_13_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Post-hearing procedure—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Corrections to transcript.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='3'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Within the period of time fixed by the Presiding Officer, any party
            may file a motion proposing corrections to the transcript.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Unless a party files a motion proposing corrections to the
            transcript in the time fixed by the Presiding Officer, the
            transcript shall be presumed, except for obvious typographical
            errors, to be a true, correct, and complete transcript of the
            testimony given at the hearing and to contain an accurate
            description or reference to all exhibits received in evidence and
            made part of the hearing record and shall be deemed to be certified
            without further action by the Presiding Officer.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             As soon as practicable after the close of the hearing and after
            consideration of any timely objection filed as to the transcript,
            the Presiding Officer shall issue an order making any corrections to
            the transcript which the Presiding Officer finds are warranted,
            which corrections shall be entered on to the original transcript by
            the Presiding Officer without obscuring the original text.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Proposed finding of fact, conclusions, order, and briefs.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Prior to the Presiding Officer&apos;s decision, each party shall be
            afforded a reasonable opportunity to submit for consideration
            proposed findings of fact, conclusions, order, and brief in support
            of the proposed findings of fact, conclusions and order. A copy of
            each such document filed by a party shall be served upon each of the
            other parties.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Presiding Officer&apos;s decision.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Presiding Officer shall issue a decision within 30 days after
            the hearing, or, if any party submits proposed findings of fact,
            conclusions, order, and a brief in support thereof in accordance
            with paragraph (i)(2) of this section, 30 days after the last such
            submission. The Presiding Officer&apos;s decision shall include the
            Presiding Officer&apos;s findings of the fact, conclusions of law,
            and the reasons or basis for the findings of fact and conclusions of
            law.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='h_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Presiding Officer&apos;s decision shall become effective
            without further proceedings 35 days after the date of service of the
            decision upon the respondent, unless there is an appeal to the
            Administrator by a party to the proceeding pursuant to paragraph (l)
            of this section.
            <PRTPAGE P='289' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Motions and requests—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All motions and requests shall be filed with the Presiding Officer,
            and served upon all the parties, except:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='j_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             requests for extensions of time pursuant to paragraph (m)(3) of
            this section; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='j_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             motions and requests made on the record during the oral hearing.
            The Presiding Officer shall rule upon all motions and requests filed
            or made prior to the filing of an appeal of the Presiding
            Officer&apos;s decision pursuant to paragraph (l) of this section
            except motions directly relating to the appeal. Thereafter, the
            Administrator will rule on any motions and requests, as well as the
            motions directly relating to the appeal.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Motions entertained.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='j_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any motion will be entertained other than a motion to dismiss on
            the pleading. (A motion by the complainant seeking the voluntary
            dismissal of the notice of violation may be entertained by the
            Presiding Officer or the Administrator.)
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='j_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All motions and requests concerning the notice of violation must be
            made within the time allowed for filing an answer, except motions by
            the complainant seeking voluntary dismissal of the notice of
            violation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Contents.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All written motions and requests shall state the particular order,
            ruling, or action desired and the grounds for the order, ruling, or
            action desired.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='j_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Response to motions and requests.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Within 10 days after service of any written motion or request, or
            within a shorter or longer period as may be fixed by the Presiding
            Officer or the Administrator, an opposing party may file a response
            to the motion or request. The other party shall have no right to
            reply to the response; however, the Presiding Officer or the
            Administrator, in their discretion, may order that a reply be filed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Presiding Officer—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='k_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Assignment.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No Presiding Officer shall be assigned to serve in any proceeding
            who:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='k_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Has any pecuniary interest in any matter or business involved in
            the proceeding;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='k_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is related within the third degree by blood or marriage to any
            party to the proceeding; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='k_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Has any conflict of interest which might impair the Presiding
            Officer&apos;s objectivity in the proceeding.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='k_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Disqualification of Presiding Officer.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='k_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any party to the proceeding may, by motion made to the Presiding
            Officer, request that the Presiding Officer withdraw from the
            proceeding because of an alleged disqualifying reason. Such motion
            shall set forth with particularity the grounds of alleged
            disqualification. The Presiding Officer may then either rule upon or
            certify the motion to the Administrator, but not both.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='k_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A Presiding Officer shall withdraw from any proceeding for any
            reason deemed by the Presiding Officer to be disqualifying.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='k_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Powers.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Presiding Officer, in any assigned proceeding, shall have power
            to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='k_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Rule upon motions and requests;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='k_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Set the time and place of a conference and the hearing, adjourn the
            hearing from time to time, and change the time and place of hearing;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='k_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Administer oaths and affirmations;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='k_3_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Summon and examine witnesses and receive evidence at the hearing;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='k_3_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Admit or exclude evidence;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='k_3_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Hear oral argument on facts or law;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='k_3_vii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Do all acts and take all measures necessary for maintenance or
            order, including the exclusion of contumacious counsel or other
            persons; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='k_3_viii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (viii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Take all other actions authorized under this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='l'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (l)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Appeal to the Administrator—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='l_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Filing of petition.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Within 30 days after receiving notice of the Presiding
            Officer&apos;s decision, a party who disagrees with the decision, or
            any part of the Presiding Officer&apos;s decision, or any ruling by
            the Presiding Officer or a party who alleges a deprivation of
            rights, may appeal the Presiding Officer&apos;s decision or rulings
            to the Administrator by filing an appeal petition with the
            Administrator. As provided in paragraph (h)(8) of this section,
            objections regarding evidence or a limitation regarding examination
            or cross examination or other ruling made before the Presiding
            Officer may be relied upon in an appeal. The appeal petition shall
            state 
            <PRTPAGE P='290' />
            the name and address of the person filing the appeal petition. Each
            issue set forth in the appeal petition, and the arguments on each
            issue, shall be separately numbered; shall be plainly and concisely
            stated; and shall contain detailed citations of the record,
            statutes, regulations, or authorities being relied upon in support
            of the argument. A brief may be filed in support of the appeal
            simultaneously with the appeal petition.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='l_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Response to appeal petition.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Within 20 days after the service of a copy of an appeal petition
            and any brief in support of the appeal petition, filed by a party to
            the proceeding, any other party may file with the Administrator a
            response in support of or in opposition to the appeal petition and,
            in such response any relevant issue, not presented in the appeal
            petition, may be raised.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='l_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Transmittal of record.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whenever an appeal to the Presiding Officer&apos;s decision is
            filed and a response to the appeal has been filed or time for filing
            a response has expired, the Presiding Officer shall transmit to the
            Administrator the record of the proceeding. The record shall
            include: the pleading; motions and requests filed and rulings on
            such motions and requests; the transcript of the testimony taken at
            the hearing, together with the exhibits filed in connection with the
            hearing; any documents or papers filed in connection with a
            conference; such proposed findings of fact, conclusions, and orders,
            and briefs in support thereof, as may have been filed in connection
            with the proceeding; the Presiding Officer&apos;s decision; and such
            exceptions, statements of objections and briefs in support thereof
            as may have been filed in the proceeding.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='l_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Decision of the Administrator on appeal.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             As soon as practicable after the receipt of the record from the
            Presiding Officer, the Administrator, upon the basis of and after
            due consideration of the record and any matter of which official
            notice is taken, shall rule on the appeal. If the Administrator
            decides that no change or modification of the Presiding
            Officer&apos;s decision is warranted, the Administrator may adopt
            the Presiding Officer&apos;s decision as the final order in the
            proceeding, preserving any right of the party bringing the appeal to
            seek judicial review of such decision in the proper forum.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='m'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (m)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Filing; service; extensions of time; and computation of time—
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='m_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Filing; number of copies.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as otherwise provided in this section, all documents or
            papers required or authorized by this section to be filed with the
            Presiding Officer or Administrator shall be filed in quadruplicate: 
            <E T='03'>
              Provided,
            </E>
             That where there are more than two parties in the proceeding, an
            additional copy shall be filed for each additional party.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='m_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Service; proof of service.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Copies of all documents or papers required or authorized by this
            section to be filed with the Presiding Officer or Administrator
            shall be served upon the parties by the person with whom such
            documents or papers are filed. Service shall be made either:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='m_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             By delivering a copy of the document or paper to the individual to
            be served or to a member of the partnership to be served, or to the
            president, secretary, or other executive officer or any director of
            the corporation or association to be served, or to the attorney of
            record representing such person; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='m_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             By leaving a copy of the document or paper at the principal office
            or place of business or residence of such individual, partnership,
            corporation, organization, or association, or of the attorney of
            record representing such person and mailing by regular mail another
            copy to such person at such address; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='m_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             By registering or certifying and mailing a copy of the document or
            paper, addressed to such individual, partnership, corporation,
            organization, or association, or to the attorney of record
            representing such person, at the last known residence or principal
            office or place of business of such person: 
            <E T='03'>
              Provided,
            </E>
             That if the registered or certified document or paper is returned
            undelivered because the addressee refused or failed to accept
            delivery, the document or paper shall be served by remailing it by
            regular mail. Proof of service under this paragraph shall be made by
            the certificate of the person who actually made the service: 
            <E T='03'>
              Provided,
            </E>
             That if the service be made by mail, under paragraph (m)(2)(iii) of
            this section, proof of service shall be made by the return 
            <PRTPAGE P='291' />
            post-office receipt, in the case of registered or certified mail, or
            by the certificate of the person who mailed the matter by regular
            mail. Any certificate or post-office receipt returned to the
            Presiding Officer or Administrator shall be filed by the Presiding
            Officer or Administrator, and made a part of the record of the
            proceeding.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='m_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Extensions of time.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The time for the filing of any document or paper required or
            authorized under this section to be filed may be extended by the
            Presiding Officer or the Administrator as provided in paragraph (j)
            of this section, if in the judgment of the Presiding Officer or the
            Administrator, as the case may be, there is good reason for the
            extension. In all instances in which time permits, notice of the
            request for extension of the time shall be given to the other party
            with opportunity to submit views concerning the request.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='m_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Effective date of filing.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any document or paper required or authorized under this section to
            be filed shall be deemed to be filed at the time when it reaches the
            person with whom the document or paper must be filed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='m_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Computation of time.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Saturdays, Sundays, and holidays shall be included in computing the
            time allowed for the filing of any document or paper: 
            <E T='03'>
              Provided,
            </E>
             That, when such time expires on a Saturday, Sunday, or holiday,
            such period shall be extended to include the next following business
            day.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='n'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (n)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Ex parte communications.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='n_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             At no stage of the proceeding between its institution and the
            issuance of the final decision shall the Presiding Officer or
            Administrator discuss ex parte the merits of the proceeding with any
            person who is connected with the proceeding in an advocative or in
            an investigative capacity, or with any representative of such
            person: 
            <E T='03'>
              Provided,
            </E>
             That the Presiding Officer or Administrator may discuss the merits
            of the case with such a person if all parties to the proceeding, or
            their attorneys have been given notice and an opportunity to
            participate. A memorandum of such discussion shall be included in
            the record.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='n_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No interested person shall make or knowingly cause to be made to
            the Presiding Officer or Administrator an ex parte communication
            relevant to the merits of the proceeding.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='n_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the Presiding Officer of the Administrator receives an ex parte
            communication in violation of this paragraph (n), the individual who
            receives the communication shall place in the public record of the
            proceeding:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='n_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any such written communication;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='n_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Memoranda stating the substance of such oral communication; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='n_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any written response, and memoranda stating the substance of any
            oral response to the ex parte communication.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='n_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For purposes of this section 
            <E T='03'>
              ex parte communication
            </E>
             means an oral or written communication not on the public record
            with respect to which reasonable prior notice to all parties is not
            given, but it shall not include requests for status reports on any
            matter or the proceeding.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='4167'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:I:E:110:-:110.9
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        110.9
      </num>
      <head>
        Miscellaneous.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='110' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
              110.9
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Miscellaneous.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          In accordance with 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            Section 3507 of
          </aref>
           the Paperwork Reduction Act of 1980 (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='44' sect='3507' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/44/3507.html'>
              44 U.S.C. 3507
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ), the recordkeeping provisions in this rule have been approved by the
          Office of Management and Budget (OMB) and there are no new
          requirements. The assigned OMB control number is 0581-AA39.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>