<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol15'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:I:2003
    </extid>
    <num>
      2003
    </num>
    <head>
      ORGANIZATION
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='5' sect='301' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/5/301.html'>
              5 U.S.C. 301
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='6941' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/6941.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 6941
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; and 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR 
            <subref title='7' part='2' sect='17' psec='' tq='N'>
              2.17
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            62 FR 67259
          </aref>
          , Dec. 24, 1997, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='15784'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:I:2003:A:2003.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2003.1
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2003' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              2003.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            EEO
          </E>
          —the Equal Employment Opportunity Act of 1972, 42 U.S.C. 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 2000e
          </aref>
          <E T='03'>
            et seq.
          </E>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            O&amp;M
          </E>
          —Operations and Management.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            P&amp;P
          </E>
          —Policy and Planning.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            RBS
          </E>
          —Rural Business-Cooperative Development Service, USDA, or any
          successor agency.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            RHS
          </E>
          —Rural Housing Service, USDA, or any successor agency.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            RTB
          </E>
          —Rural Telephone Bank authorized by 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='944' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/944.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 944
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Rural Development
          </E>
          —Rural Development mission area of USDA.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            RUS
          </E>
          —Rural Utilities Service, USDA, or any successor agency.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Secretary
          </E>
          —the Secretary of USDA.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            USDA
          </E>
          —the United States Department of Agriculture.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15785'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:I:2003:A:2003.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2003.2
      </num>
      <head>
        General.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2003' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              2003.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The Rural Development mission area of the Department of Agriculture
          was established as a result of the Department of Agriculture
          Reorganization Act of 1994, Title II of Pub.L. 103-354. Rural
          Development&apos;s basic organization consists of Headquarters in
          Washington, D.C. and 47 State Offices. Headquarters maintains overall
          planning, coordination, and control of Rural Development agency
          programs. Administrators head RHS, RBS, and RUS under the direction of
          the Under Secretary for Rural Development. State Directors head the
          State Offices and are directly responsible to the Under Secretary for
          the execution of all Rural Development agency programs within the
          boundaries of their states.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15786'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:I:2003:A:2003.3-2003.4
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        2003.3-2003.4
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='2003' sect='3-2003' psec='' tq='N'>
              2003.3-2003
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .4
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15787'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:I:2003:A:2003.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2003.5
      </num>
      <head>
        Headquarters organization.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2003' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              2003.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Headquarters organization.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Rural Development Headquarters is comprised of:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Office of the Under Secretary;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Two Deputy Under Secretaries; and,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Three Administrators and their staffs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Rural Development Headquarters is located at 1400 Independence
            Avenue, SW., Washington, DC. 20250-0700
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15788'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:I:2003:A:2003.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2003.6
      </num>
      <head>
        Office of the Under Secretary.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2003' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              2003.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Office of the Under Secretary.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          In accordance with 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR § 
            <subref title='7' part='2' sect='17' psec='' tq='N'>
              2.17
            </subref>
          </aref>
           the Secretary has delegated to the Under Secretary, Rural
          Development, authority to manage and administer programs and support
          functions of the Rural Development mission area.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Office of the Deputy Under Secretary for P&amp;P.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             This office is headed by the Deputy Under Secretary for P&amp;P.
            The Under Secretary, Rural Development, has delegated to the Deputy
            Under Secretary for P&amp;P, responsibility for formulation and
            development of short-and long-range rural development policies of
            the Department in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR § 
              <subref title='7' part='2' sect='45' psec='' tq='N'>
                2.45
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . The Deputy Under Secretary for P&amp;P reports directly to the
            Under Secretary, Rural 
            <PRTPAGE P='8' />
            Development, and provides guidance and supervision for research,
            policy analysis and development, strategic planning, partnerships
            and special initiatives. For budget and accounting purposes, all of
            the staff offices under the Deputy Under Secretary for P&amp;P are
            housed in RBS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Budget Analysis Division assesses potential impacts of
            alternative policies on the mission area&apos;s programs and
            operations and develops recommendations for change. The units are
            headed by the Chief Budget Officer, who individually serves as the
            top policy advisor to the Under Secretary and Deputy Under Secretary
            on all matters relating to mission area budget policy.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Research, Analysis and Information Division analyzes
            information on rural conditions and the strategies and techniques
            for promoting rural development. The division performs, or arranges
            to have conducted, short-term and major research studies needed to
            formulate policy.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Reinvention and Capacity Building Division coordinates the
            mission area&apos;s strategic planning initiatives, both at the
            National level and in the State Offices. The division assists the
            Rural Development agencies in their implementation of the Government
            Performance and Results Act (GPRA) and special initiatives of the
            Administration, USDA, and the Office of the Under Secretary.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Rural Initiatives and Partnership Division manages the mission
            area&apos;s involvement and coordination with other Federal and
            state departments and agencies to assess rural issues and develop
            model partnerships and initiatives to achieve shared rural
            development goals. The division is responsible for managing the
            National Rural Development Partnership and providing support and
            oversight of 37 State Rural Development Councils.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Office of the Deputy Under Secretary for O&amp;M.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR 
              <subref title='7' part='2' sect='45' psec='' tq='N'>
                2.45
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , the Under Secretary, Rural Development, has delegated to the
            Deputy Under Secretary for O&amp;M responsibility for providing
            leadership in planning, developing, and administering overall
            administrative management program policies and operational
            activities of the Rural Development mission area. The Deputy Under
            Secretary for O&amp;M reports directly to the Under Secretary, Rural
            Development.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Office of the Deputy Administrator for O&amp;M.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Headed by the Deputy Administrator for O&amp;M, this office reports
            directly to the Deputy Under Secretary for O&amp;M, and is
            responsible for directing and coordinating the consolidated
            administrative and financial management functions for Rural
            Development. This office provides overall guidance and supervision
            for budget and financial management, human resources management and
            personnel services, administrative and procurement services,
            information resources management and automated data systems. For
            budget and accounting purposes, all of the staff offices under the
            Deputy Administrator for O&amp;M are housed in RHS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Office of the Controller.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Headed by the Chief Financial Officer, this office supports the
            Deputy Administrator for O&amp;M in executing Rural Development
            requirements related to compliance with the Chief Financial Officers
            Act of 1990 and provides leadership, coordination, and oversight of
            all financial management matters and financial execution of the
            budget for the Rural Development agencies. This office also has full
            responsibility for Rural Development agencies&apos; accounting,
            financial, reporting, and internal controls. The office provides
            direct oversight to the Headquarters Budget Division, Financial
            Management Division, and the Office of the Assistant Controller,
            located in St. Louis, Missouri.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Office of Assistant Administrator for Procurement and
              Administrative Services.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Headed by the Assistant Administrator for Procurement and
            Administrative Services, this office is responsible to the Deputy
            Administrator for O&amp;M for overseeing the Procurement Management
            Division, the Property and Supply Management Division, and the
            Support Services Division:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='b_1_ii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Procurement Management Division is responsible for developing,
            implementing, and interpreting procurement and contracting policies
            for the Rural Development mission area. Major functions include
            planning outreach efforts and goals for small and disadvantaged
            businesses, providing 
            <PRTPAGE P='9' />
            staff assistance reviews in State and Local Offices, administering
            the Contracting Officer Professionalism Warrant program for Rural
            Development agencies, and coordinating the development of Rural
            Development&apos;s acquisition plans.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='b_1_ii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Property and Supply Management Division is responsible for
            developing office space acquisition and utilization policies,
            providing training to field office leasing officers, administering
            the Leasing Officer Warrant program, assuring accessibility
            compliance in Rural Development&apos;s work sites, administering
            Rural Development&apos;s Physical Security program, and establishing
            and providing oversight to the worksite Energy Conservation program.
            This office operates a nationwide supply warehousing and
            distribution program, and oversees a nationwide Personal Property
            Management and Utilization Program, manages the U.S. Department of
            Agriculture (USDA) Excess Personal Property Program for field level
            activities, and provides direct support services to Rural
            Development&apos;s St. Louis facilities.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='b_1_ii_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Support Services Division has responsibility for designing,
            developing, administering, and controlling Rural Development&apos;s
            directives management and issuance system, coordinating Rural
            Development&apos;s Regulatory Agenda and Regulatory Program
            submissions to USDA and OMB, serving as 
            <E T='04'>
              Federal Register
            </E>
             liaison, and analyzing and coordinating regulatory work plans for
            the Under Secretary. This office submits Paperwork Reduction Act
            public burden clearances to OMB, administers all printing programs,
            manages Rural Development travel policies and programs, and manages
            Freedom of Information Act, Privacy Act and Tort Claims programs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Office of Information Resources Management (IRM).
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Headed by the Chief Information Officer, this office is responsible
            to the Deputy Administrator for O&amp;M for developing Rural
            Development&apos;s IRM policies, regulations, standards and
            guidelines. This office provides overall leadership and direction to
            activities assigned to the following four major divisions:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='b_1_iii_A'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (A)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Customer Services Division is responsible for direct customer
            and technical support (hardware and software).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='b_1_iii_B'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (B)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Management Services Division coordinates all IRM acquisition,
            budget, and policy and planning activities in support of Rural
            Development automation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='b_1_iii_C'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (C)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Information Technology Division provides support technical
            services in the areas of data administration, system integrity
            management, research and development, and telecommunications.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='4' id='b_1_iii_D'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (D)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Systems Services Division is responsible for planning,
            directing, and controlling activities related to Rural
            Development&apos;s Automated Information Systems.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Office of the Assistant Administrator for Human Resources.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Headed by the Assistant Administrator for Human Resources, this
            office is responsible to the Deputy Administrator for O&amp;M for
            the overall development, implementation, and management, of
            personnel and human resources support services for Rural
            Development. The office provides direction to the Headquarters
            Personnel Services, Human Resources Training and Mission Area
            Personnel Services Division, and Labor Relations Staff offices. The
            office is also responsible for the establishment of recruitment,
            retention, and development policies and programs supporting
            workforce diversity and affirmative action.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Office of Civil Rights Staff.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Headed by a staff director, this staff has primary responsibility
            for providing leadership and administration of the Civil Rights
            Program for the Rural Development mission area. The staff conducts
            on-site reviews of borrowers and beneficiaries of Federal financial
            assistance to ensure compliance with Titles VI and VII of the Civil
            Rights Act of 1964, as amended, Title VIII of the Civil Rights Act
            of 1968, as amended, 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              Section 504 of
            </aref>
             the Rehabilitation Act, the Americans with Disabilities Act, and
            prepares compliance reports. The staff conducts and evaluates Title
            VII compliance visits to insure that EEO programs are adequately
            implemented. In addition, the office develops, monitors, and
            evaluates Affirmative Employment programs for minorities, women and 
            <PRTPAGE P='10' />
            persons with disabilities, and coordinates and conducts community
            outreach activities at historically black colleges and universities.
            It also has oversight of special emphasis programs such as the
            Federal Women&apos;s Program, Hispanic Emphasis Program, and Black
            Emphasis Program. The staff director reports directly to the Deputy
            Under Secretary for O&amp;M.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Office of Communications.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Headed by a director who reports directly to the Deputy Under
            Secretary for O&amp;M, this office has primary responsibility for
            tracking legislation and development and institution of policies to
            provide public communication and information services related to the
            Rural Development. The office maintains a constituent data base and
            conducts minority outreach efforts and administers a public
            information and media center responsible for media inquiries, news
            releases, program announcements, media advisories, and information
            retrieval. This office also serves as a liaison with Office of
            Congressional Relations (OCR), Office of the General Counsel (OGC),
            and other Departmental units involved in Congressional relations and
            public information. This office drafts testimony, prepares
            witnesses, and provides staff for hearings and markups. In addition,
            the office briefs Congressional members and staff on the Rural
            Development matters, coordinates Rural Development&apos;s
            legislative activities with other USDA agencies and OMB and develops
            and implements legislative strategy. The staff also coordinates
            development and production of brochures, press releases, and other
            public information materials.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15789'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:I:2003:A:2003.7-2003.9
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        2003.7-2003.9
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='2003' sect='7-2003' psec='' tq='N'>
              2003.7-2003
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .9
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15790'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:I:2003:A:2003.10
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2003.10
      </num>
      <head>
        Rural Development State Offices.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          62 FR 67259
        </aref>
        , Dec. 24, 1997; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          63 FR 3256
        </aref>
        , Jan. 22, 1998]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2003' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
              2003.10
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Rural Development State Offices.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Headed by State Directors, State Offices report directly to the
            Under Secretary, Rural Development, and are responsible to the three
            Rural Development agency Administrators for carrying out agency
            program operations at the State level, ensuring adherence to program
            plans approved for the State by the Under Secretary, and rendering
            staff advisory and manpower support to Area and Local offices. The
            Rural Development State Directors, for budget and accounting
            purposes, are housed in the RHS agency.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Program Directors within the State Office provide oversight and
            leadership on major program functions. Major program functions
            include: Single Family and Multi-Family Housing loans and grants,
            Community Facility, Water and Waste Disposal, Business and
            Cooperative, and the Empowerment Zones and Enterprise Communities
            (EZ/EC) programs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The USDA Rural Development State Office locations are as follows:
          </text>
        </P>
        <table class='gpotable' CDEF='s25,r25' COLS='2' OPTS='L2,i1'>
          <caption />
          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th>
                State
              </th>
              <th>
                Location
              </th>
            </tr>
          </thead>
          <tfoot />
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Alabama
              </td>
              <td>
                Montgomery, AL
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Alaska
              </td>
              <td>
                Palmer, AK
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Arizona
              </td>
              <td>
                Phoenix, AZ
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Arkansas
              </td>
              <td>
                Little Rock, AR
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                California
              </td>
              <td>
                Woodland, CA
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Colorado
              </td>
              <td>
                Lakewood, CO
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Delaware
              </td>
              <td>
                Camden, DE
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Florida
              </td>
              <td>
                Gainesville, FL
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Georgia
              </td>
              <td>
                Athens, GA
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Hawaii
              </td>
              <td>
                Hilo, HI
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Idaho
              </td>
              <td>
                Boise, ID
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Illinois
              </td>
              <td>
                Champaign, IL
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Indiana
              </td>
              <td>
                Indianapolis, IN
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Iowa
              </td>
              <td>
                Des Moines, IA
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Kansas
              </td>
              <td>
                Topeka, KS
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Kentucky
              </td>
              <td>
                Lexington, KY
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Louisiana
              </td>
              <td>
                Alexandria, LA
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Maine
              </td>
              <td>
                Bangor, ME
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Massachusetts
              </td>
              <td>
                Amherst, MA
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Michigan
              </td>
              <td>
                East Lansing, MI
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Minnesota
              </td>
              <td>
                St. Paul, MN
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Mississippi
              </td>
              <td>
                Jackson, MS
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Missouri
              </td>
              <td>
                Columbia, MO
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Montana
              </td>
              <td>
                Bozeman, MT
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Nebraska
              </td>
              <td>
                Lincoln, NE
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Nevada
              </td>
              <td>
                Carson City, NV
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                New Jersey
              </td>
              <td>
                Mt. Holly, NJ
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                New Mexico
              </td>
              <td>
                Albuquerque, NM
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                New York
              </td>
              <td>
                Syracuse, NY
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                North Carolina
              </td>
              <td>
                Raleigh, NC
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                North Dakota
              </td>
              <td>
                Bismarck, ND
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Ohio
              </td>
              <td>
                Columbus, OH
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Oklahoma
              </td>
              <td>
                Stillwater, OK
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Oregon
              </td>
              <td>
                Portland, OR
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Pennsylvania
              </td>
              <td>
                Harrisburg, PA
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Puerto Rico
              </td>
              <td>
                Hato Rey, PR
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                South Carolina
              </td>
              <td>
                Columbia, SC
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                South Dakota
              </td>
              <td>
                Huron, SD
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Tennessee
              </td>
              <td>
                Nashville, TN
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Texas
              </td>
              <td>
                Temple, TX
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Utah
              </td>
              <td>
                Salt Lake City, UT
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Vermont
              </td>
              <td>
                Montpelier, VT
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Virginia
              </td>
              <td>
                Richmond, VA
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Washington
              </td>
              <td>
                Olympia, WA
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                West Virginia
              </td>
              <td>
                Charleston, WV
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Wisconsin
              </td>
              <td>
                Stevens Point, WI
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td I='01'>
                Wyoming
              </td>
              <td>
                Casper, WY
              </td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            62 FR 67259
          </aref>
          , Dec. 24, 1997; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            63 FR 3256
          </aref>
          , Jan. 22, 1998]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15791'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:I:2003:A:2003.11-2003.13
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        2003.11-2003.13
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='11' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='2003' sect='11-2003' psec='' tq='N'>
              2003.11-2003
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .13
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15792'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:I:2003:A:2003.14
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2003.14
      </num>
      <head>
        Field Offices.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2003' sect='14' psec='' tq='N'>
              2003.14
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Field Offices.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Rural Development field offices report to their respective State
          Director and State Office Program Directors. State Directors may
          organizationally structure their offices based on the program
          workloads within their respective State. Field offices generally are
          patterned in a three or two tier program delivery structure. In a
          three tier system, Local offices report to an Area office, that
          reports to the State Office. In a two tier system, a “Local” or “Area”
          office reports to the State Office. Locations and telephone numbers of
          Area and Local Offices may be obtained from the appropriate Rural
          Development State Office.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15793'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:I:2003:A:2003.15-2003.16
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        2003.15-2003.16
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='2003' sect='15-2003' psec='' tq='N'>
              2003.15-2003
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .16
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15794'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:I:2003:A:2003.17
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2003.17
      </num>
      <head>
        Availability of information.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2003' sect='17' psec='' tq='N'>
              2003.17
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Availability of information.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Information concerning Rural Development programs and agencies may be
          obtained from the Office of Communications, Rural Development, U. S.
          Department of Agriculture, STOP 0705, 1400 Independence Avenue SW.,
          Washington, DC 20250-0705.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15795'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:I:2003:A:2003.18
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2003.18
      </num>
      <head>
        Functional organization of RHS.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          62 FR 67259
        </aref>
        , Dec. 24, 1997, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          64 FR 32388
        </aref>
        , June 17, 1999]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2003' sect='18' psec='' tq='N'>
              2003.18
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Functional organization of RHS.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Secretary established RHS pursuant to 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 233 of
            </aref>
             the Department of Agriculture Reorganization Act of 1994 (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='6943' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/6943.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 6943
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Office of the Administrator.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             According to 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR 
              <subref title='7' part='2' sect='49' psec='' tq='N'>
                2.49
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , the Administrator has responsibility for implementing programs
            aimed at delivering loans and grant assistance to rural Americans
            and their communities in obtaining adequate and affordable housing
            and community facilities, in accordance with Title V of the Housing
            Act of 1949 (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='42' sect='1471' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/42/1471.html'>
                42 U.S.C. 1471
              </subref>
            </aref>
            <E T='03'>
              et seq.
            </E>
            ) and the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='1921' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1921.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 1921
              </subref>
            </aref>
            <E T='03'>
              et seq.
            </E>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Legislative Affairs Staff.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The duties and responsibilities of this staff have now been aligned
            under the Office of Communication, headed by a director who reports
            directly to the Under Secretary for O&amp;M. The Office of
            Communication is responsible for providing and carrying out
            legislative, public communication, and information services for the
            Rural Development mission area.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Office of Program Support Staff.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Program Support Staff is headed by a staff director who is
            responsible to the Administrator for monitoring managerial and
            technical effectiveness of RHS programs. The staff coordinates
            review and analysis of legislation, Executive Orders, OMB circulars,
            and Department regulations for their impact on Agency programs. The
            staff develops, implements, and reports on architectural and
            environmental policies, in cooperation with the Department. Staff
            responsibilities also include managing RHS&apos;s Hazardous Waste
            Management Fund, coordinating the Debarment and Suspension process
            for RHS, tracking the use of Program Loan Cost Expense funds, and
            maintaining the RHS Internet “Home Page.”
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Office of Deputy Administrator, Single Family Housing.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Headed by the Deputy Administrator, Single Family Housing, this
            office is responsible to the Administrator for the development and
            implementation of RHS&apos;s Single Family Housing programs, which
            extend supervised housing credit to rural people of limited
            resources, for adequate, modest, decent, safe, and sanitary homes.
            The office is responsible for administering and managing 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              sections 502 and 504
            </aref>
             Rural Housing direct and guaranteed loan and grant programs, Rural
            Housing and Self-Help Site loans, the Self-Help Technical Assistance
            grant program, Housing Application Packaging and Technical and
            Supervisory Assistance grants, and Home Improvement and Repaid loans
            and grants. The office directs the following three divisions: Single
            Family Housing Processing Division, Single Family Housing Servicing
            and Property Management Division, and Single Family Housing
            Centralized Servicing Center in St. Louis, Mo.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Office of Single Family Housing Processing Division.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Headed by a division director, this division is responsible for
            development and nationwide implementation of policies on processing
            Single Family Housing direct and guaranteed program loans. In
            addition, the division provides direction on the following: the
            Rural Housing Targeted Area Set-Aside program, 
            <PRTPAGE P='12' />
            debarments, payment assistance, title clearance and loan closing,
            site/subdivision development, Deferred Mortgage Payment Program;
            construction defects, credit reports, appraisals, Manufactured
            Housing, coordinated assessment reviews, Home Buyer&apos;s
            Counseling/Education Program, and allocation of loan and grant
            program funds.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Office of Single Family Housing Servicing and Property Management
              Division.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Headed by a division director, this division is responsible for the
            development and implementation of nationwide policies for servicing
            RHS&apos;s multi-billion dollar portfolio of Single Family Housing
            loans, and managing and selling Single Family Housing inventory
            properties. The division also conducts state program evaluations,
            identifies program weaknesses, makes recommendations for
            improvements, and identifies corrective actions.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Office of Single Family Housing Centralized Servicing Center
              (CSC)—St. Louis, Missouri.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Headed by a director, CSC is responsible for centrally servicing
            RHS&apos;s multi-billion dollar portfolio of Single Family Housing
            loans. CSC provides interest credit or payment assistance renewals,
            performs escrow activities for real estate taxes and property hazard
            insurance, oversees collection of loan payments, and grants interest
            credit, payment assistance, and moratoria.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Office of the Deputy Administrator, Multi-Family Housing Division.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Headed by the Deputy Administrator, Multi-Family Housing, this
            office is responsible for the development and nationwide
            implementation of RHS&apos;s Multi-Family Housing programs, which
            extend supervised housing credit to rural residents an opportunity
            to have decent, safe, and sanitary rental housing. The following
            programs are administered and managed by this office: 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              Section 515
            </aref>
             Rural Rental Housing, Rural Cooperative and Congregate Housing
            Programs, 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              Section 521
            </aref>
             Rental Assistance, Farm Labor Housing loan and grant programs,
            Housing Preservation Grants, rural housing vouchers, and Housing
            Application Packaging Grants. This office directs the following two
            divisions:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_4_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Multi-Family Housing Processing Division.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Headed by a division director, this division is responsible for the
            development and nationwide implementation of policies on processing
            Multi-Family Housing program loans. The division manages the
            following program areas: elderly and family rental housing, Farm
            Labor Housing loans and grants, outreach contacts, congregate
            facilities, Housing Preservation Grants, cooperative housing, rural
            housing vouchers, appraisals, Congregate Housing Services Grants,
            Rental Assistance, Housing Application Packaging Grants, targeted
            area and nonprofit set asides, Multi-Family Housing suspensions and
            debarments, title clearance and loan closing, allocation and
            monitoring of loan and grant funds, adverse decisions and appeals,
            commercial credit reports, individual credit reports, and, site
            development.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_4_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Multi-Family Housing Portfolio Management Division.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Headed by a division director, this division is responsible for the
            development and institution of policies on the management and
            servicing of the nationwide Multi-Family Housing programs. The
            Division implements current and long range plans for servicing Rural
            Rental Housing loans, Labor Housing loans and grants, and Rental
            Assistance or similar tenant subsidies.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Office of the Deputy Administrator, Community Programs.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Headed by the Deputy Administrator, Community Programs, this office
            is responsible for overseeing the administration and management of
            Community Facilities loans and grants to hospitals and nursing
            homes, police and fire stations, libraries, schools, adult and child
            care centers, etc. The office monitors and evaluates the
            administration of loan and grant programs on a nationwide basis and
            provides guidance and direction for community programs through two
            divisions, Community Programs Loan Processing Division and Servicing
            and Special Authorities Division.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_5_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Community Programs Loan Processing Division.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Headed by a director, this division is responsible for the overall
            administration, policy development, fund distribution, and
            processing of Community Facilities loans and grants and other loan
            and grant programs assigned to the Division.
            <PRTPAGE P='13' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_5_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Servicing and Special Authorities Division.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Headed by a division director, this division is responsible for the
            overall administration, policy development, and servicing of the
            Community Facilities loan and grant programs. The division conducts
            program evaluations, identifies program weaknesses, makes
            recommendations for improvements, and identifies corrective actions.
            The division also administers and services Nonprofit National
            Corporation loans and grants.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            62 FR 67259
          </aref>
          , Dec. 24, 1997, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            64 FR 32388
          </aref>
          , June 17, 1999]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15796'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:I:2003:A:2003.19-2003.21
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        2003.19-2003.21
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='2003' sect='19-2003' psec='' tq='N'>
              2003.19-2003
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .21
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15797'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:I:2003:A:2003.22
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2003.22
      </num>
      <head>
        Functional organization of RUS.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2003' sect='22' psec='' tq='N'>
              2003.22
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Functional organization of RUS.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Secretary established RUS pursuant to 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              § 232 of
            </aref>
             the Department of Agriculture Reorganization Act of 1994 (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='6942' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/6942.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 6942
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Office of the Administrator.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             According to 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR 
              <subref title='7' part='2' sect='47' psec='' tq='N'>
                2.47
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , the Administrator has responsibility for managing and
            administering the programs and support functions of RUS to provide
            financial and technical support for rural infrastructure to include
            electrification, clean drinking water, telecommunications, and water
            disposal systems, pursuant to the Consolidated Farm and Rural
            Development Act, as amended (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='1921' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1921.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 1921
              </subref>
            </aref>
            <E T='03'>
              et seq.
            </E>
            ), and the Rural Electrification Act of 1936, as amended (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='901' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/901.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 901
              </subref>
            </aref>
            <E T='03'>
              et seq.
            </E>
            ). The office develops and implements strategic plans concerning the
            Rural Electrification Act of 1936, as amended. The Administrator
            serves as Governor of the Rural Telephone Bank (RTB) with a
            13-member board of directors, and exercises and performs all
            functions, powers, and duties of the RTB in accordance with 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='944' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/944.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 944
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Borrower and Program Support Services.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Borrower and Program Support Services consist of the three
            following staffs which are responsible to the Administrator for
            planning and carrying out a variety of program and administrative
            services in support of all RUS programs, and providing expert advice
            and coordination for the Administrator:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Administrative Liaison Staff.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Headed by a staff director, this staff advises the Administrator on
            management issues and policies relating to human resources, EEO,
            labor-management partnership, administrative services, travel
            management, automated information systems, and administrative
            budgeting and funds control.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Program Accounting Services Division.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Headed by a division director, this division develops and evaluates
            the accounting systems and procedures of Electric,
            Telecommunications, and Water and Wastewater borrowers; assures that
            accounting policies, systems, and procedures meet regulatory,
            Departmental, General Accounting Office, OMB, and Treasury
            Department requirements; examines borrowers&apos; records and
            operations, and reviews expenditures of loans and other funds;
            develops audit requirements; and approves Certified Public
            Accountants to perform audits of borrowers.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_1_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Program and Financial Services Staff.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Headed by a staff director, this staff evaluates the financial
            conditions of troubled borrowers, negotiates settlements of
            delinquent loans, and makes recommendations to program Assistant
            Administrators on ways to improve the financial health of borrowers.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Office of Assistant Administrator—Electric Program.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Headed by the Assistant Administrator—Electric Program, this office
            is responsible to the Administrator for directing and coordinating
            the Rural Electrification program of RUS nationwide. This office
            develops, maintains, and implements regulations and program
            procedures on processing and approving loans and loan-related
            activities for rural electric borrowers. The office directs the
            following three divisions:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Electric Regional Divisions.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Headed by division directors, these two divisions are responsible
            for administering the Rural Electrification program in specific
            geographic areas and serving as the single point of contact for all
            distribution borrowers. The divisions provide guidance to borrowers
            on RUS loan policies and procedures, maintain oversight of borrower
            rate actions, and make recommendations to the Administrator on
            borrower applications for RUS financing. The divisions also assure
            that power plant, distribution, 
            <PRTPAGE P='14' />
            and transmission systems and facilities are designed and constructed
            in accordance with the terms of the loan and proper engineering
            practices and specifications.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Power Supply Division.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Headed by a division director, this division is responsible for
            administering the Rural Electrification program responsibilities
            with regard to power supply borrowers nationwide and serves as
            primary point of contact between RUS and all such borrowers. The
            division develops and maintains a loan processing program for Rural
            Electrification Act purposes, and develops and administers
            engineering and construction policies related to planning, design,
            construction, operation, and maintenance for power supply borrowers.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Electric Staff Division.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Headed by a division director, this division is responsible for
            engineering activities related to the design, construction, and
            technical operations and maintenance of power plants; distribution
            of power; and transmission systems and facilities, including load
            management and communications. The division develops criteria and
            techniques for evaluating the financing and performance of electric
            borrowers and forecasting borrowers&apos; future power needs; and
            maintains financial expertise on the distribution and power supply
            loan program, and retail and wholesale rates.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Office of Assistant Administrator—Telecommunications Program.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Headed by the Assistant Administrator—Telecommunications Program,
            this office is responsible to the Administrator for directing and
            coordinating the National Rural Telecommunications, Distance
            Learning, and Telemedicine programs of RUS. The Assistant
            Administrator, Telecommunications Program, serves as Assistant
            Governor of the RTB and is responsible for the day-to-day activities
            of the RTB. The office develops, maintains, and implements
            regulations and program procedures on the processing and approval of
            grants, loans, and loan-related activities for all rural
            telecommunications borrowers and grant recipients. The office
            directs the following three divisions:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Telecommunications Standards Division.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Headed by a division director, this division is responsible for
            engineering staff activities related to the design, construction,
            and technical operation and maintenance of rural telecommunications
            systems and facilities. The office develops engineering practices,
            policies, and technical data related to borrowers&apos;
            telecommunications systems; and evaluates the application of new
            communications network technology, including distance learning and
            telemedicine, to rural telecommunications systems.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Advanced Telecommunications Services Staff.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Headed by a staff director, this staff primarily serves the
            Assistant Administrator, Telecommunications Program in the role of
            the Assistant Governor of the RTB. The office performs analyses and
            makes recommendations to the AAT on issues raised by the RTB
            Governor, Board of Directors, or RTB borrowers. This staff maintains
            official records for the RTB Board and prepares minutes of RTB Board
            meetings. The staff director serves as the Assistant Secretary to
            the RTB. The staff performs the calculations necessary to determine
            the cost of money rate to RTB borrowers and recommends and develops
            program- wide procedures for loan and grant programs. The office is
            responsible for the Telecommunications Program&apos;s home page on
            the Internet.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Telecommunications Area Offices.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Headed by area directors, these four offices are responsible for
            administering the Telecommunications, Distance Learning, and
            Telemedicine programs for specific geographic areas, and serving as
            the single point of contact for all program applicants and borrowers
            within their respective areas. The offices provide guidance to
            applicants and borrowers on RUS and RTB loan policies and
            procedures, and make recommendations to the Administrator on
            applications for loans, guarantees, and grants. The offices assure
            that borrower systems and facilities are designed and constructed in
            accordance with the terms of the loan, acceptable engineering
            practices and specifications, and acceptable loan security
            standards.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Office of the Assistant Administrator—Water and Environmental
              Programs.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Headed by the Assistant Administrator, Water and Environmental 
            <PRTPAGE P='15' />
            Programs, this office is responsible to the Administrator for
            directing and coordinating a nationwide Water and Waste Disposal
            Program for RUS as authorized under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              Section 306 of
            </aref>
             the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act, as amended (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='1926' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1926.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 1926
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ). The office oversees administration of RUS policies on making and
            servicing loans and grants for water and waste facilities in rural
            America, and the development of engineering policies, and practices
            related to the construction and operation of community water and
            waste disposal systems. This office is responsible for development
            and coordination of environmental programs with regard to the Water
            and Waste Disposal Program and directs the following two divisions:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_4_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Water Programs Division.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Headed by the division director, this division is responsible for
            administering the Water and Waste Disposal loan and grant making and
            servicing and special authorities activities nationwide. This office
            also makes allocation of loan and grant funds to field offices and
            manages National Office reserves.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_4_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Engineering and Environmental Staff.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Headed by a staff director, this staff is responsible for
            engineering activities at all stages of program implementation,
            including: review of preliminary engineering plans and
            specifications, procurement practices, contract awards, construction
            monitoring, and system operation and maintenance. The staff also
            develops Agency engineering practices, policies, and technical data
            related to the construction and operation of community water and
            waste disposal systems. The staff is responsible for coordinating
            environmental policy and providing technical support in areas such
            as: hazardous waste, debarment and suspension, flood insurance, drug
            free workplace requirements, and computer program software.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15798'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:I:2003:A:2003.23-2003.25
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        2003.23-2003.25
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='2003' sect='23-2003' psec='' tq='N'>
              2003.23-2003
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .25
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15799'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:I:2003:A:2003.26
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        2003.26
      </num>
      <head>
        Functional organization of RBS.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='2003' sect='26' psec='' tq='N'>
              2003.26
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Functional organization of RBS.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              General.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Secretary established RBS pursuant to 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 234 of
            </aref>
             the Department of Agriculture Reorganization Act of 1994 (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='6944' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/6944.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 6944
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Office of the Administrator.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             According to 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR 
              <subref title='7' part='2' sect='48' psec='' tq='N'>
                2.48
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , the Administrator is responsible for managing and administering
            the programs and support functions of RBS to provide assistance to
            disadvantaged communities through grants and loans and technical
            assistance to businesses and communities for rural citizens and
            cooperatives, pursuant to the following authorities: the Rural
            Electrification Act of 1936, as amended (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='940c' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/940c.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 940c
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' sect='950aa' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/950aa.html'>
                950aa
              </subref>
            </aref>
            <E T='03'>
              et seq.
            </E>
            ), the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='1921' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1921.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 1921
              </subref>
            </aref>
            <E T='03'>
              et seq.
            </E>
            ), the Cooperative Marketing Act of 1926 (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='451-457' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/451-457.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 451-457
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ), the Agricultural Marketing Act of 1946 (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='1621-162' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1621-162.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 1621-162
              </subref>
            </aref>
            7), and the Food Security Act of 1985 (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='1932' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1932.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 1932
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ). These grants, loans, and technical assistance improve community
            welfare by enhancing organizational and management skills,
            developing effective economic strategies, and expanding markets for
            a wide range of rural products and services.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Resources Coordination Staff.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Headed by the staff director, this staff is responsible to the
            Administrator for preparing legislative initiatives and
            modifications for program enhancement. The staff monitors
            legislative and regulatory proposals that potentially impact RBS
            functions. The staff serves as liaison on budgetary and financial
            management matters between RBS staff and the Office of the
            Controller, and assists the Administrator in presenting and
            supporting RBS&apos;s budget and program plans. The staff also
            advises the Administrator and RBS officials on management issues and
            policies related to: human resources, labor relations, civil rights,
            EEO, space, equipment, travel, Senior Executive Service and Schedule
            C activities, contracting, automated information systems, and
            accounting. The staff provides analysis and recommendations on the
            effectiveness of administrative and management activities, and
            performs liaison functions between RBS and the Office of the Deputy
            Under Secretary for O&amp;M on a wide variety of administrative
            functions.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Office of the Deputy Administrator, Business Programs.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Headed by the Deputy Administrator, Business Programs, 
            <PRTPAGE P='16' />
            this office is responsible to the Administrator for overseeing and
            coordinating the Business and Industry Guaranteed and Direct Loan
            programs, Intermediary Relending Program loans, Rural Business
            Enterprise grants, Rural Business Opportunity grants, Rural Economic
            Development loan and grant programs, and the Rural Venture Capital
            Demonstration Program. The office participates in policy planning,
            and program development and evaluation. It also directs the
            following three divisions:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Processing Division.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Headed by the division director, this division is responsible for
            developing and maintaining loan processing regulations, and directs
            the processing and approval of guaranteed and direct business and
            industry loans, and the Rural Venture Capital Demonstration Program.
            It provides technical assistance to field employees and borrowers on
            loan processing and develops approval criteria and performance
            standards for loans. The division recommends plans, programs, and
            activities related to business loan programs and provides
            environmental guidance and support.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Servicing Division.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Headed by the division director, this office is responsible for
            developing and maintaining servicing regulations. It directs and
            provides technical assistance to field employees and borrowers on
            servicing business loans and grants. The division reviews large,
            complex, or potentially controversial loan and grant dockets related
            to loan servicing and recommends servicing plans, programs, and
            activities related to business loan and grant programs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Specialty Lenders Division.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Headed by the division director, this office is responsible for
            directing and developing and maintaining regulations concerning the
            processing and approval of Intermediary Relending loans, Rural
            Business Enterprise grants, Rural Business Opportunity grants, and
            Rural Economic Development loan and grant programs. The division
            provides technical assistance to field employees and borrowers on
            loan and grant processing and other activities. It also develops
            approval criteria and performance standards and recommends plans,
            programs, and activities related to business loan and grant
            programs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Office of the Deputy Administrator, Cooperative Services Programs.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Headed by the Deputy Administrator, Cooperative Services Programs,
            this office is responsible to the Administrator for providing
            service to cooperative associations by administering a program of
            research and analysis of economic, social, legal, financial, and
            other related issues concerning cooperatives. The office administers
            programs to assist cooperatives in the organization and management
            of their associations and a program for economic research and
            analysis of the marketing aspects of cooperatives. The division
            administers and monitors activities of the National Sheep Industry
            Improvement Center and the Appropriate Technology Transfer to Rural
            Areas Program, and the Rural Cooperative Development Grant Program.
            The office directs the following three divisions:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Cooperative Marketing Division.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Headed by the division director, this division is responsible for
            participating in the formulation of National policies and procedures
            on cooperative marketing. The division conducts research and
            analysis and gives technical assistance to farmer cooperatives on
            cooperative marketing of certain crops, livestock, aquaculture,
            forestry, poultry, semen, milk, and dairy products to improve their
            market performance and economic position.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Cooperative Development Division.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Headed by the division director, this division is responsible for
            participating in the formulation of National policies and procedures
            on cooperative development. The office conducts evaluations and
            analysis of proposed new cooperatives to develop plans for
            implementing feasible operations, and advises and assists rural
            resident groups and developing cooperatives in implementing sound
            business plans for new cooperatives. It provides research, analysis,
            and technical assistance to rural residents on cooperative
            development initiatives and strategies to improve economic
            conditions through cooperative efforts.
            <PRTPAGE P='17' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Cooperative Resource Management Division.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Headed by the division director, this division is responsible for
            participating in the formulating of National policies and procedures
            on cooperative resource management. The division conducts research
            and analysis and gives technical assistance to cooperatives on their
            overall structure, strategic management and planning, financial
            issues, and operational characteristics to improve their use of
            resources, financial policies, and ability to adapt to market
            conditions. The division conducts research and analysis of policy,
            taxation, Federal laws, State statutes, and common laws that apply
            to cooperative incorporation, structure, and operation to assist
            cooperatives in meeting legal requirements.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Office of the Deputy Administrator, Community Development.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Headed by the Deputy Administrator, Community Development, this
            office is responsible to the Under Secretary, Rural Development, for
            coordinating and overseeing all functions in the Community Outreach
            and Empowerment Program areas. The office assists in providing
            leadership and coordination to National and local rural economic and
            community development efforts. For appropriation and accounting
            purposes, this office is located under RBS. The office directs the
            following two divisions:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_4_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Empowerment Program Division.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Headed by the division director, this division is responsible for
            formulating policies and developing plans, standards, procedures,
            and schedules for accomplishing RBS activities related to “community
            empowerment programs”, including EZ/EC, AmeriCorps, and other
            initiatives. The office develops informational materials and
            provides technical advice and services to support States on
            community empowerment programs. It also generates information about
            rural conditions and strategies and techniques for promoting rural
            economic development for community empowerment programs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_4_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Community Outreach Division.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Headed by the division director, this division is responsible for
            designing and overseeing overall systems and developing resources to
            support State and community level implementation activities for RBS
            programs. The office designs program delivery systems and tools,
            removes impediments to effective community-level action, supports
            field offices with specialized skills, and establishes partnerships
            with National organizations with grass-roots membership to assure
            that programs and initiatives are designed and implemented in a way
            that empowers communities. It develops methods for working with
            rural business intermediaries to assist them in providing technical
            assistance to new, small business, and provides Internet-based
            services to 1890 Land-grant universities, EZ/EC, and AmeriCorps
            volunteers, linking RBS information support to communities with high
            levels of need.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Alternative Agricultural Research and Commercialization
              Corporation.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Headed by a director, this Corporation is responsible for providing
            and monitoring financial assistance for the development and
            commercialization of new nonfood and nonfeed products from
            agricultural and forestry commodities in accordance with 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='5901' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/5901.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 5901
              </subref>
            </aref>
            <E T='03'>
              et seq.
            </E>
             The Corporation acts as a catalyst in forming private and public
            partnerships and promotes new uses of agricultural materials. It
            expands market opportunities for U.S. farmers through development of
            value-added industrial products and promotes environmentally
            friendly products. For budget and accounting purposes, this office
            is assigned to RBS. The director of the Corporation is responsible
            to the Office of the Secretary.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15800'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:I:2003:A:2003.27-2003.50
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        2003.27-2003.50
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='2003' sect='27-2003' psec='' tq='N'>
              2003.27-2003
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .50
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>