<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol6'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:D:636
    </extid>
    <num>
      636
    </num>
    <head>
      WILDLIFE HABITAT INCENTIVE PROGRAM
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='16' sect='3839bb-1' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/3839bb-1.html'>
              16 U.S.C. 3839bb-1
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            75 FR 71338
          </aref>
          , Nov. 23, 2010, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='6376'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:D:636:-:636.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        636.1
      </num>
      <head>
        Applicability.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='636' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              636.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Applicability.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The purpose of the Wildlife Habitat Incentive Program (WHIP) is to
            help participants develop fish and wildlife habitat on private
            agricultural land, nonindustrial private forest land (NIPF), and
            Indian land.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The regulations in this part set forth the requirements for WHIP.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Chief, Natural Resources Conservation Service (NRCS), may
            implement WHIP in any of the 50 States, District of Columbia, Puerto
            Rico, Guam, the Virgin Islands of the United States, American Samoa,
            and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6377'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:D:636:-:636.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        636.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Administration.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='636' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              636.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Administration.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The regulations in this part will be administered under the general
            supervision and direction of the Chief. The funds, facilities, and
            authorities of the Commodity Credit Corporation (CCC) are available
            to NRCS to carry out WHIP. Accordingly, where NRCS is mentioned in
            this part, it also refers to CCC&apos;s funds, facilities, and
            authorities, where applicable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State Conservationist may accept recommendations from the State
            Technical Committee and Tribal Conservation Advisory Council (for
            tribal land) in the implementation of the program and in
            establishing program direction for WHIP in the applicable State or
            tribal land. The State Conservationist has the authority to accept
            or reject the State Technical Committee and the Tribal Conservation
            Advisory Council&apos;s (for tribal land) recommendation; however,
            the State Conservationist will give strong consideration to the
            State Technical Committee and the Tribal Conservation Advisory
            Council&apos;s recommendation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS may enter into agreements with Federal and State agencies,
            Indian tribes, conservation districts, local units of government,
            public and private organizations, and individuals to assist with
            program implementation, including the provision of technical
            assistance. NRCS may make payments pursuant to said agreements for
            program implementation and for other goals consistent with the
            program provided for in this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS will provide the public with notice of opportunities to apply
            for participation in the program.
            <PRTPAGE P='548' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No delegation in this part to lower organizational levels will
            preclude the Chief, or designee, from determining any issues arising
            under this part or from reversing or modifying any determination
            made under this part.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6378'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:D:636:-:636.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        636.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='636' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              636.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The following definitions will apply to this part, and all documents
          issued in accordance with this part, unless specified otherwise:
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Agricultural lands
          </E>
           means cropland, grassland, rangeland, pastureland, and other land
          determined by NRCS to be suitable for fish and wildlife habitat
          development on which agricultural and forest-related products or
          livestock are or have the potential to be produced. Agricultural lands
          may include cropped woodland, wetlands, waterways, streams, incidental
          areas included in the agricultural operation, and other types of land
          used for or have the potential to be used for production.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Applicant
          </E>
           means a person, legal entity, joint operation, or Indian tribe that
          has an interest in agricultural land, NIPF, Indian land, or other
          lands identified in 636.4(c)4, who has requested in writing to
          participate in WHIP.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            At-risk species
          </E>
           means any plant or animal species listed as threatened or endangered;
          proposed or candidate for listing under the Endangered Species Act
          (ESA); a species listed as threatened or endangered under State law or
          tribal law on tribal land; State or tribal land species of
          conservation concern; or other plant or animal species or community,
          as determined by the State Conservationist, with advice from the State
          Technical Committee and Tribal Conservation Advisory Council (for
          tribal land), that has undergone, or likely to undergo, population
          decline and may become imperiled without direct intervention.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Beginning farmer or rancher
          </E>
           means an individual or entity who:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Has not operated a farm or ranch, or who has operated a farm or
            ranch for not more than 10 consecutive years. This requirement
            applies to all members of an entity, who will materially and
            substantially participate in the operation of the farm or ranch.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the case of a cost-share agreement with an individual,
            individually, or with the immediate family, material and substantial
            participation requires that the individual provide substantial
            day-to-day labor and management of the farm or ranch consistent with
            the practices in the county or State where the farm is located.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the case of a cost-share agreement with an entity or joint
            operation, all members must materially and substantially participate
            in the operation of the farm or ranch. Material and substantial
            participation requires that each of the members provide some amount
            of the management, or labor and management necessary for day-to-day
            activities, such that if each of the members did not provide these
            inputs, operation of the farm or ranch would be seriously impaired.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Chief
          </E>
           means the Chief of NRCS or designee.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Conservation activities
          </E>
           means conservation systems, practices, or management measures needed
          to address a resource concern or improve environmental quality through
          the treatment of natural resources, and includes structural,
          vegetative, and management activities, as determined by NRCS.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Conservation district
          </E>
           means any district or unit of State, tribal, or local government
          formed under State, tribal, or territorial law for the express purpose
          of developing and carrying out a local soil and water conservation
          program. Such district or unit of government may be referred to as a
          conservation district, soil conservation district, soil and water
          conservation district, resource conservation district, natural
          resource district, land conservation committee, or similar name.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Conservation practice
          </E>
           means one or more conservation improvements and activities, including
          structural practices, land management practices, vegetative practices,
          forest management, and other improvements that benefit the eligible
          land and achieve program purposes. Approved conservation practices are
          listed in the NRCS Field Office Technical Guide (FOTG).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Cost-share agreement
          </E>
           means a financial assistance document that specifies 
          <PRTPAGE P='549' />
          the rights and obligations of any participant accepted into the
          program. A WHIP cost-share agreement is a binding agreement for the
          transfer of assistance from the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to
          the participant to share in the costs of applying conservation
          activities.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Cost-share payment
          </E>
           means the payments under the WHIP cost-share agreement to develop
          fish and wildlife habitat or accomplish other goals consistent with
          the program provided for in this part.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Designated conservationist
          </E>
           means an NRCS employee whom the State Conservationist has designated
          as responsible for WHIP administration in a specific area.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Field Office Technical Guide
          </E>
           means the official local NRCS source of resource information and
          interpretations of guidelines, criteria, and requirements for planning
          and applying conservation practices and conservation management
          systems. It contains detailed information on the conservation of soil,
          water, air, plant, and animal resources applicable to the local area
          for which it is prepared.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Habitat development
          </E>
           means the conservation activities implemented to establish, improve,
          protect, enhance, or restore the conditions of the land for the
          specific purpose of improving conditions for fish and wildlife.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Historically underserved producer
          </E>
           means an eligible person, joint operation, legal entity, or Indian
          tribe who is a beginning farmer or rancher, socially disadvantaged
          farmer or rancher, limited resource farmer or rancher, or NIPF
          landowner who meets the beginning, socially disadvantaged, or limited
          resource qualifications set forth in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='636' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              636.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Indian land
          </E>
           means:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land held in trust by the United States for individual Indians or
            Indian tribes, or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land, the title to which is held by individual Indians or Indian
            tribes subject to Federal restrictions against alienation or
            encumbrance, or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land which is subject to rights of use, occupancy, and benefit of
            certain Indian tribes, or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land held in fee title by an Indian, Indian family, or Indian
            tribe.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Indian tribe
          </E>
           means any Indian tribe, band, nation, or other organized group or
          community, including any Alaska Native village or regional or village
          corporation as defined in or established pursuant to the Alaska Native
          Claims Settlement Act (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='43' sect='1601' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/43/1601.html'>
              43 U.S.C. 1601
            </subref>
          </aref>
           et seq.) that is eligible for the special programs and services
          provided by the United States to Indians because of their status as
          Indians.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Joint operation
          </E>
           means, as defined in 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR part 
            <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
              1400
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , a general partnership, joint venture, or other similar business
          organization in which the members are jointly and severally liable for
          the obligations of the organization.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Legal entity
          </E>
           means, as defined in 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR part 
            <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
              1400
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , an entity created under Federal or State law that:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Owns land or an agricultural commodity, product, or livestock; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Produces an agricultural commodity, product, or livestock.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Lifespan
          </E>
           means the period of time during which a conservation practice is to
          be operated and maintained for the intended purpose.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Limited resource farmer or rancher
          </E>
           means:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A person with direct or indirect gross farm sales of not more than
            $142,000 in each of the previous 2 years (this is the amount for
            2010, and adjusted for inflation using Prices Paid by Farmer Index
            as compiled by National Agricultural Statistical Service); and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Has a total household income at or below the national poverty level
            for a family of four, or less than 50 percent of county median
            household income in each of the previous 2 years (to be determined
            annually using the Department of Commerce Data).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Liquidated damages
          </E>
           means a sum of money stipulated in the WHIP cost-share agreement that
          the participant agrees to pay NRCS if the participant fails to
          adequately complete the terms of the cost-share agreement. The sum
          represents an estimate of the technical assistance expenses incurred
          to service the agreement, and reflects the difficulties of proof of
          loss and the inconvenience or non-feasibility of otherwise obtaining
          an adequate remedy.
          <PRTPAGE P='550' />
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Livestock
          </E>
           means all animals produced on farms and ranches, as determined by the
          Chief.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Natural Resources Conservation Service
          </E>
           is an agency of USDA, which has the responsibility for administering
          WHIP using the funds, facilities, and authorities of the CCC.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Nonindustrial private forest land
          </E>
           means rural land, as determined by the Secretary, that has existing
          tree cover or is suitable for growing trees and is owned by any
          nonindustrial private individual, group, association, corporation,
          Indian tribe, or other private legal entity that has definitive
          decisionmaking authority over the land.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Operation and maintenance
          </E>
           means work performed by the participant to keep the applied
          conservation activities functioning for the intended purpose during
          the conservation practice lifespan. Operation includes the
          administration, management, and performance of non-maintenance actions
          needed to keep the completed activity functioning as intended.
          Maintenance includes work to prevent deterioration of the practice,
          repairing damage, or replacement of the practice to its original
          condition if one or more components fail.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Operation and maintenance agreement
          </E>
           means the document that, in conjunction with the WHIP plan of
          operations, specifies the operation and maintenance (O&amp;M)
          responsibilities of the participants for conservation activities
          implemented with WHIP assistance.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Participant
          </E>
           means a person, legal entity, joint operation, or Indian tribe that
          is receiving payment or is responsible for implementing the terms and
          conditions of a WHIP cost-share agreement.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Person
          </E>
           means, as defined in 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR part 
            <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
              1400
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , an individual, natural person and does not include a legal entity.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Producer
          </E>
           means, as defined in 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR part 
            <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
              1400
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , a person, legal entity, joint operation, or Indian tribe who has an
          interest in the agricultural operation or who is engaged in
          agricultural production or forestry management.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Resource concern
          </E>
           means a specific natural resource problem that represents a
          significant concern in a State or region, and is likely to be
          addressed successfully through the implementation of the conservation
          activities by participants.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Secretary
          </E>
           means the Secretary of USDA.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Socially disadvantaged farmer or rancher
          </E>
           means a farmer or rancher who has been subjected to racial or ethnic
          prejudices because of their identity as a member of a group without
          regard to their individual qualities. Those groups include African
          Americans, American Indians or Alaskan Natives, Hispanics, and Asians
          or Pacific Islanders.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State Conservationist
          </E>
           means the NRCS employee authorized to implement WHIP and direct and
          supervise NRCS activities in a State, Caribbean Area, or the Pacific
          Islands Area.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State Technical Committee
          </E>
           means a committee established by the Secretary in a State pursuant to
          
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='16' sect='3861' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/3861.html'>
              16 U.S.C. 3861
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Technical assistance
          </E>
           means technical expertise, information, and tools necessary for the
          conservation of natural resources on land active in agricultural,
          forestry, or related uses. The term includes the following:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Technical services provided directly to farmers, ranchers, and
            other eligible entities, such as conservation planning, technical
            consultation, and assistance with design and implementation of
            conservation practices; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Technical infrastructure, including activities, processes, tools,
            and agency functions needed to support delivery of technical
            services, such as technical standards, resource inventories,
            training, data, technology, monitoring, and effects analyses.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Technical service provider
          </E>
           means an individual, entity, Indian tribe, or public agency either:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Certified by NRCS and placed on the approved list to provide
            technical services to participants; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Selected by the Department to assist the Department in the
            implementation of conservation programs covered by this part through
            a procurement contract, contribution agreement, or cooperative
            agreement with the Department.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Tribal Conservation Advisory Council
          </E>
           means a committee established by a State Conservationist to implement
          consultation as defined in General Manual 410 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            Part 
            <subref title='7' part='405' tq='N'>
              405
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
          <PRTPAGE P='551' />
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            WHIP plan of operations
          </E>
           means the document that identifies the location and timing of
          conservation activities that the participant agrees to implement on
          eligible land in order to develop fish and wildlife habitat and
          provide environmental benefits. The WHIP plan of operations is a part
          of the WHIP cost-share agreement.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Wildlife
          </E>
           means non-domesticated birds, fishes, reptiles, amphibians,
          invertebrates, and mammals.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Wildlife habitat
          </E>
           means the aquatic and terrestrial environments required for fish and
          wildlife to complete their life cycles, providing air, food, cover,
          water, and spatial requirements.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6379'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:D:636:-:636.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        636.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Program requirements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='636' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              636.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Program requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To participate in WHIP, an applicant must:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be in compliance with the highly erodible and wetland conservation
            provisions found in 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='12' tq='N'>
                12
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be in compliance with the terms of all other USDA-administered
            conservation program contracts to which the participant is a party;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Develop and agree to comply with a WHIP plan of operations and
            O&amp;M agreement, as described in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='636' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
                636.8
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Enter into a cost-share agreement for the development of fish and
            wildlife habitat as described in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='636' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
                636.9
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provide NRCS with written evidence of ownership or legal control of
            land for the term of the proposed cost-share agreement, including
            the O&amp;M agreement. An exception may be made by the Chief in the
            case of land allotted by the Bureau of Indian Affairs (BIA) or
            Indian land where there is sufficient assurance of control;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Agree to provide all information to NRCS determined to be necessary
            to assess the merits of a proposed project and to monitor cost-share
            agreement compliance;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Agree to grant to NRCS or its representatives access to the land
            for purposes related to application, assessment, monitoring,
            enforcement, verification of certifications, or other actions
            required to implement this part;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provide a list of all members of the legal entity and embedded
            entities along with members&apos; tax identification numbers and
            percentage interest in the entity. Where applicable, American
            Indians, Alaska Natives, and Pacific Islanders may use another
            unique identification number for each individual eligible for
            payment;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             With regard to cost-share agreements with individual Indians or
            Indians represented by the BIA, payments exceeding the payment
            limitation may be made to the tribal participant if a BIA or tribal
            official certifies in writing that no one individual, directly or
            indirectly, will receive more than the payment limitation. The BIA
            or tribal entity must also provide annually, a listing of
            individuals and payments made, by tax identification number or other
            unique identification number, during the previous year for
            calculation of overall payment limitations. The tribal entity must
            also produce, at the request of NRCS, proof of payments made to the
            person or legal entity that incurred costs related to conservation
            activity implementation;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Supply information, as required by NRCS, to determine eligibility
            for the program including, but not limited to, information to verify
            the applicant&apos;s status as a limited resource farmer or rancher
            or beginning farmer or rancher and payment eligibility as
            established by 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
                1400
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , Adjusted Gross Income (AGI);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_11'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (11)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             With regard to any participant that utilizes a unique
            identification number as an alternative to a tax identification
            number, the participant will utilize only that identifier for any
            and all other WHIP cost-share agreements to which the participant is
            a party. Violators will be considered to have provided fraudulent
            representation and are subject to 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='636' sect='13' psec='' tq='N'>
                636.13
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_12'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (12)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Comply with applicable registration and reporting requirements of
            the Federal Funding Accountability and Transparency Act of 2006 (
            <aref target='_blank' title='Pub. L. 109-282' alt='Pub. L. 109-282' href='http://www.gpo.gov/fdsys/pkg/PLAW-109publ282/html/PLAW-109publ282.htm'>
              Pub. L. 109-282
            </aref>
            , as amended) and 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              2 CFR parts 
              <subref title='2' part='25' tq='N'>
                25
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='2' part='170' tq='N'>
                170
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Eligible land includes:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Private agricultural land;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NIPF;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Indian land; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Trust land owned in fee title by a State, including an agency or
            subdivision of a State, when such trust land is held under a
            long-term lease by a person or nongovernmental entity and 
            <PRTPAGE P='552' />
            when the Chief determines that (i) by the nature of the lease, such
            land is tantamount to private agricultural land; (ii) the duration
            of the lease is at least the length of any WHIP agreement; and (iii)
            no funds under the WHIP program are paid to a governmental entity.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Ineligible land.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS will not provide cost-share assistance with respect to land:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Enrolled in a program where fish and wildlife habitat objectives
            have been sufficiently achieved, as determined by NRCS;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             With onsite or offsite conditions which NRCS determines would
            undermine the benefits of the habitat development or otherwise
            reduce its value;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             On which habitat for threatened or endangered species, as defined
            in 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              section 3 of
            </aref>
             the ESA, 
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='16' sect='1532' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/1532.html'>
                16 U.S.C. 1532
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , would be adversely affected; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             That is owned in fee title by an agency of the United States, other
            than:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_4_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Land held in trust for Indian tribes, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_4_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Lands owned in fee title by a State, including an agency or
            subdivision of a State or a unit of government except as provided in
            
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='636' sect='4' psec='#b_4' tq='N'>
                636.4(b)(4)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6380'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:D:636:-:636.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        636.5
      </num>
      <head>
        National priorities.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='636' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              636.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          National priorities.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The following national priorities will be used in WHIP
            implementation:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Promote the restoration of declining or important native fish and
            wildlife habitats;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Protect, restore, develop, or enhance fish and wildlife habitat to
            benefit at-risk species;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Reduce the impacts of invasive species on fish and wildlife
            habitats;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Protect, restore, develop, or enhance declining or important
            aquatic wildlife species&apos; habitats; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Protect, restore, develop, or enhance important migration and other
            movement corridors for wildlife.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS, with advice of other Federal agencies, will undertake
            periodic reviews of the national priorities and the effects of
            program delivery at the State, tribal, and local levels to adapt the
            program to address emerging resource issues. NRCS will:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Use the national priorities to guide the allocation of WHIP funds
            to the State offices;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Use the national priorities in conjunction with State, tribal, and
            local priorities to assist with prioritization and selection of WHIP
            applications; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Periodically review and update the national priorities utilizing
            input from the public, Indian tribes, and affected stakeholders to
            ensure that the program continues to address priority resource
            concerns.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6381'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:D:636:-:636.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        636.6
      </num>
      <head>
        Establishing priority for enrollment in WHIP.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='636' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              636.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Establishing priority for enrollment in WHIP.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS, in consultation with Federal and State agencies, tribal, and
            conservation partners, may identify priorities for enrollment in
            WHIP that will complement the goals and objectives of relevant fish
            and wildlife conservation initiatives at the State, regional, tribal
            land, or national levels. In response to national, tribal, regional,
            or State fish and wildlife habitat concerns, the Chief may focus
            program implementation in any given year to specific geographic
            areas or to address specific habitat development needs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State Conservationist, with recommendations from the State
            Technical Committee and Tribal Conservation Advisory Council (for
            tribal land), may give priority to WHIP projects that will address
            unique habitats or special geographic areas identified in the State.
            Subsequent cost-share agreement offers that would complement
            previous cost-share agreements due to geographic proximity of the
            lands involved or other relationships may receive priority
            consideration for participation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS will evaluate the applications and make enrollment decisions
            based on the fish and wildlife habitat need using some or all of the
            following criteria:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Contribution to resolving an identified habitat concern of
            national, tribal, regional, or State importance including at-risk
            species;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Relationship to any established wildlife or conservation priority
            areas;
            <PRTPAGE P='553' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Duration of benefits to be obtained from the habitat development
            practices;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Self-sustaining nature of the habitat development practices;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Availability of other partnership matching funds or reduced funding
            request by the person applying for participation;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Estimated costs of fish and wildlife habitat development
            activities;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Other factors determined appropriate by NRCS to meet the objectives
            of the program; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Willingness of the applicant to complete all conservation
            improvements during the first 2 years of the WHIP cost-share
            agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6382'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:D:636:-:636.7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        636.7
      </num>
      <head>
        Cost-share payments.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='636' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              636.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Cost-share payments.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS may share the cost with a participant for implementing the
            conservation activities as provided in the WHIP plan of operations
            that is a component of the WHIP cost-share agreement:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as provided in paragraph (a)(2) of this section and in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='636' sect='9' psec='#c' tq='N'>
                636.9(c)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , NRCS will offer to pay no more than 75 percent of the costs to
            develop fish and wildlife habitat. The cost-share payment to a
            participant will be reduced proportionately below 75 percent to the
            extent that direct Federal financial assistance is provided to the
            participant from sources other than NRCS, except for certain cases
            that merit additional cost-share assistance to achieve the intended
            goals of the program, as determined by the State Conservationist.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Historically underserved producers, as defined in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='636' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
                636.3
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , and Indian tribes may receive the applicable payment rate and an
            additional rate that is not less than 25 percent above the
            applicable rate, provided that this increase does not exceed 90
            percent of the estimated costs associated with WHIP plan of
            operations implementation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Cost-share payments may be made only upon a determination by NRCS
            that a conservation activity or an identifiable component of a
            conservation activity has been established in compliance with
            appropriate standards and specifications.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payments will not be made for a conservation activity that was:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Applied prior to application for the program; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Initiated or implemented prior to cost-share agreement approval,
            unless a waiver was granted by the State Conservationist or
            designated conservationist prior to implementation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS, in consultation with the State Technical Committee, will
            identify and provide public notice of the conservation activities
            eligible for payment under the program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Cost-share payments may be made for the establishment and
            installation of additional eligible conservation activities, or the
            maintenance or replacement of an eligible conservation activity, but
            only if NRCS determines the conservation activity is needed to meet
            the objectives of the program, or that the failure of the original
            project was due to reasons beyond the control of the participant.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payments made or attributed to a participant, directly or
            indirectly, may not exceed, in the aggregate, $50,000 per year.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Eligibility for payment in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
                1400
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , subpart G, average AGI limitation, will be determined prior to
            cost-share agreement approval.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subject to fund availability, the payment rates identified in a
            WHIP contract may be adjusted by NRCS to reflect increased costs.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A participant will not be eligible for payments for conservation
            activities on eligible land if the participant receives payments or
            other benefits for the same activity on the same land under any
            other conservation program administered by USDA.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Before NRCS will approve and issue final payment, the participant
            must certify that the conservation activity has been completed in
            accordance with the cost-share agreement, and NRCS or an approved
            Technical Service Provider (TSP) must certify that the activity has
            been carried out in accordance with the applicable FOTG.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS, for a fiscal year, may use up to 25 percent of WHIP funds to
            carry out cost-share agreements described in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='636' sect='9' psec='#c' tq='N'>
                636.9(c)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6383'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:D:636:-:636.8
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        636.8
      </num>
      <head>
        WHIP plan of operations.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='554' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='636' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              636.8
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          WHIP plan of operations.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             As a condition of participation, the participant develops a WHIP
            plan of operations with the assistance of NRCS or other public or
            private natural resource professionals who are approved by NRCS. A
            WHIP plan of operations encompasses the parcel of land where habitat
            will be established, improved, protected, enhanced, or restored. The
            WHIP plan of operations will be approved by NRCS and address at
            least one of the following as determined by NRCS:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Fish and wildlife habitat conditions that are of concern to the
            participant;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Fish and wildlife habitat concerns identified in State, regional,
            tribal land, or national conservation initiatives, as referenced in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='636' sect='6' psec='#a' tq='N'>
                636.6(a)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Fish and wildlife habitat concerns identified in an approved
            area-wide plan that addresses the wildlife resource habitat concern.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The WHIP plan of operations forms the basis for the WHIP cost-share
            agreement and will be attached and included as part of the
            cost-share agreement, along with the O&amp;M agreement. The WHIP
            plan of operations includes a schedule for implementation and
            maintenance of the conservation activities, as determined by NRCS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The WHIP plan of operations may be modified in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='636' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
                636.10
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All conservation activities in the WHIP plan of operations must be
            approved by NRCS and developed and carried out in accordance with
            the applicable FOTG.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The participant is responsible for the implementation of the WHIP
            plan of operations.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6384'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:D:636:-:636.9
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        636.9
      </num>
      <head>
        Cost-share agreements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='636' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
              636.9
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Cost-share agreements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To apply for WHIP cost-share assistance, a person, tribe, or legal
            entity must submit an application for participation at a USDA
            Service Center to an NRCS representative.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A WHIP cost-share agreement will:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Incorporate the WHIP plan of operations;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be for a time period agreed to by the participant and NRCS, with a
            minimum duration of one year after the completion of conservation
            activities identified in the WHIP plan of operations and a maximum
            of 10 years, except for agreements entered into under paragraph (c)
            of this section;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Include all provisions as required by law or statute;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Include any participant reporting and recordkeeping requirements to
            determine compliance with the cost-share agreement and program;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be signed by the participant;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Specify payment limits described in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='636' sect='7' psec='#f' tq='N'>
                636.7(f)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             including any additional payment limitation associated with
            determinations made under 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='636' sect='7' psec='#g' tq='N'>
                636.7(g)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Include an O&amp;M agreement that describes the O&amp;M for each
            conservation activity and the agency expectation that WHIP-funded
            conservation activities will be operated and maintained for their
            expected lifespan; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Include any other provision determined necessary or appropriate by
            the NRCS representative.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notwithstanding any limitation of this part, NRCS may enter into a
            long-term cost-share agreement that:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Is for a term of at least 15 years;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Protects and restores essential plant or animal habitat, as
            determined by NRCS; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provides cost-share payments of no more than 90 percent of the cost
            of implementing the WHIP plan of operations to develop fish and
            wildlife habitat.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6385'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:D:636:-:636.10
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        636.10
      </num>
      <head>
        Modifications.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='636' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
              636.10
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Modifications.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The participant and NRCS may modify a cost-share agreement if both
            parties agree to the modification. The WHIP plan of operations is
            revised in accordance with NRCS requirements, and the agreement is
            approved by the designated conservationist.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any modifications made under this section must meet WHIP program
            objectives and must be in compliance with this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the event implementation of a conservation activity fails
            through no fault of the participant, the State Conservationist may
            modify the cost-share agreement in order to issue payments to
            re-implement the activity, at the rates established in accordance
            with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='636' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
                636.7
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , provided such payments do not exceed the payment limitation
            requirements as set forth in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='636' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
                636.7
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
            <PRTPAGE P='555' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Where circumstances beyond the participant&apos;s control or when
            it is in the public interest, such as matters of health or safety,
            the State Conservationist may independently or by mutual agreement
            with the parties modify or terminate the cost-share agreement as
            provided for in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='636' sect='12' psec='' tq='N'>
                636.12
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6386'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:D:636:-:636.11
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        636.11
      </num>
      <head>
        Transfer of interest in a cost-share agreement.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='636' sect='11' psec='' tq='N'>
              636.11
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Transfer of interest in a cost-share agreement.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A participant is responsible for notifying NRCS when he or she
            anticipates the voluntary or involuntary loss of control of the land
            covered by a WHIP cost-share agreement during the term of the
            agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The participant and NRCS may agree to transfer a cost-share
            agreement to another potential participant. The transferee must be
            determined by NRCS to be eligible to participate in WHIP and must
            assume full responsibility under the cost-share agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             With respect to any and all payments owed to participants who wish
            to transfer ownership or control of land subject to a cost-share
            agreement, the division of payment will be determined by the
            original party and that party&apos;s successor. In the event of a
            dispute or claim on the distribution of cost-share payments, NRCS
            may withhold payments without the accrual of interest pending a
            settlement or adjudication on the rights to the funds.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If new participants are not willing or not eligible to assume the
            responsibilities of an existing WHIP cost-share agreement, including
            the O&amp;M agreement, and the participant fails to implement the
            cost-share agreement, then NRCS will terminate the agreement and may
            require that all cost-share payments be forfeited, refunded, or
            both, with applicable interest in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='636' sect='12' psec='' tq='N'>
                636.12
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . Participants may be subject to liquidated damages in accordance
            with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='636' sect='12' psec='' tq='N'>
                636.12
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6387'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:D:636:-:636.12
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        636.12
      </num>
      <head>
        Termination of cost-share agreements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='636' sect='12' psec='' tq='N'>
              636.12
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Termination of cost-share agreements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State Conservationist may, independently or by mutual agreement
            with the parties to the cost-share agreement, terminate the
            cost-share agreement where:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The parties to the cost-share agreement are unable to comply with
            the terms of the cost-share agreement as the result of conditions
            beyond their control;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Termination of the cost-share agreement would, as determined by the
            State Conservationist, be in the public interest; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A participant fails to correct a violation of a cost-share
            agreement within the period provided by NRCS in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='636' sect='13' psec='' tq='N'>
                636.13
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If NRCS terminates a cost-share agreement, in accordance with the
            provisions of paragraphs (a)(1) and (a)(2) of this section the State
            Conservationist may allow the participant to retain a portion of any
            payments received appropriate to the effort the participant has made
            to comply with the contract.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS may require a participant to provide only a partial refund of
            the payments received if a previously implemented conservation
            activity can function independently, and is not adversely affected
            by the violation or the absence of other conservation activities
            that would have been implemented under the cost-share agreement; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State Conservationist will have the option to waive all or part
            of the liquidated damages assessed, depending upon the circumstances
            of the case.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When making termination decisions, NRCS may reduce the amount of
            money owed by the participant by a proportion that reflects:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The good faith effort of the participant to comply with the
            cost-share agreement; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The existence of hardships beyond the participant&apos;s control
            that have prevented compliance. If a participant claims hardship,
            that claim must be documented and cannot have existed when the
            applicant applied for participation in the program.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6388'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:D:636:-:636.13
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        636.13
      </num>
      <head>
        Violations and remedies.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='636' sect='13' psec='' tq='N'>
              636.13
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Violations and remedies.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If NRCS determines that a participant is in violation of a
            cost-share agreement, NRCS will give the parties to the cost-share
            agreement notice of the violation and a minimum of 60 days to
            correct the violation and comply with the terms of the cost-share
            agreement and attachments thereto.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the participant fails to correct the violation of a cost-share
            agreement 
            <PRTPAGE P='556' />
            within the period provided by NRCS under paragraph (a) of this
            section, NRCS may terminate the agreement and require the
            participant to refund all or part of any of the funds issued under
            that cost-share agreement, plus interest, and may assess liquidated
            damages as indicated in the cost-share agreement appendix, as well
            as require the participant to forfeit all rights to any future
            payment under the agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If NRCS terminates a cost-share agreement due to breach of
            contract, the participant will forfeit all rights to future payments
            under the agreement, may be required to pay liquidated damages in an
            amount determined by the State Conservationist in accordance with
            the terms of the agreement, and will refund all or part of the
            payments received, plus interest. Participants violating WHIP
            cost-share agreements may be determined ineligible for future
            NRCS-administered conservation program funding.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6389'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:D:636:-:636.14
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        636.14
      </num>
      <head>
        Misrepresentation and scheme or device.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='636' sect='14' psec='' tq='N'>
              636.14
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Misrepresentation and scheme or device.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A participant who is determined to have erroneously represented any
            fact affecting a program determination made in accordance with this
            part, will not be entitled to cost-share agreement payments and must
            refund to NRCS all payments and pay liquidated damages, plus
            interest, as determined by NRCS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A participant will refund to NRCS all payments, plus interest, as
            determined by NRCS, with respect to all NRCS cost-share agreements
            to which they are a party if they are determined to have knowingly:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Adopted any scheme or device that tends to defeat the purpose of
            the program;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Made any fraudulent representation; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Misrepresented any fact affecting a program determination.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Other NRCS cost-share agreements where this person is a participant
            may be terminated.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6390'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:D:636:-:636.15
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        636.15
      </num>
      <head>
        Offsets and assignments.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='636' sect='15' psec='' tq='N'>
              636.15
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Offsets and assignments.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as provided in paragraph (b) of this section, any payment or
            portion thereof to any person or legal entity will be made without
            regard to questions of title under State law and without regard to
            any claim or lien against the land, or proceeds thereof, in favor of
            the owner or any other creditor except agencies of the United States
            Government. The regulations governing offsets and withholdings found
            at 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1403' tq='N'>
                1403 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
             will be applicable to cost-share agreement payments.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             WHIP participants may assign any payments in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1404' tq='N'>
                1404
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6391'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:D:636:-:636.16
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        636.16
      </num>
      <head>
        Appeals.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='636' sect='16' psec='' tq='N'>
              636.16
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Appeals.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any participant may obtain reconsideration and review of
            determinations affecting participation in this program in accordance
            with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR parts 
              <subref title='7' part='11' tq='N'>
                11
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='614' tq='N'>
                614
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , except as provided in paragraph (b) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In accordance with the provisions of the Department of Agriculture
            Reorganization Act of 1994, 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             (
            <aref type='USC'>
              <subref title='7' sect='6901' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/6901.html'>
                7 U.S.C. 6901
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ), the following decisions are not appealable:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payment rates, payment limits, and cost-share percentages;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The designation of approved fish and wildlife priority areas,
            habitats, or activities;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS program funding decisions;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Eligible conservation activities; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Other matters of general applicability.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Before a participant may seek judicial review of any action taken
            under this part, the participant must exhaust all administrative
            appeal procedures set forth in paragraph (a) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6392'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:D:636:-:636.17
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        636.17
      </num>
      <head>
        Compliance with regulatory measures.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='636' sect='17' psec='' tq='N'>
              636.17
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Compliance with regulatory measures.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Participants who implement the WHIP plan of operations will be
            responsible for obtaining the authorities, rights, easements,
            permits, or other approvals necessary for the implementation,
            operation, and maintenance of the conservation activities in keeping
            with applicable laws and regulations. The requirement for the
            participant to obtain necessary permits is included in the terms and
            conditions of the contract appendix.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Participants will be responsible for compliance with all laws and
            for all 
            <PRTPAGE P='557' />
            effects or actions resulting from the participants&apos; performance
            under the cost-share agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6393'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:D:636:-:636.18
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        636.18
      </num>
      <head>
        Technical services provided by qualified personnel not affiliated with
        USDA.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='636' sect='18' psec='' tq='N'>
              636.18
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Technical services provided by qualified personnel not affiliated with
          USDA.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS may use the services of qualified TSPs in performing its
            responsibilities for technical assistance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Participants may use technical services from qualified personnel of
            other Federal, State, and local agencies, Indian tribes, or
            individuals who are certified as TSPs by NRCS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Technical services provided by qualified personnel not affiliated
            with USDA may include, but are not limited to, conservation
            planning; conservation practice survey, layout, design,
            installation, and certification; and related technical services as
            defined in 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='652' tq='N'>
                652
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS retains approval authority over certification of work done by
            non-NRCS personnel for the purpose of approving WHIP payments.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6394'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:D:636:-:636.19
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        636.19
      </num>
      <head>
        Access to operating unit.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='636' sect='19' psec='' tq='N'>
              636.19
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Access to operating unit.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          As a condition of program participation, any authorized NRCS
          representative will have the right to enter an agricultural operation
          or tract for the purposes of determining eligibility and for
          ascertaining the accuracy of any representations related to cost-share
          agreements and performance. Access will include the right to provide
          technical assistance; determine eligibility; inspect any work
          undertaken under the cost-share agreements, including the WHIP plan of
          operations and O&amp;M agreement; and collect information necessary to
          evaluate the habitat development performance specified in the
          cost-share agreements. The NRCS representative will make a reasonable
          effort to contact the participant prior to the exercising of this
          provision.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6395'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:D:636:-:636.20
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        636.20
      </num>
      <head>
        Equitable relief.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='636' sect='20' psec='' tq='N'>
              636.20
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Equitable relief.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a participant relied upon the advice or action of any authorized
            NRCS representative and did not know, or have reason to know, that
            the advice or action was improper or erroneous, NRCS may grant
            relief in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='635' tq='N'>
                635
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . Where a participant believes that detrimental reliance on the
            advice or action of a NRCS representative resulted in an
            ineligibility or program violation, the participant may request
            equitable relief under 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR 
              <subref title='7' part='635' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
                635.3
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . The financial or technical liability for any action by a
            participant that was taken based on the advice of a NRCS certified
            non-USDA TSP is the responsibility of the certified TSP and will not
            be assumed by NRCS when NRCS authorizes payment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If during the term of a WHIP cost-share agreement a participant has
            been found in violation of a provision of the cost-share agreement,
            the O&amp;M agreement, or any document incorporated by reference
            through failure to fully comply with that provision, the participant
            may be eligible for equitable relief under 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR 
              <subref title='7' part='635' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
                635.4
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='6396'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:VI:D:636:-:636.21
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        636.21
      </num>
      <head>
        Environmental services credits for conservation improvements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='636' sect='21' psec='' tq='N'>
              636.21
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Environmental services credits for conservation improvements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          USDA recognizes that environmental benefits will be achieved by
          implementing conservation activities funded through WHIP, and that
          environmental credits may be gained as a result of implementing
          activities compatible with the purposes of a WHIP cost-share
          agreement. NRCS asserts no direct or indirect interest on any such
          credits. However, NRCS retains the authority to ensure that program
          purposes are met and the requirements for WHIP funded improvements are
          met and maintained consistent with 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='636' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              636.8
            </subref>
             and 
            <subref title='7' part='636' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
              636.9
            </subref>
          </aref>
          . Where activities required under an environmental credit agreement
          may affect land covered under a WHIP cost-share agreement,
          participants are highly encouraged to request a compatibility
          assessment from NRCS prior to entering into such agreements. The WHIP
          cost-share agreement may be modified, in accordance with policies
          outlined in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='636' sect='10' psec='' tq='N'>
              636.10
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , provided the modification meets WHIP purposes and is in compliance
          with this part.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>