<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol10'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:A:1402
    </extid>
    <num>
      1402
    </num>
    <head>
      POLICY FOR CERTAIN COMMODITIES AVAILABLE FOR SALE
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='7285' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/7285.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 7285
            </subref>
            , 
            <subref title='7' sect='15' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/15.html'>
              15
            </subref>
          </aref>
           U.S.C. 714b and 714c.
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            71 FR 40642
          </aref>
          , July 18, 2006, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='12224'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:A:1402:-:1402.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1402.1
      </num>
      <head>
        General.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1402' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              1402.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          To facilitate trade through usual and customary channels, facilities,
          and arrangements of trade and commerce, the Commodity Credit
          Corporation (CCC) will disseminate general sales offering information
          on the Farm Service Agency&apos;s (FSA) Commodity Operations Web site
          located on the Worldwide Web at 
          <E T='03'>
            http://www.fsa.usda.gov/daco/default.htm.
          </E>
           The Web site will be reviewed and amended as necessary to reflect
          current general sales offering information. CCC will make regular
          amendments as necessary deleting or adding to the sales provisions or
          changing prices or methods of sales. The information posted at this
          Web site is for the purpose of public information and does not
          constitute an offer to sell by CCC or an invitation for offers to
          purchase from CCC. CCC may make its commodities available for sale
          without prior notification to storing warehouse operators. Information
          pertaining to opportunities to purchase commodities from CCC 
          <PRTPAGE P='441' />
          will be published on the FSA Commodity Operations Web site when such
          opportunities are available.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12225'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:A:1402:-:1402.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1402.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Sales of inventory.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1402' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              1402.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Sales of inventory.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          CCC will entertain offers from prospective buyers for the purchase of
          any commodities owned by CCC, including those commodities that are
          marketed through commercial, Internet-based marketing services.
          Various commodities owned by CCC may be offered for sale through
          commercial, Internet-based marketing services. Interested parties may
          submit requests for information related to Internet-based commodity
          sales to the Director, Warehouse and Inventory Division, Stop 0553,
          1400 Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC 20250-9860.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12226'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:A:1402:-:1402.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1402.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Submission of offers, terms, and conditions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1402' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              1402.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Submission of offers, terms, and conditions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Offers accepted by CCC will be subject to terms and conditions
          prescribed by CCC. These terms include, among other things, payment by
          wire transfer of funds, certified check or cashiers check before
          delivery of the commodity, removal of the commodity from CCC storage
          within a reasonable period of time, and in sales that require a
          commodity to be used for only a specific purpose, documentation that
          use of the commodity was for only that purpose.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12227'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:A:1402:-:1402.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1402.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Information availability.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1402' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              1402.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Information availability.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The terms and conditions of sale with respect to commodities that are
          not sold through Internet-based marketing service are available
          online. Requests for terms and conditions may be addressed to the
          Director, Warehouse and Inventory Division, Stop 0553, 1400
          Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC 20250-9860.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12228'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:A:1402:-:1402.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1402.5
      </num>
      <head>
        Late payments.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1402' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              1402.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Late payments.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          If payment is not received by CCC within the period specified in the
          sales contract, interest will be assessed by CCC. If a buyer fails to
          make arrangements for payment according to the provisions of the
          contract, CCC retains the right to terminate the sales contract. If
          CCC terminates the sales contract for default in whole or in part, CCC
          may offer the commodity for sale and the original party will be liable
          to CCC for any losses incurred and damages sustained as a result of
          the party&apos;s failure to timely remit payment for the commodity.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>