<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol13'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1948
    </extid>
    <num>
      1948
    </num>
    <head>
      RURAL DEVELOPMENT
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='5' sect='301' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/5/301.html'>
              5 U.S.C. 301
            </subref>
            , 
            <subref title='5' sect='7' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/5/7.html'>
              7
            </subref>
          </aref>
           U.S.C. 1932 note.
        </P>
      </AUTH>
    </text>
    <section orderid='15295'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1948:B:1948.51
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1948.51
      </num>
      <head>
        General.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          44 FR 35984
        </aref>
        , June 19, 1979, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          58 FR 228
        </aref>
        , Jan. 5, 1993]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1948' sect='51' psec='' tq='N'>
              1948.51
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          This subpart sets forth policies and procedures for designation,
          approval of designation, and making grants for assistance to areas
          impacted by increased coal and uranium production, processing, or
          transportation. The Farmers Home Administration (FmHA) or its
          successor agency under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
           will fully consider all A-95 clearing-house review comments and
          recommendations in selecting applications for funding. Any processing
          or servicing activity conducted pursuant to this subpart involving
          authorized assistance to FmHA or its successor agency under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
           employees, members of their families, known close relatives, or
          business or close personal associates, is subject to the provisions of
          subpart D of 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='1900' tq='N'>
              1900 of this chapter
            </subref>
          </aref>
          . Applicants for this assistance are required to identify any known
          relationship or association with an FmHA or its successor agency under
          
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
           employee.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            44 FR 35984
          </aref>
          , June 19, 1979, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            58 FR 228
          </aref>
          , Jan. 5, 1993]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15296'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1948:B:1948.52
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1948.52
      </num>
      <head>
        Objectives.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='308' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1948' sect='52' psec='' tq='N'>
              1948.52
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Objectives.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The objective of the program is to help areas impacted by coal or
          uranium development activities by providing assistance for the
          development of growth management and housing plans and in developing
          and acquiring sites for housing and public facilities and services.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15297'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1948:B:1948.53
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1948.53
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          44 FR 35984
        </aref>
        , June 19, 1979, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          45 FR 26943
        </aref>
        , Apr. 22, 1980; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          46 FR 33021
        </aref>
        , June 26, 1981]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1948' sect='53' psec='' tq='N'>
              1948.53
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Approved designated area.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A group of counties, a county, or a part of a county designated as
            an energy impacted area by the Governor of a State and approved by
            the Secretary of Energy.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Available financial resources.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All existing financial resources which could be used for impact
            assistance including Federal, State, and local financial resources
            and financial resources accruing to States and local governments as
            a result of coal or uranium development activity and not already
            committed to other programs by low or historical precedent.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Coal.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Coal means anthracite and bituminous coal, lignite, and any fuel
            derivative thereof.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Coal or uranium development activities.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The production, processing, or transportation of coal or uranium.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Production includes the mining of coal or uranium and all mine site
            operations connected with such mining operations and processing
            activities. This includes construction activities on mine sites
            relating to mining, production, and processing.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Processing includes all operations performed on coal or uranium
            including construction of processing plants. However, processing
            does not include conversion into electrical energy.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Transportation which directly relates to the production and
            processing of coal or uranium including transportation networks in
            the county of origin of the coal or uranium and counties of
            processing of coal and uranium. This includes transportation depots
            along transportation networks that are used primarily for the
            transfer of coal or uranium for domestic consumption. This also
            includes unit train rolling stock construction and repair
            facilities.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Condemnation by U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA).
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The use of Federal authority by the Secretary of Agriculture to
            condemn real property.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Council of local governments.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An areawide development organization which includes one or more
            local governments servicing at least a portion of an approved
            designated area. Such organization must either have a policymaking
            body made up of a majority of local elected officials.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Eligible employment.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Full time work related to coal or uranium development activities.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Eligible employment facility.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A coal or uranium mine, processing plant, or transportation depot.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Energy impacted areas.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An area where coal and uranium development activities have a
            significant impact on the socio-economic structure of the area and
            which meet the criteria set out at 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              § 1948.68 of
            </aref>
             this subpart.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Fair market value.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The price at which a property will sell in the open market allowing
            a reasonable period of time for typical, fully-informed buyers and
            sellers to react, assuming that the purchaser and seller are both
            willing participants in the transaction.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Grantee.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An entity with whom FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             has entered into a grant agreement under this program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='l'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (l)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Growth management planning.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Planning for the orderly development of an approved designated
            area. This planning includes, but is not limited to: Planning for
            provision of resources to support housing, public facility needs,
            sewer and water needs; planning for the provision of additional
            public services needed; overall plans for the coordinated
            development of all approved designated areas within a State; the
            development of State Investment Strategies for Energy Impacted
            Areas; and coordination of development of approved designated areas
            at the interstate level where impact is interstate in nature.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='m'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (m)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Housing planning.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Identification of present and future housing needs within an
            approved designated area and providing methods for developing needed
            housing. This planning includes, but is not limited to the
            identification of: 
            <PRTPAGE P='309' />
            housing sites; housing site development needs; data and resource
            needs; funding needs; acquisition methods; and agencies of
            government responsible for delivery of housing services.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='n'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (n)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Industry reports.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Those reports concerning production, expected production, and
            employment within an approved designated area which are requested by
            the Governor and submitted by a person to the Secretary of Energy.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='o'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (o)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Local government.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any county, parish, city, town, township, village, or other general
            purpose political subdivision of a State with the power to levy
            taxes and expend Federal, State, and local funds and exercise
            governmental powers and which is located in, or has authority over,
            the energy impact area. With the concurrence of the Governor, the
            term may also include such school, water, sewer, highway, or other
            public special purpose districts or authorities, or public or
            private nonprofit corporations as may be appropriate to carry out
            the purpose for which a grant is being made. These corporations or
            special purpose districts or authorities may apply (including
            applications previously received) for grants from fiscal year 1981
            and earlier fiscal year funds only.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='p'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (p)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Person.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any corporation, individual, partnership, company, association,
            firm, institution, society, trust, joint venture, or joint stock
            company, any State or any agency or instrumentality thereof.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='q'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (q)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Public facilities.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Installations open to the public and used for the public welfare.
            This includes but is not limited to: hospitals, clinics, firehouses,
            parks, recreation areas, sewer plants, water plants, community
            centers, libraries, city or town halls, jailhouses, courthouses, and
            schoolhouses.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='r'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (r)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Public services.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The provision to the public of services such as: health care, fire
            and police protection, recreation, etc.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='s'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (s)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Site.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A site is a plot of land which is suitable or can be made suitable
            for providing housing, public facilities, or services.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='t'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (t)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Site acquisition.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Obtaining legal title to a site (or sites) or obtaining leaseholds
            or other interests in land, by an instrumentality of a state or
            local Government, or by FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
            , for housing, public facilities, or services.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='u'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (u)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Site development.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Site restoration, necessary off-site improvements and such on-site
            improvements as the construction of sewerage collection and water
            distribution lines (does not include individual taps) and
            construction of access roads; but does not include the construction
            of houses or public facilities.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Site restoration.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             On-site improvements to the real property (such as backfilling,
            compacting, grading and leveling) necessary for the construction of
            houses and public facilities.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='w'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (w)
            </enum>
            <head>
              State.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any of the fifty States, Puerto Rico, and any territory or
            possession of the United States.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='x'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (x)
            </enum>
            <head>
              State Investment Strategy for Energy Impacted Areas.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The investment strategy for the development of approved designated
            areas within a State as proposed by the Governor and approved by
            FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='y'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (y)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Substandard housing.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All housing units which do not have complete plumbing fixtures,
            lack adequate heating systems, are not structurally sound, or
            contain any other conditions that would cause a safety, sanitary, or
            health hazard to the family or community.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            44 FR 35984
          </aref>
          , June 19, 1979, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            45 FR 26943
          </aref>
          , Apr. 22, 1980; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            46 FR 33021
          </aref>
          , June 26, 1981]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15298'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1948:B:1948.54
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1948.54
      </num>
      <head>
        Eligible applicants.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          46 FR 33022
        </aref>
        , June 26, 1981]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1948' sect='54' psec='' tq='N'>
              1948.54
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Eligible applicants.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Organizations eligible for grants include local governments, councils
          of local government, and State governments that have the leval
          authority necessary to undertake the proposed project.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            46 FR 33022
          </aref>
          , June 26, 1981]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15299'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1948:B:1948.55
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1948.55
      </num>
      <head>
        Source of funds.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1948' sect='55' psec='' tq='N'>
              1948.55
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Source of funds.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Grants will be awarded from appropriate funds specifically
            allocated for this program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Grants made for growth management and housing planning may equal
            but will not exceed 10 percent of the total amount of funds
            appropriated for and allocated to this program.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15300'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1948:B:1948.56
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1948.56
      </num>
      <head>
        Program purposes.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='310' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1948' sect='56' psec='' tq='N'>
              1948.56
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Program purposes.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             will make grants for assistance to approved designated areas in
            accordance with criteria contained in this subpart by providing
            assistance to fill gaps in growth management and housing planning,
            and to provide supplementary support for acquisition and development
            of sites for housing and public facilities and services by States,
            local governments, and councils of local government.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Efforts will be made to provide comprehensive assistance to
            approved designated areas through the coordination power of the
            Secretary of Agriculture by utilizing existing plans, State and
            local programs, and other Federal programs to the maximum extent
            possible. Particular attention will be given to the utilization of
            existing FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             authorities under other FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             programs in conjunction with this subpart for providing assistance
            to approved designated areas in accordance with the Governor&apos;s
            approved State Investment Strategy for Energy Impacted Areas.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Where existing plans are unsuitable or nonexistent, and other
            assistance programs are inadequate or unavailable on a timely basis,
            FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             will provide assistance under this subpart to States, councils of
            local governments, and local governments for the modification,
            updating, and/or development of growth management and/or housing
            plans to deal with problems resulting from coal or uranium
            development within approved designated areas according to the
            criteria contained in this subpart.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Where needed, FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             will provide assistance for the development of sites and/or the
            acquisition of sites for housing and public facilities and services
            within approved designated areas according to the criteria contained
            in this subpart. Such assistance for site development and
            acquisition will be made in accordance with FmHA or its successor
            agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             approved plans and State Investment Strategies for Energy Impacted
            Areas in accordance with the criteria contained in the subpart.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             At the request of the Governor of the appropriate State, FmHA or
            its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             will take action to acquire real property directly for sites for
            housing and/or public facilities and services in accordance with
            procedures set forth in this subpart.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             At the request of the Governor of the appropriate State, where
            neither the State nor local government has power to do so for this
            purpose, FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             may take action through condemnation to acquire real property for
            sites necessary for housing, public facilities, or services.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15301'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1948:B:1948.57
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1948.57
      </num>
      <head>
        Eligible activities.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1948' sect='57' psec='' tq='N'>
              1948.57
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Eligible activities.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Grant Funds may be used for:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The preparation of growth management and/or housing plans (or
            aspects thereof) for which financial resources are not available for
            approved designated areas as set forth in the grant agreement,
            including but limited to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             One hundred percent of the total cost of developing growth
            management and/or housing plans.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             One hundred percent of the cost of developing aspects of growth
            management plans and/or housing plans including but not limited to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Sewer plans;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Water plans;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Recreation plans;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Transportation plans;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Education plans; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_2_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subdivision plans.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payment of salaries of professional, technical, and clerical staff
            to carry out growth management and housing planning and evaluation;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payment of necessary reasonable office expenses such as office
            rental, office utilities, and office equipment rental;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Purchase of office supplies;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payment of necessary reasonable administrative posts, such as
            workmen&apos;s compensation, liability insurance, and
            employer&apos;s share of social security and travel; and
            <PRTPAGE P='311' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payment of costs to undertake tests, make appraisals, and arrange
            for engineering/architectural services necessary for the planning
            activity.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Up to 75 percent of the actual cost of developing or acquiring
            sites for housing, public facilities, or services for which
            financial resources are otherwise not available as set forth in the
            grant agreement, including but not limited to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Necessary grading and leveling;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Sewer and water connections;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Necessary water and sewer lines to housing and public facilities
            sites;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Access roads to housing and public facilities sites;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Restoring previously mined sites;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Necessary engineering reports in connection with site development;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payment of costs to undertake tests, make appraisals, and
            engineering/architectural services necessary for the site
            development and/or site acquisition;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Necessary legal fees involved in the transfer of the real property.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15302'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1948:B:1948.58
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1948.58
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1948' sect='58' psec='' tq='N'>
              1948.58
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15303'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1948:B:1948.59
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1948.59
      </num>
      <head>
        Ineligible activities.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1948' sect='59' psec='' tq='N'>
              1948.59
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Ineligible activities.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Growth management and housing planning grant funds may not be used
            for:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Acquisition, construction, repair, or rehabilitation of existing
            housing and public facilities;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Replacement of, or substitution for, any financial support
            previously provided or assured from any other source which would
            result in a reduction of current efforts on the part of the
            applicant;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Duplication of current services;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Routine administrative activities not allowed under Federal
            Management Circular FMC 74-4, “Cost Principles Applicable to Grants
            and Contracts with State and Local Governments;”
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Planning for areas other than approved designated areas;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Planning other than growth management and housing planning; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Political activities.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Grant funds for site development may not be used for:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Construction, repair, or rehabilitation of housing and public
            facilities;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Replacement of, or substitution for, any financial support
            previously provided or assured from any other source which would
            result in a reduction of effort on the part of the applicant;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Administrative expenses not allowed under FMC 74-4;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Purposes for which funding exists under other State or Federal
            programs that may reasonably be obtained on a timely basis by the
            applicants;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Duplication of current services; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Political activities.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15304'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1948:B:1948.60
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1948.60
      </num>
      <head>
        Delegation and redelegation of authority.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1948' sect='60' psec='' tq='N'>
              1948.60
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Delegation and redelegation of authority.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The FmHA or its successor agency under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
           State Director is responsible for implementing the authorities
          contained in this subpart and may issue State supplements redelegating
          these authorities to appropriate FmHA or its successor agency under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
           employees.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15305'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1948:B:1948.61
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1948.61
      </num>
      <head>
        State supplements and guides.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1948' sect='61' psec='' tq='N'>
              1948.61
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          State supplements and guides.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          FmHA or its successor agency under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
           State Directors will obtain National Office clearance for all State
          supplements and guides in accordance with paragraph VIII of FmHA
          Instruction 021.2, (available in any FmHA or its successor agency
          under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
           office).
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              State supplements.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State Directors may supplement this subpart as appropriate to meet
            State and local laws and regulations and to provide for orderly
            application processing and efficient service to applicants. State
            supplements shall not contain any requirements pertaining to
            designations, designation approval, or plan approvals more
            restrictive than those in this subpart.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              State guides.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State Directors may develop guides for use by applicants if the
            guides to this subpart are not adequate. State Directors may prepare
            guides for: items needed for the application; items necessary for
            the docket; and items required prior to grant closing or
            construction starts.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15306'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1948:B:1948.62
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1948.62
      </num>
      <head>
        Environmental impact requirements.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          44 FR 35984
        </aref>
        , June 19, 1979, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          49 FR 3764
        </aref>
        , Jan. 30, 1984]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='312' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1948' sect='62' psec='' tq='N'>
              1948.62
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Environmental impact requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The policies and regulations contained in subpart G of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1940' tq='N'>
                1940 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
             apply to grants made and other actions under this program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Subsequent to an energy impact area designation by the Governor and
            establishment of priorities, the FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             State Director, in consultation with the Governor, shall define the
            geographic boundaries or otherwise delineate the areas which will be
            studied for environmental impacts.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Boundaries shall define the area within which the environmental
            impacts of the proposed action can be reasonably studied. Proper
            delineation of impact areas will avoid duplication of effort by
            using one assessment or impact statement to study a broad area
            rather than numerous overlapping documents prepared for smaller
            projects.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            44 FR 35984
          </aref>
          , June 19, 1979, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            49 FR 3764
          </aref>
          , Jan. 30, 1984]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15307'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1948:B:1948.63
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1948.63
      </num>
      <head>
        Historic preservation requirements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1948' sect='63' psec='' tq='N'>
              1948.63
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Historic preservation requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The policies and regulations contained in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='1901' tq='N'>
              1901
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , subpart F, of this chapter apply to this program.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15308'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1948:B:1948.64
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1948.64
      </num>
      <head>
        Equal opportunity requirements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1948' sect='64' psec='' tq='N'>
              1948.64
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Equal opportunity requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The policies and regulations contained in 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
            part 
            <subref title='7' part='1901' tq='N'>
              1901
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , subpart E, of this chapter apply to grants made under this program.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15309'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1948:B:1948.65
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1948.65
      </num>
      <head>
        Relocation Act requirements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1948' sect='65' psec='' tq='N'>
              1948.65
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Relocation Act requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The policies and regulations contained in title 7, subtitle A, 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            part 21 of
          </aref>
           the Code of Federal Regulations (Uniform Relocation Assistance and
          Real Property Acquisition Policies Act of 1970) will apply to site
          development and acquisition grants and other actions under this
          program.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15310'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1948:B:1948.66
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1948.66
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1948' sect='66' psec='' tq='N'>
              1948.66
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15311'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1948:B:1948.67
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1948.67
      </num>
      <head>
        Procedure for designation.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1948' sect='67' psec='' tq='N'>
              1948.67
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Procedure for designation.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Local governments may request the Governor of the State in which
            they are located to designate an area served by them as an energy
            impacted area.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Governor will define the geographic area of a designated area
            consistent with the nature of the impact and the socio-economic
            integration of the area.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Governor may designate an area as an energy impacted area based
            on the criteria contained in this subpart.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15312'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1948:B:1948.68
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1948.68
      </num>
      <head>
        Criteria for designation.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          44 FR 35984
        </aref>
        , June 19, 1979, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          46 FR 33022
        </aref>
        , June 26, 1981]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1948' sect='68' psec='' tq='N'>
              1948.68
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Criteria for designation.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An area designated by the Governor must have the following
            characteristics:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             During the most recent calendar year, the eligible employment in
            coal or uranium development activities within the area has increased
            by eight percent or more from the preceding year, or such employment
            (as projected by generally acceptable estimates) will increase by
            eight percent (of the eligible employment in the year of the
            designation) or more per year during each of the next three calendar
            years.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Because of increased employment in coal or uranium development
            activities, a shortage of housing, inadequate public facilities, or
            services exists or will exist in the area. Such shortages or
            inadequacies may be demonstrated by: Housing shortage statistics;
            higher occupancy rates of substandard houses than has historically
            occurred within the area; an increase (for which data or projected
            data is available) in eligible employment from the year of the
            designation of at least 100 workers and one-half of one percent of
            the designated area&apos;s population; or data showing that
            available public facilities and services in the area are below
            generally accepted standards due to the increased demand resulting
            from coal and uranium development activities.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Available State and local financial resources are inadequate to
            meet the public need for housing or public facilities and services
            at present or in the next three years. In making this determination
            the Governor should consider the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State revenue increases resulting from coal and uranium development
            activity based on existing tax laws;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Federal funds transferred to the State for impact assistance;
            <PRTPAGE P='313' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Local revenue increases resulting from coal or uranium development
            activities based on existing tax laws;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Other federal financial assistance to which the area may have
            access;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All other available State and local sources of funding;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_vi'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vi)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The time during which the resources will be available;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_vii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (vii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Existing laws committing increases in State and local revenues and
            Federal transfers to purposes other than impact assistance; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_3_viii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (viii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The estimated cost of development based on the best available
            informed judgment.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Designations submitted to the Secretary of Energy for approval must
            have the following attached:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A list of all counties and parts of counties covered by the
            designation;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the area is smaller than a county, a map showing the boundary of
            the area and the approximate location of all eligible employment
            facilities in the area and nearby;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A written justification for the inclusion of an area if the area is
            smaller than a county;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The level of eligible employment within the designated area for
            each of the two most recent calendar years. This data should be
            obtained from a single source for the entire State, if possible;
            special surveys may be used when the Governor determines that these
            more accurately reflect employment conditions within the designated
            area, or in cases where data from other sources for the most recent
            calendar year is unavailable at the time of designation. Reference
            should be made to the data sources used if it is a Federal source;
            if a non-Federal sources is used, a copy of the source and a brief
            description of the procedures used for justification should be
            included. If projections of eligible employment are to be
            considered, projections of such employment for the next three years
            must be attached; identification of data sources and methodology
            used in developing those projections and a copy of any survey data
            used should be included.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In areas where the impacted area covers counties or parts of
            counties located in more than one State, the Governors of the
            affected States may jointly designate such area and submit the
            designation to the Secretary of Energy for approval.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             After examining these factors and determining that the area meets
            the criteria of (a) above, the Governor may so certify in a letter
            bearing his or her signature and submit the letter of certification
            with all data and estimates upon which the designation is based to
            the Secretary of Energy for approval.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each designation submitted should have the name and phone number of
            a contact person in the Governor&apos;s designating office.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An original and one copy of the designation should be submitted to
            the Secretary of Energy, Department of Energy, Mail Stop 8G-031,
            Forrestal Building, Washington, DC 20585.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Two copies of all designations submitted for approval shall be
            submitted to the appropriate FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             State Director. The FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             State Director shall forward one copy to the Office of Area
            Development Assistance in the FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             National Office.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Governor should designate all areas expected to be considered
            in fiscal year 1979 allocations of funds before July 1, 1979.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            44 FR 35984
          </aref>
          , June 19, 1979, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            46 FR 33022
          </aref>
          , June 26, 1981]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15313'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1948:B:1948.69
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1948.69
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1948' sect='69' psec='' tq='N'>
              1948.69
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15314'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1948:B:1948.70
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1948.70
      </num>
      <head>
        Designation approval.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1948' sect='70' psec='' tq='N'>
              1948.70
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Designation approval.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Upon receipt of a request for approval of a designation made under
          this section, the Secretary of Energy shall:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Determine to the best of his ability the consistency of the
            supporting data submitted along with the designation by the
            Governor;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Confer with FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             on approval;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notify the Governor and the Administrator of FmHA or its successor
            agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             of action taken on each designation within 30 calendar days of the
            receipt of a request for approval;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Consult with the Governor before the disapproval of any
            designation; and
            <PRTPAGE P='314' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Publish a description in the 
            <E T='04'>
              Federal Register
            </E>
             of all designated areas approved within 30 days of their approval.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15315'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1948:B:1948.71
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1948.71
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1948' sect='71' psec='' tq='N'>
              1948.71
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15316'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1948:B:1948.72
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1948.72
      </num>
      <head>
        Industry reports.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1948' sect='72' psec='' tq='N'>
              1948.72
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Industry reports.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Any person regularly engaged in any coal or uranium development
          activity within an area designated and approved in accordance with
          this subpart, shall prepare and transmit a report to the Secretary of
          Energy, Department of Energy, Mail Stop 8G-031, Forrestal Building,
          Washington, DC 20585 within 90 days after a written request to such
          person by the Governor of the State in which such area is located.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The report shall contain:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Projected levels of employment in coal or uranium development
            activities within the approved designated area for the next three
            calendar years;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The projected number of new jobs to be created in coal or uranium
            development activities by the person within the approved designated
            area in each of the following three calendar years;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Current or planned actions of the person in relation to the
            provision of housing or public facilities for such person&apos;s
            employees in the next three calendar years;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Contracts in force whereby the person intends to provide funds to
            State government, local governments, and public or private nonprofit
            organizations for the provision of housing or public facilities for
            such person&apos;s employees; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The projected quantity of coal or uranium to be produced,
            processed, or transported by the person in each of the next three
            years.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Governor requesting the report will notify the Secretary of
            Energy of persons from whom reports have been requested.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Secretary of Energy shall provide a copy of these reports to
            the Secretary of Agriculture, the appropriate Governor, and the
            appropriate county or local officials, and make it available for
            public inspection and copying in the public reading room of the
            Department of Energy, Room GA152, Forrestal Building, Washington, DC
            20585.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15317'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1948:B:1948.73-1948.77
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1948.73-1948.77
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1948' sect='73-1948' psec='' tq='N'>
              1948.73-1948
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .77
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15318'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1948:B:1948.78
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1948.78
      </num>
      <head>
        Growth management and housing planning projects.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          44 FR 35984
        </aref>
        , June 19, 1979, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          48 FR 29121
        </aref>
        , June 24, 1983]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1948' sect='78' psec='' tq='N'>
              1948.78
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Growth management and housing planning projects.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Existing plans for growth management and housing may be used to
            meet the planning requirements of this subpart.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A reasonable effort should be made to modify existing plans for use
            in meeting the planning requirements of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Governor shall be responsible for the coordination of planning
            within a State.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The planning process developed with assistance under this section
            should begin at the local level and flow upward to the State.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Planning processes developed with assistance under this section
            should have the maximum possible citizen involvement in the
            development of plans.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Governors should give full consideration to local and substate
            priorities in the development of the State Investment Strategy for
            Energy Impacted Areas.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Plans developed with assistance under this section should be fully
            coordinated with other Federal, State, substate, and local planning
            activities affected by the project.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Planning conducted by the State include effective management
            activities for coordinated development of approved designated areas
            through the plan implementation stage.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            44 FR 35984
          </aref>
          , June 19, 1979, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            48 FR 29121
          </aref>
          , June 24, 1983]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15319'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1948:B:1948.79
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1948.79
      </num>
      <head>
        Application procedure for planning grants.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          44 FR 35984
        </aref>
        , June 19, 1979, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          48 FR 29121
        </aref>
        , June 24, 1983; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          49 FR 3764
        </aref>
        , Jan. 30, 1984; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          55 FR 13503
        </aref>
         and 13504, Apr. 11, 1990; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          76 FR 80731
        </aref>
        , Dec. 27, 2011]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1948' sect='79' psec='' tq='N'>
              1948.79
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Application procedure for planning grants.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Applicants may submit a preapplication for a planning grant upon
            designation of the area as an energy impacted area by the Governor.
            FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             will not take final action on the preapplication until the
            designation has been approved by the Secretary of Energy.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Intergovernmental consultation should be carried out in accordance
            with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3015' tq='N'>
                3015
              </subref>
            </aref>
             subpart V, “Intergovernmental Review of Department of Agriculture
            office.”
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Applicants shall file an original and one copy of SF 424.1,
            “Application 
            <PRTPAGE P='315' />
            for Federal Assistance (For Non-construction),” with the appropriate
            FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             office. A copy should also be filed with the Governor&apos;s office
            of the appropriate State. This form is available in all FmHA or its
            successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             offices. Local governments and councils of local governments shall
            submit preapplications to the appropriate FmHA or its successor
            agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             District Office. State governments shall apply to the appropriate
            FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             State Office. The FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             District Office will forward the preapplication with written
            comments within 10 working days to the appropriate State Office.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All preapplications shall be accompanied by:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Evidence of applicant&apos;s legal existence;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Evidence of applicant&apos;s authority to prepare growth management
            and/or housing plans;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A statement declaring that the planning neither duplicates nor
            conflicts with current activities;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An original and one copy of Forms FmHA 400-1, “Equal Opportunity
            Agreement,” and Form FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             400-4, “Assurance Agreement;” and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A statement regarding other financial resources available to the
            area for this planning.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             District and State FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             Offices receiving preapplications will:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Determine if the area to be covered by this project is an “approved
            designated area” as defined in this subpart;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Comply with the environmental requirements set forth in this
            subpart; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Prepare a Historic Preservation Assessment in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1901' tq='N'>
                1901
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , subpart F, of this chapter.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             District FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             Offices receiving preapplications will also provide written
            comments reflecting planning grant selection criteria listed in this
            subpart.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             District Office will forward the original of the preapplication and
            accompanying documents including those described in paragraphs
            (e)(1) through (e)(3) and (f) of this section to the appropriate
            FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             State Director within 10 working days of receipt of the
            preapplication.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon receipt of a preapplication, the FmHA or its successor agency
            under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             State Office will:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Review and evaluate the preapplication and accompanying documents;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Consult with the Governor of the appropriate State concerning the
            Governor&apos;s priorities and recommended funding level for the
            project; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Respond to the applicant within 30 days of the date of receipt of
            the preapplication using Form AD-622, “Notice of Preapplication
            Review Action,” indicating the action taken on the preapplication.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon notification that the applicant is eligible to compete with
            other applicants for funding, a SF 424.1 may be submitted to the
            FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             State Office by all applicants.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             State Office will send evidence of the applicant&apos;s legal
            existence and authority to the USDA Regional Office of General
            Counsel (OGC) and request that a legal determination be made of the
            applicant&apos;s legal existence and authority to prepare growth
            management and/or housing plans in those cases where an application
            (SF 424.1) is requested.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon receipt of an application on SF 424.1 by the FmHA or its
            successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             State Office, a docket will be prepared which will include the
            following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='k_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Form SF 424.1;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='k_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Form AD-622;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='k_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any comments received in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3015' tq='N'>
                3015
              </subref>
            </aref>
             subpart V, “Intergovernmental Review of Department of Agriculture
            Programs and Activities”. See RD Instruction 1970-I, 
            <PRTPAGE P='316' />
            `Intergovernmental Review,&apos; available in any Agency office or
            on the Agency&apos;s Web site.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='k_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             SF 424.1;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='k_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Evidence of the applicant&apos;s legal existence and authority to
            prepare growth management and/or housing plans;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='k_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             OGC legal determinations;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='k_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Grant agreement and scope of work;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='k_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Form FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             440-1, “Request for Obligation of Funds;”
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='k_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Form FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             400-1;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='k_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Form FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             400-4;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='k_11'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (11)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Historic Preservation Assessment;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='k_12'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (12)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             District, where appropriate, and State FmHA or its successor agency
            under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             written comments, assessments, and analysis of the proposed
            projects in accordance with the grant selection criteria; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='k_13'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (13)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All certificates and statements accompanying the pre-application
            and/or application.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            44 FR 35984
          </aref>
          , June 19, 1979, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            48 FR 29121
          </aref>
          , June 24, 1983; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            49 FR 3764
          </aref>
          , Jan. 30, 1984; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            55 FR 13503
          </aref>
           and 13504, Apr. 11, 1990; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 80731
          </aref>
          , Dec. 27, 2011]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15320'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1948:B:1948.80
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1948.80
      </num>
      <head>
        Planning grant selection criteria.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          44 FR 35984
        </aref>
        , June 19, 1979, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          48 FR 29121
        </aref>
        , June 24, 1983; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          76 FR 80731
        </aref>
        , Dec. 27, 2011]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1948' sect='80' psec='' tq='N'>
              1948.80
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Planning grant selection criteria.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The following criteria will be used in the selection of planning grant
          recipients:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Planning assistance which could be used for the purpose of the
            proposed planning process is not available from other sources on a
            timely basis (Mandatory);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The increase in the number of new employees and the percentage of
            increase in employment in coal and/or uranium development activities
            in the year of designation within the approved designated area
            (years projected will be averaged and treated equally);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The need for planning in relation to the financial resources
            available for such planning;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The planning priorities and recommended funding level of the
            Governor(s) of the appropriate State(s);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The appropriateness of the proposed planning activity for meeting
            the planning needs of the area, including but not limited to the
            building of planning capacity and the local priority for the
            project;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The inadequacy of existing plans for mitigating the effects of coal
            and/or uranium development activities; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The nature of comments and recommendation received in accordance
            with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3015' tq='N'>
                3015
              </subref>
            </aref>
             subpart V, “Intergovernmental Review of Department of Agriculture
            Programs and Activities”. (See RD Instruction 1970-I,
            `Intergovernmental Review,&apos; available in any Agency office or
            on the Agency&apos;s Web site.)
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            44 FR 35984
          </aref>
          , June 19, 1979, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            48 FR 29121
          </aref>
          , June 24, 1983; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 80731
          </aref>
          , Dec. 27, 2011]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15321'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1948:B:1948.81
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1948.81
      </num>
      <head>
        State Investment Strategy for Energy Impacted Areas.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1948' sect='81' psec='' tq='N'>
              1948.81
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          State Investment Strategy for Energy Impacted Areas.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State Investment Strategy for Energy Impacted Areas should be a
            dynamic document updated as each plan or group of plans is submitted
            to FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             for approval.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Governor shall consult with the FmHA or its successor agency
            under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             State Director when developing or updating a State Investment
            Strategy for Energy Impacted Areas.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State Investment Strategy for Energy Impacted Areas will
            include but is not limited to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A list of projects in order of priority;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Governor&apos;s recommended level of and method of funding for
            each project through completion of the project identified in the
            plans submitted and incorporated into the State Investment Strategy
            for Energy Impacted Areas;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Methods of coordinating assistance with other State and Federal
            development programs;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The differential between available financial resources and the cost
            of needed site development and acquisition for housing and public
            facilities and services within the area covered by the State
            Investment Strategy for Energy Impacted Areas;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             References to plan and page number of plan on which each priority
            project is described.
            <PRTPAGE P='317' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State Investment Strategy for Energy Impacted Areas having
            projects expected to be funded in FY 1979 should be submitted to the
            FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             State Director of the appropriate State before July 15, 1979. A
            copy should also be forwarded to the Administrator, FmHA or its
            successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15322'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1948:B:1948.82
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1948.82
      </num>
      <head>
        Plan and State Investment Strategy approval procedure.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1948' sect='82' psec='' tq='N'>
              1948.82
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Plan and State Investment Strategy approval procedure.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any plan submitted for FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             approval, whether it is a plan developed with assistance under this
            section, an existing plan, or a modified plan, should contain:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The present level of coal or uranium production, processing, or
            transportation within the approved designated area covered by the
            plan;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The anticipated level of coal or uranium production, processing, or
            transportation in each of the next three calendar years within the
            area covered by the plan;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A brief description of the socio-economic impacts that have
            occurred during the two most recent calendar years in the approved
            designated area covered by the plan;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A brief description of the socio-economic impacts that are expected
            to occur in the approved designated area covered by the plan within
            each of the next three calendar years;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The anticipated number of new employees expected to be hired in
            coal or uranium development activities in each of the next three
            years within the approved designated area covered by the plan;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Available financial resources and federal programs that may be
            applied to meeting the needs of the approved designated area
            including but not limited to the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_6_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The expected amount of State assistance and State expenditures in
            the approved designated area covered by the plan which will be used
            for impact assistance in the next three years;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_6_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The amount of tax revenues expected to accrue to local governments
            serving the approved designated area covered by the plan in each of
            the next three years due to increased economic activities which have
            occurred since the year prior to designation or are expected to
            occur as a result of coal and uranium development activity;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_6_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Sources and amount of assistance State and local governments are
            now receiving or are expected to receive from persons for the
            provision of housing and public facility and services; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='a_6_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Existing budget surplus at the State and local level.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The specific needs of the area covered by the plan as to the number
            of housing units now needed and the number that are expected to be
            needed in each of the next three years, and/or the number and type
            of public facilities and services now needed or expected to be
            needed in the next three years;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The type and quantity of real property now needed or expected to be
            needed in the next three years for the construction of public
            facilities and/or housing and/or in the provisions of public
            services;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Proposed method of acquisition for each site to be acquired by the
            State or local governments; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An estimate of assistance that will be necessary under this section
            and/or other FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             or Federal programs for the development of the site.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All plans meeting the criteria in paragraph (a) of this section
            should be forwarded to the Governor of the appropriate State or
            States for possible incorporation into the State Investment Strategy
            for Energy Impacted Areas.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Appropriate growth management and/or housing plans received by the
            Governor under this section may be submitted to the appropriate FmHA
            or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             State Office by the Governor.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Governor shall submit a copy of the State Investment Strategy
            for Energy Impacted Areas along with all plans the Governor is
            submitting to FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             for approval.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             During fiscal year 1979 the Governor may submit existing plans to
            FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             for qualified approval in which some sections under 
            <PRTPAGE P='318' />
            paragraph (a) above are incomplete, provided that planning is
            presently being done to fill these gaps, or application for a
            planning grant has been submitted or is to be submitted to cover the
            cost of the needed planning. These plans must be resubmitted for
            final approval on or before December 31, 1980. No requested grant
            will be approved for land acquisition or site development unless the
            request is cited in the FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
            -approved comprehensive growth management plan for the designated
            area in which the project is located.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             State Director shall review all plans and the State Investment
            Strategy for Energy Impacted Areas and provide comments on the
            following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Appropriateness of FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             assistance under this section as called for in the plans;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Appropriateness of FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             assistance under other programs as called for in the plans;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Appropriateness of the State Investment Strategy for Energy
            Impacted Areas;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Other Federal programs which could be used instead of, or in
            addition to, assistance under this section; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Recommended action.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             State Director shall submit all plans received from the Governor,
            the State Investment Strategy Energy Impacted Areas, and any
            comments to the FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             National Office for approval within 10 days of the submission of
            plans and the State Investment Strategies for Energy Impacted Areas
            to the State Director.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             National Office shall review all plans and State Investment
            Strategy for Energy Impacted Areas received and approve or return
            them for modification within 30 days of their receipt in the FmHA or
            its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             National Office.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             National Office shall notify the appropriate State Director of all
            plans that have been approved by the Administrator.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon approval of the plans and State Investment Strategies for
            Energy Impacted Areas by the Administrator, FmHA or its successor
            agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
            , the FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             State Director may exercise the authority of the Secretary of
            Agriculture under 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              Section 603 of
            </aref>
             the Rural Development Act of 1972 to convene a meeting of the
            appropriate representatives of all Federal and State agencies which
            are requested to supply development funds by the State Investment
            Strategy for Energy Impacted Areas for the purpose of obtaining
            tentative funding commitments consistent with their authorities.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             State Office shall notify the Governor and the appropriate District
            Directors of all plans approved by the Administrator, FmHA or its
            successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='l'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (l)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Modifications to approved plans shall be approved by the
            Administrator of FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             following the above procedure.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='m'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (m)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Governor&apos;s modification to the State Investment Strategy
            for Energy Impacted Areas may be approved by the FmHA or its
            successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             State Director provided the modification is consistent with FmHA or
            its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             approved plans.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15323'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1948:B:1948.83
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1948.83
      </num>
      <head>
        Performance of site development work.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1948' sect='83' psec='' tq='N'>
              1948.83
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Performance of site development work.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Site development work will be done in accordance with 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            § 1942.18 of
          </aref>
           FmHA Instruction 1942-A.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15324'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1948:B:1948.84
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1948.84
      </num>
      <head>
        Application procedure for site development and acquisition grants.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          44 FR 35984
        </aref>
        , June 19, 1979, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          46 FR 61991
        </aref>
        , Dec. 21, 1981; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          48 FR 29121
        </aref>
        , June 24, 1983; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          49 FR 3764
        </aref>
        , Jan. 30, 1984; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          55 FR 13503
        </aref>
         and 13504, Apr. 11, 1990; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          67 FR 78329
        </aref>
        , Dec. 24, 2002; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          76 FR 80731
        </aref>
        , Dec. 27, 2011]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1948' sect='84' psec='' tq='N'>
              1948.84
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Application procedure for site development and acquisition grants.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For those projects for which Federal funding is sought in excess of
            $100,000 the applicant shall file SF 
            <PRTPAGE P='319' />
            424.2, “Application for Federal Assistance (For Construction)” with
            the appropriate FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             office. For those projects for which Federal funding is sought for
            less than $100,000, the applicant shall file SF 424.2 with the
            appropriate FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             office. A copy should also be filed with the Governor&apos;s office
            of the appropriate State.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             office receiving a SF 424.2 shall reply to the applicant with-in 45
            calendar days regarding the applicant&apos;s eligibility to compete
            for funding under this program using Form AD-622. (FmHA or its
            successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             District offices will send each preapplication to the FmHA or its
            successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             State Offices for review before replying to the applicant. FmHA or
            its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             District offices will send a copy of Form AD-622 to the FmHA or its
            successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             State Office at the time the AD-622 is sent to the applicant.)
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Intergovernmental consultation should be carried out in accordance
            with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3015' tq='N'>
                3015
              </subref>
            </aref>
             subpart V, “Intergovernmental Review of Department of Agriculture
            Programs and Activities”. (See RD Instruction 1970-I,
            `Intergovernmental Review,&apos; available in any Agency office or
            on the Agency&apos;s Web site.)
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Applicants shall file an original and one copy of SF 424.2, with
            the appropriate FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             office. Local governments and councils of local government shall
            submit applications to the FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             District Office and State governments to the FmHA or its successor
            agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             State Office. Applications shall include:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Evidence of applicant&apos;s legal existence and authority to
            undertake the proposed project;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Evidence of ownership of or lease on a site to be developed or
            “Options to Purchase Real Property,” Form FmHA or its successor
            agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             440-34, (Lease on a site for a public facility will be in
            accordance with FmHA Instruction 1942-A and lease on a site for
            housing will be in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3550' tq='N'>
                3550
              </subref>
            </aref>
            );
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Description of project and relationship to approved growth
            management and housing plan. Applicant must cite pages and section
            of the approved plan;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A plat of the area including elevations;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Preliminary plans and specifications on proposed development which
            will contain an estimate of the projected cost of site development
            prepared by independent qualified appraisers or
            architects/engineers;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The amount of Federal grant needed;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The amount and source of applicant&apos;s financial contribution to
            the project;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An original and one copy of Form FmHA or its successor agency under
            
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             1940-20;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An original and one copy of Forms FmHA or its successor agency
            under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             400-1 and Form FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             400-4;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Evidence that the land is stable if the land has been previously
            mined (include relevant data on soil and analysis);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_11'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (11)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Assurance that the requirements set forth in title 7, subtitle A, 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              part 21 of
            </aref>
             the Code of Federal Regulations (Uniform Relocation Assistance and
            Real Property Acquisition Policies Act of 1970) have been met.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_12'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (12)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Specific concurrence of the Governor if the proposed applicant is
            neither a council of local governments nor a general purpose
            political subdivision of a State;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             District and State FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             Offices receiving applications shall:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Determine if the project is in accordance with a FmHA or its
            successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             approved growth management and/or housing plan covering the
            approved designated area;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Comply with environmental requirements set forth in subpart G of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1940' tq='N'>
                1940 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
            <PRTPAGE P='320' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Prepare a Historic Preservation Assessment in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1901' tq='N'>
                1901
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , subpart F, of this chapter;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Determine site stability if the land has been previously mined; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             District FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             Offices receiving applications shall also provide written comments
            reflecting site development and acquisition grant selection criteria
            (
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1948' sect='86' psec='' tq='N'>
                1948.86
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ) listed in this subpart.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             District Office shall forward the original of the application and
            accompanying documents including those required in paragraph (e) of
            this section to the FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             State Director within 10 working days of receipt of the
            application.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon receipt of an application, the FmHA or its successor agency
            under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             State Office shall:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Review and evaluate the application and accompanying documents;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Determine that the project is a part of and consistent with the
            State Investment Strategy for Energy Impacted Areas;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Send a copy of the applicant&apos;s evidence of legal existence and
            authority to the USDA Regional OGC for review;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If applicant is local government(s), consult with the Governor on
            funding recommendation of the project; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Respond to the applicant within 30 days of the date of receipt of
            the application.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon receipt of an application by the FmHA or its successor agency
            under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             State Office, a docket shall be prepared which shall include the
            following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Application SF 424.2 and enclosures;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any comments received in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='3015' tq='N'>
                3015
              </subref>
            </aref>
             subpart V, “Intergovernmental Review of Department of Agriculture
            Programs and Activities”. (See RD Instruction 1970-I,
            `Intergovernmental Review,&apos; available in any Agency office or
            on the Agency&apos;s Web site.)
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Evidence of ownership or lease of site to be developed;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Evidence of applicant&apos;s legal existence and authority;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             OGC legal determination;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Preliminary plans and specifications concerning the proposed
            development;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Grant agreement and scope of work;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An estimate of projected cost of site development prepared by
            independent qualified appraisers or engineers/architects;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A topographical map of the area;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Form FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             440-1;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_11'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (11)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Form FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             400-1;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_12'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (12)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Form FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             400;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_13'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (13)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Form FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             1940-20, if required by subpart G of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1940' tq='N'>
                1940 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_14'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (14)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A copy of the appropriate FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             environmental review required by subpart G of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1940' tq='N'>
                1940 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_15'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (15)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Historic Preservation Assessment;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_16'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (16)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A copy of the State Investment for Energy Areas; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='i_17'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (17)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             District, where appropriate, and State FmHA or its successor agency
            under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             written comments, assessments and analysis of the proposed project
            in accordance with the grant selection criteria.
          </text>
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            44 FR 35984
          </aref>
          , June 19, 1979, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            46 FR 61991
          </aref>
          , Dec. 21, 1981; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            48 FR 29121
          </aref>
          , June 24, 1983; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            49 FR 3764
          </aref>
          , Jan. 30, 1984; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            55 FR 13503
          </aref>
           and 13504, Apr. 11, 1990; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            67 FR 78329
          </aref>
          , Dec. 24, 2002; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 80731
          </aref>
          , Dec. 27, 2011]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15325'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1948:B:1948.85
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1948.85
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1948' sect='85' psec='' tq='N'>
              1948.85
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15326'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1948:B:1948.86
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1948.86
      </num>
      <head>
        Site development and acquisition grant selection criteria.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1948' sect='86' psec='' tq='N'>
              1948.86
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Site development and acquisition grant selection criteria.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The following criteria will be considered in the selection of site
          development and/or acquisition grant recipients:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Required criteria.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Each project must meet the following criteria:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The area is covered by a FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             approved plan;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             approved plan 
            <PRTPAGE P='321' />
            specifically calls for the site development and/or acquisition;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Other Federal funds that the community could receive for the
            project are inadequate or not available, and no State or local funds
            for site development are available to permit development on a timely
            basis;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The site is to be developed and/or acquired and is to be used for
            housing, public facilities, or services;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The applicant has title to the site, lease on site, or an option on
            the site and funds to purchase the site, or is applying for site
            acquisition funds;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The site will comply with Executive Orders 11988, “Flood Plain
            Management” and 11990, “Protection of Wetlands;”
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An appraisal of the fair market value of the site must have been
            completed;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Priority has been given in the selection of site to unoccupied or
            previously mined land;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Class I or Class II farm land was included in the site only if
            other suitable land was not available;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The land is stable if previously mined; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_11'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (11)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Assurance that the requirements set forth in title 7, subtitle A, 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              part 21 of
            </aref>
             the Code of Federal Regulations (Uniform Relocation Assistance and
            Real Property Acquisition Policies Act of 1970) have been met.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
            <head>
              Competitive criteria.
            </head>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The following criteria will be considered in the selection of
            grantees:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Priority assigned and recommended funding level by the Governor in
            the State Investment Strategy for Energy Impacted Areas;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The increase in the number of new employees and the percentage of
            increase in employment in coal and/or uranium development activities
            in the year of designation within the approved designated area
            (years projected will be averaged and treated equally);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The severity of need for housing, public facilities, services that
            has resulted from coal or uranium development activities in relation
            to available financial resources within the approved designated area
            covered by the plan calling for the project;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Local priority for the project;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The amount of effort by State and local government to meet the
            needs of the area covered by the application as called for in the
            State Investment Strategy for Energy Impacted Areas in relation to
            available financial resources;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An assessment of the environmental impacts of the project; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The nature of comments and recommendations of A-95 clearing-
            house(s).
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15327'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1948:B:1948.87
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1948.87
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1948' sect='87' psec='' tq='N'>
              1948.87
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15328'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1948:B:1948.88
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1948.88
      </num>
      <head>
        Direct land acquisition by FmHA or its successor agency under Public Law
        103-354.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1948' sect='88' psec='' tq='N'>
              1948.88
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Direct land acquisition by FmHA or its successor agency under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
          .
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             may take action to acquire real property directly upon the written
            request of the Governor of the State in which the real property is
            located. FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             will not acquire real property directly under this section without
            such a request.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All requests for direct land acquisition should be submitted to the
            FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             State Director. The following conditions must be met prior to the
            submission of a request for direct acquisition by FmHA or its
            successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
            :
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State or local government serving the area must lack power to
            condemn land of this type for this purpose and must supply an
            opinion by the State Attorney General that this authority is
            lacking;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The real property is to be used as a site for needed housing,
            public facilities, or services;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The site acquisition is called for in a FmHA or its successor
            agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             approved plan;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The site is specifically identified by a FmHA or its successor
            agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             approved plan;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State and local governments have been unable to obtain the real
            property for a price which does not substantially exceed its fair
            market value; and suitable alternate sites are not available;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The land is not Indian Trust land;
            <PRTPAGE P='322' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The land is not U.S. Forest Service land; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             There is legal authority to undertake the proposed project.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             may acquire Federal real property not prohibited in paragraphs (b)
            (6) and (7) of this section for purposes contained in this subpart.
            Farm land (Class I and II) will not be considered unless there is no
            other suitable land available.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the State Director determines that no other suitable real
            property exists that can be obtained at a price which does not
            substantially exceed its fair market value, and if the appropriate
            State or local government lacks condemnation authority as evidenced
            by opinion from the Attorney General, and there is authority to
            undertake the proposed project, then the State Director shall follow
            the procedures set out in title 7, subtitle A, 
            <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
              part 21 of
            </aref>
             the Code of Federal Regulations (Uniform Relocation Assistance and
            Real Property Acquisition Policies Act of 1970) and immediately open
            negotiations to directly acquire the real property through purchase
            or trade.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             State Director may acquire real property by purchase to trade for
            other real property when FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             has been requested to acquire real property by the Governor of the
            State in which the real property is located.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Governor shall submit, with this request, a commitment from the
            State to acquire real property, together with a plan of compensation
            to FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             and evidence of the State&apos;s legal authority to enter into this
            agreement with FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             to accept the real property and repay FmHA or its successor agency
            under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             for the fair market value of the real property for the intended
            purpose.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Real property acquired by FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             shall be transferred to the State requesting by a quitclaim deed
            for a price equal to the fair market value in accordance with the
            terms of a transfer agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             After obtaining title to the real property and prior to transfer to
            the State, the property shall be managed by FmHA or its successor
            agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1955' tq='N'>
                1955
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , subpart B of this chapter.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State Director shall inform the Governor that FmHA or its
            successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             real property acquisition is not likely to occur by purchase or
            trade if negotiations have failed to produce acceptable results
            within 90 days of the request for FmHA or its successor agency under
            
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             acquisition of real property.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15329'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1948:B:1948.89
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1948.89
      </num>
      <head>
        Land condemnation by FmHA or its successor agency under Public Law
        103-354.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1948' sect='89' psec='' tq='N'>
              1948.89
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Land condemnation by FmHA or its successor agency under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
          .
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             attempts to acquire real property at the request of a Governor
            through purchase or trade and is unable to do so, FmHA or its
            successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             may take action to condemn the real property by the following
            procedures:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A request for condemnation shall be submitted by the FmHA or its
            successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             State Director to the Administrator, FmHA or its successor agency
            under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
            , Washington, DC 20250 at the request of the Governor of the
            appropriate State. A copy of the Governor&apos;s request for FmHA or
            its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             real property condemnation and the State Attorney General&apos;s
            opinion that State and local government condemnation authority is
            lacking shall be attached to the FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             State Director&apos;s request.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Administrator shall forward all requests for Federal
            condemnation to the OGC, USDA with a recommendation for action.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Administrator, FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             shall inform the Governor of any action on the request for
            condemnation.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Real property condemned by FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <PRTPAGE P='323' />
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             shall be transferred to the requesting State by a quitclaim Deed
            for a price equal to the fair market value of the real property in
            accordance with terms of a negotiated real property transfer
            agreement.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             After obtaining title to real property and prior to transfer to the
            State, the property shall be managed by FmHA or its successor agency
            under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1955' tq='N'>
                1955
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , subpart B of this chapter.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             may not condemn Indian Trust Land or U.S. Forest Service Land.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15330'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1948:B:1948.90
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1948.90
      </num>
      <head>
        Land transfers.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          44 FR 35984
        </aref>
        , June 19, 1979, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          46 FR 33022
        </aref>
        , June 26, 1981; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          56 FR 28038
        </aref>
        , June 19, 1991; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          68 FR 61331
        </aref>
        , Oct. 28, 2003]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1948' sect='90' psec='' tq='N'>
              1948.90
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Land transfers.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Transfers of real property acquired by FmHA or its successor agency
            under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A request for FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             acquisition of real property by a Governor of a State constitutes
            an agreement by that State to receive said real property and to
            reimburse FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             for the fair market value of said real property for the intended
            use.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Terms and conditions, including reimbursement terms, for real
            property transfers shall be set forth in a Real Property Transfer
            Agreement between the Administrator, FmHA or its successor agency
            under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             and the appropriate Governor. These terms and conditions will be
            agreed upon by FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             and the State prior to FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             attempting to acquire the property. These agreements shall be
            prepared after consulting with OGC, and forwarded for prior approval
            by the FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             National Office.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All funds from real property transfers received by FmHA or its
            successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             shall be deposited in the U.S. Treasury.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Transfer of real property acquired and/or developed with grant
            funds from a grant made under this subpart to a person.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Real property acquired and/or developed under this subpart may be
            transferred to a person for the purposes of construction of
            privately-owned housing.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All transfers of real property to a person must be approved by the
            FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             State Director of the appropriate State.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Transfer of real property by a recipient of assistance under this
            subpart to a person must be by contract which: acknowledges the use
            of funds provided under this subpart to acquire or develop the site;
            specifies the date of performance prior to delivery of the deed;
            provides for FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             concurrence before changes or modifications; and assures FmHA or
            its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             that the real property will be used for the purposes under which
            the grant was made.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Proceeds derived from the sale of land acquired or developed
            through the use of a grant provided under this subpart must be
            divided between the grantee and Rural Development on a pro rata
            basis. A grantee may not recover its cost from sale proceeds to the
            exclusion of Rural Development. The amount to be returned to Rural
            Development is to be computed by applying the percentage of the
            Rural Development grant participation in the total cost of the
            project to the proceeds from the sale.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All funds received by FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             from real property transfers shall be deposited in the U.S.
            Treasury.
          </text>
        </P>
        <SECAUTH>
          (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='42' sect='8401' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/42/8401.html'>
              42 U.S.C. 8401
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; delegation of authority by the Secretary of Agriculture, 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR 
            <subref title='7' part='2' sect='23' psec='' tq='N'>
              2.23
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; delegation of authority by the Assistant Secretary for Rural
          Development, 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR 
            <subref title='7' part='2' sect='70' psec='' tq='N'>
              2.70
            </subref>
          </aref>
          )
        </SECAUTH>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            44 FR 35984
          </aref>
          , June 19, 1979, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            46 FR 33022
          </aref>
          , June 26, 1981; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            56 FR 28038
          </aref>
          , June 19, 1991; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            68 FR 61331
          </aref>
          , Oct. 28, 2003]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15331'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1948:B:1948.91
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1948.91
      </num>
      <head>
        Inspections of development.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1948' sect='91' psec='' tq='N'>
              1948.91
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Inspections of development.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Inspections will be made by the FmHA or its successor agency under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
           State Engineer or other employee designated by the FmHA or its
          successor agency under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
           State Director to ascertain whether site development is proceeding in
          accordance with plans and specifications. Such inspections 
          <PRTPAGE P='324' />
          are solely for the benefit of the Government and not for the benefit
          of the Grantee or any other person.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15332'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1948:B:1948.92
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1948.92
      </num>
      <head>
        Grant approval and fund obligation.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          44 FR 35984
        </aref>
        , June 19, 1979, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          47 FR 36416
        </aref>
        , Aug. 20, 1982; 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          48 FR 30946
        </aref>
        , July 6, 1983]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1948' sect='92' psec='' tq='N'>
              1948.92
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Grant approval and fund obligation.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             State Office shall review the docket to determine whether the
            proposed grant complies with this subpart and that funds are
            available.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             State Director shall be the approving officer on all grants made
            under this subpart.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If at any time prior to grant approval it is decided that favorable
            action will not be taken on a preapplication or application, the
            FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             State Director will notify the applicant in writing of the reasons
            why the request was not favorably considered. The notification to
            the applicant will state that a review of this decision by FmHA or
            its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             may be requested by the applicant in accordance with FmHA
            Instruction 1900-B.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If a grant is recommended, Form FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             440-1 and the proposed grant agreement and scope of work will be
            prepared and forwarded to the applicant for signature.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When Form FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             440-1 and the grant agreement and scope of work are received by the
            applicant, the applicant will sign these documents and forward them
            to the State Director.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Exhibit A to FmHA Instruction 2015-C (available in any FmHA or its
            successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             Office) will be prepared by the State Director and sent to the
            Director of Information, Farmers Home Administration or its
            successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the State Director approves the project, the following actions
            will be taken in the order listed:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State Director, or a designee, will telephone the Finance
            Office requesting that grant funds for a particular project be
            obligated. Immediately after contacting the Finance Office, the
            requesting official shall furnish the requesting office&apos;s
            security identification code. Failure to furnish the security code
            will result in the rejection of the request of obligation. After the
            security code is furnished, the required information from Form FmHA
            or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             440-1 shall be furnished to the Finance Office. Upon receipt of the
            telephone request for obligation of funds, the Finance Office shall
            record all information necessary to process the request for
            obligation in addition to the date and time of request.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The individual making the request shall record the date and time of
            the request.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Finance Office will notify the FmHA or its successor agency
            under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             State Office by telephone when funds are reserved and the date the
            funds will be obligated. If funds cannot be reserved for a project,
            the Finance Office will notify the FmHA or its successor agency
            under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             State Office that funds are not available. The obligation date will
            be six working days from the date the request for obligation is
            processed.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Finance Office will send Form FmHA or its successor agency
            under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             440-57, “Acknowledgement of Obligated Funds/Check Request,” to the
            FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             State Director, informing the State Director of the reservation of
            funds with the obligation date inserted as required by Item 9 on the
            Forms Manual Insert (FMI) for Form FmHA or its successor agency
            under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             440-57.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Form FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             440-1 will not be mailed to the Finance Office.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A copy of Form FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             440-1 will be sent the FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             National Office.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The State Director shall notify the Director of Information in the
            FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             National Office with a recommendation that the project announcement
            be released.
            <PRTPAGE P='325' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An executed copy of Form FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             440-1 shall be sent to the applicant along with an executed copy of
            the grant agreement and scope of work on or before the date funds
            are obligated.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The actual date of applicant notification will be entered on the
            original of Form FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             440-1 and the original of the form will be included as a permanent
            part of the file.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_10'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (10)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For planning grants, Standard Form 270, “Request for Advance or
            Reimbursement,” will be sent to the applicant for completion and
            return to FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
            . For site acquisition and site development grants, Standard Form
            271, “Outlay Report and Request for Reimbursement for Construction
            Programs,” will be sent to the applicant for completion and returned
            to FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='g_11'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (11)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If it is determined that a project will not be funded or if major
            changes in the scope of the project are made after release of the
            approval announcement, the FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             State Director will notify the Director, Legislative Affairs and
            Public Information Staff (LAPIS) by telephone or electronic mail
            giving the reasons for such action. The Director, LAPIS, will inform
            all parties who were notified by the project announcement that the
            project will not be funded or of major changes in the project using
            a procedure similar to the announcement process. Form FmHA or its
            successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             1940-10, “Cancellation of U.S. Treasury Check and/or Obligation,”
            will not be submitted to the Finance Office until five working days
            after notifying the Director, LAPIS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <SECAUTH>
          (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='1989' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/1989.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 1989
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='42' sect='1480' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/42/1480.html'>
              42 U.S.C. 1480
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; 
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='5' sect='301' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/5/301.html'>
              5 U.S.C. 301
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            sec. 10
          </aref>
          <aref target='_blank' title='Pub. L. 93-357' alt='Pub. L. 93-357' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d93:./list/bd/d93pl.lst:357%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Pub. L. 93-357
          </aref>
          ; delegation of authority by the Sec. of Agri., 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR 
            <subref title='7' part='2' sect='23' psec='' tq='N'>
              2.23
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; delegation of authority by the Under Secretary for Small Community
          and Rural Development, 
          <aref type='CFR'>
            7 CFR 
            <subref title='7' part='2' sect='70' psec='' tq='N'>
              2.70
            </subref>
          </aref>
          )
        </SECAUTH>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            44 FR 35984
          </aref>
          , June 19, 1979, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            47 FR 36416
          </aref>
          , Aug. 20, 1982; 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            48 FR 30946
          </aref>
          , July 6, 1983]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15333'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1948:B:1948.93
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1948.93
      </num>
      <head>
        Appeal procedure.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1948' sect='93' psec='' tq='N'>
              1948.93
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Appeal procedure.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Any grantee or applicant for FmHA or its successor agency under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
           assistance under this subpart who has been directly and adversely
          affected by an administrative decision by FmHA or its successor agency
          under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
           may appeal such decision in accordance with FmHA Instruction 1900-B.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15334'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1948:B:1948.94
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1948.94
      </num>
      <head>
        Reporting requirements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1948' sect='94' psec='' tq='N'>
              1948.94
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Reporting requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For planning grants, SF-270 shall be submitted by grantees on an
            as-needed basis but not more frequently that once every 30 days.
            SF-269, “Financial Status Report,” and a project performance
            activity report will be required of all grantees on a quarterly
            basis. SF-269 and a final project performance report will also be
            required. These final reports may serve as the last quarterly
            reports. Grantees shall constantly monitor performance to ensure
            that time schedules are being met, projected work by time periods is
            being accomplished, and other performance objectives are being
            achieved. All grantees except States should submit an original of
            each report and one copy to the appropriate FmHA or its successor
            agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             District Office. When the grantee is a State, an original should be
            submitted to the appropriate FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             State Office. The project performance reports shall include, but
            need not be limited to the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A comparison of actual accomplishments to the objectives
            established for that period;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Reasons why established objectives were not met;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Problems, delays, or adverse conditions which will materially
            affect attainment of planned project objectives, prevent the meeting
            of time schedules or objectives, or preclude the attainment of
            project work elements during established time periods. This
            disclosure shall be accompanied by a statement of the action taken
            or contemplated and any Federal assistance needed to resolve the
            situation; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Objectives established for the next reporting period.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For site development and land acquisition grants, grantees shall
            submit 
            <PRTPAGE P='326' />
            Form SF-271 for payment of site development costs. Multiple advances
            will be made in accordance with FmHA Instruction 402.1 (available in
            any FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             office) and will be made as needed to cover required disbursements
            for not less than 30 day periods. Advances will be requested for the
            next 30 day period by the grantee on Form SF-272, “Report of Federal
            Cash Transactions.” Each payment estimate must be approved by the
            grantee. A final Form SF-272 will be submitted to FmHA or its
            successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             to include the final advance not later than 90 days after the final
            advance.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15335'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1948:B:1948.95
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1948.95
      </num>
      <head>
        Grant monitoring.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1948' sect='95' psec='' tq='N'>
              1948.95
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Grant monitoring.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Each grant will be monitored by FmHA or its successor agency under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
           to ensure that the Grantee is complying with the terms of the grant
          and that the project activities are completed as approved. This will
          involve on-site visits to the project area and review of quarterly and
          final reports by FmHA or its successor agency under 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Public Law 103-354
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15336'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1948:B:1948.96
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1948.96
      </num>
      <head>
        Audit requirements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1948' sect='96' psec='' tq='N'>
              1948.96
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Audit requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Audit requirements for Site Development and Acquisition Grants will
            be made in accordance with FmHA Instruction 1942-G.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Audits for planning grants made in accordance with State statutes
            or regulatory agencies will be acceptable provided they are prepared
            in sufficient detail to permit FmHA or its successor agency under 
            <aref target='_blank' title='Public Law 103-354' alt='Public Law 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
              Public Law 103-354
            </aref>
             to determine that grant funds have been used in compliance with the
            proposal, any applicable laws and regulations, and the grant
            agreement. A copy of the audit shall be submitted to the State
            Director as soon as possible but in no case later than 90 days
            following the period covered by the grant.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15337'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1948:B:1948.97
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1948.97
      </num>
      <head>
        Grant closing and fund disbursement.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1948' sect='97' psec='' tq='N'>
              1948.97
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Grant closing and fund disbursement.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Grant closing and fund disbursement will be accomplished in accordance
          with FmHA Instruction 1942-G.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15338'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1948:B:1948.98
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1948.98
      </num>
      <head>
        Grant agreements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1948' sect='98' psec='' tq='N'>
              1948.98
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Grant agreements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The following Grant Agreements are a part of this regulation.
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Exhibit A of this subpart is a Grant Agreement for Growth
            Management and Housing Planning Grants for approved Designated
            Energy Impacted Areas.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Exhibit B of this subpart is a Grant Agreement for Site Development
            and/or Site Acquisition for Housing and/or Public Facilities and/or
            Services.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='15339'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVIII:H:1948:B:1948.99-1948.100
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1948.99-1948.100
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1948' sect='99-1948' psec='' tq='N'>
              1948.99-1948
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .100
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>