<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol10'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1468
    </extid>
    <num>
      1468
    </num>
    <head>
      CONSERVATION FARM OPTION
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='16' sect='3839bb' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/3839bb.html'>
              16 U.S.C. 3839bb
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            63 FR 51786
          </aref>
          , Sept. 29, 1998, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='12984'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1468:A:1468.1
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1468.1
      </num>
      <head>
        Purpose.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1468' sect='1' psec='' tq='N'>
              1468.1
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Purpose.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Through the Conservation Farm Option (CFO), the Commodity Credit
            Corporation (CCC) provides financial assistance to eligible farmers
            and ranchers to address soil, water, and related natural resource
            concerns, water quality protection or improvement; wetland
            restoration and protection; wildlife habitat development and
            protection; and other similar conservation purposes on their lands
            in an environmentally beneficial and cost-effective manner. The
            Natural Resources Conservation Service (NRCS) may provide technical
            assistance, upon request by the producer or landowner.
            <PRTPAGE P='825' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The CCC provides a single contract and annual payments for
            implementation of innovative and environmentally-sound methods for
            addressing natural resource concerns for producers of wheat, feed
            grains, cotton, and rice, resulting in consolidation of payments
            that would have been available under the Conservation Reserve
            Program (CRP), the Wetlands Reserve Program cost-share agreements
            (WRP), and the Environmental Quality Incentives Program (EQIP). CFO
            participation is determined through two step process: first, the
            Chief, with FSA concurrence, selects CFO pilot project areas based
            on proposals submitted by the public; then CCC accepts applications
            from eligible producers or owners within the selected pilot project
            area.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12985'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1468:A:1468.2
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1468.2
      </num>
      <head>
        Administration.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1468' sect='2' psec='' tq='N'>
              1468.2
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Administration.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CFO is carried out using Commodity Credit Corporation funds and
            will be administered on behalf of CCC by the Natural Resources
            Conservation Service (NRCS) and the Farm Service Agency (FSA) as set
            forth below.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS will:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provide overall program management and implementation for CFO;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Establish policies, procedures, priorities, and guidance for
            program implementation, including determination of pilot project
            areas;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Establish annual payment rates consistent with EQIP, CRP, and WRP
            payment rates;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Make funding decisions and determine allocations of program funds,
            with FSA concurrence;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Determine eligibility of practices;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provide technical leadership for conservation planning and
            implementation, quality assurance, and evaluation of program
            performance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             FSA will:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be responsible for the administrative processes and procedures
            including applications, contracting, and financial matters, such as
            payments to participants, assistance in determining participant
            eligibility, and program accounting; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provide leadership for establishing, implementing, and overseeing
            administrative processes for applications, contracts, payment
            processes, and administrative and financial performance reporting.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             NRCS and FSA will cooperate in establishing program policies,
            priorities, and guidelines related to the implementation of this
            part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             No delegation herein to lower organizational levels shall preclude
            the Chief of NRCS, or the Administrator of FSA, or a designee, from
            determining any question arising under this part or from reversing
            or modifying any determination made under this part that is the
            responsibility of their respective agencies.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12986'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1468:A:1468.3
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1468.3
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation>
        [
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          63 FR 51786
        </aref>
        , Sept. 29, 1998, as amended at 
        <aref type='FREGIST'>
          76 FR 4806
        </aref>
        , Jan. 27, 2011]
      </citation>
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1468' sect='3' psec='' tq='N'>
              1468.3
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The following definitions apply to this part and all documents issued
          in accordance with this part, unless specified otherwise:
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Applicant
          </E>
           means a producer or owner in an approved pilot project area who has
          requested in writing to participate in CFO.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Chief
          </E>
           means the Chief of NRCS, or designee.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Conservation district
          </E>
           means a political subdivision of a State, Indian tribe, or territory,
          organized pursuant to the State or territorial soil conservation
          district law, or tribal law. The subdivision may be a conservation
          district, soil conservation district, soil and water conservation
          district, resource conservation district, natural resource district,
          land conservation committee, or similar legally constituted body.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Conservation farm plan
          </E>
           means a record of a participant&apos;s decisions, and supporting
          information for treatment of a unit of land or water as a result of
          the planning process, that meets the local NRCS Field Office Technical
          Guide (FOTG) criteria for each natural resource and takes into account
          economic and social considerations. The plan describes the schedule of
          operations and activities needed to solve identified natural resource
          problems, and take advantage of opportunities, at a conservation
          management system level. In the conservation farm plan, the needs of
          the client, the resources, and Federal, state, Tribal, and local
          requirements will be met.
          <PRTPAGE P='826' />
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Conservation practice
          </E>
           means a specified treatment, such as structural, vegetative, or a
          land management practice, which is planned and applied according to
          NRCS standards and specifications.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Contract
          </E>
           means a legal document that specifies the rights and obligations of
          any person who has been accepted for participation in the program.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            County executive director
          </E>
           means the FSA employee responsible for directing and managing program
          and administrative operations in one or more FSA county offices.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Farm Service Agency county committee
          </E>
           means a committee elected by the agricultural producers in the county
          or area, in accordance with 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            Sec. 8(b) of
          </aref>
           the Soil Conservation and Domestic Allotment Act, as amended, or
          designee.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Field office technical guide
          </E>
           means the official NRCS guidelines, criteria, and standards for
          planning and applying conservation treatments and conservation
          management systems. The guide contains detailed information on the
          conservation of soil, water, air, plant, and animal resources
          applicable to the local area for which it is prepared. A copy of the
          guide for that area is available at the appropriate NRCS field office.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Indian tribe
          </E>
           means any Indian tribe, band, nation, or other organized group or
          community, including any Alaska Native village or regional or village
          corporation as defined in or established pursuant to the Alaska Native
          Claims Settlement Act (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='43' sect='1601' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/43/1601.html'>
              43 U.S.C. 1601
            </subref>
          </aref>
          <E T='03'>
            et seq.
          </E>
          ) which is recognized as eligible for the special programs and
          services provided by the United States to Indians because of their
          status as Indians.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Innovative technology
          </E>
           means the use of new management techniques, specific treatments, or
          procedures such as structural or vegetative measures used in field
          trials or as interim conservation practice standards that have the
          purpose of solving or reducing the severity of natural resource use
          problems or that take advantage of resource opportunities. Innovative
          technologies used by program participants must be able to achieve the
          required level of resource protection.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Land management practice
          </E>
           means conservation practices that primarily require site-specific
          management techniques and methods to conserve, protect from
          degradation, or improve soil, water, or related natural resources in
          the most cost-effective manner. Land management practices include, but
          are not limited to nutrient management, manure management, integrated
          pest management, integrated crop management, irrigation water
          management, tillage or residue management, stripcropping, contour
          farming, grazing management, wildlife management, resource conserving
          crop rotations, cover crop management, and organic matter and carbon
          sink management.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Liquidated damages
          </E>
           means a sum of money stipulated in the contract which the participant
          agrees to pay, in addition to refunds and other charges, if the
          participant breaches the contract, and represents an estimate of the
          anticipated or actual harm caused by the breach, and reflects the
          difficulties of proof of loss and the inconvenience or nonfeasibility
          of otherwise obtaining an adequate remedy.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Local work group
          </E>
           means representatives of FSA, the National Institute of Food and
          Agriculture (NIFA), the conservation district, and other Federal,
          State, and local government agencies, including Tribes and Resource
          Conservation and Development councils, with expertise in natural
          resources who consult with NRCS on decisions related to CFO
          implementation.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Operation and maintenance
          </E>
           means work performed by the participant to keep the applied
          conservation practice functioning for the intended purpose during its
          life span. Operation includes the administration, management, and
          performance of non-maintenance actions needed to keep the completed
          practice safe and functioning as intended. Maintenance includes work
          to prevent deterioration of the practice, repairing damage, or
          replacement of the practice to its original condition if one or more
          components fail.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Participant
          </E>
           means an applicant who is a party to a CFO contract.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Secretary
          </E>
           means the Secretary of the United States Department of Agriculture.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State conservationist
          </E>
           means the NRCS employee authorized to direct and supervise NRCS
          activities in a State, the 
          <PRTPAGE P='827' />
          Caribbean Area, or the Pacific Basin Area.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            State technical committee
          </E>
           means a committee established by the Secretary in a state pursuant to
          
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='16' sect='3861' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/16/3861.html'>
              16 U.S.C. 3861
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Technical assistance
          </E>
           means the personnel and support resources needed to conduct
          conservation planning; conservation practice survey, layout, design,
          installation, and certification; training, certification, and quality
          assurance for professional conservationists; and evaluation and
          assessment of the program.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Unit of concern
          </E>
           means a parcel of agricultural land that has natural resource
          conditions that are of concern to the participant.
        </P>
        <CITA>
          [
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            63 FR 51786
          </aref>
          , Sept. 29, 1998, as amended at 
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            76 FR 4806
          </aref>
          , Jan. 27, 2011]
        </CITA>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12987'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1468:A:1468.4
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1468.4
      </num>
      <head>
        Establishing Conservation Farm Option (CFO) pilot project areas.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1468' sect='4' psec='' tq='N'>
              1468.4
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Establishing Conservation Farm Option (CFO) pilot project areas.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC may periodically solicit proposals from the public to establish
            pilot project areas in the 
            <E T='04'>
              Federal Register
            </E>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Pilot projects may involve one or more participants. Each owner or
            producer within an approved pilot project area must submit an
            application in order to be considered for enrollment in the CFO.
            This pilot project area may be a watershed, a subwatershed, an area,
            or an individual farm that can be geographically described and has
            specific environmental sensitivities or significant soil, water, and
            related natural resource concerns. The pilot project area must have
            acreage enrolled in a production flexibility contract, which is
            authorized by the Agricultural Marketing and Transition Act of 1996.
            After these pilot project area proposals are received, the Chief,
            with FSA concurrence, will select proposals for funding.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC will select pilot project areas based on the extent the
            individual proposal:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Demonstrates innovative approaches to conservation program delivery
            and administration;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Proposes innovative conservation technologies and system;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provides assurances that the greatest amount of environmental
            benefits will be delivered in a cost effective manner;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Ensures effective monitoring and evaluation of the pilot effort;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Considers multiple stakeholder participation (partnerships) within
            the pilot area;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provides additional non-Federal funding; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Addresses the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_7_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Conservation of soil, water, and related natural resources,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_7_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Water quality protection or improvement,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_7_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Wetland restoration and protection, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_7_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Wildlife habitat development and protection,
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_7_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Or other similar conservation purposes.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12988'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1468:A:1468.5
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1468.5
      </num>
      <head>
        General provisions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1468' sect='5' psec='' tq='N'>
              1468.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          General provisions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Program participation is voluntary.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Participation in the CFO is limited to producers of wheat, feed
            grains, cotton, or rice who have a production flexibility contract,
            in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1412' tq='N'>
                1412 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , on the farm enrolling in CFO and who are eligible for either CRP (
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1410' tq='N'>
                1410
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ), EQIP (
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1466' tq='N'>
                1466
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ), or WRP (
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1467' tq='N'>
                1467
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The participant is responsible for the development of a
            conservation farm plan for the farm or ranch and may request
            assistance from NRCS or a third party in writing both the
            conservation farm plan and installing the practices outlined within
            the plan. Conservation practices in the conservation farm plan that
            would have been eligible for payment under CRP, EQIP, or cost-share
            agreements under WRP are eligible for CFO payment. The provisions
            for determining eligibility for payment and the calculation of
            payment under CFO will be similar to those specified for the
            eligible conservation practices under CRP, EQIP, or cost-share
            agreements under WRP. For land retirement payments, the CRP payment
            schedule in effect for the applicable soils at the time the CFO
            contract is signed will be utilized. CCC will provide annual
            payments to a participant for such conservation practices as
            specified in the time schedule set forth in the conservation farm
            plan.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12989'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1468:A:1468.6
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1468.6
      </num>
      <head>
        Practice eligibility provisions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='828' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1468' sect='6' psec='' tq='N'>
              1468.6
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Practice eligibility provisions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Practices may be eligible for payment under CFO if the conservation
            practice specified in the conservation farm plan is determined to be
            an eligible practice, as determined by the Chief, in accordance
            with:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1410' tq='N'>
                1410
              </subref>
            </aref>
             for land retirement rental payments and practices that are eligible
            under CRP;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1467' tq='N'>
                1467
              </subref>
            </aref>
             for wetland restoration or protection practices that are eligible
            under WRP; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1466' tq='N'>
                1466
              </subref>
            </aref>
             for conservation practices that are eligible under EQIP.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For practices that are installed on retired land, the CRP
            cost-share rate for practices must be utilized.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12990'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1468:A:1468.7
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1468.7
      </num>
      <head>
        Participant eligibility provisions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1468' sect='7' psec='' tq='N'>
              1468.7
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Participant eligibility provisions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Participants in the CFO must at the time of enrollment:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Have a production flexibility contract in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1412' tq='N'>
                1412 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
             on the farm enrolling in CFO.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Agree to forgo earning future payments under the Conservation
            Reserve Program authorized by 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1410' tq='N'>
                1410 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , the Wetlands Reserve Program cost-share payments authorized by 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1467' tq='N'>
                1467 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , and Environmental Quality Incentives Program authorized by 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1466' tq='N'>
                1466 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , on the farm enrolled in the CFO for the term of the CFO contract.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be in compliance with the highly erodible land and wetland
            conservation provisions found at 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='12' tq='N'>
                12 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Have control of the land for the term of the proposed contract
            period;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An exception may be made by the Chief in the case of land allotted
            by the Bureau of Indian Affairs (BIA), tribal land, or other
            instances in which the Chief determines that there is sufficient
            assurance of control.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the applicant is a tenant of the land involved in agricultural
            production the applicant shall provide CCC with the written
            authorization by the landowner to apply the structural or vegetative
            practice.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the applicant is a landowner, the landowner is presumed to have
            control.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Submit a proposed conservation farm plan to CCC that is in
            compliance with the terms and conditions of the program. To receive
            payment under the CFO, the participant must also meet the
            eligibility requirements, as determined by the Chief, in:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1410' tq='N'>
                1410
              </subref>
            </aref>
             if the land retirement rental payment and practice determined
            eligible in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1468' sect='6' psec='#a' tq='N'>
                1468.6(a)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1467' tq='N'>
                1467
              </subref>
            </aref>
             if the wetland restoration or protection practice was determined
            eligible in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1468' sect='6' psec='#b' tq='N'>
                1468.6(b)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1466' tq='N'>
                1466
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , if the conservation practice was determined eligible in accordance
            with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1468' sect='6' psec='#c' tq='N'>
                1468.6(c)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Comply with the provisions at 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1412' sect='304' psec='' tq='N'>
                1412.304
              </subref>
               of this chapter
            </aref>
             for protecting the interests of tenants and sharecroppers,
            including provisions for sharing, on a fair and equitable basis,
            payments made available under this part, as may be applicable.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Supply information as required by CCC to determine eligibility for
            the program.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='e_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Comply with all the provisions of the CFO contract which includes
            the conservation farm plan approved by the local conservation
            district.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12991'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1468:A:1468.8
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1468.8
      </num>
      <head>
        Land eligibility provisions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1468' sect='8' psec='' tq='N'>
              1468.8
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Land eligibility provisions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Land may be eligible for enrollment in CFO, if CCC determines that the
          farm or ranch is enrolled in a production flexibility contract,
          authorized by the Agricultural Marketing Transition Act of 1996 and if
          the land upon which the CFO conservation practice, will be applied is
          determined to be eligible land as determined by the Chief, in
          accordance with:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1410' tq='N'>
                1410
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , if the practice was determined an eligible land retirement rental
            payment and cost-share practice similar to CRP in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1468' sect='6' psec='#a' tq='N'>
                1468.6(a)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1467' tq='N'>
                1467
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , if the practice was determined an eligible wetland restoration or
            protection practice similar to WRP in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1468' sect='6' psec='#b' tq='N'>
                1468.6(b)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ; or
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='CFR'>
              7 CFR part 
              <subref title='7' part='1466' tq='N'>
                1466
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , if the practice was determined an eligible conservation practice
            similar to EQIP in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1468' sect='6' psec='#c' tq='N'>
                1468.6(c)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12992'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1468:A:1468.9
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1468.9
      </num>
      <head>
        Conservation farm plan.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='829' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1468' sect='9' psec='' tq='N'>
              1468.9
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Conservation farm plan.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The conservation farm plan forms the basis of the CFO contract.
            Prior to contract approval, a conservation farm plan must be written
            and approved. In deciding whether to approve a conservation farm
            plan, CCC may consider whether:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The participant will use conservation practices to solve the
            natural resource concerns that will maximize environmental benefits
            per dollar expended, and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The conservation practice would have been eligible for enrollment
            in the CRP, EQIP, or under the WRP cost-share agreements.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The conservation farm plan for the farm or ranch unit of concern
            shall:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Describe any resource conserving crop rotation, and all other
            conservation practices, to be implemented and maintained on the
            acreage that is subject to contract during the contact period;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Address the resource concerns identified in the CFO pilot project
            area proposal;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Contain a schedule for the implementation and maintenance of the
            practices described in the conservation farm plan;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Ensure that net environmental benefits under a CRP contract are
            maintained or exceeded for the whole farm, as constituted by FSA,
            when terminating a CRP contract and enrolling in a CFO contract; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Meet the objectives of the pilot project area.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The conservation farm plan is part of the CFO contract.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The conservation farm plan must allow the participant to achieve a
            cost-effective resource management system, or some appropriate
            portion of that system, identified in the applicable NRCS field
            office technical guide or as approved by the State Conservationist.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Participants are responsible for implementing the conservation farm
            plan in compliance with this part.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon a participant&apos;s request, the NRCS may provide technical
            assistance to a participant.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Participants may, at their own cost, use qualified professionals,
            other than NRCS personnel, to provide technical assistance. NRCS
            retains approval authority over the technical adequacy of work done
            by non-NRCS personnel for the purpose of determining CFO contract
            compliance.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='f_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Technical and other assistance provided by qualified personnel not
            affiliated with NRCS may include, but not limited to: conservation
            planning; conservation practice survey, layout, design, and
            installation; information, education, and training for producers;
            and training and quality assurance for professional
            conservationists.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All conservation practices scheduled in the conservation farm plan
            are to be carried out in accordance with the applicable NRCS Field
            Office Technical Guide. The State Conservationist may approve use of
            innovative conservation measures that are not contained in the NRCS
            Field Office Technical Guide.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             To simplify the conservation planning process for the participant,
            the conservation farm plan may be developed, at the request of the
            participant, as a single plan that incorporates, other Federal,
            state, Tribal, or local government program or regulatory
            requirements. CCC development or approval of a conservation farm
            plan shall not constitute compliance with program, statutory and
            regulatory requirements administered or enforced by a non-USDA
            agency, except as agreed to by the participant and the relevant
            Federal, state, local or tribal entities.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='h_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC may accept an existing conservation plan developed and required
            for participation in any other CCC or USDA program if the
            conservation plan otherwise meets the requirements of this part.
            When a participant develops a single conservation farm plan for more
            than one program, the participant shall clearly identify the
            portions of the plan that are applicable to the CFO contract. It is
            the responsibility of the participant to ascertain and comply with
            all applicable statutory and regulatory requirements.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12993'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1468:B:1468.20
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1468.20
      </num>
      <head>
        Application for CFO program participation.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1468' sect='20' psec='' tq='N'>
              1468.20
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Application for CFO program participation.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any eligible owner or producer within an approved pilot project
            area 
            <PRTPAGE P='830' />
            may submit an application for participation in the CFO to a service
            center or other USDA county or field office(s) of FSA or NRCS, where
            the pilot project area is located.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC will accept applications throughout the fiscal year. CCC will
            rank and select the offers of applicants periodically, as determined
            appropriate by the State Conservationist. The application period
            will begin after a pilot project area has been approved.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The designated conservationist, in consultation with the local work
            group, will develop ranking criteria to prioritize applications
            within a pilot project area which consists of more than one owner or
            producer. NRCS will prioritize applications from the same pilot
            project area using the criteria specific to the area. The FSA county
            committee, with the assistance of the designated conservationist and
            designated FSA official, will approve for funding the application in
            a pilot project area based on eligibility factors of the applicant
            and the NRCS ranking.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The designated conservationist will work with the applicant to
            collect the information necessary to evaluate the application using
            the ranking criteria. An applicant has the option of offering and
            accepting less than the maximum program payments allowed, offering
            to apply more conservation practices to the land in order to
            increase the likelihood of being enrolled. In evaluating the
            applications, the designated conservationist will take into
            consideration the following factors:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Soil erosion;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Water quality;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Wildlife benefits;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Soil productivity;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Conservation compliance considerations;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Likelihood to remain in conserving uses beyond the contract period,
            including tree planting and permanent wildlife habitat;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_7'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (7)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             State water quality priority areas;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_8'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (8)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The environmental benefits per dollar expended; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_9'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (9)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The degree to which application is consistent with the pilot
            project proposal.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If two or more applications have an equal rank, the application
            that will result in the least cost to the program will be given
            greater consideration.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12994'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1468:B:1468.21
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1468.21
      </num>
      <head>
        Contract requirements.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1468' sect='21' psec='' tq='N'>
              1468.21
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Contract requirements.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In order for an applicant to receive annual payments, the applicant
            must enter into a contract agreeing to implement a conservation farm
            plan. The FSA county committee, with NRCS concurrence, will use the
            NRCS ranking consistent with the provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1468' sect='20' psec='' tq='N'>
                1468.20
              </subref>
            </aref>
             and grant final approval of the contract.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A CFO contract will:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Incorporate by reference all portions of a conservation farm plan
            applicable to CFO;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Be for a duration of 10 years, and may be renewed, subject to the
            availability of funds, for a period not to exceed 5 years upon
            mutual agreement of CCC and the participant;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provide that the participant will:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Not conduct any practices on the farm or ranch unit of concern
            consistent with the goals of the contract that would tend to defeat
            the purposes of the contract, or reduce net environmental and
            societal benefits;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Refund with interest any program payments received and forfeit any
            future payments under the program, on the violation of a term or
            condition of the contract, in accordance with the provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1468' sect='25' psec='' tq='N'>
                1468.25
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Refund all program payments received on the transfer of the right
            and interest of the producer in land subject to the contract, unless
            the transferee of the right and interest agrees to assume all
            obligations of the contract, in accordance with the provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1468' sect='24' psec='' tq='N'>
                1468.24
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_iv'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iv)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Agree to forego participation in CRP, EQIP, and the cost-share
            agreements under WRP, along with future payments associated with
            these programs, with regard to the land under the CFO contract;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='b_3_v'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (v)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Supply information as required by CCC to determine compliance with
            the contract and requirements of the program;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Specify the participant&apos;s requirements for operation and
            maintenance of the applied conservation practices in accordance with
            the provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1468' sect='22' psec='' tq='N'>
                1468.22
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
            , and
            <PRTPAGE P='831' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Include any other provision determined necessary or appropriate by
            CCC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             There is a limit of one CFO contract at any one time for each farm,
            as constituted by FSA.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The contract will incorporate the operation and maintenance of
            conservation practices applied under the contract, including those
            practices transferred from terminated CRP and EQIP contracts and WRP
            cost-share agreements. For persons wishing to transfer from CRP,
            EQIP, or WRP to CFO, practices included in CRP or EQIP contracts or
            WRP cost-share agreements must be included in a CFO contract if an
            owner or producer wishes to participate, unless otherwise stated in
            the conservation farm plan.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Acreage that is subject to a WRP easement will not be included in
            the CFO contract.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon completion, the participant must certify that a conservation
            practice is completed in accordance with the conservation farm plan
            to establish compliance with the contract.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12995'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1468:B:1468.22
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1468.22
      </num>
      <head>
        Conservation practice operation and maintenance.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1468' sect='22' psec='' tq='N'>
              1468.22
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Conservation practice operation and maintenance.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The participant will operate and maintain the conservation practice
            for its intended purpose for the life span of the conservation
            practice, as identified in the conservation farm plan. Conservation
            practices installed before the execution of a CFO contract, but
            needed in the contract to obtain the environmental benefits agreed
            upon, are to be operated and maintained as specified in the
            contract. NRCS may periodically inspect the conservation practice
            during the lifespan of the practice as specified in the contract to
            ensure that the operation and maintenance is occurring.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             For those persons who are signatories to existing CRP or EQIP
            contracts, or WRP cost-share agreements, practices will be
            transferred from EQIP and CRP contracts or WRP cost-share
            agreements, as agreed upon in the CFO conservation farm plan and CFO
            contract. Remaining rights and obligations under CRP, EQIP, or WRP
            will be incorporated into the new CFO contract. Practices included
            in CRP, EQIP, or WRP will be incorporated into the new CFO contract.
            Practices included in CRP or EQIP contracts or WRP cost-share
            agreements must be included in a CFO contract if an owner or
            producer wishes to participate. Participants in CFO with CRP, EQIP,
            or WRP practices incorporated into CFO contracts are responsible for
            operating and maintaining these practices for the balance of the
            period specified in the original program contract, unless otherwise
            stated in the conservation farm plan and CFO contract.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12996'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1468:B:1468.23
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1468.23
      </num>
      <head>
        Annual payments.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1468' sect='23' psec='' tq='N'>
              1468.23
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Annual payments.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC will determine annual payments, subject to the availability of
            funds, based on the value of the expected payments that would have
            been paid to the participant for that practice as specified in:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              Part 
              <subref title='7' part='1410' tq='N'>
                1410 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , if the practice is a land retirement rental payment or cost-share
            practice which would have qualified for payment under CRP in
            accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1468' sect='6' psec='#a' tq='N'>
                1468.6(a)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              Part 
              <subref title='7' part='1467' tq='N'>
                1467 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , if the practice is a wetland restoration or protection practice
            which would have qualified for payment under WRP which was
            determined eligible in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1468' sect='6' psec='#b' tq='N'>
                1468.6(b)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              Part 
              <subref title='7' part='1466' tq='N'>
                1466 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , if the practice was a conservation practice which would have
            qualified for payment under EQIP which was determined eligible in
            accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1468' sect='6' psec='#c' tq='N'>
                1468.6(c)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            ;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The maximum amount of annual payments which a person may receive
            under the CFO for any fiscal year shall not exceed the total of the
            amounts calculated in accordance with paragraph (a) of this section
            after being limited as follows:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The payment calculated in accordance with paragraph (a)(1) of this
            section is limited in accordance with CRP payment limitation
            provisions set forth in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1410' tq='N'>
                1410 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The payment calculated in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1467' sect='9' psec='#a_2' tq='N'>
                1467.9(a)(2)
              </subref>
               of this chapter
            </aref>
             is not limited.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The payment calculated in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1466' sect='23' psec='#a_3' tq='N'>
                1466.23(a)(3)
              </subref>
               of this chapter
            </aref>
             is limited in accordance with EQIP payment limitation provisions in
            
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1466' sect='23' psec='#b' tq='N'>
                1466.23(b)
              </subref>
               of this chapter
            </aref>
            .
            <PRTPAGE P='832' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The regulations set forth at 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1400' tq='N'>
                1400 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
             will be applicable in making payment eligibility determinations for
            CFO and in making person determination as they apply to the
            limitation of payments determined in accordance with paragraph (b)
            of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The CCC cost-share payments to a participant shall be reduced so
            that total financial contributions for a structural or vegetative
            practice from all public and private entity sources do not exceed
            the cost of the practice.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A landowner or producer that enrolls in CFO and terminates a CRP or
            EQIP contract or WRP cost-share agreement will be eligible to
            receive payments for practices which have been determined,
            established, or completed by the technical agency under those
            contracts or agreements. Once the CFO contract is effective, all
            payments for practices, including any practice transferred from the
            terminated contract agreement will be made under the CFO contract,
            except for payments already earned under prior contracts or
            cost-share agreements.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payments will not be made to a participant who has applied or
            initiated the application of a conservation practice for the
            purposes of CFO prior to approval of the CFO contract.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When requested by the State Conservationist on a case-by-case
            basis, the Chief may approve, based upon availability of funding,
            cost share on the reapplication of a practice to replace or repair
            practice destroyed by unusual circumstances beyond the control of
            the landowner.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The participant and NRCS must certify that a conservation practice
            is completed in accordance with the conservation farm plan to
            establish compliance with the contract before the CCC will approve
            the payment of any cost-share, incentive, or land retirement
            payment.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12997'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1468:B:1468.24
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1468.24
      </num>
      <head>
        Contract modifications and transfers of land.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1468' sect='24' psec='' tq='N'>
              1468.24
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Contract modifications and transfers of land.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The participant and CCC may modify a contract if the participant
            and CCC agree to the contract modification and the conservation farm
            plan is revised in accordance with CCC requirements and is approved
            by the conservation district.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The participant may agree to transfer a contract to another
            eligible owner or operator with the agreement of CCC. The transferee
            shall assume full responsibility under the contract, including
            operation and maintenance of those conservation practices already
            installed and to be installed as a condition of the contract. By
            agreeing to participate in CFO, CCC may require operation and
            maintenance of those conservation practices installed under CRP,
            EQIP, or WRP.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC may require a participant to refund all or a portion of any
            assistance earned under a CRP or EQIP contract, or WRP cost-share
            agreement that was terminated as a condition of participation in
            CFO, if the participant sells or loses control of the land under a
            CFO contract and the new owner or controller does not assume
            responsibility under the contract.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12998'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1468:B:1468.25
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1468.25
      </num>
      <head>
        Contract violations and termination.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1468' sect='25' psec='' tq='N'>
              1468.25
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Contract violations and termination.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If it is determined that a participant is in violation of the
            provisions of this part, or the terms of the contract including
            portions of the contract that incorporate transferred obligations
            from CRP or EQIP contracts, or WRP cost-share agreements, CCC will
            give the participant written notice of a reasonable time to correct
            the violation and comply with the terms of the contract and
            attachments thereto, as determined by the FSA county committee, in
            consultation with NRCS. If a participant continues in violation
            after the time to comply has elapsed, the FSA county committee may,
            in consultation with NRCS, terminate the CFO contract.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph (a)(1) of this section,
            a contract termination shall be effective immediately upon a
            determination by the FSA county committee, in consultation with
            NRCS, that the participant has submitted false information, filed a
            false claim, or engaged in any act for which a finding of
            ineligibility for payments is permitted under the provisions of 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1468' sect='35' psec='' tq='N'>
                1468.35
              </subref>
               of this part
            </aref>
            , or in a case in which the actions of the party involved are deemed
            to be sufficiently 
            <PRTPAGE P='833' />
            purposeful or negligent to warrant a termination without delay.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='2'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If CCC terminates a contract, the participant shall forfeit all
            rights for future payments under the contract and shall refund all
            or part of the payments received, plus interest, determined in
            accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1403' tq='N'>
                1403 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            . CCC has the option of requiring only partial refund of the
            payments received if a previously installed conservation practice
            can function independently, is not affected by the violation or
            other conservation practices that would have been installed under
            the contract, and the participant agrees to operate and maintain the
            installed conservation practice for the life span of the practice.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If CCC terminates a contract for any reason stated above, before
            any contractual payments have been made, the participant shall
            forfeit all rights for further payments under the contract and shall
            pay such liquidated damages as are prescribed in the contract.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When making all contract termination decisions, CCC may reduce the
            amount of money owed by the participant by a proportion which
            reflects the good-faith effort of the participant to comply with the
            contract, or the hardships beyond the participant&apos;s control
            that have prevented compliance with the contract.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The participant may voluntarily terminate a contract without
            penalty, if CCC determines that such termination would be in the
            public interest.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='12999'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1468:C:1468.30
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1468.30
      </num>
      <head>
        Appeals.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1468' sect='30' psec='' tq='N'>
              1468.30
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Appeals.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An applicant or participant may obtain administrative review of an
            adverse decision made with respect to this part and the CFO contract
            in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              parts 
              <subref title='7' part='11' tq='N'>
                11
              </subref>
               and 
              <subref title='7' part='614' tq='N'>
                614 of this title
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , except as provided in paragraph (b) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The following decisions are not appealable:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             CCC funding allocations;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Eligible conservation practices;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Payment rates, and cost-share percentages;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Science-based formulas and factor values;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Soils mapping and information; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='b_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Other matters of general applicability.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13000'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1468:C:1468.31
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1468.31
      </num>
      <head>
        Compliance with regulatory measures.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1468' sect='31' psec='' tq='N'>
              1468.31
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Compliance with regulatory measures.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Participants who carry out conservation practices shall be responsible
          for obtaining the authorities, rights, easements, permits, or other
          approvals necessary for the implementation, operation, and maintenance
          of the conservation practices in keeping with applicable laws and
          regulations. Participants shall be responsible for compliance with all
          laws and for all effects or actions resulting from the
          participant&apos;s performance under the contract.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13001'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1468:C:1468.32
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1468.32
      </num>
      <head>
        Access to operating unit.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1468' sect='32' psec='' tq='N'>
              1468.32
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Access to operating unit.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Any authorized CCC representative shall have the right to enter an
          operating unit or tract for the purpose of ascertaining the accuracy
          of any representations made in a contract or in anticipation of
          entering a contract, or as to the performance of the terms and
          conditions of the contract. Access shall include the right to provide
          technical assistance and inspect any work undertaken under the
          contract. The CCC representative shall make a reasonable effort to
          contact the participant prior to the exercise of this right to access.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13002'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1468:C:1468.33
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1468.33
      </num>
      <head>
        Performance based upon advice or action of representatives of CCC.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1468' sect='33' psec='' tq='N'>
              1468.33
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Performance based upon advice or action of representatives of CCC.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          If a participant relied upon the advice or action of any authorized
          representative of CCC, and did not know or have reason to know that
          the action or advice was improper or erroneous, the FSA county
          committee, in consultation with NRCS, may accept the advice or action
          as meeting the requirements of the program and may grant relief, to
          the extent it is deemed desirable, to provide a fair and equitable
          treatment because of the good-faith reliance on the part of the
          participant.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13003'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1468:C:1468.34
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1468.34
      </num>
      <head>
        Offsets and assignments.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <PRTPAGE P='834' />
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1468' sect='34' psec='' tq='N'>
              1468.34
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Offsets and assignments.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Except as provided in paragraph (b) of this section, any payment or
            portion thereof to any participant shall be made without regard to
            questions of title under State law and without regard to any claim
            or lien against the crop, or proceeds thereof, in favor of the owner
            or any other creditor except agencies of the United States. The
            regulations governing offsets and withholdings found at 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1403' tq='N'>
                1403 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
             shall apply to contract payments.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Any participant entitled to any payment may assign any payments in
            accordance with regulations governing assignment of payment found at
            
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1404' tq='N'>
                1404 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='13004'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XIV:B:1468:C:1468.35
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1468.35
      </num>
      <head>
        Misrepresentation and scheme or device.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1468' sect='35' psec='' tq='N'>
              1468.35
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Misrepresentation and scheme or device.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A participant who is determined to have erroneously represented any
            fact affecting a program determination made in accordance with this
            part shall not be entitled to contract payments and must refund to
            CCC all payments, plus interest determined in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1403' tq='N'>
                1403 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             An applicant or participant who is determined to have knowingly
            adopted any scheme or device that tends to defeat the purpose of the
            program; made any fraudulent representation; or misrepresented any
            fact affecting a program determination, shall refund to CCC all
            payments, plus interest determined in accordance with 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-PART'>
              part 
              <subref title='7' part='1403' tq='N'>
                1403 of this chapter
              </subref>
            </aref>
            , received by such applicant or participant with respect to CFO
            contracts.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>