<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lii_cfr_xml>
  <title>
    <num>
      7
    </num>
    <year>
      2013
    </year>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0
    </extid>
    <head>
      Title 7—Agriculture
    </head>
    <published>
      2013-01-01
    </published>
    <ingested>
      2013-05-14; Tuesday, May 14, 2013; 16:47:56 [-04:00]
    </ingested>
    <sections>
      17956
    </sections>
    <gpo_volumes>
      <total>
        15
      </total>
      <missing>
        NONE
      </missing>
    </gpo_volumes>
  </title>
  <part volid='CFR-2013-title7-vol12'>
    <extid>
      lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1789
    </extid>
    <num>
      1789
    </num>
    <head>
      USE OF CONSULTANTS FUNDED BY BORROWERS
    </head>
    <text>
      <AUTH>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Authority:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='901-950b' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/901-950b.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 901-950b
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ; 
          <aref target='_blank' title='Pub. L. 103-354' alt='Pub. L. 103-354' href='http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:354%28Public_Laws%29'>
            Pub. L. 103-354
          </aref>
          , 
          <aref target='_blank' href='http://frwebgate.access.gpo.gov/cgi-bin/getpage.cgi?dbname=103_statutes2_at_large&amp;position=all&amp;page=3178'>
            108 Stat. 3178
          </aref>
           (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='6941' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/6941.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 6941
            </subref>
          </aref>
           et seq.).
        </P>
      </AUTH>
      <SOURCE>
        <HD SOURCE='HED'>
          Source:
        </HD>
        <P>
          <aref type='FREGIST'>
            61 FR 48606
          </aref>
          , Sept. 16, 1996, unless otherwise noted.
        </P>
      </SOURCE>
    </text>
    <section orderid='14727'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1789:A:1789.150
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1789.150
      </num>
      <head>
        Purpose.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1789' sect='150' psec='' tq='N'>
              1789.150
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Purpose.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          This part sets forth policies and the procedures for implementing
          subsection (c) of 
          <aref type='UNKNOWN'>
            section 18 of
          </aref>
           the Rural Electrification Act of 1936, as amended (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='7' sect='901' note='' psec='' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/7/901.html'>
              7 U.S.C. 901
            </subref>
          </aref>
           et seq.)(RE Act) which authorizes the Rural Utilities Service (RUS)
          to use the services of Consultants funded by the Borrowers to
          facilitate timely action on Applications by Borrowers for financial
          assistance and other approvals.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14728'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1789:A:1789.151
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1789.151
      </num>
      <head>
        Definitions.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1789' sect='151' psec='' tq='N'>
              1789.151
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Definitions.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          As used in this part:
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Administrator
          </E>
           means the Administrator of the Rural Utilities Service (RUS).
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Application
          </E>
           means a request for financial assistance under the RE Act or such
          other approvals as may be required of the RUS pursuant to the terms of
          outstanding loan or security instruments or otherwise.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Borrower
          </E>
           means any organization which has an outstanding loan(s) made or
          guaranteed by RUS or its predecessor agency, the Rural Electrification
          Administration (REA) under the RE Act or any organization which has
          submitted or submits an Application before RUS.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Consultant
          </E>
           means a person or firm which has been retained pursuant to this
          subpart under a contract to provide financial, legal, engineering,
          environmental, or other technical advice and services.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Consultant Contract
          </E>
           means a contract for the performance of consulting services for RUS,
          to be paid using funds provided by a Borrower, which may be in the
          form of a Retainer Contract, purchase order, or other form as may be
          appropriate.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Escrow Account
          </E>
           means an account established pursuant to 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1789' sect='158' psec='' tq='N'>
              1789.158
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Escrow Agreement
          </E>
           means an agreement, between a Borrower, a Consultant and a
          Third-party Commercial Institution, meeting the requirements of 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1789' sect='167' psec='' tq='N'>
              1789.167
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Final Invoice
          </E>
           means the closing Invoice prepared for a given Task Order.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Financial Consultant
          </E>
           means a Consultant retained pursuant to this part to provide
          financial advisory services.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Funding Agreement
          </E>
           means an agreement, between a Borrower and a Consultant, providing
          for the Borrower to fund the costs of a Task Order and otherwise
          meeting the requirements of 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1789' sect='166' psec='' tq='N'>
              1789.166
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Indemnification Agreement
          </E>
           means an agreement by a Borrower meeting the requirements of 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1789' sect='162' psec='' tq='N'>
              1789.162
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Invoice
          </E>
           means an invoice prepared by a Consultant pursuant to the terms of a
          Consultant Contract.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Legal Consultant
          </E>
           means any Consultant retained pursuant to this part to provide legal
          services to RUS.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Notice of Proposal to Fund
          </E>
           means a notice meeting the requirements of 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1789' sect='156' psec='' tq='N'>
              1789.156
            </subref>
          </aref>
           provided to RUS by the Borrower.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Organizational conflict of interest
          </E>
           means that because of other activities or relationships with other
          persons, a person is unable or potentially unable to render impartial
          assistance or advice to the Government, or the person&apos;s
          objectivity in performing the contract work is or might be otherwise
          impaired, or a person has an unfair competitive advantage.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Retainer Contract
          </E>
           means a Consultant Contract providing for a minimum required payment
          to a Consultant irrespective of whether services are utilized by RUS
          thereunder.
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Task Order
          </E>
           means a written request for consultant services pursuant to the terms
          of a Consultant Contract.
          <PRTPAGE P='397' />
        </P>
        <P>
          <E T='03'>
            Third-party Commercial Institution
          </E>
           means a commercial financial institution mutually acceptable to the
          Borrower and the Consultant.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14729'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1789:A:1789.152
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1789.152
      </num>
      <head>
        Policy.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1789' sect='152' psec='' tq='N'>
              1789.152
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Policy.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             As provided in this subpart, RUS may, at its discretion, use the
            services of Consultants funded by a Borrower where such services
            will facilitate timely action on an Application by such Borrower for
            financial assistance or other approvals. Such Consultants may
            provide financial, legal, engineering, environmental or other
            technical advice and services in connection with the review of an
            Application.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             With the approval of RUS, a Borrower may fund the cost of
            consulting services in connection with the review by RUS of an
            Application by such Borrower. Such funding shall be provided
            pursuant to the terms of a Funding Agreement between the Borrower
            and the Consultant designated by RUS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             RUS may not, without the consent of the Borrower, require, as a
            condition of processing any Application for approval, that the
            Borrower agree to pay the costs of a Consultant hired to provide
            services to RUS.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The government shall retain sole discretion in the selection of
            Consultants to provide services to RUS and the form of contract
            utilized. RUS may either use the services of one or more Consultants
            retained under Retainer Contracts or the government may elect to
            retain a Consultant not otherwise on retainer. The government shall
            have sole discretion to prescribe terms and conditions of Consultant
            Contracts. The Borrower may bring considerations to the attention of
            the government which the Borrower deems pertinent to the selection
            process.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             RUS shall retain sole discretion as to whether to further pursue
            use of an outside consultant for the relevant application in the
            event the Borrower does not enter into the agreements referenced in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1789' sect='158' psec='#c_3_iii' tq='N'>
                1789.158(c)(3)(iii)
              </subref>
            </aref>
             within 60 days of the government providing to the Borrower the
            information set forth in 
            <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
              § 
              <subref title='7' part='1789' sect='158' psec='#c_3' tq='N'>
                1789.158(c)(3)
              </subref>
            </aref>
            .
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14730'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1789:A:1789.153
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1789.153
      </num>
      <head>
        Borrower funding.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1789' sect='153' psec='' tq='N'>
              1789.153
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Borrower funding.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Borrowers shall use their general funds for the purposes of funding
          consultant services hereunder. Borrowers may not use the proceeds of
          loans made or guaranteed under the RE Act for costs incurred by
          Borrowers pursuant to the funding of consultant services for RUS.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14731'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1789:A:1789.154
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1789.154
      </num>
      <head>
        Eligible borrowers.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1789' sect='154' psec='' tq='N'>
              1789.154
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Eligible borrowers.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          All Borrowers are eligible to fund consultant services under this
          part.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14732'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1789:A:1789.155
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1789.155
      </num>
      <head>
        Approval criteria.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1789' sect='155' psec='' tq='N'>
              1789.155
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Approval criteria.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          RUS will consider approving the use of consultant services funded by a
          Borrower on a case by case basis taking into account, among other
          matters, the following:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whether such services are required to facilitate timely action on a
            Borrower&apos;s Application. RUS shall determine what represents
            timely action with respect to each Application considering, among
            other matters, the review period normally required for such projects
            by RUS and other lenders and the consequences to the Borrower of
            adjusting the review period.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The availability of staff resources, the priorities of other
            projects then before RUS, and the efficiencies to be realized from
            the use of consultant services.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Whether it is in the best interest of RUS to use Borrower-funded
            Consultants. Certain types of projects, such as those involving
            issues of program-wide significance, may not be well suited for the
            use of Borrower funded Consultants.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14733'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1789:A:1789.156
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1789.156
      </num>
      <head>
        Proposal procedure.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1789' sect='156' psec='' tq='N'>
              1789.156
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Proposal procedure.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             In the event RUS determines that consideration should be given to
            the use of a Borrower-funded consultant in connection with the
            review of an Application, the RUS Regional Director or the Director
            of the Power Supply Division, as appropriate, will discuss with the
            Borrower the nature of the Application and the projected review
            period required of RUS. If RUS concludes that the projected review
            period will not result in timely action on the Application, and
            after being so notified in writing by RUS the Borrower wishes to
            fund consultant services to facilitate RUS review, the Borrower
            shall submit 
            <PRTPAGE P='398' />
            to the same Director a funding proposal. The proposal shall set
            forth the following:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Identification in the heading or caption as a Notice of Proposal to
            Fund Consulting Services;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Borrower&apos;s REA/RUS designation;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Borrower&apos;s legal name and address;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A description of the Application, critical issues and concerns
            relating to the Application, time deadlines, and the consequences of
            any delays in RUS review;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A description of the consulting service(s) that would facilitate
            timely RUS review of the Application; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Such additional documents and information as RUS may request.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             RUS will review the Notice of Proposal to Fund and any additional
            information RUS deems relevant in determining whether to proceed
            with procuring Borrower funded Consultants. If RUS proposes to
            utilize Legal Consultants, RUS must obtain the concurrence of the
            Office of General Counsel (OGC) of the Department of Agriculture.
            RUS will notify the Borrower in writing of its determination.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14734'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1789:A:1789.157
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1789.157
      </num>
      <head>
        Consultant contract.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1789' sect='157' psec='' tq='N'>
              1789.157
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Consultant contract.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Federal Acquisition Regulation (FAR), 48 CFR Ch. 1, and the
            Agriculture Acquisition Regulation (AGAR), 48 CFR Ch. 4, shall apply
            to all Consultant Contracts entered into pursuant to this part
            except as provided in this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Contracts for Legal Consultants shall provide for a technical
            representative from OGC.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All Consultant Contracts shall provide for an escrow account
            funding mechanism pursuant to this part and for the
            government&apos;s sole discretion in determining whether payments
            are to be made from the Escrow Account to the Consultant.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='a_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             All Consultant Contracts shall provide that payment of all
            obligations for work performed thereunder must be satisfied by
            amounts available in the Escrow Account; with the exception of the
            annual retainer fee, if any, Consultants shall not be entitled to
            any payments from the government.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The provisions of paragraph (a) of this section shall be given
            prominent emphasis in requests for proposals issued under this part.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14735'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1789:A:1789.158
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1789.158
      </num>
      <head>
        Implementation.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1789' sect='158' psec='' tq='N'>
              1789.158
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Implementation.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon making a determination to go forward with Borrower funding for
            consulting services, RUS shall initiate a procurement request for a
            Consultant to provide the services. The government may either
            contract with a Consultant on a case by case basis or elect to use a
            Consultant pursuant to an outstanding Retainer Contract. The
            Borrower will not be informed of the Consultant selected until such
            time as the government provides the information set forth in
            paragraph (c)(3) of this section.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the government determines to contract with a Consultant on a
            case by case basis, the government shall notify the Borrower of the
            applicable procedures.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             If the government determines to contract with a Consultant under an
            outstanding Retainer Contract, the following procedures will
            normally apply:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Pursuant to the terms of the contract, the government will prepare
            a draft Task Order requesting consultant services in connection with
            the review of the Borrower&apos;s Application. The draft Task Order
            shall set forth for the Consultant&apos;s review and acceptance, a
            description of the services to be provided and applicable time
            frames for the provision of such services.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The government will request that the Consultant:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notify the government as to the acceptability of the form and
            substance of the draft Task Order;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Notify the government as to its ability to provide a satisfactory
            conflict of interest certification consistent with the requirements
            of the FAR (48 CFR ch. 1); and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_2_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provide a cost estimate for the draft Task Order.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_3'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (3)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             When the government is satisfied with the response(s) received
            pursuant to paragraph (c)(2) of this section, the government shall
            promptly provide to the Borrower:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_3_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A copy of the draft Task Order identifying the Consultant;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_3_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Consultant&apos;s cost estimate for the draft Task Order; and
            <PRTPAGE P='399' />
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_3_iii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (iii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Contract information required to enable the Borrower to develop a
            Funding Agreement, an Escrow Agreement and an Indemnification
            Agreement (the “agreements”).
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_4'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (4)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Borrower shall develop and submit to the government for
            approval executed originals of:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_4_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The agreements; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_4_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A certified copy of a resolution of the board of directors
            authorizing the Borrower to enter into the agreements and to take
            such other action as is necessary to effect the purposes of the
            agreements.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_5'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (5)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Upon receiving written RUS approval of the agreements and the form
            and substance of the board resolution, the Borrower shall:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_5_i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Establish and fund the Escrow Account; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='3' id='c_5_ii'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (ii)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Provide written notice to the government of the Escrow Account
            number, the funding thereof, and such other information as required
            pursuant to the agreements.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='c_6'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (6)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             After the Borrower has funded the Escrow Account, the government
            shall issue Task Order(s) for consultant services in accordance with
            the terms and conditions of the applicable Retainer Contract.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14736'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1789:A:1789.159
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1789.159
      </num>
      <head>
        Contract administration.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1789' sect='159' psec='' tq='N'>
              1789.159
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Contract administration.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The government shall be solely responsible for the administration of a
          Consulting Contract and shall have complete control over the scope of
          the Consultant&apos;s work, the timetable for performance, the
          standards to be applied in determining the acceptability of
          deliverables and the approval of payment of Invoices.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14737'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1789:A:1789.160
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1789.160
      </num>
      <head>
        Access to information.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1789' sect='160' psec='' tq='N'>
              1789.160
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Access to information.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The Borrower shall not have rights in nor right of access to the work
          product of the Consultant. All analyses, studies, opinions, memoranda,
          and other documents and information provided by the Consultant
          pursuant to a Consulting Contract may be released and made available
          to the Borrower only with the approval of RUS. This section does not
          restrict release of information by RUS pursuant to the Freedom of
          Information Act (
          <aref type='USC'>
            <subref title='5' sect='552' note='' psec='#a_2' tq='N' target='http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/5/552.html#a_2'>
              5 U.S.C. 552(a)(2)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ) or other legal process.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14738'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1789:A:1789.161
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1789.161
      </num>
      <head>
        Conflicts of interest.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1789' sect='161' psec='' tq='N'>
              1789.161
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Conflicts of interest.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          The standard for determining organizational conflicts of interest
          shall be as set forth in the FAR 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SUBPART'>
            subpart 
            <subref title='7' part='9' subpart='5' tq='N'>
              9.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
           (
          <aref type='CFR'>
            48 CFR part 
            <subref title='48' part='9' tq='N'>
              9
            </subref>
          </aref>
          , 
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SUBPART'>
            subpart 
            <subref title='7' part='9' subpart='5' tq='N'>
              9.5
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ); however, the identification of the existence of an organizational
          conflict of interest may be made by either the Administrator or the
          cognizant Contracting Officer. In the event an organizational conflict
          of interest is determined to exist, the cognizant Contracting Officer
          shall take the actions prescribed at FAR 9.504 (
          <aref type='CFR'>
            48 CFR 
            <subref title='48' part='9' sect='504' psec='' tq='N'>
              9.504
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ) to attempt to avoid, neutralize or mitigate the conflict. Should
          these actions be deemed by the Administrator and the Contracting
          Officer to adequately resolve the conflict, the contracting action
          with the offeror/contractor may proceed. Should the Administrator or
          the Contracting Officer determine that an organizational conflict of
          interest still exists such that contract award or other contracting
          action cannot be taken (award of task/delivery order, etc.) the
          offeror/contractor shall be so informed by the Contracting Officer and
          be provided a reasonable opportunity to respond in accordance with FAR
          9.504(e) (
          <aref type='CFR'>
            48 CFR 
            <subref title='48' part='9' sect='504' psec='#e' tq='N'>
              9.504(e)
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ). After considering the contractor&apos;s response, if it is found by
          both the Administrator and Contracting Officer to remedy the conflict
          of interest, the contracting action may proceed. If the Administrator
          and Contracting Officer determine that the contractor&apos;s response
          does not resolve the conflict of interest, yet continuing with the
          contracting action with the offeror/contractor in question is
          considered in the best interest of the United States, a waiver in
          accordance with FAR 9.503 (
          <aref type='CFR'>
            48 CFR 
            <subref title='48' part='9' sect='503' psec='' tq='N'>
              9.503
            </subref>
          </aref>
          ) may be executed. This waiver shall be submitted under the
          Contracting Officer&apos;s signature and approved by the
          Administrator. The Administrator has been delegated Head of
          Contracting Activity authority by the USDA Senior Procurement
          Executive solely for the purpose of waiver approval.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14739'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1789:A:1789.162
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1789.162
      </num>
      <head>
        Indemnification agreement.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1789' sect='162' psec='' tq='N'>
              1789.162
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Indemnification agreement.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          As a condition of approving Borrower funding, the government will
          require the Borrower to enter into an Indemnification Agreement, in
          form and substance satisfactory to RUS, providing 
          <PRTPAGE P='400' />
          that the Borrower will indemnify and hold harmless the government and
          any officers, agents or employees of the government from any and all
          liability, including costs, fees, and settlements arising out of, or
          in any way connected with the payment of the Consultant&apos;s fee
          pursuant to the Consultant Contract. The Indemnification Agreement may
          recognize, as a condition of liability thereunder, the rights of the
          borrower to prompt notice, to use of counsel of its own choosing, and
          to participation in any settlement of a claim against which
          indemnification is sought.
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14740'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1789:A:1789.163
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1789.163
      </num>
      <head>
        Waiver.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1789' sect='163' psec='' tq='N'>
              1789.163
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Waiver.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          RUS may waive any requirement or procedure of this subpart by
          determining that its application in a particular situation would not
          be in the government&apos;s interest, except that certain provision
          that the subject contracts are subject to the provisions of the FAR
          (48 CFR ch. 1) and AGAR (48 CFR ch. 4).
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14741'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1789:A:1789.164-1789.165
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1789.164-1789.165
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1789' sect='164-1789' psec='' tq='N'>
              1789.164-1789
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .165
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14742'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1789:B:1789.166
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1789.166
      </num>
      <head>
        Terms and conditions of funding agreement.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1789' sect='166' psec='' tq='N'>
              1789.166
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Terms and conditions of funding agreement.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Funding Agreements between the Borrower and a Consultant shall be in
          form and substance satisfactory to RUS and provide for, among other
          matters, the following:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Specific reference by number to the applicable Consulting Contract
            entered into between the government and the Consultant;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Specific reference by number to the applicable Task Order (where
            applicable);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A brief description of the Application;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A requirement that Invoices make specific reference to:
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_1'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (1)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The applicable contract and Task Order(s); and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='2' id='d_2'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (2)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Escrow Account from which payment is to be made;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A requirement that the Final Invoice for a Task Order be clearly
            identified as such;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A description of the services to be provided by the Consultant to
            RUS and the applicable time frames for the provision of such
            services;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Agreement that the Borrower shall pay for the Consultant services
            provided to RUS under the applicable contract through an Escrow
            Account established pursuant to an Escrow Agreement, the Consultant
            shall not provide services to RUS under the applicable contract
            unless there are sufficient funds in the Escrow Account to pay for
            such services, the Consultant shall seek compensation for services
            provided under the applicable contract from, and only from, funds
            made available through the Escrow Account, and the Consultant must
            submit all Invoices to the government for approval.
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A form of Escrow Agreement satisfactory to the Borrower, Consultant
            and the designated Third-party Commercial Institution;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='i'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (i)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             A schedule setting forth when and in what amounts the Borrower
            shall fund the Escrow Account;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='j'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (j)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Acknowledgment by the Consultant of the Indemnification Agreement
            provided by the Borrower to the government; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='k'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (k)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Funding Agreement shall not be effective unless and until
            approved in writing by RUS.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14743'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1789:B:1789.167
      </extid>
      <num st='1'>
        1789.167
      </num>
      <head>
        Terms and conditions of escrow agreement.
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            § 
            <subref title='7' part='1789' sect='167' psec='' tq='N'>
              1789.167
            </subref>
          </aref>
        </SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>
          Terms and conditions of escrow agreement.
        </SUBJECT>
        <P>
          Escrow Agreements between and among the Borrower, Consultant and
          Third-party Commercial Institution shall be in form and substance
          satisfactory to RUS and provide for, among other matters, the
          following:
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='a'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (a)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Specific reference by number to the applicable contract for
            services;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='b'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (b)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Specific reference by number to the applicable Task Order;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='c'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (c)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Specific reference by number to the Escrow Account into which funds
            are to be deposited;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='d'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (d)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Invoices to specifically identify the applicable contract and Task
            Order(s);
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='e'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (e)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             Funds to be held in the Escrow Account by the escrow agent until
            paid to the Consultant pursuant to the government&apos;s
            authorization;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='f'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (f)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Escrow Account to be closed and all remaining funds remitted to
            
            <PRTPAGE P='401' />
            the Borrower after payment of the Final Invoice, unless otherwise
            directed by the government;
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='g'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (g)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The government, the Consultant and the Borrower to have the right
            to be informed, in a timely manner and in such form as they may
            reasonably request, as to the status of and activity in the Escrow
            Account; and
          </text>
        </P>
        <P>
          <npcatch lev='1' id='h'>
            <enum src='gpotxt' cln='1'>
              (h)
            </enum>
          </npcatch>
          <text>
             The Escrow Agreement shall not be effective unless and until
            approved in writing by RUS.
          </text>
        </P>
      </contents>
    </section>
    <section orderid='14744'>
      <extid>
        lii:cfr:2013:7:0:B:XVII:-:1789:B:1789.168-1789.175
      </extid>
      <num st='2'>
        1789.168-1789.175
      </num>
      <head>
        [Reserved]
      </head>
      <citation />
      <contents>
        <SECTNO>
          <aref type='CFR-TIC-SECT'>
            §§ 
            <subref title='7' part='1789' sect='168-1789' psec='' tq='N'>
              1789.168-1789
            </subref>
          </aref>
          .175
        </SECTNO>
        <RESERVED>
          [Reserved]
        </RESERVED>
      </contents>
    </section>
  </part>
</lii_cfr_xml>